The/DT/O offer/NN/O came/VBD/O just/RB/O prior/RB/O to/TO/O arguments/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG over/IN/O whether/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG should/MD/O be/VB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O into/IN/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O operating/NN/O pact/NN/O with/IN/O Gannett/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Detroit/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O led/VBD/O by/IN/O Birmingham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O publicist/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON McMaster/NNP/I-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O name/VB/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O banker/NN/O backing/VBG/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O or/CC/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O its/PRP$/O members/NNS/O will/MD/O contribute/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O paper/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O rebuffed/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O McMaster/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O earlier/JJR/O requests/NNS/O for/IN/O access/NN/O to/TO/O Free/NNP/B-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG financial/JJ/O statements/NNS/O ././O
