It/PRP/O was/VBD/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O routine/JJ/O courtesy/NN/O call/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O after/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O pleasantries/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O unexpectedly/RB/O got/VBD/O serious/JJ/O ././O
Would/MD/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O like/VB/O a/DT/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ?/./O
The/DT/O visitors/NNS/O then/RB/O listed/VBD/O technologies/NNS/O up/IN/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O launch/NN/O services/NNS/O and/CC/O propulsion/NN/O hardware/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O were/VBD/O just/RB/O surprised/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Tad/NNP/B-PERSON Inada/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O NASDA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O director/NN/O for/IN/O international/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Shocked/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O ``/``/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O areas/NNS/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O behind/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Shapovalov/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Soviet/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O obtained/VBN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O development/NN/O of/IN/O Cosmos/NNP/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O space/NN/O program/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O technologies/NNS/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O see/VB/O anywhere/RB/O else/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O sales/NNS/O pitch/NN/O might/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O as/RB/O farfetched/JJ/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O despite/IN/O its/PRP$/O image/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O technology/NN/O superpower/NN/O ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O weaknesses/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O world/NN/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O semiconductors/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O behind/RB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O computers/NNS/O that/WDT/O use/VBP/O those/DT/O chips/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O world/NN/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O auto/NN/O manufacturing/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O aviation/NN/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O struggling/VBG/O ,/,/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O space/NN/O program/NN/O is/VBZ/O years/NNS/O behind/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O Europeans/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O also/RB/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O better/JJR/O use/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O considerable/JJ/O expertise/NN/O in/IN/O theoretical/JJ/O science/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O helped/VBN/O them/PRP/O win/VB/O twice/RB/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O Nobel/NNP/O science/NN/O prizes/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O ././O
Where/WRB/O they/PRP/O lag/VBP/O behind/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O turning/VBG/O the/DT/O scientific/JJ/O inventiveness/NN/O into/IN/O improved/VBN/O production/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O contrast/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O have/VBP/O proved/VBN/O adept/JJ/O at/IN/O making/VBG/O use/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O inventions/NNS/O ././O
Kobe/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG adopted/VBD/O Soviet/JJ/O casting/VBG/O technology/NN/O in/IN/O 1966/CD/O and/CC/O used/VBD/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O 14/CD/O years/NNS/O until/IN/O it/PRP/O developed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O system/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O will/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O journalist/NN/O into/IN/O space/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O Japanese/NN/O to/TO/O go/VB/O into/IN/O orbit/NN/O ././O
Soviet/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O their/PRP$/O technology/NN/O abroad/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O appear/VB/O to/TO/O worry/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O principal/JJ/O ally/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O never/RB/O opposed/VBN/O the/DT/O development/NN/O of/IN/O economic/JJ/O relations/NNS/O between/IN/O our/PRP$/O allies/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Frankly/NNP/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O to/TO/O get/VB/O hooked/JJ/O on/IN/O anybody/NN/O 's/POS/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O least/JJS/O of/IN/O all/DT/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
Under/IN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON perestroika/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O have/VBP/O sought/VBN/O economic/JJ/O ties/NNS/O all/DT/O over/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O new/JJ/O export/NN/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O delegation/NN/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O push/VB/O more/JJR/O space/NN/O technologies/NNS/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O target/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O representatives/NNS/O of/IN/O Keidanren/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O business/NN/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O visited/VBD/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O explore/VB/O exports/NNS/O and/CC/O investments/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O help/VB/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
Out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O blue/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Soviet/NNP/I-ORG Chamber/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG handed/VBD/O over/RP/O details/NNS/O on/IN/O 59/CD/O technologies/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O might/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O ././O
These/DT/O mainly/RB/O involved/VBD/O such/JJ/O areas/NNS/O as/IN/O materials/NNS/O --/:/O advanced/JJ/O soldering/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O medical/JJ/O developments/NNS/O derived/VBN/O from/IN/O experimentation/NN/O in/IN/O space/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O artificial/JJ/O blood/NN/O vessels/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O main/JJ/O motive/NN/O is/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O cash/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O direct/JJ/O technology/NN/O flow/NN/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O they/PRP/O also/RB/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O benefit/VB/O from/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O manufacturing/NN/O expertise/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O contemplating/VBG/O a/DT/O flexible/JJ/O system/NN/O under/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O possible/JJ/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O technology/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O jointly/RB/O and/CC/O even/RB/O to/TO/O market/VB/O it/PRP/O jointly/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O find/VBP/O Soviet/JJ/O technology/NN/O desirable/JJ/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O discussions/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O fraught/JJ/O with/IN/O political/JJ/O complications/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O stinging/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O international/JJ/O backlash/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O of/IN/O sensitive/JJ/O military/JJ/O technology/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O by/IN/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Toshiba/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O many/JJ/O Japanese/NNS/O are/VBP/O eager/JJ/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O appearing/VBG/O to/TO/O help/VB/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O in/IN/O any/DT/O way/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O hurdle/NN/O concerns/VBZ/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O attempts/NNS/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O relinquish/VB/O its/PRP$/O post-World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O control/NN/O of/IN/O four/CD/O islands/NNS/O north/RB/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
So/IN/O far/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O have/VBP/O provided/VBN/O only/RB/O the/DT/O sketchiest/JJS/O information/NN/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O business/NN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O shown/VBN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O impressive/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O My/PRP$/O impression/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O anything/NN/O which/WDT/O arouses/VBZ/O our/PRP$/O interest/NN/O at/IN/O first/JJ/O glance/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O an/DT/O official/NN/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Ministry/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Industry/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Gumbel/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
