Revco/NNP/B-ORG reacted/VBD/O cautiously/RB/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O would/MD/O add/VB/O $/$/O 260/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O debt/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O highly/RB/O leveraged/VBN/O company/NN/O ././O
Revco/NNP/B-ORG insists/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O is/VBZ/O simply/RB/O an/DT/O ``/``/O expression/NN/O of/IN/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O because/IN/O under/IN/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O Revco/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O ``/``/O exclusivity/NN/O rights/NNS/O ''/''/O until/IN/O Feb./NNP/O 28/CD/O ././O
Those/DT/O rights/NNS/O prevent/VBP/O anyone/NN/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O Revco/NNP/B-ORG from/IN/O proposing/VBG/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O financial/JJ/O adviser/NN/O for/IN/O Revco/NNP/B-ORG bondholders/NNS/O ,/,/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Schulte/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O of/IN/O Chilmark/NNP/B-ORG Partners/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O mixed/VBN/O reactions/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O feared/VBD/O a/DT/O Revco/NNP/B-ORG reorganization/NN/O might/MD/O force/VB/O bondholders/NNS/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O cheap/JJ/O deal/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Bass/NNP/B-PERSON group/NN/O 's/POS/O offer/NN/O would/MD/O give/VB/O them/PRP/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O ././O
Revco/NNP/B-ORG received/VBD/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O Oct./NNP/O 20/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O issued/VBD/O a/DT/O response/NN/O yesterday/NN/O only/RB/O after/IN/O a/DT/O copy/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O was/VBD/O made/VBN/O public/NN/O by/IN/O bondholders/NNS/O ././O
Acadia/NNP/B-ORG Partners/NNP/I-ORG Limited/NNP/I-ORG Partnership/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Fort/NNP/B-GPE Worth/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O partnership/NN/O that/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Robert/NNP/I-ORG M./NNP/I-ORG Bass/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O made/VBD/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bass/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Fort/NNP/B-GPE Worth/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Sales/NNS/O were/VBD/O $/$/O 597.8/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O up/RB/O 2.4/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Twinsburg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O before/IN/O depreciation/NN/O and/CC/O amortization/NN/O increased/VBD/O 51/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O $/$/O 9.2/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 6.1/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Acadia/NNP/B-ORG Partners/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Bass/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O partnership/NN/O also/RB/O includes/VBZ/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Equitable/NNP/B-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Assurance/NNP/I-ORG Society/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O offer/NN/O consists/VBZ/O of/IN/O $/$/O 410.5/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O cash/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O in/IN/O notes/NNS/O ././O
Acadia/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O sell/VB/O up/IN/O to/TO/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O equity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O reorganized/VBN/O company/NN/O to/TO/O creditors/NNS/O and/CC/O bondholders/NNS/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O cash/NN/O distribution/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O creditors/NNS/O and/CC/O bondholders/NNS/O would/MD/O receive/VB/O no/DT/O discount/NN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Revco/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O Boake/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Sells/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O both/DT/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O bondholders/NNS/O have/VBP/O put/VBN/O forth/RB/O reorganization/NN/O plans/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O little/JJ/O progress/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O made/VBN/O since/IN/O negotiations/NNS/O began/VBD/O this/DT/O summer/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O met/VBN/O with/IN/O representatives/NNS/O from/IN/O Acadia/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Any/DT/O reorganization/NN/O proposal/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sells/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O assess/VB/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O must/MD/O be/VB/O agreed/VBN/O upon/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O bondholders/NNS/O ,/,/O banks/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
Revco/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O claims/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Schulte/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O met/VBD/O with/IN/O Acadia/NNP/B-ORG representatives/NNS/O on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 10/CD/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O certainly/RB/O a/DT/O responsible/JJ/O offer/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O steal/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O middle/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O night/NN/O ././O
