Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O close/JJ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O back/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O recorded/VBN/O music/NN/O and/CC/O music/NN/O publishing/NN/O company/NN/O in/IN/O partnership/NN/O with/IN/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON Azoff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O as/IN/O head/NN/O of/IN/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG MCA/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O comment/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O did/VBD/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O where/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O also/RB/O been/VBN/O discussing/VBG/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O venture/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON reportedly/RB/O was/VBD/O bored/VBN/O and/CC/O frequently/RB/O clashed/VBN/O with/IN/O top/JJ/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O issues/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O compensation/NN/O and/CC/O business/NN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O was/VBD/O eager/JJ/O to/TO/O return/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O entrepreneurial/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O financial/JJ/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O ././O
