The/DT/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O had/VBD/O approached/VBN/O Ms./NNP/O Midler/NNP/B-PERSON about/IN/O appearing/VBG/O ,/,/O but/CC/O she/PRP/O declined/VBD/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O a/DT/O longstanding/JJ/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O refusing/VBG/O advertising/NN/O work/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O jury/NN/O trial/NN/O said/VBD/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O insufficient/JJ/O evidence/NN/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG liable/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O award/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O far/RB/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O punitive/JJ/O damages/NNS/O ,/,/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Midler/NNP/B-PERSON sought/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O force/VB/O Madison/NNP/O Avenue/NNP/O to/TO/O further/RBR/O rethink/VB/O how/WRB/O they/PRP/O use/VBP/O famous/JJ/O songs/NNS/O in/IN/O ads/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O spawned/VBD/O several/JJ/O suits/NNS/O ,/,/O reportedly/RB/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O action/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O heirs/NNS/O of/IN/O singer/NN/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Darin/NNP/I-PERSON against/IN/O McDonald/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG over/IN/O its/PRP$/O ``/``/O Mac/NNP/O Tonight/NNP/O ''/''/O TV/NN/O commercials/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O rough/JJ/O parody/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Darin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Mack/NNP/O the/DT/O Knife/NNP/O ''/''/O trademark/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Sinatra/NNP/B-PERSON sued/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O ``/``/O These/DT/O Boots/NNP/O are/NNP/O Made/NNP/O for/IN/O Walkin/NNP/O '/''/O ''/''/O song/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O am/VBP/O not/RB/O sure/JJ/O that/IN/O judges/NNS/O ,/,/O many/DT/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O I/PRP/O like/VBP/O very/RB/O much/RB/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O proper/JJ/O repositories/NNS/O for/IN/O making/VBG/O distinctions/NNS/O about/IN/O pop/NN/O singers/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Kurnit/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE advertising/NN/O lawyer/NN/O ././O
Joanne/NNP/B-PERSON Lipman/NNP/I-PERSON contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
