If/IN/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O somethin'/NN/O strange/JJ/O in/IN/O your/PRP$/O neighborhood/NN/O .../:/O
If/IN/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O something/NN/O '/''/O weird/JJ/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O look/VB/O good/JJ/O ././O
Who/WP/O ya/PRP/O gon/VB/O na/TO/O call/VB/O ?/./O
For/IN/O starters/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O people/NNS/O call/VBP/O Ed/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Lorraine/NNP/B-PERSON Warren/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
When/WRB/O it/PRP/O comes/VBZ/O to/TO/O busting/VBG/O ghosts/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Monroe/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O couple/NN/O are/VBP/O perfect/JJ/O demons/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O claim/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O busted/VBN/O spirits/NNS/O ,/,/O poltergeists/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O spooks/NNS/O in/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O houses/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O now/RB/O get/VBP/O three/CD/O or/CC/O four/CD/O ``/``/O legitimate/JJ/O ''/''/O calls/VBZ/O a/DT/O week/NN/O from/IN/O people/NNS/O harried/VBN/O by/IN/O haunts/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O firmly/RB/O believe/VBP/O in/IN/O angels/NNS/O ,/,/O devils/NNS/O and/CC/O ghosts/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O business/NN/O card/NN/O identifies/VBZ/O him/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O demonologist/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O psychics/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O work/VB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O your/PRP$/O house/NN/O still/RB/O seems/VBZ/O haunted/VBN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O call/VB/O any/DT/O one/CD/O of/IN/O a/DT/O swelling/VBG/O band/NN/O of/IN/O skeptics/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Busch/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
A/DT/O professional/JJ/O magician/NN/O and/CC/O musician/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O heads/VBZ/O the/DT/O Pittsburgh/NNP/B-GPE branch/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Scientific/NNP/I-ORG Investigation/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Paranormal/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Busch/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O scientific/JJ/O explanation/NN/O for/IN/O all/DT/O haunts/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O even/RB/O tell/VB/O you/PRP/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O encourage/VB/O the/DT/O spirits/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O All/DT/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O is/VBZ/O eat/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O pizza/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O then/RB/O go/VB/O to/TO/O bed/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O 'll/MD/O have/VB/O weird/JJ/O dreams/NNS/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Either/CC/O way/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O ghostbusting/NN/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O like/IN/O gangbusters/NNS/O ././O
Tales/NNS/O of/IN/O haunts/NNS/O and/CC/O horrors/NNS/O are/VBP/O proliferating/VBG/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O Elm/NNP/B-FAC Streets/NNPS/I-FAC and/CC/O Amityvilles/NNPS/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O get/VBP/O calls/NNS/O nearly/RB/O every/DT/O day/NN/O from/IN/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O ghosts/NNS/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O house/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Raymond/NNP/B-PERSON Hyman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O skeptical/JJ/O psychology/NN/O professor/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Oregon/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O opinion/NN/O poll/NN/O published/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O October/NNP/O issue/NN/O of/IN/O Parents/NNP/B-ORG Magazine/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O of/IN/O those/DT/O queried/VBN/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O ghosts/NNS/O or/CC/O spirits/NNS/O make/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O known/VBN/O to/TO/O people/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O movies/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O books/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O tabloids/NNS/O --/:/O even/RB/O Nancy/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O boosting/VBG/O this/DT/O stuff/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Kurtz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O philosophy/NN/O professor/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/I-ORG Buffalo/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O heads/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Scientific/NNP/I-ORG Investigation/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Paranormal/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O formed/VBN/O in/IN/O 1967/CD/O ,/,/O now/RB/O has/VBZ/O 60/CD/O chapters/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O spirits/NNS/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O hardly/RB/O care/VB/O less/RBR/O whether/CC/O people/NNS/O do/VBP/O or/CC/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O in/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
They/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O give/VB/O a/DT/O nod/NN/O to/TO/O human/JJ/O sensibilities/NNS/O by/IN/O celebrating/VBG/O Halloween/NNP/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O spooks/NNS/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O just/RB/O another/DT/O day/NN/O of/IN/O ectoplasmic/JJ/O business/NN/O as/IN/O usual/JJ/O ,/,/O ghostbusters/NNS/O say/VBP/O ;/:/O the/DT/O holiday/NN/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O occasion/VB/O no/DT/O unusual/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O ghost/NN/O reports/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O personally/RB/O bested/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 50/CD/O haunts/NNS/O ,/,/O from/IN/O aliens/NNS/O to/TO/O poltergeists/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON heads/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Kentucky/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Science/NNP/I-ORG Educators/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Skeptics/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Like/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Ghostbusters/NNS/O ,/,/O Kentucky/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O stand/VBP/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O roll/VB/O when/WRB/O haunts/NNS/O get/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O hand/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O careen/VB/O around/RP/O in/IN/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O Cadillac/NN/B-ORG ,/,/O wear/VB/O funny/JJ/O suits/NNS/O or/CC/O blast/VB/O away/RP/O at/IN/O slimy/JJ/O spirits/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON drives/VBZ/O a/DT/O 1987/CD/O Chevy/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O usually/RB/O wears/VBZ/O a/DT/O tweed/NN/O jacket/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O ghostbusting/NN/O forays/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O never/RB/O met/VBN/O a/DT/O ghost/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O explained/VBN/O away/RP/O by/IN/O perfectly/RB/O natural/JJ/O means/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
When/WRB/O a/DT/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE woman/NN/O complained/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O ghost/NN/O was/VBD/O haunting/VBG/O her/PRP$/O attic/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON discovered/VBD/O a/DT/O rat/NN/O dragging/VBG/O a/DT/O trap/NN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O rafters/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O weather/NN/O cools/VBZ/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O hobos/NNS/O often/RB/O hole/VBP/O up/RP/O in/IN/O abandoned/VBN/O houses/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O see/VBP/O activity/NN/O in/IN/O there/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O thing/NN/O you/PRP/O know/VBP/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBN/O a/DT/O haunting/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Stinnett/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O never/RB/O believed/VBD/O in/IN/O ghosts/NNS/O before/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O lately/RB/O her/PRP$/O vacuum/NN/O cleaner/NN/O turned/VBD/O itself/PRP/O on/RP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O telephone/NN/O flew/VBD/O off/IN/O its/PRP$/O stand/NN/O ,/,/O doors/NNS/O slammed/VBD/O inexplicably/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O she/PRP/O heard/VBD/O footsteps/NNS/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O empty/JJ/O kitchen/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O doing/VBG/O the/DT/O laundry/NN/O and/CC/O nearly/RB/O broke/VBD/O my/PRP$/O neck/NN/O running/VBG/O upstairs/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O there/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O nobody/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O eyes/NNS/O wide/JJ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O recollection/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON hears/VBZ/O her/PRP/O out/RP/O ,/,/O pokes/VBZ/O around/RP/O a/DT/O bit/NN/O ,/,/O asks/VBZ/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O questions/NNS/O and/CC/O proposes/VBZ/O some/DT/O explanations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O flying/VBG/O telephone/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O tangle/VBP/O the/DT/O base/NN/O cord/NN/O around/IN/O a/DT/O chair/NN/O leg/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O receiver/NN/O does/VBZ/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O fly/VB/O off/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O ghostly/JJ/O footsteps/NNS/O :/:/O ``/``/O Interstate/NNP/B-FAC 64/CD/I-FAC is/VBZ/O a/DT/O block/NN/O away/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O heavy/JJ/O traffic/NN/O can/MD/O sure/RB/O set/VB/O a/DT/O house/NN/O to/TO/O vibrating/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O sure/RB/O he/PRP/O 's/POS/O explained/VBD/O everything/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mrs./NNP/O Stinnett/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O grudgingly/RB/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O are/VBP/O some/DT/O things/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O gone/VBN/O on/RP/O here/RB/O that/IN/O nobody/NN/O can/MD/O explain/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON promises/VBZ/O to/TO/O return/VB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O haunting/NN/O continues/VBZ/O ././O
For/IN/O especially/RB/O stubborn/JJ/O haunts/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON carries/VBZ/O a/DT/O secret/JJ/O weapon/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O vial/NN/O of/IN/O cornstarch/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O tell/VBP/O people/NNS/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O groundup/JJ/O bones/NNS/O of/IN/O saints/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O sprinkle/VBP/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O around/RP/O and/CC/O tell/VBP/O the/DT/O demons/NNS/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O reassuring/VBG/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O usually/RB/O works/VBZ/O ././O ''/''/O
Oregon/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Hyman/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O investigated/VBN/O claims/NNS/O of/IN/O flying/VBG/O cats/NNS/O ,/,/O apparitions/NNS/O and/CC/O bouncing/VBG/O chandeliers/NNS/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O come/VBN/O up/RP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O plausible/JJ/O explanation/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O for/IN/O every/DT/O one/CD/O ././O
``/``/O Invariably/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O eyewitnesses/NNS/O are/VBP/O untrustworthy/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
To/TO/O viewers/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O distance/NN/O ,/,/O visitors/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O spot/NN/O seemed/VBD/O to/TO/O shrink/VB/O disproportionately/RB/O ,/,/O relative/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O background/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O magazine/NN/O called/VBN/O in/RP/O Mr./NNP/O Hyman/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O showed/VBD/O up/RP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O carpenter/NN/O 's/POS/O level/NN/O ,/,/O carefully/RB/O measured/VBN/O every/DT/O surface/NN/O and/CC/O showed/VBD/O how/WRB/O the/DT/O apparent/JJ/O shrinkage/NN/O was/VBD/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O perspective/NN/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O very/RB/O striking/JJ/O illusion/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Hyman/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O now/RB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O voice/NN/O dripping/VBG/O with/IN/O skepticism/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O an/DT/O illusion/NN/O nevertheless/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Canadian/NN/O wound/VBD/O up/RP/O writing/VBG/O a/DT/O check/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Rev./NNP/O Alphonsus/NNP/B-PERSON Trabold/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O theology/NN/O professor/NN/O and/CC/O exorcism/NN/O expert/NN/O at/IN/O St./NNP/B-ORG Bonaventure/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Olean/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O frequently/RB/O is/VBZ/O asked/VBN/O to/TO/O exorcise/VB/O unruly/JJ/O spirits/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O often/RB/O obliges/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O On/IN/O certain/JJ/O occasions/NNS/O a/DT/O spirit/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O earthbound/JJ/O and/CC/O make/VB/O itself/PRP/O known/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O happens/VBZ/O ././O ''/''/O
Father/NNP/O Trabold/NNP/B-PERSON often/RB/O uses/VBZ/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O calls/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O therapeutic/JJ/O exorcism/NN/O ''/''/O :/:/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O prayers/NNS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O admonition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O spirit/NN/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O the/DT/O person/NN/O believes/VBZ/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O evil/JJ/O spirit/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O ask/VBP/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O gone/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O suggestion/NN/O itself/PRP/O may/MD/O do/VB/O the/DT/O healing/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O sometimes/RB/O more/RBR/O energetic/JJ/O attacks/NNS/O are/VBP/O required/VBN/O ././O
To/TO/O wrestle/VB/O with/IN/O a/DT/O demon/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O house/NN/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O Litchfield/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O woman/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Warrens/NNS/B-PERSON recently/RB/O called/VBD/O in/RP/O an/DT/O exorcist/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Rev./NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON McKenna/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O dissident/JJ/O clergyman/NN/O who/WP/O hews/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Catholic/NNP/I-ORG Church/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG old/JJ/O Latin/NNP/O liturgy/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O attend/VBP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O so/RB/O does/VBZ/O a/DT/O television/NN/O crew/NN/O from/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON pronounces/VBZ/O the/DT/O Litchfield/NNP/B-GPE case/NN/O ``/``/O your/PRP$/O typical/JJ/O demonic/JJ/O infestation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O Scottish/JJ/O dwarf/NN/O built/VBD/O the/DT/O small/JJ/O red/JJ/O house/NN/O 110/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O and/CC/O now/RB/O his/PRP$/O demonic/JJ/O ghost/NN/O haunts/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O owner/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O begs/VBZ/O anonymity/NN/O ,/,/O asserts/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O dwarf/NN/O ,/,/O appearing/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O dark/JJ/O shadow/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O manhandled/VBN/O her/PRP/O ,/,/O tossing/VBG/O her/PRP/O around/IN/O the/DT/O living/NN/O room/NN/O and/CC/O yanking/VBG/O out/RP/O a/DT/O hank/NN/O of/IN/O hair/NN/O ././O
Two/CD/O previous/JJ/O exorcisms/NNS/O have/VBP/O failed/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O very/RB/O tenacious/JJ/O ghost/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O darkly/RB/O ././O
Father/NNP/O McKenna/NNP/B-PERSON moves/VBZ/O through/IN/O the/DT/O house/NN/O praying/VBG/O in/IN/O Latin/NNP/O ,/,/O urging/VBG/O the/DT/O demon/NN/O to/TO/O split/VB/O ././O
Suddenly/RB/O the/DT/O woman/NN/O begins/VBZ/O swaying/VBG/O and/CC/O then/RB/O writhing/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O She/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O being/VBG/O attacked/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O demon/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mrs./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON stagewhispers/VBZ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O priest/NN/O sprinkles/VBZ/O holy/JJ/O water/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O squirming/VBG/O woman/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O television/NN/O camera/NN/O grinds/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O woman/NN/O has/VBZ/O ``/``/O psychic/JJ/O burns/NNS/O ''/''/O on/IN/O her/PRP$/O back/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O confrontation/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O show/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O invisible/JJ/O ,/,/O powerful/JJ/O force/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O almost/RB/O impossible/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O layman/NN/O to/TO/O contemplate/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O solemnly/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O ghostbusting/NN/O entourage/NN/O packs/VBZ/O up/RP/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O time/NN/O though/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O we/PRP/O got/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Lyrics/NNS/O from/IN/O ``/``/O Ghostbusters/NNP/O ''/''/O by/IN/O Ray/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Parker/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON 1984/CD/O by/IN/O Golden/NNP/B-ORG Torch/NNP/I-ORG Music/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O ASCAP/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Raydiola/NNP/B-ORG Music/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O ASCAP/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
All/DT/O administrative/JJ/O rights/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE jointly/RB/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O both/DT/O companies/NNS/O ././O
International/JJ/O copyright/NN/O secured/VBN/O ././O
Made/VBN/O in/IN/O USA/NNP/B-GPE ././O
All/DT/O rights/NNS/O Reserved/VBN/O ././O
Reprinted/VBN/O by/IN/O permission/NN/O ././O
