President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O three/CD/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O cabinet/NN/O will/MD/O lead/VB/O a/DT/O presidential/JJ/O mission/NN/O to/TO/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O gauge/VB/O how/WRB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE can/MD/O help/VB/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O non-Communist/JJ/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON announced/VBD/O several/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O intended/VBD/O to/TO/O send/VB/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O mission/NN/O ,/,/O composed/VBN/O of/IN/O top/JJ/O government/NN/O aides/NNS/O and/CC/O business/NN/O and/CC/O labor/NN/O leaders/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O mission/NN/O will/MD/O visit/VB/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE from/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 29/CD/O to/TO/O Dec./NNP/O 2/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O remarks/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ceremony/NN/O marking/VBG/O Polish/NNP/O Heritage/NNP/O Month/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON announced/VBD/O that/IN/O Agriculture/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Clayton/NNP/B-PERSON Yeutter/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Mosbacher/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Labor/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON Dole/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O lead/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE group/NN/O ././O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Boskin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Advisers/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O also/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O member/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Harper/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O ConAgra/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O John/NNP/B-PERSON McGillicuddy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Manufacturers/NNP/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O among/IN/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 15/CD/O business/NN/O and/CC/O labor/NN/O representatives/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O presidential/JJ/O mission/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O group/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O ``/``/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O economic/JJ/O sectors/NNS/O where/WRB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE expertise/NN/O and/CC/O cooperation/NN/O can/MD/O indeed/RB/O make/VB/O a/DT/O difference/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O asked/VBN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O provide/VB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O economic/JJ/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O food/NN/O grants/NNS/O for/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O new/JJ/O government/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O chided/VBN/O by/IN/O Democrats/NNS/O for/IN/O failing/VBG/O to/TO/O do/VB/O more/JJR/O ././O
