The/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Pension/NNP/B-ORG Benefit/NNP/I-ORG Guaranty/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O require/VB/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O reassume/VB/O funding/NN/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 2.3/CD/O billion/CD/O shortfall/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O pension/NN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O 's/POS/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O expected/VBN/O next/JJ/O spring/NN/O ,/,/O may/MD/O affect/VB/O the/DT/O stability/NN/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O large/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O pension/NN/O plans/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O relied/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O availability/NN/O of/IN/O pension/NN/O insurance/NN/O provided/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O pension/NN/O regulatory/JJ/O and/CC/O insurance/NN/O agency/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O recently/RB/O reported/VBD/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.4/CD/O billion/CD/O and/CC/O liabilities/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O ruling/NN/O also/RB/O may/MD/O determine/VB/O how/WRB/O quickly/RB/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O its/PRP$/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O reorganization/NN/O ././O
LTV/NNP/B-ORG filed/VBD/O for/IN/O protection/NN/O under/IN/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O bankruptcy/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O filing/NN/O was/VBD/O partly/RB/O the/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 2.3/CD/O billion/CD/O shortfall/NN/O in/IN/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O three/CD/O pension/NN/O plans/NNS/O operated/VBN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O 's/POS/O employees/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O January/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O as/IN/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG continued/VBD/O operating/VBG/O while/NN/O under/IN/O reorganization/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O terminated/VBD/O the/DT/O three/CD/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG pension/NN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O its/PRP$/O insurance/NN/O liability/NN/O from/IN/O increasing/VBG/O ././O
Termination/NN/O means/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O insurance/NN/O assumes/VBZ/O the/DT/O liabilities/NNS/O and/CC/O pays/VBZ/O the/DT/O pension/NN/O benefits/NNS/O already/RB/O owed/VBN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O plans/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O workers/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O accrue/VB/O new/JJ/O benefits/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O under/IN/O pressure/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Steelworkers/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG instituted/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O program/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O retirement/NN/O benefits/NNS/O similar/JJ/O to/TO/O those/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O terminated/VBN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
Because/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O pension/NN/O agency/NN/O had/VBD/O taken/VBN/O over/RP/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O plans/NNS/O ,/,/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O responsible/JJ/O only/RB/O for/IN/O benefits/NNS/O paid/VBN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O pension/NN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O viewed/VBD/O the/DT/O creation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O plans/NNS/O as/IN/O an/DT/O abuse/NN/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O pension/NN/O law/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O transfer/VB/O the/DT/O liability/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 2.3/CD/O billion/CD/O shortfall/NN/O from/IN/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O federal/JJ/O insurance/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O also/RB/O concluded/VBD/O that/IN/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O financial/JJ/O status/NN/O had/VBD/O improved/VBN/O while/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O under/IN/O reorganization/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O September/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O ordered/VBD/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O reassume/VB/O liability/NN/O and/CC/O funding/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O original/JJ/O plans/NNS/O ././O
LTV/NNP/B-ORG challenged/VBD/O the/DT/O order/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O district/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE in/IN/O June/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O improperly/RB/O ordered/VBD/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O reassume/VB/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O plans/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O May/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE agreed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O acted/VBD/O unlawfully/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O said/VBD/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O no/DT/O evidence/NN/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG intended/VBD/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O the/DT/O pension/NN/O agency/NN/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O a/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O creation/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O benefit/NN/O plans/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O basis/NN/O for/IN/O ordering/VBG/O that/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O reassume/VB/O liability/NN/O for/IN/O old/JJ/O plans/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O disappointed/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O hear/VB/O the/DT/O case/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O the/DT/O move/NN/O will/MD/O further/RBR/O delay/VB/O its/PRP$/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O proceedings/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O come/VB/O up/RP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O sizable/JJ/O disagreement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O pension/NN/O agency/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Pension/NNP/B-ORG Benefit/NNP/I-ORG Guaranty/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG vs./IN/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
