BROKERAGE/NN/O HIRING/NN/O languishes/VBZ/O amid/IN/O market/NN/O turmoil/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O survivors/NNS/O earn/VBP/O more/JJR/O ././O
Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG counts/VBZ/O under/JJ/O 39,000/CD/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O down/RB/O 100/CD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O start/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O off/IN/O 8,500/CD/O from/IN/O after/IN/O its/PRP$/O merger/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O market/NN/O collapse/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
Another/DT/O major/JJ/O firm/NN/O has/VBZ/O cut/VBN/O 6,000/CD/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O 13/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O staff/NN/O ,/,/O since/IN/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Labor/NNP/I-ORG Statistics/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O securities/NNS/O firms/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE alone/RB/O have/VBP/O slashed/VBN/O 17,000/CD/O jobs/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O December/NNP/O 1987/CD/O peak/NN/O of/IN/O 163,000/CD/O ././O
Average/JJ/O annual/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O of/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O hung/VBN/O on/RP/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O surged/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 78,625/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O from/IN/O $/$/O 69,553/CD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
Any/DT/O hiring/VBG/O is/VBZ/O confined/VBN/O to/TO/O retail/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ././O
Illinois/NNP/B-ORG Company/NNP/I-ORG Investments/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O been/VBN/O trimming/VBG/O its/PRP$/O ranks/NNS/O until/IN/O last/JJ/O summer/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O then/RB/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O acquired/VBN/O by/IN/O Household/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Now/RB/O it/PRP/O offers/VBZ/O richer/JJR/O commissions/NNS/O to/TO/O lure/VB/O a/DT/O broker/NN/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O always/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O hire/VB/O someone/NN/O we/PRP/O consider/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O winner/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O an/DT/O Edwards/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
SKILLED/JJ/O WORKERS/NNS/O aplenty/JJ/O are/VBP/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O cope/VB/O with/IN/O earthquake/NN/O damage/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O foresee/VB/O any/DT/O shortages/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Ken/NNP/B-PERSON Allen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O official/NN/O of/IN/O Operating/NNP/B-ORG Engineers/NNP/I-ORG Local/NNP/I-ORG 3/CD/I-ORG in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Ironically/RB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O up/IN/O until/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O desperately/RB/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O jobs/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O especially/RB/O for/IN/O crane/NN/O and/CC/O bulldozer/NN/O operators/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Oct./NNP/O 17/CD/O temblor/NN/O put/VBD/O a/DT/O halt/NN/O to/TO/O much/JJ/O nonessential/JJ/O building/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O heavy/JJ/O rains/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O slowed/VBD/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O ,/,/O freeing/VBG/O construction/NN/O workers/NNS/O for/IN/O earthquake/NN/O repairs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O supply/NN/O of/IN/O experienced/VBN/O civil/JJ/O engineers/NNS/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O tighter/JJR/O ././O
In/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Transportation/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O recruiting/VBG/O in/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O engineers/NNS/O experienced/VBN/O in/IN/O road/NN/O and/CC/O bridge/NN/O design/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O offering/VBG/O only/RB/O $/$/O 39,000/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O high/JJ/O standard/NN/O of/IN/O living/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O to/TO/O choose/VB/O from/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Brent/NNP/B-PERSON Scott/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O recruiting/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O department/NN/O now/RB/O has/VBZ/O 75/CD/O openings/NNS/O and/CC/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O hire/VB/O 625/CD/O civil/JJ/O engineers/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O 15/CD/O months/NNS/O ././O
THE/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O taketh/VB/O what/WP/O the/DT/B-ORG Labor/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG giveth/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O stay/VB/O tuned/VBN/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O advisory/JJ/O letter/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O department/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O starting/VBG/O Oct./NNP/O 18/CD/O ,/,/O loans/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O limited/VBN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O parties/NNS/O in/IN/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O generally/RB/O means/VBZ/O active/JJ/O workers/NNS/O but/CC/O also/RB/O includes/VBZ/O retirees/NNS/O who/WP/O continue/VBP/O as/IN/O directors/NNS/O and/CC/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O shareholders/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O comes/VBZ/O word/NN/O that/IN/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG regulations/NNS/O being/VBG/O drafted/VBN/O could/MD/O put/VB/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O code/NN/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O make/VBP/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O retiree/NN/O shareholders/NNS/O and/CC/O directors/NNS/O but/CC/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O them/PRP/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O former/JJ/O workers/NNS/O who/WP/O usually/RB/O earned/VBD/O less/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O the/DT/O question/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O settled/VBN/O until/IN/O the/DT/O regulations/NNS/O are/VBP/O issued/VBN/O ``/``/O shortly/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O violation/NN/O could/MD/O bring/VB/O substantial/JJ/O tax/NN/O penalties/NNS/O to/TO/O both/DT/O employer/NN/O and/CC/O employees/NNS/O ././O
Frederick/NNP/B-PERSON Rumack/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Buck/NNP/B-ORG Consultants/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O asked/VBN/O Labor/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O recraft/VB/O its/PRP$/O rule/NN/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG threat/NN/O ././O
CORPORATE/JJ/O DOWNSIZING/NN/O digs/VBZ/O deeper/JJR/O ././O
Outplacement/NN/O consultant/NN/O Right/NNP/B-ORG Associates/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O the/DT/O average/JJ/O pay/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O fell/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 66,743/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O from/IN/O $/$/O 70,765/CD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ;/:/O severance/JJ/O pay/NN/O dropped/VBD/O to/TO/O 25/CD/O weeks/NNS/O from/IN/O 29/CD/O ././O
FIRST/RB/O TEACH/VB/O THYSELF/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O three/CD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O four/CD/O managers/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O accurately/RB/O state/VBP/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O packages/NNS/O ,/,/O consultant/NN/O Noble/NNP/B-PERSON Lowndes/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
MEA/NNP/O CULPA/NNP/O ././O
NO/RB/O ,/,/O YOU/PRP/O WORK/VBP/O !/./O
Only/RB/O one/CD/O in/IN/O four/CD/O companies/NNS/O with/IN/O flexible/JJ/O benefit/NN/O plans/NNS/O lets/VBZ/O workers/NNS/O buy/VB/O or/CC/O sell/VB/O vacation/NN/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O consultant/NN/O Towers/NNP/O Perrin/NNP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Employees/NNS/O like/VBP/O the/DT/O option/NN/O but/CC/O firms/NNS/O say/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O too/RB/O tough/JJ/O to/TO/O run/VB/O ././O
STUDENTS/NNS/O SHUN/VBP/O burger/NN/O flipping/VBG/O for/IN/O jobs/NNS/O tied/VBN/O to/TO/O careers/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O even/RB/O study/VBP/O ././O
Working/JJ/O students/NNS/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O explains/VBZ/O ,/,/O want/VBP/O ``/``/O some/DT/O satisfaction/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Michigan/NNP/I-ORG students/NNS/O look/VBP/O for/IN/O jobs/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O planned/VBN/O careers/NNS/O ././O
Carnegie/NNP/B-ORG Mellon/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O some/DT/O students/NNS/O conclude/VBP/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O help/VB/O their/PRP$/O careers/NNS/O most/RBS/O by/IN/O hitting/VBG/O the/DT/O books/NNS/O :/:/O ``/``/O They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O opting/VBG/O to/TO/O build/VB/O their/PRP$/O resumes/NNS/O through/IN/O good/JJ/O grades/NNS/O and/CC/O leadership/NN/O roles/NNS/O in/IN/O fraternities/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Slowing/JJ/O economies/NNS/O in/IN/O some/DT/O areas/NNS/O limit/VBP/O student/NN/O choice/NN/O ././O
Student/NN/O job/NN/O postings/NNS/O at/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG slip/VBP/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O following/VBG/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O school/NN/O says/VBZ/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O an/DT/O ample/JJ/O number/NN/O and/CC/O pay/NN/O is/VBZ/O up/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 7.20/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O from/IN/O $/$/O 6.90/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
M.B.A./NNP/O candidates/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Pittsburgh/NNP/I-ORG earn/VBP/O up/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 15/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O on/IN/O marketing/NN/O or/CC/O computer/NN/O projects/NNS/O ././O
THE/DT/O CHECKOFF/NN/O :/:/O Fiery/JJ/O ambition/NN/O :/:/O
Hyatt/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG hires/VBZ/O a/DT/O University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Wyoming/NNP/I-ORG graduate/NN/O with/IN/O degrees/NNS/O in/IN/O geology/NN/O and/CC/O petroleum/NN/O engineering/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 7.50/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O to/TO/O tend/VB/O wood/NN/O fires/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE ski/NN/O resort/NN/O .../:/O ././O
Is/VBZ/O somebody/NN/O telling/VBG/O us/PRP/O something/NN/O ?/./O
Our/PRP$/O copy/NN/O of/IN/O Racine/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG Wis/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Labor/NN/I-ORG comes/VBZ/O through/IN/O the/DT/O mail/NN/O wrapped/VBN/O around/IN/O two/CD/O sections/NNS/O of/IN/O Baseball/NNP/B-ORG Card/NNP/I-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ././O
