Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Guy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O associate/JJ/O curator/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Princeton/NNP/I-ORG Art/NNP/I-ORG Museum/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O previewing/VBG/O a/DT/O June/NNP/O antiquities/NNS/O sale/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O auction/NN/O house/NN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O recognized/VBD/O the/DT/O kylix/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O specialist/NN/O in/IN/O Attic/JJ/O pottery/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O careful/JJ/O reader/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Stolen/NNP/O Art/NNP/O Alert/NNP/O in/IN/O ``/``/O IFAR/NNP/B-ORG Reports/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O knew/VBD/O was/VBD/O stolen/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O timing/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O visit/NN/O was/VBD/O fortuitous/JJ/O ;/:/O the/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O brought/VBN/O it/PRP/O in/RB/O for/IN/O an/DT/O estimate/NN/O had/VBD/O returned/VBN/O to/TO/O collect/VB/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O waiting/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hall/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O original/JJ/O owners/NNS/O happily/RB/O repaid/VBD/O the/DT/O claim/NN/O and/CC/O took/VBD/O their/PRP$/O kylix/NN/O home/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O former/JJ/O curator/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Museum/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Cartoon/NNP/I-ORG Art/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Rye/NNP/B-GPE Brook/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O to/TO/O stealing/VBG/O and/CC/O selling/VBG/O original/JJ/O signed/VBN/O and/CC/O dated/VBN/O comic/JJ/O strips/NNS/O ,/,/O among/IN/O them/PRP/O 29/CD/O Dick/NNP/B-PERSON Tracy/NNP/I-PERSON strips/NNS/O by/IN/O Chester/NNP/B-PERSON Gould/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 77/CD/O Prince/NNP/B-PERSON Valiant/NNP/I-PERSON Sunday/NNP/O cartoons/NNS/O by/IN/O Hal/NNP/B-PERSON Foster/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O Walt/NNP/B-ORG Disney/NNP/I-ORG animation/NN/O celluloids/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Barbara/NNP/B-PERSON Hammond/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O museum/NN/O 's/POS/O director/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O theft/NN/O was/VBD/O discovered/VBN/O early/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O soon/RB/O after/RB/O Ms./NNP/O Hammond/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O her/PRP$/O post/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O get/VB/O back/RB/O the/DT/O stolen/VBN/O strips/NNS/O had/VBD/O resulted/VBN/O in/IN/O recovery/NN/O of/IN/O just/RB/O three/CD/O ././O
Two/CD/O days/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O attorney/NN/O met/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Park/NNP/B-FAC Avenue/NNP/I-FAC law/NN/O office/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O cartoon/NN/O dealer/NN/O who/WP/O expected/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O 44/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O important/JJ/O stolen/VBN/O strips/NNS/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Russell/NNP/B-PERSON for/IN/O $/$/O 62,800/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O 500/CD/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O community/NN/O service/NN/O and/CC/O restitution/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O museum/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 45,000/CD/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Virginia/NNP/I-ORG Art/NNP/I-ORG Museum/NNP/I-ORG certainly/RB/O would/MD/O agree/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O reported/VBN/O stolen/VBN/O in/IN/O transit/NN/O en/IN/O route/NN/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O February/NNP/O ././O
Months/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Greek/JJ/O vase/NN/O arrived/VBN/O in/IN/O good/JJ/O condition/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O museum/NN/O in/IN/O Charlottesville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O having/VBG/O inexplicably/RB/O traveled/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O circuitous/JJ/O route/NN/O through/IN/O Nairobi/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Two/CD/O Mexican/JJ/O college/NN/O dropouts/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O professional/JJ/O art/NN/O thieves/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O arrested/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O 1985/CD/O Christmas/NNP/O Eve/NNP/O burglary/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Museum/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Anthropology/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O offered/VBD/O a/DT/O reward/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O return/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O antiquities/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O routine/JJ/O police/NN/O work/NN/O led/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O recovery/NN/O ././O
Information/NN/O from/IN/O an/DT/O arrested/VBN/O drug/NN/O trafficker/NN/O led/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O recovery/NN/O of/IN/O almost/RB/O all/DT/O the/DT/O stolen/VBN/O art/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O artist/NN/O 's/POS/O melancholy/JJ/O subjects/NNS/O bring/VBP/O high/JJ/O prices/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG notified/VBD/O IFAR/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O theft/NN/O in/IN/O February/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O precious/JJ/O canvas/NN/O ,/,/O cut/VBN/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O frame/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O theft/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O found/VBN/O in/IN/O nearby/JJ/O Jena/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O hidden/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O upholstery/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O easy/JJ/O chair/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O home/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O girlfriend/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O thieves/NNS/O ././O
No/DT/O charges/NNS/O were/VBD/O brought/VBN/O against/IN/O her/PRP/O ././O
Trompe/FW/O l'oeil/FW/O painting/NN/O is/VBZ/O meant/VBN/O to/TO/O fool/VB/O the/DT/O eye/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Lawrence/NNP/I-PERSON Trotter/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 35/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Kennett/NNP/B-GPE Square/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O took/VBD/O his/PRP$/O fooling/NN/O seriously/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Trotter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O painting/NN/O showed/VBD/O a/DT/O wall/NN/O of/IN/O wood/NN/O boards/NNS/O with/IN/O painted/VBN/O ribbons/NNS/O tacked/VBD/O down/RP/O in/IN/O a/DT/O rectangle/NN/O ;/:/O tucked/VBN/O behind/IN/O the/DT/O ribbons/NNS/O were/VBD/O envelopes/NNS/O ,/,/O folded/VBN/O ,/,/O faded/VBN/O and/CC/O crumpled/VBN/O papers/NNS/O and/CC/O currency/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Trotter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O fake/JJ/O Haberle/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O offered/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O bargain/NN/O price/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 25,000/CD/O with/IN/O a/DT/O phony/JJ/O story/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O belonged/VBD/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O 's/POS/O late/JJ/O aunt/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Canaan/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Conn/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O dealers/NNS/O immediately/RB/O showed/VBD/O their/PRP$/O new/JJ/O acquisition/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O expert/NN/O and/CC/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O see/VB/O it/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O fake/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O persuaded/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Trotter/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O take/VB/O it/PRP/O back/RB/O and/CC/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O help/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O FBI/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O taped/VBD/O their/PRP$/O conversation/NN/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
