The/DT/B-ORG Treasury/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG proposed/VBD/O that/IN/O banks/NNS/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O detailed/JJ/O records/NNS/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O wire/NN/O transfers/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O officials/NNS/O believe/VBP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O vehicle/NN/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O drug/NN/O traffickers/NNS/O to/TO/O move/VB/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O and/CC/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O recent/JJ/O testimony/NN/O on/IN/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG Hill/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O considering/VBG/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O reporting/NN/O requirements/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O expected/VBN/O publication/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Register/NNP/I-ORG today/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O official/JJ/O step/NN/O toward/IN/O creating/VBG/O final/JJ/O regulations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O still/RB/O working/VBG/O out/RP/O the/DT/O details/NNS/O with/IN/O bank/NN/O trade/NN/O associations/NNS/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O government/NN/O agencies/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O hand/NN/O in/IN/O fighting/VBG/O money/NN/O laundering/NN/O ././O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O possibilities/NNS/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O are/VBP/O requirements/NNS/O that/IN/O banks/NNS/O keep/VB/O records/NNS/O identifying/VBG/O the/DT/O originators/NNS/O and/CC/O recipients/NNS/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O wire/NN/O transfers/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O suggestion/NN/O would/MD/O draw/VB/O banks/NNS/O more/RBR/O directly/RB/O into/IN/O tracking/VBG/O down/RP/O money/NN/O launderers/NNS/O by/IN/O developing/VBG/O a/DT/O ``/``/O suspicious/JJ/O international/JJ/O wire/NN/O transfer/NN/O profile/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O banks/NNS/O would/MD/O use/VB/O to/TO/O spotlight/VB/O questionable/JJ/O payments/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O banks/NNS/O may/MD/O prefer/VB/O using/VBG/O a/DT/O profile/NN/O that/WDT/O targets/VBZ/O selected/VBN/O transactions/NNS/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O a/DT/O blanket/NN/O reporting/NN/O requirement/NN/O ././O
Banks/NNS/O now/RB/O are/VBP/O required/VBN/O only/RB/O to/TO/O report/VB/O cash/NN/O deposits/NNS/O or/CC/O withdrawals/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 10,000/CD/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O ././O
But/CC/O wire/NN/O transfers/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O standing/VBG/O account/NN/O --/:/O including/VBG/O those/DT/O bigger/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 10,000/CD/O --/:/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O reported/VBN/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O believe/VBP/O this/DT/O has/VBZ/O left/VBN/O a/DT/O gaping/JJ/O loophole/NN/O that/IN/O illegal/JJ/O drug/NN/O businesses/NNS/O are/VBP/O exploiting/VBG/O ././O
Authorities/NNS/O estimate/VBP/O that/IN/O revenues/NNS/O from/IN/O illegal/JJ/O drugs/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE total/VBP/O about/RB/O $/$/O 110/CD/O billion/CD/O annually/RB/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Kerry/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNP/I-ORG subcommittee/NN/O that/WDT/O oversees/VBZ/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O laundering/NN/O ,/,/O criticized/VBD/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O for/IN/O ignoring/VBG/O wire/NN/O transfers/NNS/O between/IN/O foreign/JJ/O banks/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O executed/VBN/O and/CC/O cleared/VBN/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE wire/NN/O systems/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Bankers/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O comment/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ././O
