Foothills/NNP/B-ORG Pipe/NNP/I-ORG Lines/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG filed/VBD/O an/DT/O application/NN/O with/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O 4.4/CD/O billion/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollar/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 3.74/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O pipeline/NN/O to/TO/O transport/VB/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O from/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Arctic/NNP/B-LOC to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE markets/NNS/O beginning/VBG/O in/IN/O
``/``/O Foothills/NNS/B-ORG wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O pipeline/NN/O companies/NNS/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O on/IN/O first/NN/O insofar/RB/O as/IN/O transporting/NN/O gas/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Arctic/NNP/B-LOC to/TO/O southern/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Hillary/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
At/IN/O least/JJS/O two/CD/O rival/JJ/O applications/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O emerge/VB/O in/IN/O coming/VBG/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O one/CD/O from/IN/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG PipeLines/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O pipeline/NN/O operator/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O consortium/NN/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O producers/NNS/O who/WP/O won/VBD/O conditional/JJ/O approval/NN/O this/DT/O month/NN/O from/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O National/NNP/B-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O export/VB/O about/RB/O 9.2/CD/O trillion/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC delta/NN/O gas/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE starting/VBG/O in/IN/O 1996/CD/O ././O
Foothills/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O main/JJ/O rival/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC Delta/NNP/I-LOC pipeline/NN/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG PipeLines/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Like/IN/O Foothills/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Polar/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG consortium/NN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O pipeline/NN/O directly/RB/O south/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC River/NNP/I-LOC delta/NN/O in/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O western/JJ/O Arctic/NNP/B-LOC with/IN/O an/DT/O initial/JJ/O capacity/NN/O to/TO/O transport/VB/O 1.2/CD/O billion/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O gas/NN/O daily/RB/O ././O
Industry/NN/O sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expect/VBP/O a/DT/O fierce/JJ/O battle/NN/O to/TO/O emerge/VB/O between/IN/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O monopoly/NN/O on/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O gas/NN/O transportation/NN/O east/JJ/O of/IN/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Nova/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Westcoast/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O control/VBP/O the/DT/O pipelines/NNS/O within/IN/O and/CC/O running/VBG/O west/NN/O of/IN/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O respectively/RB/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O virgin/JJ/O territory/NN/O ,/,/O unclaimed/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O nasty/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O one/CD/O observer/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O asked/VBD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O named/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O Neither/CC/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O back/VB/O down/RP/O easily/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/RP/O the/DT/O Foothills/NNP/B-ORG application/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O Gerald/NNP/B-PERSON Maier/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ``/``/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O party/NN/O to/TO/O any/DT/O transportation/NN/O system/NN/O that/WDT/O goes/VBZ/O up/RP/O there/RB/O ''/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O consider/VB/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O players/NNS/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O role/NN/O ././O
First/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O almost/RB/O double/VB/O ././O
Kent/NNP/B-PERSON Jesperson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Foothills/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O believes/VBZ/O the/DT/O project/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O viable/JJ/O if/IN/O gas/NN/O prices/NNS/O reach/VBP/O US$/$/O 3.25/CD/O a/DT/O thousand/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O by/IN/O 1995/CD/O ,/,/O in/IN/O current/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O current/JJ/O spot/NN/O price/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O US$/$/O 1.50/CD/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE gas/NN/O buyers/NNS/O must/MD/O also/RB/O decide/VB/O whether/IN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O firm/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O for/IN/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC delta/NN/O gas/NN/O or/CC/O develop/VB/O Alaskan/JJ/O reserves/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Prudhoe/NNP/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/O first/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O project/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O hold/NN/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O ././O
Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Pierce/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Foothills/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O too/RB/O early/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O whether/CC/O Alaskan/JJ/O or/CC/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC delta/JJ/O gas/NN/O would/MD/O flow/VB/O to/TO/O market/NN/O first/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O Foothills/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O regulatory/JJ/O approval/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O an/DT/O alternative/JJ/O line/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Alaska/NNP/O Natural/NNP/O Gas/NNP/O Transportation/NNP/O System/NNP/O further/RBR/O north/RB/O toward/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE ././O
If/IN/O that/DT/O option/NN/O is/VBZ/O favored/VBN/O by/IN/O gas/NN/O buyers/NNS/O and/CC/O regulators/NNS/O ,/,/O Foothills/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O build/VB/O another/DT/O smaller/JJR/O pipeline/NN/O connecting/VBG/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC Delta/NNP/I-LOC reserves/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE mainline/NN/O ././O
Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Stoneman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Shell/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O noted/VBD/O that/IN/O producers/NNS/O would/MD/O prefer/VB/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O hearings/NNS/O into/IN/O competing/VBG/O proposals/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O lengthen/VB/O the/DT/O regulatory/JJ/O review/NN/O process/NN/O and/CC/O bog/VB/O down/RP/O development/NN/O ././O
Interprovincial/NNP/B-ORG Pipe/NNP/I-ORG Line/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O pipeline/NN/O operator/NN/O rumored/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O mulling/VBG/O a/DT/O gas/NN/O pipeline/NN/O proposal/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O cards/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O for/IN/O Foothills/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O pre-emptive/JJ/O bid/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Haskayne/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O If/IN/O they/PRP/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O gives/VBZ/O them/PRP/O some/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O priority/NN/O position/NN/O ,/,/O well/UH/O ,/,/O that/DT/O 's/POS/O their/PRP$/O strategy/NN/O ././O
