Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Iacocca/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O No./NN/O 3/CD/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O will/MD/O need/VB/O to/TO/O close/VB/O one/CD/O or/CC/O two/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O assembly/NN/O plants/NNS/O because/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O slowdown/NN/O hitting/VBG/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O journal/NN/O Automotive/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Iacocca/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O say/VB/O which/WDT/O plants/NNS/O will/MD/O close/VB/O or/CC/O when/WRB/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O make/VB/O the/DT/O moves/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O system/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O the/DT/O older/JJR/O or/CC/O most/RBS/O inefficient/JJ/O capacity/NN/O has/VBZ/O got/VBD/O to/TO/O go/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O temporarily/RB/O close/VB/O the/DT/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Toledo/NNP/B-GPE plants/NNS/O recently/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O excess/JJ/O inventories/NNS/O of/IN/O vehicles/NNS/O built/VBN/O there/RB/O ././O
At/IN/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 1990/CD/O model/NN/O preview/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Lutz/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O No./NN/O 3/CD/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE manufacturers/NNS/O ,/,/O might/MD/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O realign/VB/O .../:/O capacity/NN/O ''/''/O if/IN/O market/NN/O demand/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O improve/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Iacocca/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remarks/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O specific/JJ/O indication/NN/O to/TO/O date/NN/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O plants/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O in/IN/O jeopardy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O overcapacity/NN/O problem/NN/O has/VBZ/O intensified/VBN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O foreign/JJ/O auto/NN/O makers/NNS/O beginning/VBG/O car/NN/O and/CC/O truck/NN/O production/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O Unless/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O goes/VBZ/O to/TO/O 19/CD/O million/CD/O units/NNS/O --/:/O which/WDT/O we/PRP/O all/DT/O know/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O do/VB/O --/:/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O inescapable/JJ/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O transplants/NNS/O are/VBP/O adding/VBG/O capacity/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Lutz/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Already/RB/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O closed/VBN/O the/DT/O Kenosha/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wis./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O plant/NN/O it/PRP/O acquired/VBD/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O bought/VBD/O American/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
