Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Telesis/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Bell/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O sustained/VBD/O property/NN/O damage/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 45/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE earthquake/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O mentioned/VBD/O increased/VBN/O capital/NN/O investment/NN/O by/IN/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Bell/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O network/NN/O improvements/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ginn/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O cellular/JJ/O operations/NNS/O now/RB/O serve/VBP/O about/RB/O 341,000/CD/O customers/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O 46/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O ././O
