Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O we/PRP/O read/VBP/O ,/,/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O kill/VB/O a/DT/O speech/NN/O that/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Gates/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O deputy/JJ/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O adviser/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O career/NN/O Soviet/NNP/O expert/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O give/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O student/NN/O colloquium/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O National/NNP/O Collegiate/NNP/O Security/NNP/O Conference/NNP/O ././O
We/PRP/O keep/VBP/O wondering/VBG/O what/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Gates/NNP/B-PERSON wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ././O
Dark/JJ/O hints/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O that/IN/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O hope/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O fail/VB/O ,/,/O just/RB/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O when/WRB/O Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O Quayle/NNP/B-PERSON voiced/VBD/O similar/JJ/O sentiments/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O somehow/RB/O OK/JJ/O for/IN/O Secretary/NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O say/VB/O all/DT/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O things/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O all/DT/O understand/VBP/O point/NN/O one/CD/O :/:/O Nothing/NN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE can/MD/O do/VB/O will/MD/O make/VB/O much/JJ/O difference/NN/O in/IN/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON succeeds/VBZ/O with/IN/O perestroika/FW/O ././O
They/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O relieved/VBN/O only/RB/O by/IN/O changing/VBG/O that/DT/O system/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O by/IN/O pouring/VBG/O Western/JJ/O money/NN/O into/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
GATT/NNP/B-ORG membership/NN/O will/MD/O not/RB/O matter/VB/O to/TO/O Donbas/NNP/B-GPE coal/NN/O miners/NNS/O short/JJ/O of/IN/O soap/NN/O ,/,/O nor/CC/O will/MD/O a/DT/O START/NNP/O treaty/NN/O make/VBP/O any/DT/O difference/NN/O to/TO/O Ukrainian/JJ/B-GPE nationalists/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O contradictory/NN/O in/IN/O all/DT/O this/DT/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O nice/JJ/O to/TO/O think/VB/O that/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE could/MD/O tolerate/VB/O a/DT/O reasonably/RB/O sophisticated/JJ/O ,/,/O complex/JJ/O view/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O especially/RB/O sensitive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ailment/NN/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O Beltway-itis/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Western/JJ/O interest/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON succeed/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O odds/NNS/O are/VBP/O against/IN/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O himself/PRP/O would/MD/O no/RB/O doubt/VB/O tell/VB/O you/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O outcome/NN/O depends/VBZ/O on/IN/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O ,/,/O not/RB/O on/IN/O what/WP/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O ././O
