Fletcher/NNP/B-ORG Challenge/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Petrocorp/NNP/B-ORG unit/NN/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O certain/JJ/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O interests/NNS/O from/IN/O Amoco/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Canadian/JJ/O unit/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O about/RB/O 130/CD/O million/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 110.6/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
The/DT/O proposed/VBN/O purchase/NN/O requires/VBZ/O approval/NN/O from/IN/O Investment/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O monitors/VBZ/O large/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Amoco/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O operates/VBZ/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O properties/NNS/O included/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O asset/NN/O package/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O streamline/VB/O its/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O ././O
