The/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O reached/VBD/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O with/IN/O independent/JJ/O home/NN/O delivery/NN/O dealers/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O metropolitan/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O free/VB/O the/DT/O newspaper/NN/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O home/NN/O delivery/NN/O circulation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O settlement/NN/O stemmed/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O the/DT/O dealers/NNS/O filed/VBD/O in/IN/O 1982/CD/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Times/NNP/B-ORG began/VBD/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O competing/VBG/O direct/JJ/O delivery/NN/O service/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O pact/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Times/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O pay/VB/O dealers/NNS/O $/$/O 3.6/CD/O million/CD/O over/IN/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O other/JJ/O payments/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O form/NN/O of/IN/O subsidies/NNS/O over/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O new/JJ/O customers/NNS/O started/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O dealers/NNS/O and/CC/O on/IN/O pricing/VBG/O structures/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O Times/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O charge/NN/O against/IN/O earnings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O settlement/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O involves/VBZ/O most/RBS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 300/CD/O independent/JJ/O newspaper/NN/O dealers/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O allow/VB/O the/DT/O Times/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O freely/RB/O operate/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O direct/JJ/O home/NN/O delivery/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
Home/NN/O delivery/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O fastest/JJS/O growing/VBG/O segment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Times/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 1.1/CD/O million/CD/O daily/JJ/O circulation/NN/O ././O
