Their/PRP$/O factories/NNS/O may/MD/O look/VB/O like/IN/O sets/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O Spielberg/NNP/B-PERSON movie/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O their/PRP$/O offices/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O rows/NNS/O of/IN/O clerks/NNS/O hunched/VBN/O over/IN/O ledgers/NNS/O and/CC/O abacuses/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O more/RBR/O like/IN/O scenes/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Dickens/NNP/B-PERSON novel/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O with/IN/O a/DT/O labor/NN/O shortage/NN/O and/CC/O intense/JJ/O competitive/JJ/O pressure/NN/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O efficiency/NN/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O concluding/VBG/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O choice/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O home/NN/O offices/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Yoshio/NNP/B-PERSON Hatakeyama/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Productivity/NNP/O in/IN/O Japanese/NNP/O offices/NNS/O is/VBZ/O relatively/RB/O low/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O offers/VBZ/O opportunities/NNS/O ;/:/O Americans/NNS/O are/VBP/O well/RB/O poised/VBN/O to/TO/O supply/VB/O the/DT/O weapons/NNS/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O market/NN/O for/IN/O outsiders/NNS/O to/TO/O penetrate/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O hopelessly/RB/O behind/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O certain/JJ/O technologies/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O for/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O Americans/NNS/O are/VBP/O far/RB/O better/JJR/O at/IN/O making/VBG/O PCs/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O software/NN/O that/WDT/O runs/VBZ/O them/PRP/O ././O
After/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O talking/VBG/O about/IN/O selling/VBG/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O seriously/RB/O pouring/VBG/O in/RP/O ././O
Apple/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O doubled/VBN/O its/PRP$/O staff/NN/O here/RB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Lotus/NNP/B-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O slashed/VBN/O the/DT/O lag/NN/O between/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE product/NN/O introductions/NNS/O to/TO/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O from/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O go/VB/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O way/NN/O to/TO/O catch/VB/O up/RP/O ././O
Typical/JJ/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O office/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Industry/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Machinery/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Information/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O overseeing/VBG/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O American/JJ/O PC/NN/O sales/NNS/O have/VBP/O averaged/VBN/O roughly/RB/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O annual/JJ/O growth/NN/O since/IN/O 1984/CD/O and/CC/O West/JJ/O European/JJ/O sales/NNS/O a/DT/O whopping/JJ/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O Japanese/JJ/O sales/NNS/O were/VBD/O flat/JJ/O for/IN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O Japanese/JJ/O offices/NNS/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O use/VB/O computers/NNS/O less/RBR/O efficiently/RB/O than/IN/O American/JJ/O offices/NNS/O do/VBP/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O PCs/NNS/O commonly/RB/O perform/VBP/O many/JJ/O tasks/NNS/O and/CC/O plug/VBP/O into/IN/O a/DT/O broad/JJ/O network/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O many/JJ/O desktop/NN/O terminals/NNS/O are/VBP/O limited/VBN/O to/TO/O one/CD/O function/NN/O and/CC/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O communicate/VB/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O planning/NN/O and/CC/O sales/JJ/O promotion/NN/O office/NN/O of/IN/O Nomura/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 30/CD/O computers/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O 60/CD/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O respectable/JJ/O ratio/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O machines/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O on/IN/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O desks/NNS/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O ring/VBP/O the/DT/O perimeter/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O large/JJ/O office/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O machines/NNS/O make/VBP/O charts/NNS/O for/IN/O presentations/NNS/O ././O
Others/NNS/O analyze/VBP/O the/DT/O data/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O transfer/VB/O information/NN/O from/IN/O one/CD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O ,/,/O employees/NNS/O make/VBP/O printouts/NNS/O and/CC/O enter/VBP/O the/DT/O data/NN/O manually/RB/O ././O
To/TO/O transmit/VB/O charts/NNS/O to/TO/O branch/NN/O offices/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O use/VBP/O a/DT/O fax/NN/O machine/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O efficient/JJ/O setup/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O PC/NNP/O could/MD/O perform/VB/O all/DT/O those/DT/O tasks/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O PC/NN/O software/NN/O sold/VBN/O is/VBZ/O either/DT/O for/IN/O spreadsheets/NNS/O or/CC/O for/IN/O database/NN/O analysis/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Lotus/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O those/DT/O functions/NNS/O account/VBP/O for/IN/O only/RB/O about/RB/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O software/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Machines/NNS/O dedicated/VBN/O solely/RB/O to/TO/O word/NN/O processing/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O all/DT/O but/CC/O disappeared/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O more/RBR/O common/JJ/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE than/IN/O PCs/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O about/RB/O 1/CD/O %/NN/O are/VBP/O linked/VBN/O ././O
Of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O simply/RB/O buying/VBG/O computers/NNS/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O always/RB/O solve/VB/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O American/JJ/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O erred/VBN/O by/IN/O purchasing/VBG/O technology/NN/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O understand/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O healthy/JJ/O skepticism/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O PC/NNP/O lag/NN/O ././O
Various/JJ/O cultural/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O forces/NNS/O have/VBP/O suppressed/VBN/O demand/NN/O ././O
Because/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O ``/``/O alphabet/NN/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O huge/JJ/O ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O no/DT/O history/NN/O of/IN/O typewriter/NN/O use/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O so/IN/O ``/``/O keyboard/NN/O allergy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O especially/RB/O among/IN/O older/JJR/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O common/JJ/O affliction/NN/O ././O
Top/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O executives/NNS/O often/RB/O make/VBP/O decisions/NNS/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O consensus/NN/O and/CC/O personal/JJ/O relationships/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O complex/JJ/O financial/JJ/O projections/NNS/O and/CC/O fancy/JJ/O presentations/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O management/NN/O system/NN/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O impose/VB/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O ,/,/O integrated/VBN/O computer/NN/O system/NN/O corporatewide/JJ/O ././O
Besides/IN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O computer/NN/O processing/VBG/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O language/NN/O needs/VBZ/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O memory/NN/O and/CC/O much/JJ/O processing/NN/O capability/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O screen/NN/O and/CC/O printer/NN/O need/VBP/O far/RB/O better/JJR/O definition/NN/O to/TO/O depict/VB/O accurately/RB/O the/DT/O intricate/JJ/O symbols/NNS/O ././O
Until/IN/O recently/RB/O ,/,/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O necessary/JJ/O technology/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O unavailable/JJ/O or/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O unaffordable/JJ/O ././O
Some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O estimate/VBP/O the/DT/O average/JJ/O PC/NN/O costs/VBZ/O about/RB/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O more/JJR/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE than/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O complex/JJ/O language/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O reason/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O little/JJ/O competition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O here/RB/O is/VBZ/O inefficient/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O dominated/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O giant/NN/O ,/,/O International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O early/RB/O on/RB/O ,/,/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG offered/VBD/O its/PRP$/O basic/JJ/O design/NN/O to/TO/O anybody/NN/O wanting/VBG/O to/TO/O copy/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O small/JJ/O companies/NNS/O did/VBD/O ,/,/O swiftly/RB/O establishing/VBG/O a/DT/O standard/NN/O operating/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O spurs/VBZ/O competition/NN/O and/CC/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O allows/VBZ/O users/NNS/O to/TO/O change/VB/O and/CC/O mix/VB/O brands/NNS/O easily/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O increases/VBZ/O software/NN/O firms/NNS/O '/POS/O incentive/NN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O packages/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O users/NNS/O of/IN/O virtually/RB/O any/DT/O computer/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O a/DT/O record/NN/O industry/NN/O lacked/VBD/O a/DT/O common/JJ/O standard/NN/O ,/,/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG CD/NN/O owners/NNS/O could/MD/O listen/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG version/NN/O of/IN/O Madonna/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Like/IN/O a/DT/O Prayer/NN/O ''/''/O but/CC/O not/RB/O one/CD/O made/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O Panasonic/NNP/B-ORG player/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
NEC/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O release/VB/O its/PRP$/O code/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O every/DT/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O dozen/NN/O or/CC/O so/RB/O makers/NNS/O has/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O proprietary/NN/O operating/NN/O system/NN/O --/:/O all/DT/O incompatible/JJ/O with/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG established/VBD/O its/PRP$/O standard/NN/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O falling/VBG/O behind/IN/O upstart/NN/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O ahead/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O start/NN/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O need/VB/O to/TO/O invite/VB/O in/RP/O competitive/JJ/O allies/NNS/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O big/JJ/O players/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O tried/VBN/O to/TO/O copy/VB/O the/DT/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG standard/NN/O ././O
Corporate/JJ/O pride/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O close/JJ/O ties/NNS/O common/JJ/O among/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O manufacturers/NNS/O help/VBP/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O ././O
Most/JJS/O rivals/NNS/O ``/``/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O working/NN/O relationship/NN/O with/IN/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O often/RB/O through/IN/O cross-licensing/NN/O of/IN/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/B-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG Personal/NNP/I-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Software/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG noted/VBD/O recently/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O many/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O higher/JJR/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O less/JJR/O innovation/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O tens/NNS/O of/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O software/NN/O packages/NNS/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG standard/NN/O are/VBP/O available/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O they/PRP/O say/VBP/O only/RB/O about/RB/O 8,000/CD/O are/VBP/O written/VBN/O for/IN/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
A/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Fair/NNP/B-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG warned/VBD/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG about/IN/O possible/JJ/O violations/NNS/O of/IN/O anti-monopoly/JJ/O laws/NNS/O for/IN/O discouraging/VBG/O retailers/NNS/O from/IN/O discounting/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O price/NN/O wars/NNS/O ,/,/O no/DT/O competition/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
An/DT/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O responds/VBZ/O that/IN/O prices/NNS/O are/VBP/O higher/JJR/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE because/IN/O customers/NNS/O put/VBP/O a/DT/O greater/JJR/O emphasis/NN/O on/IN/O quality/NN/O and/CC/O service/NN/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
She/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O that/IN/O some/DT/O technological/JJ/O advances/NNS/O trail/VBP/O those/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE because/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O still/RB/O import/VBP/O basic/JJ/O operating/VBG/O systems/NNS/O from/IN/O American/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O changing/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O funding/VBG/O several/JJ/O projects/NNS/O to/TO/O push/VB/O PC/NN/O use/NN/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O public/JJ/O schools/NNS/O will/MD/O get/VB/O 1.5/CD/O million/CD/O PCs/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O 15-fold/JJ/O increase/NN/O from/IN/O current/JJ/O levels/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O private/JJ/O sector/NN/O ,/,/O practically/RB/O every/DT/O major/JJ/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O setting/VBG/O explicit/JJ/O goals/NNS/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O exposure/NN/O to/TO/O computers/NNS/O ././O
Within/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Kao/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O cosmetics/NNS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O eliminate/VB/O 1,000/CD/O clerical/JJ/O jobs/NNS/O by/IN/O putting/VBG/O on/RP/O a/DT/O central/JJ/O computer/NN/O network/NN/O some/DT/O work/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O credit/NN/O reports/NNS/O ,/,/O currently/RB/O performed/VBN/O in/IN/O 22/CD/O separate/JJ/O offices/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O increasing/VBG/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O PCs/NNS/O it/PRP/O uses/VBZ/O from/IN/O 66/CD/O to/TO/O 1,000/CD/O ,/,/O Omron/NNP/B-ORG Tateishi/NNP/I-ORG Electronics/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Kyoto/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O hopes/VBZ/O not/RB/O only/JJ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O certain/JJ/O tasks/NNS/O easier/RBR/O but/CC/O also/RB/O to/TO/O transform/VB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O run/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O Managers/NNS/O have/VBP/O long/RB/O been/VBN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O supervise/VBP/O their/PRP$/O subordinates/NNS/O so/IN/O orders/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O properly/RB/O acted/VBN/O on/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O new/JJ/O managers/NNS/O will/MD/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O creators/NNS/O and/CC/O innovators/NNS/O .../:/O and/CC/O for/IN/O that/DT/O purpose/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O create/VB/O an/DT/O environment/NN/O where/WRB/O information/NN/O from/IN/O both/DT/O inside/IN/O and/CC/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O easily/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O also/RB/O shared/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O computer/NN/O makers/NNS/O now/RB/O are/VBP/O competing/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
Seiko/NNP/B-ORG Epson/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O newcomer/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O fought/VBN/O off/RP/O a/DT/O legal/JJ/O challenge/NN/O and/CC/O started/VBD/O selling/VBG/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG clones/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O won/VBN/O about/RB/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O retail/JJ/O PC/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O temporarily/RB/O dropped/VBD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O PC/NN/O business/NN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O started/VBD/O selling/VBG/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O station/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O quickly/RB/O became/VBD/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O Japanese/JJ/O company/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O country/NN/O where/WRB/O elbow/NN/O room/NN/O is/VBZ/O scarce/JJ/O ,/,/O laptop/JJ/O machines/NNS/O will/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O future/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O even/RB/O dropping/VBG/O their/PRP$/O traditional/JJ/O independence/NN/O and/CC/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O band/VB/O together/RB/O to/TO/O create/VB/O some/DT/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O standard/NN/O ././O
Two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O smaller/JJR/O makers/NNS/O joined/VBD/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Microsoft/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG umbrella/NN/O to/TO/O adopt/VB/O a/DT/O version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/B-ORG IBM/NNP/B-ORG AT/NNP/O standard/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O healthy/JJ/O ,/,/O coherent/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O market/NN/O could/MD/O also/RB/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O far/RB/O easier/RBR/O for/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O their/PRP$/O share/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O minimal/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O also/RB/O help/VB/O American/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O starting/VBG/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O open/VB/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O with/IN/O many/JJ/O other/JJ/O goods/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O share/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O PC/NN/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O far/RB/O below/IN/O that/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE makers/NNS/O have/VBP/O under/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O market/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O at/IN/O home/NN/O ././O
Though/IN/O no/DT/O formal/JJ/O trade/NN/O barriers/NNS/O exist/VBP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O difficult/JJ/O for/IN/O outsiders/NNS/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O it/PRP/O were/VBD/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O market/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O in/RB/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O or/CC/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Eckhard/NNP/B-PERSON Pfeiffer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O heads/VBZ/O Compaq/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG European/JJ/O and/CC/O international/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ././O
His/PRP$/O company/NN/O ,/,/O without/IN/O any/DT/O major/JJ/O effort/NN/O ,/,/O sells/VBZ/O more/JJR/O machines/NNS/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE than/IN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
And/CC/O because/IN/O general/JJ/O retail/JJ/O centers/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O ComputerLand/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O little/JJ/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O sales/NNS/O remain/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O iron/NN/O grip/NN/O of/IN/O established/VBN/O computer/NN/O makers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Americans/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O to/TO/O blame/VB/O ././O
They/PRP/O long/RB/O made/VBD/O little/JJ/O effort/NN/O here/RB/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O though/IN/O long/RB/O a/DT/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O mainframe/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O introduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O PC/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE until/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O after/IN/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O compatible/JJ/O even/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE IBM/NNP/B-ORG standard/NN/O ././O
Apple/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O introduce/VB/O a/DT/O kanji/FW/O machine/NN/O --/:/O one/NN/O that/WDT/O handles/VBZ/O the/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O characters/NNS/O of/IN/O written/VBN/O Japanese/NNP/O --/:/O until/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O after/IN/O entering/VBG/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Critics/NNS/O also/RB/O say/VBP/O American/JJ/O companies/NNS/O charge/VBP/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O investigating/VBG/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O allegedly/RB/O discouraging/VBG/O retailers/NNS/O from/IN/O discounting/VBG/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O redoubling/VBG/O their/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O introduced/VBD/O a/DT/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O powerful/JJ/O kanji/FW/O operating/NN/O system/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O kanji/FW/O laser/NN/O printer/NN/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG just/RB/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O started/VBD/O selling/VBG/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O machine/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O run/VB/O in/IN/O both/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O and/CC/O English/NNP/O and/CC/O that/WDT/O substantially/RB/O enhances/VBZ/O compatibility/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O American/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O enormous/JJ/O business/NN/O opportunity/NN/O ././O
