West/JJ/O German/JJ/O insurance/NN/O giant/NN/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG entered/VBD/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O battle/NN/O between/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Cie/NNP/B-ORG ././I-ORG Financiere/NNP/I-ORG de/IN/I-ORG Paribas/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Cie./NNP/B-ORG de/IN/I-ORG Navigation/NNP/I-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O comes/VBZ/O a/DT/O week/NN/O after/IN/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG announced/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O preparing/VBG/O to/TO/O bid/VB/O for/IN/O 66.7/CD/O %/NN/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O blow/NN/O to/TO/O both/DT/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Each/DT/O had/VBD/O claimed/VBN/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O insurance/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O tacit/JJ/O ally/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG statement/NN/O also/RB/O reinforced/VBD/O the/DT/O belief/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O battle/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O one/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O led/VBD/O to/TO/O broad/JJ/O market/NN/O speculation/NN/O that/IN/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG now/RB/O will/MD/O sweeten/VB/O its/PRP$/O bid/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O formally/RB/O launched/VBN/O later/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O approval/NN/O from/IN/O French/JJ/O government/NN/O regulators/NNS/O ././O
Allianz/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O entry/NN/O reflects/VBZ/O the/DT/O increasing/VBG/O eagerness/NN/O of/IN/O West/NNP/O German/NNP/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O looking/VBG/O ahead/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG internal/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O in/IN/O 1992/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O get/VB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O what/WP/O until/IN/O now/RB/O were/VBD/O considered/VBN/O internal/JJ/O French/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
Deutsche/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Dresdner/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Commerzbank/NNP/B-ORG all/RB/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O expressed/VBN/O eagerness/NN/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE before/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Dresdner/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG this/DT/O month/NN/O moved/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Banque/NNP/B-ORG Internationale/NNP/I-ORG des/NNP/I-ORG Placements/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O French/JJ/O merchant/NN/O bank/NN/O that/IN/O Deutsche/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O looked/VBN/O at/IN/O and/CC/O passed/VBD/O over/IN/O ././O
Commerzbank/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O hoped/VBN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O a/DT/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Credit/NNP/B-ORG Lyonnais/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O until/IN/O the/DT/O Socialists/NNS/B-ORG returned/VBD/O to/TO/O government/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O and/CC/O canceled/VBD/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O privatize/VB/O the/DT/O large/JJ/O French/JJ/O bank/NN/O ././O
Deutsche/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O actively/RB/O sought/VBN/O a/DT/O French/JJ/O acquisition/NN/O for/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Lately/RB/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O Deutsche/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O shocked/VBN/O some/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O French/JJ/O financial/JJ/O community/NN/O by/IN/O indicating/VBG/O it/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O bank/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O branches/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O looking/VBG/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O Deutsche/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O in/IN/O any/DT/O detail/NN/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O plans/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG currently/RB/O holds/VBZ/O between/IN/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O apparent/JJ/O increase/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O that/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O had/VBD/O earlier/RBR/O announced/VBN/O ././O
Paris/NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O believed/VBD/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O buying/VBG/O yesterday/NN/O morning/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG moved/VBD/O up/RB/O 108/CD/O francs/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 17.19/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O close/VB/O at/IN/O 1,908/CD/O francs/NNS/O in/IN/O heavy/JJ/O trading/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O day/NN/O of/IN/O trading/NN/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O suspension/NN/O of/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O last/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG announced/VBD/O its/PRP$/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O 1,850/CD/O francs/NNS/O for/IN/O each/DT/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG share/NN/O ././O
Allianz/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O holds/VBZ/O a/DT/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG insurance/NN/O subsidiary/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O insurance/NN/O groups/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O bought/VBD/O for/IN/O about/RB/O 6.5/CD/O billion/CD/O francs/NNS/O just/RB/O before/RB/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG launched/VBD/O its/PRP$/O bid/NN/O ././O
Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG holds/VBZ/O the/DT/O remaining/JJ/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Allianz/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O statement/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O acting/VBG/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O that/DT/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O ties/VBZ/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O a/DT/O partner/NN/O ././O
Allianz/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O statement/NN/O stressed/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/VBZ/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O position/NN/O that/IN/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O offer/NN/O price/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O low/JJ/O ././O
Allianz/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O suggested/VBD/O ,/,/O without/IN/O saying/VBG/O so/RB/O directly/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O regrets/VBZ/O that/IN/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O bidding/VBG/O for/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG shares/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG wins/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O 66.7/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O remaining/JJ/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O will/MD/O fall/VB/O in/IN/O value/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O displeases/VBZ/O many/JJ/O current/JJ/O holders/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O sure/JJ/O of/IN/O selling/VBG/O all/DT/O their/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O tendered/VBD/O to/TO/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG statement/NN/O led/VBD/O to/TO/O speculation/NN/O that/IN/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG eventually/RB/O could/MD/O sell/VB/O to/TO/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O bad/JJ/O news/NN/O for/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG current/JJ/O management/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O counting/VBG/O on/IN/O Allianz/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O help/VB/O fend/VB/O off/RP/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Allianz/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O whom/WP/O ,/,/O if/IN/O anyone/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O support/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O simply/RB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O boost/VB/O its/PRP$/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG stake/NN/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O fit/JJ/O over/IN/O the/DT/O coming/VBG/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O itself/PRP/O ,/,/O as/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O French/JJ/O regulatory/JJ/O officials/NNS/O '/POS/O approval/NN/O ././O
Paribas/NNP/B-ORG currently/RB/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O 1,850/CD/O francs/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O for/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O that/WDT/O receive/VBP/O full/JJ/O dividends/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O 1,800/CD/O francs/NNS/O for/IN/O shares/NNS/O created/VBN/O on/IN/O July/NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O receive/VBP/O partial/JJ/O dividends/NNS/O ././O
Alternatively/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O offer/VB/O to/TO/O swap/VB/O three/CD/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG shares/NNS/O for/IN/O one/CD/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG share/NN/O ././O
Paribas/NNP/B-ORG already/RB/O holds/VBZ/O about/RB/O 18.7/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O additional/JJ/O 48/CD/O %/NN/O would/MD/O cost/VB/O it/PRP/O about/RB/O 11/CD/O billion/CD/O francs/NNS/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O bid/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bid/NN/O values/VBZ/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/O around/RB/O 23/CD/O billion/CD/O francs/NNS/O ,/,/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O holders/NNS/O of/IN/O Navigation/NNP/B-ORG Mixte/NNP/I-ORG warrants/NNS/O exchange/VBP/O them/PRP/O for/IN/O shares/NNS/O before/RB/O the/DT/O bid/NN/O expires/VBZ/O ././O
