Conservatives/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O faction/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE politics/NNS/O which/WDT/O always/RB/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O friends/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O an/DT/O election/NN/O in/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Liberals/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O faction/NN/O that/WDT/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O Give/VB/O peace/NN/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O ;/:/O now/RB/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O saying/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O give/VB/O them/PRP/O a/DT/O break/NN/O ,/,/O lest/IN/O the/DT/O conservatives/NNS/O ask/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O vote/VB/O for/IN/O bullets/NNS/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O bandages/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O suspect/VBP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Ortega/NNP/I-PERSON knows/VBZ/O the/DT/O difference/NN/O between/IN/O a/DT/O blunder/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O strategy/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON understands/VBZ/O better/RBR/O than/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O worry/VBP/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O behavior/NN/O that/IN/O what/WP/O sustains/VBZ/O the/DT/O Sandinista/NNP/B-ORG movement/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O democratic/JJ/O peace/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O nondemocratic/JJ/O unpeace/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O presence/NN/O of/IN/O internal/JJ/O and/CC/O external/JJ/O ``/``/O enemies/NNS/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O justifies/VBZ/O the/DT/O need/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O ,/,/O active/JJ/O army/NN/B-ORG that/IN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Soviet/NNP/B-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O supply/VB/O with/IN/O bullets/NNS/O ././O
