MiniScribe/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O disk/NN/O drives/NNS/O have/VBP/O more/JJR/O memory/NN/O capacity/NN/O than/IN/O other/JJ/O disks/NNS/O that/DT/O size/NN/O ././O
MiniScribe/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O full/JJ/O volume/NN/O production/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O drives/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O drive/NN/O with/IN/O 120/CD/O megabytes/NNS/O of/IN/O capacity/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O release/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O of/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
MiniScribe/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O rocks/NNS/O since/IN/O it/PRP/O disclosed/VBD/O early/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O earnings/NNS/O reports/NNS/O for/IN/O 1988/CD/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O accurate/JJ/O ././O
