Mazda/NNP/B-ORG makes/VBZ/O the/DT/O Tracer/NNP/O for/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG ././O
A/DT/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Dearborn/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O any/DT/O injuries/NNS/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O windshield/NN/O problem/NN/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O owners/NNS/O should/MD/O return/VB/O the/DT/O cars/NNS/O to/TO/O dealers/NNS/O so/IN/O the/DT/O windshields/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O removed/VBN/O and/CC/O securely/RB/O reinstalled/VBN/O ././O
Mazda/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O combination/NN/O of/IN/O limited/JJ/O crankcase/NN/O ventilation/NN/O and/CC/O improper/JJ/O maintenance/NN/O could/MD/O cause/VB/O engine/NN/O oil/NN/O in/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Mercury/NNP/B-ORG Tracers/NNP/O and/CC/O Mazda/NNP/B-ORG 323s/NNS/O to/TO/O deteriorate/VB/O more/RBR/O rapidly/RB/O than/IN/O normal/JJ/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O increased/VBN/O engine/NN/O noise/NN/O or/CC/O reduced/VBN/O engine/NN/O life/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O safety/NN/O related/VBN/O ././O
Both/DT/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O replace/VB/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O filler/NN/O cap/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O ventilated/VBN/O oil/NN/O filler/NN/O cap/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O also/RB/O will/MD/O inspect/VB/O and/CC/O replace/VB/O ,/,/O if/IN/O necessary/JJ/O ,/,/O oil/NN/O filters/NNS/O and/CC/O oil/NN/O strainers/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O no/DT/O charge/NN/O to/TO/O owners/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O normal/JJ/O term/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O 1986/CD/O and/CC/O 1987/CD/O model/NN/O 323/CD/O is/VBZ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O or/CC/O 24,000/CD/O miles/NNS/O ;/:/O the/DT/O term/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O 1988/CD/O 323/CD/O is/VBZ/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O or/CC/O 50,000/CD/O miles/NNS/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O term/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O warranty/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O or/CC/O 60,000/CD/O miles/NNS/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O offer/NN/O will/MD/O begin/VB/O Saturday/NNP/O and/CC/O run/VB/O indefinitely/RB/O ././O
