It/PRP/O was/VBD/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O routine/JJ/O courtesy/NN/O call/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O sales/NNS/O pitch/NN/O might/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O as/RB/O farfetched/JJ/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O world/NN/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O semiconductors/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O behind/RB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O computers/NNS/O that/WDT/O use/VBP/O those/DT/O chips/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O world/NN/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O auto/NN/O manufacturing/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O aviation/NN/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O struggling/VBG/O ,/,/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O space/NN/O program/NN/O is/VBZ/O years/NNS/O behind/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O Europeans/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O also/RB/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O better/JJR/O use/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O considerable/JJ/O expertise/NN/O in/IN/O theoretical/JJ/O science/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O helped/VBN/O them/PRP/O win/VB/O twice/RB/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O Nobel/NNP/O science/NN/O prizes/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O ././O
Kobe/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG adopted/VBD/O Soviet/JJ/O casting/VBG/O technology/NN/O in/IN/O 1966/CD/O and/CC/O used/VBD/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O 14/CD/O years/NNS/O until/IN/O it/PRP/O developed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O system/NN/O ././O
Soviet/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O their/PRP$/O technology/NN/O abroad/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O appear/VB/O to/TO/O worry/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O principal/JJ/O ally/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O delegation/NN/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O push/VB/O more/JJR/O space/NN/O technologies/NNS/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O target/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O ././O
These/DT/O mainly/RB/O involved/VBD/O such/JJ/O areas/NNS/O as/IN/O materials/NNS/O --/:/O advanced/JJ/O soldering/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O medical/JJ/O developments/NNS/O derived/VBN/O from/IN/O experimentation/NN/O in/IN/O space/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O artificial/JJ/O blood/NN/O vessels/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O main/JJ/O motive/NN/O is/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O cash/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O hurdle/NN/O concerns/VBZ/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O attempts/NNS/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O relinquish/VB/O its/PRP$/O post-World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O control/NN/O of/IN/O four/CD/O islands/NNS/O north/RB/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Gumbel/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
