The/DT/O following/VBG/O were/VBD/O among/IN/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O offerings/NNS/O and/CC/O pricings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O non-U.S./JJ/B-GPE capital/NN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O terms/NNS/O and/CC/O syndicate/NN/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O compiled/VBN/O by/IN/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Capital/NNP/O Markets/NNP/O Report/NNP/O :/:/O
New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE --/:/I-GPE
Collateralized/NNP/B-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
$/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O Remic/JJ/B-ORG mortgage/NN/O securities/NNS/O offered/VBD/O in/IN/O 12/CD/O classes/NNS/O by/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Beneficial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
The/DT/O issue/NN/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O expected/VBN/O final/JJ/O maturity/NN/O date/NN/O of/IN/O 1998/CD/O ././O
Rochester/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG Savings/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
$/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O 8.85/CD/O %/NN/O certificates/NNS/O backed/VBD/O by/IN/O automobile/NN/O loans/NNS/O priced/VBN/O to/TO/O yield/VB/O 8.99/CD/O %/NN/O via/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O offering/NN/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O expected/VBN/O average/JJ/O life/NN/O of/IN/O 1.7/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O final/JJ/O maturity/NN/O date/NN/O of/IN/O May/NNP/O 15/CD/O ,/,/O 1995/CD/O ././O
South/NNP/B-ORG Australian/NNP/I-ORG Government/NNP/I-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Authority/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O agency/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O --/:/O
Guaranteed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG South/NNP/I-ORG Australian/NNP/I-ORG Treasury/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Government/NNP/B-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG South/NNP/I-ORG Wales/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O agency/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O --/:/O
Swedish/NNP/B-ORG Export/NNP/I-ORG Credit/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O Sweden/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O --/:/O
