Cray/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG won/VBD/O government/NN/O clearance/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O proposed/VBN/O reorganization/NN/O of/IN/O founder/NN/O Seymour/NNP/B-PERSON Cray/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O supercomputer/NN/O design/NN/O team/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O company/NN/O ././O
Cray/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O directors/NNS/O set/VBD/O Nov./NNP/O 15/CD/O as/IN/O the/DT/O record/NN/O date/NN/O for/IN/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O shares/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O Cray/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O trade/VB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O counter/NN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O symbol/NN/O CRAY/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O plan/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O Cray/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG holders/NNS/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O one/CD/O share/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O for/IN/O every/DT/O two/CD/O shares/NNS/O held/VBD/O ././O
An/DT/O estimated/VBN/O 14.7/CD/O million/CD/O Cray/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O distributed/VBN/O ,/,/O Cray/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Cray/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O retain/VB/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE Springs/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Colo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
