Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Iacocca/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O No./NN/O 3/CD/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O will/MD/O need/VB/O to/TO/O close/VB/O one/CD/O or/CC/O two/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O assembly/NN/O plants/NNS/O because/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O slowdown/NN/O hitting/VBG/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O temporarily/RB/O close/VB/O the/DT/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Toledo/NNP/B-GPE plants/NNS/O recently/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O excess/JJ/O inventories/NNS/O of/IN/O vehicles/NNS/O built/VBN/O there/RB/O ././O
