Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O portfolio/NN/O currently/RB/O includes/VBZ/O $/$/O 95/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O receivables/NNS/O ,/,/O GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Commercial/NNP/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Savings/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O market/VB/O Visa/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O MasterCard/NNP/B-ORG programs/NNS/O while/IN/O Monogram/NNP/B-ORG provides/VBZ/O ``/``/O operational/JJ/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O support/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O actually/RB/O owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O accounts/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O ,/,/O Monogram/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Blue/NNP/B-GPE Ash/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 2.4/CD/O million/CD/O total/JJ/O accounts/NNS/O ,/,/O GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG added/VBD/O ././O
