Hospital/NN/O Regulation/NN/O Sparks/VBZ/O Kentucky/NNP/B-GPE Feud/NN/O
WHICH/WDT/O IS/VBZ/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O medicine/NN/O for/IN/O runaway/JJ/O health/NN/O costs/NNS/O :/:/O competition/NN/O or/CC/O regulation/NN/O ?/./O
The/DT/O law/NN/O has/VBZ/O prevented/VBN/O $/$/O 216/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O unnecessary/JJ/O expenditures/NNS/O since/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O William/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Conn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Kentucky/NNP/I-ORG Hospital/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Jones/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Humana/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O promotes/VBZ/O technology/NN/O monopolies/NNS/O ,/,/O stifles/VBZ/O innovation/NN/O and/CC/O raises/VBZ/O prices/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O Legislature/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O repeal/VB/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ,/,/O due/JJ/O for/IN/O revision/NN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Jones/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O Humana/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O move/VB/O its/PRP$/O insurance/NN/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O 3,000/CD/O jobs/NNS/O in/IN/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O another/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O complains/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O paid/VBD/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O non-Humana/JJ/B-ORG hospitals/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O latest/JJS/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O for/IN/O services/NNS/O provided/VBN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O insurance/NN/O plan/NN/O members/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Humana/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O could/MD/O serve/VB/O its/PRP$/O insured/VBN/O for/IN/O less/JJR/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O properly/RB/O equipped/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Conn/NNP/B-PERSON charges/VBZ/O that/IN/O Humana/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O own/JJ/O actions/NNS/O undermine/VBP/O its/PRP$/O argument/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Humana/NNP/B-ORG hospital/NN/O responded/VBD/O by/IN/O jacking/VBG/O up/RP/O prices/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O up/RP/O for/IN/O lost/VBN/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Conn/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O now/RB/O charges/VBZ/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 8,000/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O procedure/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O costs/VBZ/O only/RB/O about/RB/O $/$/O 3,500/CD/O in/IN/O Lexington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Humana/NNP/B-ORG contends/VBZ/O that/IN/O $/$/O 8,000/CD/O represents/VBZ/O an/DT/O extreme/JJ/O case/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O regular/JJ/O charge/NN/O for/IN/O lithotripsy/NN/O is/VBZ/O $/$/O 4,900/CD/O ././O
Humana/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O machines/NNS/O itself/PRP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O record/NN/O as/IN/O opposed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O 81/CD/O %/NN/O preferred/VBD/O a/DT/O group/NN/O practice/NN/O or/CC/O health/NN/O maintenance/NN/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O just/RB/O 11/CD/O %/NN/O favored/VBD/O solo/NN/O practice/NN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O do/VB/O that/DT/O very/RB/O often/RB/O today/NN/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O something/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O safe/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O numbers/NNS/O behind/IN/O such/JJ/O fears/NNS/O :/:/O The/DT/O average/JJ/O debt/NN/O of/IN/O medical/JJ/O school/NN/O graduates/NNS/O who/WP/O borrowed/VBD/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O education/NN/O jumped/VBD/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 42,374/CD/O this/DT/O year/NN/O from/IN/O $/$/O 38,489/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Colleges/NNP/I-ORG ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O 115/CD/O %/NN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O in/IN/O 1981/CD/O ././O
Money/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O shift/NN/O in/IN/O practice/NN/O preferences/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O social/JJ/O fabric/NN/O of/IN/O medicine/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Related/JJ/O Roommates/NNS/O Trim/VBP/O Hospital/NN/O Bills/NNS/O
WHEN/WRB/O Catherine/NNP/B-PERSON Bobar/NNP/I-PERSON spent/VBD/O several/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Vermont/NNP/I-ORG recently/RB/O with/IN/O a/DT/O bone/NN/O infection/NN/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O toe/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O shared/VBD/O a/DT/O room/NN/O just/RB/O like/IN/O most/JJS/O patients/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O unlike/IN/O most/JJS/O patients/NNS/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O roommate/NN/O was/VBD/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O certainly/RB/O good/JJ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O him/PRP/O handy/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mrs./NNP/O Bobar/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O philosophy/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O patient/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O family/NN/O very/RB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O care/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Anthony/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Grieco/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O medical/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O cooperative/JJ/O care/NN/O at/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O concept/NN/O began/VBD/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O saves/VBZ/O money/NN/O ././O
Because/IN/O patients/NNS/O require/VBP/O less/JJR/O attention/NN/O from/IN/O nurses/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O staff/NN/O ,/,/O room/NN/O charges/NNS/O are/VBP/O lower/JJR/O --/:/O about/RB/O $/$/O 100/CD/O less/JJR/O per/IN/O day/NN/O than/IN/O a/DT/O regular/JJ/O room/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Vermont/NNP/B-GPE hospital/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O approach/NN/O has/VBZ/O generated/VBN/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O interest/NN/O that/IN/O NYU/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O host/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O conference/NN/O on/IN/O cooperative/JJ/O care/NN/O Nov./NNP/O 30/CD/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O really/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hospital/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 21st/JJ/O century/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Dr./NNP/O Grieco/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Odds/NNS/O and/CC/O Ends/NNS/O
So/RB/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Commonwealth/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE philanthropist/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O sponsoring/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O project/NN/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O joint/JJ/O masters/NNS/O in/IN/O business/NN/O and/CC/O nursing/NN/O programs/NNS/O at/IN/O 10/CD/O universities/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
Meharry/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG College/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Nashville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tenn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O launches/VBZ/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O research/NN/O publication/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O spring/NN/O :/:/O the/DT/B-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Care/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Poor/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Underserved/NNP/I-ORG ././O
