General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O planning/VBG/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O engine/NN/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC that/WDT/O may/MD/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O provided/VBN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O can/MD/O reach/VB/O a/DT/O satisfactory/JJ/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O unions/NNS/O ,/,/O sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Officials/NNP/O of/IN/O Vauxhall/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O GM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O British/JJ/O unit/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O meeting/VBG/O with/IN/O union/NN/O leaders/NNS/O late/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O in/IN/O hopes/NNS/O of/IN/O winning/VBG/O such/JJ/O an/DT/O accord/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O engine/NN/O plant/NN/O may/MD/O encompass/VB/O plans/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O components/NNS/O venture/NN/O with/IN/O Jaguar/NNP/B-ORG ././O
