Edison/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNP/I-ORG Stores/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O 229/CD/O Foxmoor/NNP/B-ORG women/NNS/O 's/POS/O apparel/NN/O stores/NNS/O from/IN/O Foxmoor/NNP/B-ORG Specialty/NNP/I-ORG Stores/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Dylex/NNP/B-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Toronto/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Edison/NN/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O acquired/VBN/O stores/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O integrated/VBN/O into/IN/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ././O
