Penn/NNP/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Cincinnati/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O in/IN/O principle/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Noranda/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Carol/NNP/B-ORG Cable/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 177/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O Carol/NNP/B-ORG Cable/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Pawtucket/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O R.I./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O leading/VBG/O supplier/NN/O of/IN/O electrical/JJ/O and/CC/O electronic/JJ/O wire/NN/O and/CC/O cable/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O distributor/NN/O ,/,/O retail/JJ/O and/CC/O original/JJ/O equipment/NN/O manufacturer/NN/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Carol/NNP/B-ORG Cable/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O operates/VBZ/O 12/CD/O manufacturing/NN/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 11.7/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 153.3/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 25.6/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 294.6/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O telecommunications/NNS/O and/CC/O defense/NN/O equipment/NN/O said/VBD/O Carol/NNP/B-ORG Cable/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG portfolio/NN/O and/CC/O market/NN/O focus/NN/O would/MD/O complement/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O current/JJ/O wire/NN/O and/CC/O cable/NN/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O plan/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O satisfactory/JJ/O due/JJ/O diligence/NN/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O Carol/NNP/B-ORG Cable/NNP/I-ORG by/IN/O Penn/NNP/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O and/CC/O regulatory/JJ/O approvals/NNS/O ././O
