The/DT/O commercial/NN/O was/VBD/O absolutely/RB/O silent/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O Due/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O donating/VBG/O its/PRP$/O commercial/JJ/O air/NN/O time/NN/O to/TO/O broadcast/VB/O American/NNP/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG Emergency/NNP/O Relief/NNP/O messages/NNS/O ././O
Please/VB/O contribute/VB/O what/WP/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG logo/NN/O flashed/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O screen/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O moment/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O then/RB/O came/VBD/O a/DT/O taped/VBN/O plea/NN/O for/IN/O donations/NNS/O from/IN/O former/JJ/O President/NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON --/:/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O silent/JJ/O print/NN/O telling/VBG/O viewers/NNS/O where/WRB/O to/TO/O call/VB/O ././O
Within/IN/O two/CD/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O viewers/NNS/O pledged/VBN/O over/IN/O $/$/O 400,000/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG executive/NN/O ././O
Call/VB/O it/PRP/O disaster/NN/O marketing/NN/O ././O
Nissan/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O just/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O a/DT/O slew/NN/O of/IN/O advertisers/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O hitched/VBN/O their/PRP$/O ads/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O devastating/JJ/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE quake/NN/O and/CC/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O ././O
Sometimes/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O ads/NNS/O attempt/VB/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O money/NN/O ;/:/O always/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O try/VBP/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O good/JJ/O will/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O advertising/VBG/O disaster/NN/O relief/NN/O ,/,/O these/DT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O hoping/VBG/O to/TO/O don/VB/O a/DT/O white/JJ/O hat/NN/O and/CC/O come/VBN/O out/RP/O a/DT/O hero/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O deterred/VBD/O plenty/JJ/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Along/IN/O with/IN/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Grand/NNP/B-ORG Metropolitan/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Burger/NNP/B-ORG King/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O tied/VBN/O ads/NNS/O to/TO/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG donations/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O felt/VBD/O we/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O something/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O them/PRP/O gather/VB/O money/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O this/DT/O airtime/NN/O on/IN/O Monday/NNP/O Night/NNP/O Football/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O explains/VBZ/O Brooke/NNP/B-PERSON Mitzel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG advertising/VBG/O creative/JJ/O manager/NN/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O did/VBD/O we/PRP/O get/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ?/./O
We/PRP/O got/VBD/O some/DT/O exposure/NN/O .../:/O and/CC/O pretty/RB/O much/JJ/O good/JJ/O will/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O ads/NNS/O are/VBP/O just/RB/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O television/NN/O advertising/NN/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O faster/RBR/O on/IN/O the/DT/O draw/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O TV/NN/O commercials/NNS/O typically/RB/O take/VBP/O weeks/NNS/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O ,/,/O advertisers/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O years/NNS/O have/VBP/O learned/VBN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O dime/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O crash/VB/O out/RP/O ads/NNS/O in/IN/O days/NNS/O or/CC/O even/JJ/O hours/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O big/JJ/O brokerage/NN/O houses/NNS/O learned/VBD/O the/DT/O art/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O instant/JJ/O commercial/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O reassuring/JJ/O ads/NNS/O inviting/VBG/O investors/NNS/O right/RB/O back/RB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O trotted/VBD/O out/RP/O another/DT/O crop/NN/O of/IN/O instant/JJ/O commercials/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O sudden/JJ/O market/NN/O dip/NN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
Nissan/NNP/B-ORG created/VBD/O its/PRP$/O quake/NN/O ad/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O weekend/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O as/IN/O advertisers/NNS/O latch/VBP/O onto/IN/O disasters/NNS/O with/IN/O increasing/JJ/O frequency/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O risk/VBP/O hurting/VBG/O themselves/PRP/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O helping/VBG/O the/DT/O cause/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O chance/VBP/O alienating/VBG/O the/DT/O customers/NNS/O they/PRP/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O woo/VB/O by/IN/O looking/VBG/O like/IN/O opportunistic/JJ/O sharks/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O see/VBP/O extra/JJ/O messages/NNS/O in/IN/O advertising/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O if/IN/O a/DT/O manufacturer/NN/O is/VBZ/O clearly/RB/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O get/VB/O something/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O .../:/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O too/RB/O transparent/JJ/O .../:/O then/IN/O consumers/NNS/O will/MD/O see/VB/O through/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O warns/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Philip/NNP/I-PERSON Jones/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O advertising/NN/O department/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Newhouse/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/O Syracuse/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O can/MD/O backfire/VB/O because/IN/O companies/NNS/O can/MD/O step/VB/O across/IN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O and/CC/O go/VB/O too/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O be/VB/O too/RB/O pushy/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O agrees/VBZ/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Stibel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O principal/NN/O with/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG Consulting/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Westport/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O form/NN/O of/IN/O charity/NN/O is/VBZ/O when/WRB/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O tell/VB/O anyone/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O consider/VB/O that/DT/O ambulance/NN/O chasing/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O companies/NNS/O running/VBG/O the/DT/O disaster/NN/O ads/NNS/O certainly/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O see/VB/O themselves/PRP/O as/IN/O ambulance/NN/O chasers/NNS/O ,/,/O either/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O started/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O and/CC/O runs/VBZ/O through/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 23/CD/O ,/,/O with/IN/O funds/NNS/O earmarked/VBN/O for/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O and/CC/O Hugo/NNP/O ,/,/O ``/``/O was/VBD/O Barry/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O idea/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Barry/NNP/B-PERSON felt/VBD/O very/RB/O committed/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O felt/VBD/O we/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O giving/VBG/O something/NN/O back/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
While/IN/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O was/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Gibbons/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O idea/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O paying/VBG/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O :/:/O The/DT/O donations/NNS/O will/MD/O come/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O 's/POS/O national/JJ/O advertising/NN/O fund/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O franchisees/NNS/O ././O
Toyota/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O upscale/JJ/O Lexus/NNP/B-ORG division/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O sponsor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O ,/,/O also/RB/O put/VBD/O in/RP/O a/DT/O plug/NN/O for/IN/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG donations/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O game/NN/O it/PRP/O sponsored/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O is/VBZ/O brought/VBN/O to/TO/O you/PRP/O by/IN/O Lexus/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O urges/VBZ/O you/PRP/O to/TO/O help/VB/O relieve/VB/O the/DT/O suffering/NN/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O earthquake/NN/O .../:/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O game/NN/O announcer/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
And/CC/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG made/VBD/O a/DT/O plea/NN/O for/IN/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG donations/NNS/O in/IN/O newspaper/NN/O ads/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O ,/,/O latching/VBG/O onto/IN/O the/DT/O coattails/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG impeccable/JJ/O reputation/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O helping/VBG/O people/NNS/O for/IN/O 125/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O doing/VBG/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O for/IN/O over/IN/O 140/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Nancy/NNP/B-PERSON Craig/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O advertising/NN/O manager/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O readily/RB/O admits/VBZ/O ``/``/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O piggybacking/VBG/O on/IN/O our/PRP$/O reputation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O problem/NN/O with/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O In/IN/O the/DT/O meanwhile/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O helping/VBG/O us/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O track/VB/O contributions/NNS/O raised/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O disaster/NN/O ads/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O amassed/VBN/O $/$/O 46.6/CD/O million/CD/O since/IN/O it/PRP/O first/RB/O launched/VBD/O its/PRP$/O hurricane/NN/O relief/NN/O effort/NN/O Sept./NNP/O 23/CD/O ././O
Ad/NN/O Notes/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
NEW/JJ/O ACCOUNT/NN/O :/:/O
TV/NN/O GUIDE/NNP/O :/:/O
N/NNP/B-ORG W/NNP/I-ORG Ayer/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE agency/NN/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O handled/VBN/O the/DT/O account/NN/O since/IN/O 1963/CD/O ,/,/O resigned/VBD/O the/DT/O account/NN/O about/RB/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
NO/DT/O ALCOHOL/NNP/O :/:/O
Miller/NNP/B-ORG Brewing/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O introduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O non-alcoholic/JJ/O beer/NN/O Jan./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
