Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O close/JJ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O back/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O recorded/VBN/O music/NN/O and/CC/O music/NN/O publishing/NN/O company/NN/O in/IN/O partnership/NN/O with/IN/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON Azoff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O as/IN/O head/NN/O of/IN/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG MCA/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O comment/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O did/VBD/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O where/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O also/RB/O been/VBN/O discussing/VBG/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O venture/NN/O ././O
Among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O develop/VB/O musical/JJ/O acts/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O record/NN/O label/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON wo/MD/O n't/RB/O produce/VB/O films/NNS/O at/IN/O first/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O possible/JJ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O do/VB/O so/RB/O later/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Like/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Geffen/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O arrangement/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O gives/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O link/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O and/CC/O most/RBS/O successful/JJ/O record/NN/O distributor/NN/O ;/:/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE alone/RB/O ,/,/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ,/,/O about/RB/O double/JJ/O its/PRP$/O nearest/JJS/O competitor/NN/O ,/,/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG CBS/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNP/I-ORG ././O
For/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O gives/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O young/JJ/O partner/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O finger/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O pulse/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hottest/JJS/O trends/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O music/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O negotiating/VBG/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG contract/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O expired/VBD/O in/IN/O 1991/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON reportedly/RB/O was/VBD/O bored/VBN/O and/CC/O frequently/RB/O clashed/VBN/O with/IN/O top/JJ/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O issues/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O compensation/NN/O and/CC/O business/NN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O was/VBD/O eager/JJ/O to/TO/O return/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O entrepreneurial/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O financial/JJ/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O resignation/NN/O from/IN/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O rather/RB/O build/VB/O a/DT/O company/NN/O than/IN/O run/VB/O one/CD/O ././O
