The/DT/O combined/VBN/O operations/NNS/O had/VBD/O 1988/CD/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
James/NNP/B-ORG River/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O pulp/NN/O ,/,/O paper/NN/O and/CC/O plastic/NN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O already/RB/O has/VBZ/O interests/NNS/O in/IN/O tissue/NN/O businesses/NNS/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O form/VB/O European/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O with/IN/O Italian/JJ/O and/CC/O Finnish/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Celtona/NNP/B-ORG operations/NNS/O would/MD/O become/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
