Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG resumed/VBD/O settlement/NN/O talks/NNS/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O legal/JJ/O battle/NN/O over/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE producers/NNS/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Guber/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Jon/NNP/B-PERSON Peters/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O continued/VBD/O to/TO/O level/VB/O strong/JJ/O accusations/NNS/O at/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O in/IN/O legal/JJ/O documents/NNS/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O documents/NNS/O filed/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG Vice/NNP/O Chairman/NNP/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Schulof/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Yetnikoff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O taken/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON at/IN/O their/PRP$/O word/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O told/VBD/O them/PRP/O that/IN/O getting/VBG/O out/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O no/DT/O problem/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O previous/JJ/O oral/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O statements/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG filings/NNS/O were/VBD/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O attorneys/NNS/O who/WP/O did/VBD/O have/VB/O access/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O contracts/NNS/O but/CC/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O negotiations/NNS/O between/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O duo/NN/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O also/RB/O filed/VBD/O new/JJ/O sworn/JJ/O affidavits/NNS/O denying/VBG/O claims/NNS/O by/IN/O Messrs./NNS/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O had/VBD/O an/DT/O oral/JJ/O agreement/NN/O that/WDT/O enabled/VBD/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O to/TO/O terminate/VB/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O run/VB/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O studio/NN/O come/VBN/O up/RP/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG described/VBD/O as/IN/O ``/``/O nonsense/NN/O ''/''/O yesterday/NN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O assertions/NNS/O in/IN/O prior/JJ/O court/NN/O filings/NNS/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O in/IN/O theory/NN/O run/VBN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG while/IN/O still/RB/O fulfilling/VBG/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O movies/NNS/O for/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O
