The/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Equal/NNP/I-ORG Employment/NNP/I-ORG Opportunity/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG sued/VBD/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE state/NN/O for/IN/O age/NN/O discrimination/NN/O against/IN/O appointed/VBN/O state/NN/O judges/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O charges/VBZ/O that/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE mandatory/JJ/O retirement/NN/O age/NN/O of/IN/O 76/CD/O violates/VBZ/O federal/JJ/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O commission/NN/O 's/POS/O filing/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O case/NN/O challenges/VBZ/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O mandatory/JJ/O retirement/NN/O age/NN/O of/IN/O 70/CD/O for/IN/O appointed/VBN/O judges/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE suit/NN/O was/VBD/O filed/VBN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O Justice/NNP/O Isaac/NNP/B-PERSON Rubin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O appointment/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O state/NN/O appellate/JJ/O division/NN/O expires/VBZ/O at/IN/O year/NN/O end/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O all/DT/O other/JJ/O judges/NNS/O hurt/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O alleged/VBN/O age/NN/O discrimination/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O assigned/VBN/O to/TO/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O Kimba/NNP/B-PERSON Wood/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O seeks/VBZ/O a/DT/O permanent/JJ/O injunction/NN/O ,/,/O back/JJ/O pay/NN/O for/IN/O judges/NNS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O retire/VB/O ,/,/O reinstatement/NN/O of/IN/O retired/VBN/O judges/NNS/O and/CC/O ``/``/O other/JJ/O affirmative/JJ/O relief/NN/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O eradicate/VB/O the/DT/O effects/NNS/O of/IN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O unlawful/JJ/O employment/NN/O practices/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O The/DT/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O age/NN/O --/:/O age/NN/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O a/DT/O number/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O a/DT/O judge/NN/O 's/POS/O experience/NN/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O competence/NN/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O physical/JJ/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O bench/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Justice/NNP/O Rubin/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O problems/NNS/O performing/VBG/O my/PRP$/O duties/NNS/O and/CC/O responsibilities/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Because/IN/O Justice/NNP/O Rubin/NNP/B-PERSON turned/VBD/O 76/CD/O on/IN/O May/NNP/O 9/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O eligible/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O reappointed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bench/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O 's/POS/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE may/MD/O be/VB/O narrow/JJ/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O Office/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O state/NN/O currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O 35/CD/O appointed/VBN/O judges/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O over/IN/O 70/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O state/NN/O judges/NNS/O are/VBP/O appointed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O governor/NN/O and/CC/O approved/VBD/O by/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O legislature/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O Vermont/NNP/B-GPE case/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O mandatory/JJ/O age/NN/O of/IN/O 70/CD/O for/IN/O appointed/VBN/O judges/NNS/O was/VBD/O illegal/JJ/O ;/:/O Vermont/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O appeal/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O decision/NN/O is/VBZ/O pending/VBG/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Second/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Appeals/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Aaron/NNP/B-PERSON Ment/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O court/NN/O administrator/NN/O ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O EEOC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O intervention/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O state/NN/O has/VBZ/O 165/CD/O appointed/VBN/O judges/NNS/O and/CC/O 15/CD/O ``/``/O trial/NN/O referees/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O former/JJ/O judges/NNS/O over/RB/O age/NN/O 70/CD/O and/CC/O serve/VBP/O a/DT/O restricted/VBN/O role/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O bench/NN/O ././O
ORGANIZED/VBN/O CRIME/NN/O Strike/NN/O Forces/NNS/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O abolished/VBN/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O February/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Thornburgh/NNP/B-PERSON announced/VBD/O his/PRP$/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O abolish/VB/O the/DT/O units/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG next/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG temporarily/RB/O halted/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Thornburgh/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O effort/NN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O appropriation/NN/O resolution/NN/O that/WDT/O prohibited/VBD/O him/PRP/O from/IN/O using/VBG/O budgeted/VBN/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O implement/VB/O his/PRP$/O plan/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Those/DT/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O left/VBN/O have/VBP/O expressed/VBN/O an/DT/O opinion/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O strike/NN/O force/NN/O should/MD/O continue/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Ms./NNP/O Brevetti/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O 27/CD/O lawyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O left/VBN/O and/CC/O 21/CD/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O hired/VBN/O since/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Thornburgh/NNP/B-PERSON announced/VBD/O his/PRP$/O plan/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O was/VBD/O announced/VBN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O 135/CD/O lawyers/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O congressional/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O intend/VBP/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O for/IN/O independent/JJ/O strike/NN/O forces/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Edward/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Kennedy/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Mass/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Thornburgh/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O reinstate/VB/O the/DT/O units/NNS/O next/IN/O year/NN/O if/IN/O an/DT/O proposed/VBN/O omnibus/NN/O crime/NN/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O passed/VBN/O ././O
Among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O shortly/RB/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O senator/NN/O 's/POS/O spokesman/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Runkel/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O doubts/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Kennedy/NNP/B-PERSON can/MD/O muster/VB/O enough/JJ/O congressional/JJ/O support/NN/O to/TO/O reorganize/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O will/MD/O vigorously/RB/O oppose/VB/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O is/VBZ/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O happen/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Golenbock/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O 35/CD/O lawyers/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O lost/VBN/O several/JJ/O partners/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
SHORT/NNP/O SKIRTS/NNP/O not/RB/O welcome/JJ/O in/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE court/NN/O :/:/O
The/DT/O woman/NN/O appeared/VBD/O in/IN/O court/NN/O Thursday/NNP/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O her/PRP/O plea/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O when/WRB/O she/PRP/O started/VBD/O to/TO/O approach/VB/O the/DT/O bench/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O stopped/VBN/O by/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Hancock/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON Blaine/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O that/IN/O the/DT/O short/JJ/O skirt/NN/O was/VBD/O inappropriate/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O court/NN/O appearance/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Blaine/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O protests/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O rescheduled/VBD/O her/PRP$/O case/NN/O for/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 27/CD/O ././O
Kelly/NNP/B-PERSON Siegler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O assistant/JJ/O district/NN/O attorney/NN/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O courtroom/NN/O ,/,/O disputed/VBD/O suggestions/NNS/O the/DT/O action/NN/O was/VBD/O sexist/JJ/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O she/PRP/O had/VBD/O seen/VBN/O Judge/NNP/O Hancock/NNP/B-PERSON turn/VB/O away/RP/O male/JJ/O defendants/NNS/O dressed/VBN/O in/IN/O shorts/NNS/O ,/,/O tank/NN/O tops/NNS/O or/CC/O muscle/NN/O shirts/NNS/O ``/``/O many/JJ/O times/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Judge/NNP/O Hancock/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O return/VB/O phone/NN/O calls/NNS/O ././O
