Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O we/PRP/O read/VBP/O ,/,/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O kill/VB/O a/DT/O speech/NN/O that/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Gates/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O deputy/JJ/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O adviser/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O career/NN/O Soviet/NNP/O expert/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O give/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O student/NN/O colloquium/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O National/NNP/O Collegiate/NNP/O Security/NNP/O Conference/NNP/O ././O
We/PRP/O keep/VBP/O wondering/VBG/O what/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Gates/NNP/B-PERSON wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O he/PRP/O 'd/MD/O have/VB/O called/VBD/O for/IN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O decentralized/VBN/O political/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O system/NN/O ''/''/O without/IN/O a/DT/O dominant/JJ/O communist/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
Or/CC/O political/JJ/O arrangements/NNS/O ``/``/O to/TO/O alleviate/VB/O the/DT/O grievances/NNS/O and/CC/O demands/NNS/O of/IN/O Soviet/NNP/O ethnic/JJ/O minorities/NNS/O and/CC/O republics/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Why/WRB/O ,/,/O a/DT/B-PERSON Bob/NNP/I-PERSON Gates/NNP/I-PERSON might/MD/O even/RB/O have/VB/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Nor/CC/O are/VBP/O Soviet/NNP/O problems/NNS/O susceptible/JJ/O to/TO/O rescue/NN/O from/IN/O abroad/RB/O through/IN/O abundant/JJ/O Western/JJ/O credits/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gates/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O these/DT/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O would/MD/O now/RB/O be/VB/O hearing/VBG/O about/IN/O ``/``/O discord/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O disarray/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
Dark/JJ/O hints/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O that/IN/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O hope/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O fail/VB/O ,/,/O just/RB/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O when/WRB/O Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O Quayle/NNP/B-PERSON voiced/VBD/O similar/JJ/O sentiments/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O somehow/RB/O OK/JJ/O for/IN/O Secretary/NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O say/VB/O all/DT/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O things/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O ;/:/O the/DT/O quotes/NNS/O above/RB/O are/VBP/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O speech/NN/O of/IN/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O see/VB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O disagreement/NN/O among/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Quayle/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Mr./NNP/O Gates/NNP/B-PERSON we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O read/VBN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O for/IN/O that/DT/O matter/NN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
They/PRP/O all/DT/O understand/VBP/O point/NN/O one/CD/O :/:/O Nothing/NN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE can/MD/O do/VB/O will/MD/O make/VB/O much/JJ/O difference/NN/O in/IN/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON succeeds/VBZ/O with/IN/O perestroika/FW/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Gates/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O emphasize/VB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON the/DT/O many/JJ/O hurdles/NNS/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O leader/NN/O must/MD/O leap/VB/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O everyone/NN/O agrees/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O problems/NNS/O result/VBP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O failure/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O system/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O relieved/VBN/O only/RB/O by/IN/O changing/VBG/O that/DT/O system/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O by/IN/O pouring/VBG/O Western/JJ/O money/NN/O into/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
GATT/NNP/B-ORG membership/NN/O will/MD/O not/RB/O matter/VB/O to/TO/O Donbas/NNP/B-GPE coal/NN/O miners/NNS/O short/JJ/O of/IN/O soap/NN/O ,/,/O nor/CC/O will/MD/O a/DT/O START/NNP/O treaty/NN/O make/VBP/O any/DT/O difference/NN/O to/TO/O Ukrainian/JJ/B-GPE nationalists/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O hand/NN/O ,/,/O so/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O easing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O grip/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O empire/NN/O ,/,/O everyone/NN/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O heard/VBN/O agrees/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE can/MD/O benefit/VB/O by/IN/O engaging/VBG/O him/PRP/O ././O
If/IN/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O Ortegas/NNPS/B-PERSON loose/RB/O from/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O why/WRB/O not/RB/O ?/./O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O contradictory/NN/O in/IN/O all/DT/O this/DT/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O nice/JJ/O to/TO/O think/VB/O that/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE could/MD/O tolerate/VB/O a/DT/O reasonably/RB/O sophisticated/JJ/O ,/,/O complex/JJ/O view/NN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O culture/NN/O seems/VBZ/O intent/NN/O on/IN/O castigating/VBG/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O for/IN/O not/RB/O ``/``/O helping/VBG/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
So/IN/O every/DT/O time/NN/O a/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON official/NN/O raises/VBZ/O a/DT/O doubt/NN/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE community/NN/O shouts/VBZ/O ``/``/O Cold/NNP/O War/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O timidity/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O an/DT/O administration/NN/O spokesman/NN/O is/VBZ/O quickly/RB/O trotted/VBN/O out/RP/O to/TO/O reply/VB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON wants/VBZ/O perestroika/FW/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O especially/RB/O sensitive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ailment/NN/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O Beltway-itis/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O symptoms/NNS/O include/VBP/O a/DT/O cold/JJ/O sweat/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O sound/NN/O of/IN/O debate/NN/O ,/,/O clammy/JJ/O hands/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O face/NN/O of/IN/O congressional/JJ/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O fainting/NN/O spells/NNS/O when/WRB/O someone/NN/O writes/VBZ/O the/DT/O word/NN/O ``/``/O controversy/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O one/CD/O unidentified/JJ/O official/NN/O clearly/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O stages/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O disease/NN/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O Times/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON just/RB/O felt/VBD/O that/IN/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O some/DT/O lines/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O speech/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O be/VB/O misinterpreted/VBN/O and/CC/O seized/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O short/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O intra-administration/JJ/O disagreement/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O preoccupation/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O that/DT/O perestrokia/NN/O might/MD/O fail/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O political/JJ/O opponents/NNS/O will/MD/O ask/VB/O ``/``/O Who/WP/O lost/VBD/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ?/./O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O criticism/NN/O from/IN/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Majority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Mitchell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O as/IN/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG his/PRP$/O audience/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O Free/JJ/O World/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O just/RB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O he/PRP/O muzzles/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O more/JJR/O leaks/NNS/O will/MD/O pop/VB/O up/RP/O all/DT/O around/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O lesson/NN/O once/RB/O learned/VBN/O by/IN/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Kissinger/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Letting/VBG/O officials/NNS/O express/VB/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O nuances/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O educational/JJ/O ././O
We/PRP/O note/VBP/O that/IN/O in/IN/O Rome/NNP/B-GPE yesterday/NN/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Cheney/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O European/JJ/O euphoria/NN/O over/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O starting/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O tempered/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O recognition/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O magnitude/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O deal/VB/O with/IN/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Western/JJ/O interest/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON succeed/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O odds/NNS/O are/VBP/O against/IN/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O himself/PRP/O would/MD/O no/RB/O doubt/VB/O tell/VB/O you/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O outcome/NN/O depends/VBZ/O on/IN/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O ,/,/O not/RB/O on/IN/O what/WP/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O is/VBZ/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O seize/VB/O and/CC/O misinterpret/VB/O ,/,/O these/DT/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O very/RB/O complicated/VBN/O thoughts/NNS/O ././O
Surely/RB/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O someone/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O ,/,/O maybe/RB/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Gates/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O could/MD/O explain/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O college/NN/O students/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O even/RB/O schoolchildren/NNS/O ././O
