Giant/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Delaware/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O denied/VBN/O a/DT/O motion/NN/O by/IN/O Rally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Inc./NN/I-ORG seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O block/VB/O a/DT/O group/NN/O led/VBD/O by/IN/O Giant/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Burt/NNP/B-PERSON Sugarman/NNP/I-PERSON from/IN/O acquiring/VBG/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sugarman/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O contended/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O major/JJ/O shareholder/NN/O group/NN/O --/:/O whose/WP$/O interests/NNS/O are/VBP/O represented/VBN/O by/IN/O three/CD/O other/JJ/O directors/NNS/O connected/VBN/O to/TO/O trusts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O children/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O founder/NN/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Patterson/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O has/VBZ/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O competing/VBG/O fast/JJ/O food/NN/O chain/NN/O ,/,/O Wendy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Each/DT/O group/NN/O controls/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Rally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG stock/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O just/RB/O went/VBD/O public/JJ/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
