EAST/NNS/O GERMANS/NNS/O RALLIED/VBD/O in/IN/O three/CD/O cities/NNS/O to/TO/O demand/VB/O democratic/JJ/O freedoms/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O leader/NN/O ,/,/O Egon/NNP/B-PERSON Krenz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O prepared/VBD/O to/TO/O travel/VB/O to/TO/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE today/NN/O for/IN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O leader/NN/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O East/NNP/O Germans/NNP/O massed/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O of/IN/O Leipzig/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Halle/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Schwerin/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O call/VB/O for/IN/O internal/JJ/O freedoms/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O legalization/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-ORG Forum/NNP/I-ORG opposition/NN/O group/NN/O ././O
Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O vowed/VBD/O to/TO/O preserve/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Communist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG hold/NN/O on/IN/O political/JJ/O power/NN/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O East/NNS/O Germans/NNS/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O destabilize/VB/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O with/IN/O unrealistic/JJ/O demands/NNS/O ././O
Communist/JJ/O officials/NNS/O this/DT/O month/NN/O have/VBP/O faced/VBN/O nearly/RB/O daily/JJ/O pro-democracy/JJ/O protests/NNS/O ,/,/O accompanied/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O flight/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O by/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O East/NNS/O Germans/NNS/O ././O
Soviet/JJ/O police/NNS/O clashed/VBD/O with/IN/O demonstrators/NNS/O in/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE following/VBG/O a/DT/O candlelight/NN/O vigil/NN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O KGB/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Lubyanka/NNP/B-FAC headquarters/NN/O in/IN/O memory/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O persecuted/VBN/O under/IN/O Stalin/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
More/RBR/O than/IN/O 1,000/CD/O Muscovites/NNS/O attended/VBD/O the/DT/O service/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O splinter/NN/O group/NN/O demonstrated/VBD/O in/IN/O Pushkin/NNP/B-FAC Square/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O police/NN/O clubbed/VBD/O and/CC/O detained/VBD/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O protesters/NNS/O ././O
Police/NNP/O in/IN/O Yugoslavia/NNP/B-GPE dispersed/VBD/O about/RB/O 1,000/CD/O ethnic/JJ/O Albanians/NNS/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O protesting/VBG/O the/DT/O trial/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Communist/NNP/B-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG chief/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O southern/JJ/O province/NN/O of/IN/O Kosovo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Azem/NNP/B-PERSON Vlasi/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O 14/CD/O others/NNS/O are/VBP/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O inciting/VBG/O riots/NNS/O and/CC/O strikes/NNS/O and/CC/O opposing/VBG/O constitutional/JJ/O limits/NNS/O to/TO/O Kosovo/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O autonomy/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O convicted/VBN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O be/VB/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O death/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Jerusalem/NNP/B-GPE sentenced/VBD/O a/DT/O Palestinian/NN/O to/TO/O 16/CD/O life/NN/O terms/NNS/O for/IN/O forcing/VBG/O a/DT/O bus/NN/O off/IN/O a/DT/O cliff/NN/O July/NNP/O 6/CD/O ,/,/O killing/VBG/O 16/CD/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O Israeli/JJ/O radio/NN/O reported/VBD/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O Kremlin/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O urged/VBN/O a/DT/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O output/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O poison/NN/O gases/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O producing/VBG/O the/DT/O weapons/NNS/O even/RB/O after/IN/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O treaty/NN/O calling/VBG/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O destruction/NN/O is/VBZ/O signed/VBN/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE government/NN/O said/VBD/O peaceful/JJ/O demonstrations/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O anti-apartheid/JJ/O rally/NN/O Sunday/NNP/O near/IN/O Soweto/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O helped/VBN/O ease/VB/O tensions/NNS/O and/CC/O assisted/VBN/O political/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ././O
About/RB/O 70,000/CD/O people/NNS/O attended/VBD/O the/DT/O anti-government/JJ/O rally/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O which/WDT/O leaders/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O banned/VBN/O African/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG refused/VBD/O to/TO/O renounce/VB/O violence/NN/O to/TO/O end/VB/O apartheid/NN/O ././O
Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Baker/NNP/B-PERSON expressed/VBD/O concern/NN/O that/IN/O Nicaraguan/NNP/O President/NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O attempt/VB/O to/TO/O use/VB/O alleged/JJ/O attacks/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S.backed/JJ/B-GPE Contra/NNP/B-ORG rebels/NNS/O as/IN/O an/DT/O excuse/NN/O to/TO/O scuttle/VB/O elections/NNS/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O February/NNP/O ././O
Baker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remarks/NNS/O came/VBD/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG urged/VBD/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O to/TO/O honor/VB/O the/DT/O truce/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O USS/NNP/O Lexington/NNP/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O dock/NN/O in/IN/O Pensacola/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Fla./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O following/VBG/O an/DT/O accident/NN/O Sunday/NNP/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O pilot/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O training/NN/O jet/NN/O crashed/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O ship/NN/O ,/,/O killing/VBG/O five/CD/O sailors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O captain/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O aircraft/NN/O carrier/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O oldest/JJS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O flier/NN/O was/VBD/O making/VBG/O his/PRP$/O first/JJ/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O land/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O carrier/NN/O ././O
Four/CD/O people/NNS/O torched/VBD/O three/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE flags/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O steps/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Capitol/NNP/B-FAC in/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O test/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O federal/JJ/O law/NN/O protecting/VBG/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O flag/NN/O from/IN/O desecration/NN/O ././O
All/DT/O four/CD/O demonstrators/NNS/O were/VBD/O arrested/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O law/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON allowed/VBD/O to/TO/O take/VB/O effect/NN/O without/IN/O his/PRP$/O signature/NN/O ,/,/O went/VBD/O into/IN/O force/NN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Embassy/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O filed/VBN/O three/CD/O protests/NNS/O in/IN/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O days/NNS/O with/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O government/NN/O ,/,/O alleging/VBG/O harassment/NN/O of/IN/O diplomats/NNS/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O families/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O embassy/NN/O source/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Authorities/NNP/O in/IN/O Algeria/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O the/DT/O toll/NN/O from/IN/O two/CD/O earthquakes/NNS/O Sunday/NNP/O had/VBD/O reached/VBN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 30/CD/O dead/JJ/O and/CC/O about/RB/O 250/CD/O injured/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O heaviest/JJS/O damage/NN/O was/VBD/O reported/VBN/O in/IN/O Tipasa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O about/RB/O 40/CD/O miles/NNS/O west/RB/O of/IN/O Algiers/NNP/B-GPE ././O
As/IN/O rescue/NN/O teams/NNS/O continued/VBD/O searching/VBG/O for/IN/O victims/NNS/O ,/,/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O suvivors/NNS/O accused/VBD/O the/DT/O government/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O feeble/JJ/O response/NN/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O temblors/NNS/O ././O
Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON summoned/VBD/O senior/JJ/O advisers/NNS/O for/IN/O strategy/NN/O talks/NNS/O as/IN/O opinion/NN/O polls/NNS/O showed/VBD/O the/DT/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O 's/POS/O popularity/NN/O had/VBD/O hit/VBN/O a/DT/O record/NN/O low/NN/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O resignation/NN/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O of/IN/O Chancellor/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Exchequer/NNP/B-ORG Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
One/CD/O poll/NN/O ,/,/O conducted/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG British/JJ/I-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O found/VBD/O that/IN/O 52/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O voters/NNS/O believed/VBD/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O should/MD/O quit/VB/O ././O
Lawmakers/NNS/O in/IN/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE approved/VBD/O legislation/NN/O granting/VBG/O amnesty/NN/O to/TO/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O crimes/NNS/O punishable/JJ/O by/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O also/RB/O established/VBD/O an/DT/O office/NN/O to/TO/O control/VB/O government/NN/O and/CC/O party/NN/O finances/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O laws/NNS/O take/VBP/O effect/NN/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Died/VBN/O :/:/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON V./NNP/I-PERSON Van/NNP/I-PERSON Fossan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 63/CD/O ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Mutual/NNP/B-ORG Benefit/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Sunday/NNP/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Morristown/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O of/IN/O cancer/NN/O ././O
