Their/PRP$/O factories/NNS/O may/MD/O look/VB/O like/IN/O sets/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O Spielberg/NNP/B-PERSON movie/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O their/PRP$/O offices/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O rows/NNS/O of/IN/O clerks/NNS/O hunched/VBN/O over/IN/O ledgers/NNS/O and/CC/O abacuses/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O more/RBR/O like/IN/O scenes/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Dickens/NNP/B-PERSON novel/NN/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O market/NN/O for/IN/O outsiders/NNS/O to/TO/O penetrate/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O hopelessly/RB/O behind/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O certain/JJ/O technologies/NNS/O ././O
Apple/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O doubled/VBN/O its/PRP$/O staff/NN/O here/RB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Lotus/NNP/B-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O slashed/VBN/O the/DT/O lag/NN/O between/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE product/NN/O introductions/NNS/O to/TO/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O from/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Typical/JJ/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O office/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Industry/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Machinery/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Information/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O overseeing/VBG/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O planning/NN/O and/CC/O sales/JJ/O promotion/NN/O office/NN/O of/IN/O Nomura/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 30/CD/O computers/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O 60/CD/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O respectable/JJ/O ratio/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O machines/NNS/O make/VBP/O charts/NNS/O for/IN/O presentations/NNS/O ././O
Others/NNS/O analyze/VBP/O the/DT/O data/NN/O ././O
Machines/NNS/O dedicated/VBN/O solely/RB/O to/TO/O word/NN/O processing/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O all/DT/O but/CC/O disappeared/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O more/RBR/O common/JJ/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE than/IN/O PCs/NNS/O ././O
Various/JJ/O cultural/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O forces/NNS/O have/VBP/O suppressed/VBN/O demand/NN/O ././O
Top/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O executives/NNS/O often/RB/O make/VBP/O decisions/NNS/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O consensus/NN/O and/CC/O personal/JJ/O relationships/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O complex/JJ/O financial/JJ/O projections/NNS/O and/CC/O fancy/JJ/O presentations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O dominated/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O giant/NN/O ,/,/O International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O small/JJ/O companies/NNS/O did/VBD/O ,/,/O swiftly/RB/O establishing/VBG/O a/DT/O standard/NN/O operating/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O spurs/VBZ/O competition/NN/O and/CC/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O allows/VBZ/O users/NNS/O to/TO/O change/VB/O and/CC/O mix/VB/O brands/NNS/O easily/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O increases/VBZ/O software/NN/O firms/NNS/O '/POS/O incentive/NN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O packages/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O users/NNS/O of/IN/O virtually/RB/O any/DT/O computer/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
NEC/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O release/VB/O its/PRP$/O code/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O every/DT/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O dozen/NN/O or/CC/O so/RB/O makers/NNS/O has/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O proprietary/NN/O operating/NN/O system/NN/O --/:/O all/DT/O incompatible/JJ/O with/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG established/VBD/O its/PRP$/O standard/NN/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O falling/VBG/O behind/IN/O upstart/NN/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O ahead/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O start/NN/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O need/VB/O to/TO/O invite/VB/O in/RB/O competitive/JJ/O allies/NNS/O ././O
Corporate/JJ/O pride/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O close/JJ/O ties/NNS/O common/JJ/O among/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O manufacturers/NNS/O help/VBP/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O ././O
Most/JJS/O rivals/NNS/O ``/``/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O working/NN/O relationship/NN/O with/IN/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O often/RB/O through/IN/O cross-licensing/NN/O of/IN/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/B-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG Personal/NNP/I-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Software/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG noted/VBD/O recently/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O many/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O higher/JJR/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O less/JJR/O innovation/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Fair/NNP/B-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG warned/VBD/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG about/IN/O possible/JJ/O violations/NNS/O of/IN/O anti-monopoly/JJ/O laws/NNS/O for/IN/O discouraging/VBG/O retailers/NNS/O from/IN/O discounting/VBG/O ././O
She/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O that/IN/O some/DT/O technological/JJ/O advances/NNS/O trail/VBP/O those/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE because/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O still/RB/O import/VBP/O basic/JJ/O operating/VBG/O systems/NNS/O from/IN/O American/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O funding/VBG/O several/JJ/O projects/NNS/O to/TO/O push/VB/O PC/NN/O use/NN/O ././O
Seiko/NNP/B-ORG Epson/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O newcomer/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O fought/VBN/O off/RP/O a/DT/O legal/JJ/O challenge/NN/O and/CC/O started/VBD/O selling/VBG/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG clones/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O won/VBN/O about/RB/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O retail/JJ/O PC/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O temporarily/RB/O dropped/VBD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O PC/NN/O business/NN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O started/VBD/O selling/VBG/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O station/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O quickly/RB/O became/VBD/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O Japanese/JJ/O company/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O even/RB/O dropping/VBG/O their/PRP$/O traditional/JJ/O independence/NN/O and/CC/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O band/VB/O together/RB/O to/TO/O create/VB/O some/DT/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O standard/NN/O ././O
Two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O smaller/JJR/O makers/NNS/O joined/VBD/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Microsoft/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG umbrella/NN/O to/TO/O adopt/VB/O a/DT/O version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/B-ORG IBM/NNP/B-ORG AT/NNP/O standard/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O healthy/JJ/O ,/,/O coherent/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O market/NN/O could/MD/O also/RB/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O far/RB/O easier/RBR/O for/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O their/PRP$/O share/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O minimal/JJ/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE makers/NNS/O have/VBP/O under/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O market/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O at/IN/O home/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O company/NN/O ,/,/O without/IN/O any/DT/O major/JJ/O effort/NN/O ,/,/O sells/VBZ/O more/JJR/O machines/NNS/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE than/IN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
They/PRP/O long/RB/O made/VBD/O little/JJ/O effort/NN/O here/RB/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O though/IN/O long/RB/O a/DT/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O mainframe/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O introduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O PC/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE until/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O after/IN/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O compatible/JJ/O even/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE IBM/NNP/B-ORG standard/NN/O ././O
Apple/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O introduce/VB/O a/DT/O kanji/FW/O machine/NN/O --/:/O one/NN/O that/WDT/O handles/VBZ/O the/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O characters/NNS/O of/IN/O written/VBN/O Japanese/NNP/O --/:/O until/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O after/IN/O entering/VBG/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Critics/NNS/O also/RB/O say/VBP/O American/JJ/O companies/NNS/O charge/VBP/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O investigating/VBG/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O allegedly/RB/O discouraging/VBG/O retailers/NNS/O from/IN/O discounting/VBG/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG just/RB/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O started/VBD/O selling/VBG/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O machine/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O run/VB/O in/IN/O both/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O and/CC/O English/NNP/O and/CC/O that/WDT/O substantially/RB/O enhances/VBZ/O compatibility/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O American/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
