-LRB-/-LRB-/O During/IN/O its/PRP$/O centennial/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O report/VB/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O century/NN/O that/WDT/O stand/VBP/O as/IN/O milestones/NNS/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O business/NN/O history/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Jefferson/NNP/I-PERSON sold/VBD/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O decimal/JJ/O system/NN/O for/IN/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O saving/VBG/O Americans/NNPS/O the/DT/O headaches/NNS/O of/IN/O pounds/NNS/O ,/,/O shillings/NNS/O and/CC/O pence/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O struck/VBD/O out/RP/O with/IN/O the/DT/O decimal/JJ/O system/NN/O of/IN/O metric/JJ/O weights/NNS/O and/CC/O measures/VBZ/O the/DT/O French/NNP/O had/VBD/O invented/VBN/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG opted/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O inches/NNS/O ,/,/O feet/NNS/O and/CC/O yards/NNS/O the/DT/O colonists/NNS/B-PERSON had/VBD/O brought/VBN/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
Americans/NNPS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O dislike/VB/O metrics/NNS/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O simply/RB/O ignored/VBD/O them/PRP/O ././O
Scientists/NNS/O felt/VBD/O differently/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O 1807/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Swiss/JJ/O mathematician/NN/O who/WP/O headed/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Coast/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Geodetic/NNP/I-ORG Survey/NNP/I-ORG made/VBD/O an/DT/O ``/``/O iron/NN/O meter/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O brought/VBN/O from/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC the/DT/O standard/NN/O of/IN/O measure/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O century/NN/O scientists/NNS/O had/VBD/O embraced/VBN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O ././O
Businessmen/NNS/O took/VBD/O their/PRP$/O cue/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O engineers/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG finally/RB/O passed/VBD/O the/DT/O Metric/NNP/O Conversion/NNP/O Act/NNP/O in/IN/O 1975/CD/O ,/,/O industry/NN/O was/VBD/O far/RB/O ahead/RB/O ././O
Because/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O made/VBD/O compliance/NN/O voluntary/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O inspired/VBD/O little/JJ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O jokes/NNS/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O the/DT/O public/NN/O is/VBZ/O barely/RB/O aware/JJ/O ,/,/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE industry/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O companies/NNS/O manufacturing/VBG/O or/CC/O selling/VBG/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O metrics/NNS/O routine/JJ/O ././O
General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O uses/VBZ/O metric/JJ/O terms/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O automobile/NN/O bodies/NNS/O and/CC/O power/NN/O trains/NNS/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O In/IN/O auto/NN/O advertising/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O items/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O wheelbases/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O described/VBN/O in/IN/O inches/NNS/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
The/DT/O liquor/NN/O industry/NN/O went/VBD/O metric/JJ/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
New/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O systems/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O around/RB/O until/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O century/NN/O ,/,/O notes/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Tascher/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG metric/JJ/O coordinator/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O like/IN/O the/DT/O auto/NN/O makers/NNS/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Everyman/NNP/B-PERSON the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG sticks/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O tried/JJ/O and/CC/O true/JJ/O ././O
Soldiers/NNS/O and/CC/O sailors/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O measured/VBN/O in/IN/O inches/NNS/O and/CC/O pounds/NNS/O ././O
