The/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG network/NN/O canceled/VBD/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O new/JJ/O series/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O fall/NN/O TV/NN/O season/NN/O ,/,/O killing/VBG/O Mel/NNP/B-PERSON Brooks/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON wacky/JJ/O hotel/NN/O comedy/NN/O ``/``/O The/NNP/O Nutt/NNP/O House/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O show/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O five/CD/O new/JJ/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG series/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O casualty/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O networks/NNS/O so/RB/O far/RB/O this/DT/O fall/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG canceled/VBD/O ``/``/O The/NNP/O People/NNP/O Next/NNP/O Door/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
NBC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O decided/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O permanent/JJ/O replacement/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O canceled/VBN/O series/NN/O ././O
