The/DT/O pact/NN/O also/RB/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O coordination/NN/O between/IN/O Finnair/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O national/JJ/O carrier/NN/O ,/,/O Swissair/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O which/WDT/O SAS/NNP/B-ORG entered/VBD/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O alliance/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Finnair/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O SAS/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O plan/VBP/O to/TO/O swap/VB/O stakes/NNS/O in/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
Neither/DT/O disclosed/VBD/O details/NNS/O pending/VBG/O board/NN/O meetings/NNS/O next/IN/O month/NN/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O hinted/VBD/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O SAS/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O stake/NN/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 6/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O Finnair/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O at/IN/O current/JJ/O market/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
Finnair/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O receive/VB/O SAS/NNP/B-ORG shares/NNS/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O amount/NN/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
