This/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O electronic/JJ/O devices/NNS/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O replaced/VBD/O all/DT/O five/CD/O incumbent/JJ/O directors/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O meeting/NN/O called/VBN/O by/IN/O Milton/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Hollander/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O High/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE acquired/VBD/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 49.4/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Newport/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O August/NNP/O ././O
Elected/VBN/O as/IN/O directors/NNS/O were/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Hollander/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Frederick/NNP/B-PERSON Ezekiel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Frederick/NNP/B-PERSON Ross/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Crozier/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON Pothier/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Removed/VBN/O from/IN/O office/NN/O were/VBD/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Pratt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Davis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Norman/NNP/B-PERSON Gray/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Virtue/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O corporate/JJ/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Barrett/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Weekes/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ././O
Newport/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O respond/VB/O Friday/NNP/O to/TO/O requests/NNS/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O but/CC/O earlier/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Weekes/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Hollander/NNP/B-PERSON wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O have/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O team/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
