The/DT/O government/NN/O directly/RB/O owns/VBZ/O 51.4/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O Factorex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O holds/VBZ/O 8.42/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O is/VBZ/O listed/VBN/O on/IN/O Spanish/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Luzon/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O team/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O merger/NN/O ././O
Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O 1929/CD/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O subsidized/JJ/O credits/NNS/O for/IN/O Spanish/JJ/O exports/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O export/NN/O financing/NN/O was/VBD/O liberalized/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1980s/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O forcing/VBG/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O to/TO/O face/NN/O competition/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O two/CD/O main/JJ/O pillars/NNS/O of/IN/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG traditional/JJ/O business/NN/O --/:/O wholesale/JJ/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O currency/NN/O trading/NN/O --/:/O also/RB/O began/VBD/O to/TO/O crumble/VB/O under/IN/O the/DT/O weight/NN/O of/IN/O heavy/JJ/O competition/NN/O and/CC/O changing/VBG/O client/NN/O needs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O was/VBD/O hamstrung/JJ/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O face/VB/O the/DT/O challenges/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O changing/VBG/O market/NN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O links/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O employs/VBZ/O 8,000/CD/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O 2,000/CD/O abroad/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O aggressively/RB/O marketing/VBG/O retail/JJ/O services/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O domestic/JJ/O branches/NNS/O ././O
Though/NNP/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O an/DT/O excess/NN/O of/IN/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O country/NN/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O profitable/JJ/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O aid/VB/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O the/DT/O tough/JJ/O tasks/NNS/O it/PRP/O faces/VBZ/O ahead/RB/O ././O
Expansion/NN/O plans/NNS/O also/RB/O include/VBP/O acquisitions/NNS/O in/IN/O growing/VBG/O foreign/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O interested/VBN/O in/IN/O purchasing/VBG/O banks/NNS/O in/IN/O Morocco/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Portugal/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O banks/NNS/O to/TO/O create/VB/O a/DT/O brokerage/NN/O house/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O four/CD/O Spanish/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O underwent/VBD/O sweeping/JJ/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O late/JJ/O start/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O handicap/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O as/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O open/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O market/NN/O to/TO/O foreign/JJ/O competition/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O also/RB/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 'll/MD/O use/VB/O its/PRP$/O international/JJ/O network/NN/O to/TO/O channel/VB/O investment/NN/O from/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Zurich/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE into/IN/O the/DT/O Spanish/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O ././O
