The/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O measure/NN/O builds/VBZ/O on/IN/O a/DT/O pattern/NN/O set/VBN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O by/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG defense/NN/O authorizing/VBG/O committees/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O --/:/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O retrenchment/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O military/NN/O and/CC/O concern/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/VBZ/O standing/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O economy/NN/O --/:/O overseas/JJ/O spending/NN/O is/VBZ/O most/RBS/O vulnerable/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O extra/JJ/O margin/NN/O for/IN/O bases/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE enhances/VBZ/O the/DT/O power/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O appropriations/NNS/O committees/NNS/O ;/:/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O lawmakers/NNS/O used/VBD/O their/PRP$/O positions/NNS/O to/TO/O garner/VB/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O six/CD/O times/NNS/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O requested/VBN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O individual/JJ/O states/NNS/O ././O
House/NNP/B-ORG Appropriations/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Jamie/NNP/B-PERSON Whitten/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Miss/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O helped/VBD/O secure/VB/O $/$/O 49.7/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O state/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O double/RB/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O budget/NN/O ././O
West/NNP/B-GPE Virginia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O home/NN/O of/IN/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Appropriations/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Byrd/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O would/MD/O receive/VB/O $/$/O 21.5/CD/O million/CD/O --/:/O four/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O military/NN/O 's/POS/O request/NN/O ././O
Tennessee/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O North/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O home/NN/O states/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O Democratic/JJ/O chairmen/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG military/JJ/O construction/NN/O subcommittees/NNS/O ,/,/O receive/VBP/O $/$/O 243.2/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O above/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O request/NN/O ././O
Though/IN/O spending/NN/O for/IN/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Oregon/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O far/RB/O less/JJR/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O increases/NNS/O above/IN/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG requests/NNS/O --/:/O 640/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O 430/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O respectively/RB/O --/:/O were/VBD/O much/RB/O greater/JJR/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O influence/NN/O of/IN/O Republicans/NNPS/O at/IN/O critical/JJ/O junctures/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O swift/JJ/O passage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O cleared/VBD/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O House/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O simple/JJ/O voice/NN/O votes/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O contrasts/VBZ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O still/RB/O facing/VBG/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O cumbersome/JJ/O $/$/O 66.8/CD/O billion/CD/O measure/NN/O funding/VBG/O housing/NN/O ,/,/O environmental/JJ/O ,/,/O space/NN/O and/CC/O veterans/NNS/O programs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG Democratic/JJ/O leadership/NN/O could/MD/O seek/VB/O to/TO/O waive/VB/O these/DT/O restrictions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O underlying/JJ/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O under/IN/O attack/NN/O for/IN/O excesses/NNS/O elsewhere/RB/O ././O
Appropriations/NNS/O committees/NNS/O have/VBP/O used/VBN/O an/DT/O assortment/NN/O of/IN/O devices/NNS/O to/TO/O disguise/VB/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O spending/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O as/IN/O critics/NNS/O have/VBP/O awakened/VBN/O to/TO/O these/DT/O devices/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O can/MD/O seem/VB/O like/IN/O a/DT/O wounded/JJ/O caribou/NN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O past/IN/O ice/NN/O and/CC/O wolves/NNS/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O safer/JJR/O winter/NN/O grazing/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 177/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O nearly/RB/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O account/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O marked/VBN/O for/IN/O potential/JJ/O transfers/NNS/O to/TO/O research/NN/O ,/,/O management/NN/O and/CC/O flight/NN/O accounts/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O spent/VBN/O out/RP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O faster/JJR/O clip/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O 's/POS/O managers/NNS/O face/VBP/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O unusual/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O conditions/NNS/O openly/RB/O imposed/VBN/O on/IN/O where/WRB/O funds/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O spent/VBN/O ././O
Within/IN/O discretionary/JJ/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O community/NN/O development/NN/O grants/NNS/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 3.7/CD/O million/CD/O is/VBZ/O allocated/VBN/O to/TO/O six/CD/O projects/NNS/O in/IN/O Michigan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O home/NN/O state/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O subcommittee/NN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Traxler/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
House/NNP/B-ORG Speaker/NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Foley/NNP/I-PERSON won/VBD/O $/$/O 510,000/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O project/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O district/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O earmarked/VBN/O by/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Inouye/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O amounts/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O business/NN/O subsidy/NN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O title/NN/O ``/``/O Hawaiian/JJ/O sugar/NN/O mills/NNS/O job/NN/O retention/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O powerful/JJ/O Democrat/NNP/O had/VBD/O first/RB/O wanted/VBN/O to/TO/O add/VB/O language/NN/O relaxing/VBG/O environmental/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O two/CD/O mills/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Hamakua/NN/I-LOC coast/NN/I-LOC that/WDT/O are/VBP/O threatening/VBG/O to/TO/O close/VB/O ././O
When/WRB/O this/DT/O plan/NN/O met/VBD/O resistance/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O agreed/VBN/O instead/RB/O to/TO/O take/VB/O money/NN/O from/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O subsidize/VB/O needed/JJ/O improvements/NNS/O in/IN/O two/CD/O settling/NN/O ponds/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O mills/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O employ/VBP/O an/DT/O estimated/JJ/O 1,500/CD/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Inouye/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O office/NN/O ././O
