Texas/NNP/B-ORG Instruments/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O once/RB/O a/DT/O pioneer/NN/O in/IN/O portable/JJ/O computer/NN/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O today/NN/O will/MD/O make/VB/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O reassert/VB/O itself/PRP/O in/IN/O that/DT/O business/NN/O by/IN/O unveiling/VBG/O three/CD/O small/JJ/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O introduction/NN/O comes/VBZ/O only/RB/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O after/IN/O Compaq/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O believing/VBG/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O lead/NN/O of/IN/O three/CD/O to/TO/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O on/IN/O competitors/NNS/O ,/,/O introduced/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE notebook/NN/O computer/NN/O with/IN/O such/JJ/O features/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O introductions/NNS/O also/RB/O mark/VBP/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Instruments/NNP/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG plunge/NN/O back/RB/O into/IN/O a/DT/O technology/NN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O all/RB/O but/RB/O ignored/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O stopped/VBD/O selling/VBG/O a/DT/O standard/JJ/O personal/JJ/O computer/NN/O a/DT/O while/NN/O ago/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O laptops/NNS/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O revolutionary/JJ/O and/CC/O ,/,/O indeed/RB/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O tardy/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O market/NN/O first/RB/O opened/VBN/O by/IN/O GRiD/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O now/RB/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Tandy/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O almost/RB/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O keyboard/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O industry/NN/O consultants/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O better/JJR/O than/IN/O Compaq/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O battery/NN/O life/NN/O of/IN/O two/CD/O to/TO/O three/CD/O hours/NNS/O is/VBZ/O shorter/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/O notebook/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O TI/NNP/O Model/NNP/O 12/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O priced/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 4,199/CD/O ././O
