Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O trim/VB/O its/PRP$/O Aeronautical/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG work/NN/O force/NN/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O several/JJ/O hundred/CD/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O reflecting/VBG/O the/DT/O defense/NN/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O decline/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG unit/NN/O has/VBZ/O 24,000/CD/O workers/NNS/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O cuts/NNS/O through/IN/O a/DT/O combination/NN/O of/IN/O furloughs/NNS/O ,/,/O attrition/NN/O and/CC/O retirements/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O reductions/NNS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O complete/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O exact/JJ/O number/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O determined/VBN/O ././O
Noting/VBG/O that/IN/O other/JJ/O defense/NN/O contractors/NNS/O are/VBP/O complaining/VBG/O of/IN/O losses/NNS/O on/IN/O such/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O taxpayers/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O getting/VBG/O illusionary/JJ/O bargains/NNS/O on/IN/O weapons/NNS/O systems/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
Defense/NN/O contractors/NNS/O ``/``/O can/MD/O not/RB/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O get/VB/O contracts/NNS/O on/IN/O that/DT/O basis/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Howard/NNP/B-PERSON Rubel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O with/IN/O C.J./NNP/B-ORG Lawrence/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O pain/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O great/JJ/O ././O
