Retailers/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC are/VBP/O entering/VBG/O the/DT/O critical/JJ/O Christmas/NNP/O shopping/NN/O season/NN/O with/IN/O more/JJR/O momentum/NN/O than/IN/O those/DT/O in/IN/O other/JJ/O regions/NNS/O ././O
Sales/NNS/O increased/VBD/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O modest/JJ/O 4.8/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O 4.4/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Midwest/NNP/B-LOC ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O Northeast/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O sales/NNS/O declined/VBD/O 0.4/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O period/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O sales/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-LOC England/NNP/I-LOC falling/VBG/O 2.6/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O numbers/NNS/O show/VBP/O that/IN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O monolithic/JJ/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Isaac/NNP/B-PERSON Lagnado/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O council/NN/O research/NN/O director/NN/O ././O
Sales/NNS/O nationally/RB/O rose/VBD/O 3.9/CD/O %/NN/O through/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O month/NN/O for/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O figures/NNS/O are/VBP/O available/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O council/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Northern/NNP/O California/NNP/B-GPE earthquake/NN/O and/CC/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O temporarily/RB/O damp/VB/O sales/JJ/O growth/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Lagnado/NNP/B-PERSON predicted/VBD/O the/DT/O regional/JJ/O trends/NNS/O would/MD/O continue/VB/O through/IN/O Christmas/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O big/JJ/O mo/NN/O is/VBZ/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O a/DT/O factor/NN/O in/IN/O retailing/NN/O as/IN/O in/IN/O politics/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Christmas/NNP/O quarter/NN/O is/VBZ/O important/JJ/O to/TO/O retailers/NNS/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O represents/VBZ/O roughly/RB/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O nearly/RB/O half/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O profits/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O council/NN/O 's/POS/O report/NN/O is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O data/NNS/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O group/NN/O buys/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Census/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O council/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O release/VB/O its/PRP$/O regional/JJ/O reports/NNS/O monthly/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lagnado/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O strength/NN/O in/IN/O employment/NN/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O growth/NN/O ././O
El/NNP/B-GPE Paso/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Austin/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Fort/NNP/B-GPE Worth/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O three/CD/O strongest/JJS/O retail/JJ/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O all/DT/O located/VBN/O in/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O employment/NN/O grew/VBD/O a/DT/O relatively/RB/O strong/JJ/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O results/NNS/O reflect/VBP/O a/DT/O reversal/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fortunes/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O regions/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC had/VBD/O the/DT/O slowest/JJS/O sales/NNS/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O the/DT/O Midwest/NNP/B-LOC were/VBD/O first/JJ/O and/CC/O second/JJ/O respectively/RB/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O council/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lagnado/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O although/IN/O retailers/NNS/O probably/RB/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O ever/RB/O recover/VB/O sales/NNS/O lost/VBN/O because/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE quake/NN/O and/CC/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O see/VB/O some/DT/O benefits/NNS/O later/RB/O on/RB/O ././O
