The/DT/O following/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Treasury/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O corporate/JJ/O and/CC/O municipal/JJ/O offerings/NNS/O are/VBP/O tentatively/RB/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNP/I-ORG Report/NNP/I-ORG :/:/O
Chemex/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceuticals/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 1.2/CD/O million/CD/O units/NNS/O consisting/VBG/O of/IN/O two/CD/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O common/JJ/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O one/CD/O common/JJ/O warrant/NN/O ,/,/O via/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Comcast/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O convertible/JJ/O debentures/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Energy/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 9.5/CD/O million/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Alex/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Harmonia/NNP/B-ORG Bancorp/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 4,750,000/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Immune/NNP/B-ORG Response/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O Three/CD/O million/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Potash/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Saskatchewan/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 13/CD/O million/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Municipal/JJ/O
New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE Wastewater/NNP/O Treatment/NNP/O Trust/NNP/O --/:/O $/$/O 75,075,000/CD/O of/IN/O various/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O $/$/O 40.86/CD/O million/CD/O Wastewater/NNP/O Treatment/NNP/O insured/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O Series/NNP/O 1989A/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O $/$/O 34,215,000/CD/O Wastewater/NNP/O Treatment/NNP/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O Series/NNP/O 1989B/NNP/O ,/,/O via/IN/O competitive/JJ/O bid/NN/O ././O
Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Municipal/NNP/I-LOC Water/NNP/I-LOC District/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 56,565,000/CD/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O certificates/NNS/O of/IN/O participation/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O treatment/NN/O plant/NN/O projects/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O via/IN/O competitive/JJ/O bid/NN/O ././O
California/NNP/B-GPE Health/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNP/I-ORG Financing/NNP/I-ORG Authority/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O $/$/O 114/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O health/NN/O facility/NN/O revenue/NN/O bonds/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Catholic/NNP/B-ORG Healthcare/NNP/I-ORG West/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O Series/NNP/O 1989A/NNP/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O ././O
Detroit/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 130/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O distributable/JJ/O state/NN/O aid/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O ././O
Matagorda/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE Navigation/NNP/B-LOC District/NNP/I-LOC No./NN/I-LOC 1/CD/I-LOC ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 70,315,000/CD/O of/IN/O pollution/NN/O control/NN/O revenue/NN/O Alternative/NNP/O Minimum/NNP/O Tax/NNP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O AMT/NNP/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O bonds/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O South/NNP/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE Project/NNP/B-ORG Units/NNP/I-ORG No./VB/I-ORG 1/CD/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG 2/CD/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O ././O
Pending/NNP/O Shelby/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Tenn./NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 80/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O refunding/VBG/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O Series/NNP/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O First/NNP/B-ORG Tennessee/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O ././O
