While/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O 's/POS/O tough/JJ/O times/NNS/O and/CC/O lower/JJR/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O undermine/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ,/,/O weakness/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O offset/VB/O those/DT/O factors/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O late/JJ/O Friday/NNP/O afternoon/NN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE trading/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O was/VBD/O at/IN/O 1.8300/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 141.65/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O off/RB/O from/IN/O late/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O 's/POS/O 1.8400/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 142.10/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O pound/NN/O strengthened/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.5795/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.5765/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE currency/NN/O opened/VBD/O for/IN/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O 141.70/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O down/IN/O from/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE close/NN/O of/IN/O 142.75/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O began/VBD/O Friday/NNP/O on/IN/O a/DT/O firm/NN/O note/NN/O ,/,/O gaining/VBG/O against/IN/O all/DT/O major/JJ/O currencies/NNS/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE dealings/NNS/O and/CC/O early/JJ/O European/JJ/O trading/NN/O despite/IN/O reports/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O seen/VBN/O unloading/VBG/O dollars/NNS/O around/RB/O 142.70/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O rise/NN/O came/VBD/O as/IN/O traders/NNS/O continued/VBD/O to/TO/O dump/VB/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O sudden/JJ/O resignation/NN/O Thursday/NNP/O of/IN/O British/NNP/O Chancellor/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Exchequer/NNP/O Nigel/NNP/B-PERSON Lawson/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
While/IN/O some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O eventually/RB/O could/MD/O test/VB/O support/NN/O at/IN/O 1.75/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 135/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Scalfaro/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O see/VB/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O decisively/RB/O sliding/VBG/O under/IN/O support/NN/O at/IN/O 1.80/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 140/CD/O yen/NNS/O soon/RB/O ././O
Predictions/NNS/O for/IN/O limited/JJ/O dollar/NN/O losses/NNS/O are/VBP/O based/VBN/O largely/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O 's/POS/O weak/JJ/O state/NN/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O resignation/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O 's/POS/O inability/NN/O to/TO/O strengthen/VB/O substantially/RB/O when/WRB/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O dollar/NN/O retreats/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O lagging/VBG/O behind/IN/O other/JJ/O major/JJ/O currencies/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O confirmation/NN/O ''/''/O that/IN/O a/DT/O sharp/JJ/O dollar/NN/O downturn/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O works/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mike/NNP/B-PERSON Malpede/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O currency/NN/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O Refco/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ././O
As/RB/O far/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O goes/VBZ/O ,/,/O some/DT/O traders/NNS/O say/VB/O a/DT/O slide/NN/O toward/IN/O support/NN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.5500/CD/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O favorable/JJ/O development/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O has/VBZ/O attempted/VBN/O to/TO/O stabilize/VB/O ,/,/O currency/NN/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O critical/JJ/O condition/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O succeeded/VBN/O by/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Major/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O Friday/NNP/O expressed/VBD/O a/DT/O desire/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O firm/JJ/O pound/NN/O and/CC/O supported/VBD/O the/DT/O relatively/RB/O high/JJ/O British/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O working/VBG/O exactly/RB/O as/RB/O intended/VBN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O reducing/VBG/O inflation/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O market/NN/O remains/VBZ/O uneasy/JJ/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Major/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O policy/NN/O strategy/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O prospects/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O ,/,/O currency/NN/O analysts/NNS/O contend/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O fair/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O more/JJR/O risks/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O under/IN/O Major/JJ/B-PERSON than/IN/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O under/IN/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON Roberts/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O bond/NN/O market/NN/O research/NN/O at/IN/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O some/DT/O other/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O stormier/JJR/O forecast/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O because/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O inflation/NN/O is/VBZ/O hovering/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O relatively/RB/O lofty/JJ/O annual/JJ/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O 7.6/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O is/VBZ/O burdened/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O struggling/VBG/O government/NN/O and/CC/O large/JJ/O current/JJ/O account/NN/O and/CC/O trade/NN/O deficits/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O pound/NN/O was/VBD/O at/IN/O 2.8896/CD/O marks/NNS/O late/JJ/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O off/RB/O sharply/RB/O from/IN/O 2.9511/CD/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE trading/NN/O a/DT/O week/NN/O earlier/RBR/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O falls/VBZ/O closer/RBR/O to/TO/O 2.80/CD/O marks/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O raise/VB/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O base/NN/O lending/NN/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O one/CD/O percentage/NN/O point/NN/O to/TO/O 16/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Rendell/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O such/PDT/O an/DT/O increase/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O could/MD/O be/VB/O viewed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O too/RB/O little/JJ/O too/RB/O late/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Pound/NN/O concerns/NNS/O aside/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O strong/JJ/O buying/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O is/VBZ/O another/DT/O boon/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O traders/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O yen/NN/O 's/POS/O softness/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O apparently/RB/O stems/VBZ/O from/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O investors/NNS/O '/POS/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O buying/VBG/O dollars/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE bond/NN/O issues/NNS/O and/CC/O persistent/JJ/O worries/NNS/O about/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O upheaval/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O government/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE Commodity/NNP/B-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O gold/NN/O for/IN/O current/JJ/O delivery/NN/O jumped/VBD/O $/$/O 5.80/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O $/$/O 378.30/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O settlement/NN/O since/IN/O July/NNP/O 12/CD/O ././O
Estimated/JJ/O volume/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O heavy/JJ/O seven/CD/O million/CD/O ounces/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O early/JJ/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O gold/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 378.87/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ././O
