ABB/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O ,/,/O signed/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Dutch/JJ/O utility/NN/O N.V/NNP/B-ORG ././I-ORG Energieproduktiebedrijf/NNP/I-ORG UNA/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O valued/VBN/O in/IN/O excess/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
ABB/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O order/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O placed/VBN/O with/IN/O Dutch/JJ/O subcontractors/NNS/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O a/DT/O group/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O set/VBN/O up/RP/O for/IN/O this/DT/O purpose/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Dutch/JJ/O utility/NN/O firm/NN/O serves/VBZ/O the/DT/O Amsterdam/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Utrecht/NNP/B-GPE areas/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O planned/JJ/O turbogenerator/NN/O plant/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O go/VB/O into/IN/O operation/NN/O in/IN/O 1994/CD/O ././O
