American/NNP/B-ORG Pioneer/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O in/IN/O principle/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O American/NNP/B-ORG Pioneer/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O to/TO/O Harcourt/NNP/B-ORG Brace/NNP/I-ORG Jovanovich/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG HBJ/NNP/B-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Cos./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 27/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Pioneer/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Pioneer/NNP/I-ORG Savings/NNPS/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O will/MD/O add/VB/O capital/NN/O and/CC/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O level/NN/O of/IN/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O subsidiaries/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ././O
Recently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O boards/NNS/O of/IN/O both/CD/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O also/RB/O voted/VBD/O to/TO/O suspend/VB/O dividends/NNS/O on/IN/O preferred/JJ/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O both/DT/O companies/NNS/O and/CC/O convert/VB/O all/DT/O preferred/JJ/O into/IN/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O move/NN/O was/VBD/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O capital/NN/O requirements/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O execution/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O purchase/NN/O agreement/NN/O and/CC/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O various/JJ/O regulatory/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O departments/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O states/NNS/O of/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Indiana/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Pioneer/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 7.3/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O net/JJ/O income/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O earlier/RBR/O ././O
