Mobil/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O cutting/VBG/O back/RP/O its/PRP$/O exploration/NN/O and/CC/O production/NN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O finds/VBZ/O and/CC/O develops/VBZ/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O reserves/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O by/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O sector/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O business/NN/O ././O
Management/NN/O advised/VBD/O employees/NNS/O Friday/NNP/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O employment/NN/O in/IN/O production/NN/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O by/IN/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 400/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O exploration/NN/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O has/VBZ/O recently/RB/O undergone/VBN/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O overhaul/NN/O ,/,/O during/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O lost/VBD/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 400/CD/O employees/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O company/NN/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O questions/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG restructured/VBD/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O company/NN/O during/IN/O an/DT/O industrywide/JJ/O shakeout/NN/O ././O
Mobil/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O any/DT/O additional/JJ/O charges/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O move/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O in/IN/O future/JJ/O quarters/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O Wednesday/NNP/O ,/,/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O begin/VB/O offering/VBG/O separation/NN/O packages/NNS/O and/CC/O voluntary/JJ/O retirement/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE production/NN/O operation/NN/O ././O
Mobil/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O studying/VBG/O ways/NNS/O of/IN/O streamlining/VBG/O these/DT/O operations/NNS/O since/IN/O early/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O coming/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O layers/NNS/O of/IN/O management/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O peeled/VBN/O away/RB/O and/CC/O regional/JJ/O offices/NNS/O will/MD/O become/VB/O more/RBR/O autonomous/JJ/O ././O
For/IN/O greater/JJR/O efficiency/NN/O ,/,/O employees/NNS/O at/IN/O those/DT/O locations/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O reorganized/VBN/O into/IN/O teams/NNS/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O managing/VBG/O the/DT/O properties/NNS/O under/IN/O their/PRP$/O jurisdiction/NN/O ,/,/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O main/JJ/O feature/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O organization/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O each/DT/O local/JJ/O manager/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O both/CC/O the/DT/O authority/NN/O and/CC/O accountability/NN/O for/IN/O profitable/JJ/O and/CC/O technically/RB/O sound/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Spruell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
Field/NN/O offices/NNS/O at/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Orleans/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Midland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tex./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Bakersfield/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O and/CC/O Liberal/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kan./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O maintained/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O staffs/NNS/O at/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O those/DT/O locations/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O slashed/VBN/O while/IN/O at/IN/O others/NNS/O the/DT/O work/NN/O force/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O increased/VBN/O ././O
For/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O employment/NN/O in/IN/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O be/VB/O reduced/VBN/O to/TO/O 105/CD/O from/IN/O 430/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC West/NNP/I-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O where/WRB/O profitable/JJ/O oil/NN/O production/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O likely/JJ/O than/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O midcontinent/JJ/O region/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Bakersfield/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O office/NN/O staff/NN/O of/IN/O 130/CD/O will/MD/O grow/VB/O by/IN/O 175/CD/O to/TO/O 305/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O reorganization/NN/O will/MD/O ``/``/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O and/CC/O potential/NN/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Spruell/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
