Crawford/NNP/B-ORG evaluates/VBZ/O health/NN/O care/NN/O plans/NNS/O ,/,/O manages/VBZ/O medical/JJ/O and/CC/O disability/NN/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O worker/NN/O 's/POS/O compensation/NN/O injuries/NNS/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O claims/NNS/O adjustments/NNS/O for/IN/O insurance/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O beginning/VBG/O trading/VBG/O today/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O El/NNP/B-ORG Paso/NNP/I-ORG Refinery/NNP/I-ORG Limited/NNP/I-ORG Partnership/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O El/NNP/B-GPE Paso/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O ELP/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Franklin/NNP/B-ORG Multi-Income/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Mateo/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O FMI/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
El/NNP/B-ORG Paso/NNP/I-ORG owns/VBZ/O and/CC/O operates/VBZ/O a/DT/O petroleum/NN/O refinery/NN/O ././O
