Chief/JJ/O executives/NNS/O and/CC/O presidents/NNS/O had/VBD/O come/VBN/O and/CC/O gone/VBN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O at/IN/O a/DT/O turning/NN/O point/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O done/VBN/O what/WP/O I/PRP/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O ''/''/O at/IN/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carpenter/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O return/VB/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O prominence/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O investment/NN/O bank/NN/O ././O
Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O is/VBZ/O understandably/RB/O skeptical/JJ/O ././O
Gary/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Goldstein/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Whitney/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O executive/JJ/O search/NN/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O succeed/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O good/JJ/O senior/JJ/O bankers/NNS/O who/WP/O can/MD/O bring/VB/O in/RP/O the/DT/O business/NN/O from/IN/O day/NN/O one/CD/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG eked/VBD/O out/RP/O a/DT/O $/$/O 46/CD/O million/CD/O profit/NN/O ,/,/O mainly/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O severe/JJ/O cost/NN/O cutting/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O even/RB/O that/DT/O niche/NN/O is/VBZ/O under/IN/O attack/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O several/JJ/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O firms/NNS/O pulled/VBD/O back/RP/O from/IN/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O under/IN/O pressure/NN/O from/IN/O big/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O dizzying/JJ/O parade/NN/O of/IN/O studies/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O operations/NNS/O ././O
More/JJR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O new/JJ/O managing/VBG/O directors/NNS/O and/CC/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O presidents/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O hired/VBN/O since/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carpenter/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O assumes/VBZ/O full/JJ/O control/NN/O ,/,/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O finally/RB/O tap/VB/O the/DT/O resources/NNS/O of/IN/O GE/NNP/B-ORG ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O teaming/VBG/O up/RP/O ,/,/O GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG staffers/NNS/O and/CC/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O have/VBP/O bickered/VBN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Carpenter/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VB/O really/RB/O started/VBN/O to/TO/O exploit/VB/O the/DT/O synergy/NN/O between/IN/O GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG Peabody/NNP/I-ORG ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O units/NNS/O have/VBP/O worked/VBN/O on/IN/O 37/CD/O investment/NN/O banking/NN/O deals/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O though/IN/O not/RB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O have/VBP/O panned/VBN/O out/RP/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O relationship/NN/O with/IN/O GE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O you/PRP/O could/MD/O say/VB/O that/DT/O --/:/O uh/UH/O ,/,/O let/VB/O me/PRP/O withdraw/VB/O that/DT/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O steadily/RB/O improving/VBG/O relationship/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Carpenter/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O without/IN/O many/JJ/O actual/JJ/O deals/NNS/O to/TO/O show/VB/O off/RP/O ,/,/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O left/VBN/O to/TO/O stress/VB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O finally/RB/O has/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O team/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O everyone/NN/O works/VBZ/O harder/RBR/O ././O
A/DT/O month/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O started/VBD/O serving/VBG/O dinner/NN/O at/IN/O about/RB/O 7:30/CD/O each/DT/O night/NN/O ;/:/O about/RB/O 50/CD/O to/TO/O 60/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 350/CD/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O investment/NN/O banking/NN/O operation/NN/O have/VBP/O consistently/RB/O been/VBN/O around/RB/O that/DT/O late/RB/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O working/VBG/O significantly/RB/O longer/RBR/O and/CC/O harder/RBR/O than/IN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Scott/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Newquist/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O head/NN/O of/IN/O investment/NN/O banking/NN/O since/IN/O June/NNP/O ././O
Everywhere/RB/O ,/,/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG stresses/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O always/RB/O working/VBG/O ''/''/O theme/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O head/NN/O of/IN/O mergers/NNS/O and/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O under/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Newquist/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O B.J./NNP/B-PERSON Megargel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O talks/VBZ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O rebuild/VB/O a/DT/O franchise/NN/O ''/''/O at/IN/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG name/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O only/RB/O six/CD/O or/CC/O seven/CD/O that/WDT/O every/DT/O CEO/NN/O recognizes/VBZ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O viable/JJ/O alternative/NN/O ''/''/O when/WRB/O considering/VBG/O a/DT/O merger/NN/O deal/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG story/NN/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Megargel/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O all/DT/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O do/VB/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O position/VB/O ourselves/PRP/O more/RBR/O in/IN/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O flow/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Carpenter/NNP/B-PERSON denies/VBZ/O the/DT/O speculation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carpenter/NNP/B-PERSON notes/NNS/O that/IN/O these/DT/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O investors/NNS/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O sophisticated/JJ/O ''/''/O enough/RB/O not/RB/O to/TO/O complain/VB/O about/IN/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O aggressive/JJ/O use/NN/O of/IN/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O will/MD/O get/VB/O ``/``/O new/JJ/O and/CC/O improved/JJ/O tools/NNS/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O affluent/JJ/O investor/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O brokerage/NN/O chief/NN/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON V./NNP/I-PERSON Sheehan/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Theoretically/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O brokers/NNS/O will/MD/O then/RB/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O funnel/VB/O ``/``/O leads/NNS/O ''/''/O on/IN/O corporate/JJ/O finance/NN/O opportunities/NNS/O to/TO/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O ,/,/O possibly/RB/O easing/VBG/O the/DT/O longstanding/JJ/O tension/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O camps/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O skeptics/NNS/O caution/VBP/O that/IN/O this/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O cross-pollination/NN/O between/IN/O brokers/NNS/O and/CC/O investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O looks/VBZ/O great/JJ/O on/IN/O paper/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O always/RB/O happen/VB/O ././O
Kidder/NNP/B-ORG competitors/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O outwardly/RB/O hostile/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O many/JJ/O are/VBP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O competitor/NN/O like/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG that/WDT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O long/JJ/O history/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O departing/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Cathcart/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O worries/NNS/O about/IN/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O future/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O improved/VBD/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O compliance/NN/O procedures/NNS/O for/IN/O trading/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O absolutely/RB/O marvelous/JJ/O line/NN/O and/CC/O one/CD/O I/PRP/O used/VBD/O many/JJ/O times/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
In/IN/O coming/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Cathcart/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O Kidder/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O ``/``/O gon/VBG/O na/TO/O hum/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
