Mobil/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O cutting/VBG/O back/RP/O its/PRP$/O exploration/NN/O and/CC/O production/NN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O finds/VBZ/O and/CC/O develops/VBZ/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O reserves/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O by/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O sector/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O business/NN/O ././O
Management/NN/O advised/VBD/O employees/NNS/O Friday/NNP/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O employment/NN/O in/IN/O production/NN/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O by/IN/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 400/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O exploration/NN/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O has/VBZ/O recently/RB/O undergone/VBN/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O overhaul/NN/O ,/,/O during/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O lost/VBD/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 400/CD/O employees/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O company/NN/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O questions/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG restructured/VBD/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O company/NN/O during/IN/O an/DT/O industrywide/JJ/O shakeout/NN/O ././O
Mobil/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O any/DT/O additional/JJ/O charges/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O move/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O in/IN/O future/JJ/O quarters/NNS/O ././O
Mobil/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O studying/VBG/O ways/NNS/O of/IN/O streamlining/VBG/O these/DT/O operations/NNS/O since/IN/O early/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Field/NN/O offices/NNS/O at/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Orleans/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Midland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tex./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Bakersfield/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O and/CC/O Liberal/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kan./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O maintained/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O reorganization/NN/O will/MD/O ``/``/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O and/CC/O potential/NN/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Spruell/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
