NBI/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O Oct./NNP/O 31/CD/O dividend/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O Series/NNP/O A/NNP/O convertible/JJ/O preferred/JJ/O stock/NN/O ,/,/O allowing/VBG/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O 's/POS/O holder/NN/O to/TO/O convert/VB/O the/DT/O shares/NNS/O into/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 27.7/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O NBI/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O shares/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ././O
NBI/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O dividend/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O surplus/NN/O or/CC/O profit/NN/O required/VBN/O under/IN/O Delaware/NNP/B-GPE law/NN/O for/IN/O payment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O dividend/NN/O ././O
All/PDT/O the/DT/O preferred/JJ/O stock/NN/O is/VBZ/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Yukon/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG Supply/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Ownership/NNP/I-ORG Plan/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Under/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Yukon/NNP/I-ORG ESOP/NNP/I-ORG can/MD/O demand/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O be/VB/O redeemed/VBN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 4,090,000/CD/O on/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O NBI/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O legally/RB/O prohibited/VBN/O from/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O redemption/NN/O ././O
Failure/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O dividend/NN/O allows/VBZ/O Yukon/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O convert/VB/O all/DT/O or/CC/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O into/IN/O NBI/NNP/B-ORG common/JJ/O after/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O at/IN/O a/DT/O conversion/NN/O price/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O NBI/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O closing/NN/O stock/NN/O price/NN/O ././O
