President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON insists/VBZ/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O tool/NN/O for/IN/O curbing/VBG/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O deficit/NN/O and/CC/O slicing/VBG/O the/DT/O lard/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O government/NN/O programs/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O it/PRP/O now/RB/O ././O
Whatever/WDT/O one/PRP/O thinks/VBZ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O far/RB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O budgetary/JJ/O gimmick/NN/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O seem/VB/O at/IN/O first/JJ/O glance/NN/O ././O
White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG aides/NNS/O know/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O step/NN/O that/WDT/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O lightly/RB/O --/:/O and/CC/O for/IN/O that/DT/O reason/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O may/MD/O back/VB/O down/RP/O from/IN/O launching/VBG/O a/DT/O test/NN/O case/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O issue/NN/O arose/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O when/WRB/O Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Quayle/NNP/I-PERSON told/VBD/O an/DT/O audience/NN/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O a/DT/O test/NN/O case/NN/O ././O
White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/O Secretary/NNP/O Marlin/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzwater/NNP/I-PERSON confirmed/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O cautioned/VBD/O that/IN/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O firm/JJ/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O try/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Those/DT/O bills/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O easily/RB/O be/VB/O vetoed/VBN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O entirety/NN/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O often/RB/O are/VBP/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O operating/VBG/O ././O
This/DT/O clause/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O argue/VBP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O go/VB/O beyond/IN/O an/DT/O earlier/JJR/O clause/NN/O specifying/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O can/MD/O veto/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O broad/JJ/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O strike/VB/O out/RP/O items/NNS/O and/CC/O riders/NNS/O within/IN/O bills/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/POS/O little/JJ/O doubt/NN/O that/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O move/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O immediately/RB/O challenged/VBN/O in/IN/O court/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O quickly/RB/O make/VB/O its/PRP$/O way/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O be/VB/O ultimately/RB/O resolved/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O notes/VBZ/O that/IN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O lawmaker/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O fights/VBZ/O each/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O preserve/VB/O federal/JJ/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Bay/NNP/B-ORG Area/NNP/I-ORG Rapid/NNP/I-ORG Transit/NNP/I-ORG system/NN/O ././O
Big/JJ/O chunks/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O budget/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O the/DT/O entitlement/NN/O programs/NNS/O of/IN/O Social/NNP/B-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Medicare/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O affected/VBN/O ././O
Governors/NNS/O have/VBP/O found/VBN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O use/VB/O the/DT/O device/NN/O sparingly/RB/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O political/JJ/O comity/NN/O ././O
Republicans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O interest/NN/O as/IN/O Democrats/NNPS/O in/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O way/NN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O works/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O notes/VBZ/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Edwards/NNP/B-PERSON voices/VBZ/O the/DT/O traditional/JJ/O conservative/JJ/O view/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O mistake/NN/O to/TO/O put/VB/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O power/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O person/NN/O ././O
