Under/IN/O the/DT/O direction/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Francisco/NNP/B-PERSON Luzon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O seventh/JJ/O largest/JJS/O bank/NN/O is/VBZ/O undergoing/VBG/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O that/WDT/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O step/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O privatization/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O directly/RB/O owns/VBZ/O 51.4/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O Factorex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O holds/VBZ/O 8.42/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O is/VBZ/O listed/VBN/O on/IN/O Spanish/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O ././O
Catching/VBG/O up/RP/O with/IN/O commercial/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O in/IN/O retail/JJ/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O argue/VBP/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O difficult/JJ/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O if/IN/O market/NN/O conditions/NNS/O turn/VBP/O sour/JJ/O ././O
If/IN/O that/DT/O proves/VBZ/O true/JJ/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG could/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O prime/JJ/O partner/NN/O --/:/O or/CC/O even/RB/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O target/NN/O --/:/O for/IN/O either/CC/O a/DT/O Spanish/JJ/O or/CC/O foreign/JJ/O bank/NN/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O its/PRP$/O market/NN/O share/NN/O after/IN/O 1992/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O dismantle/VB/O financial/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O 700/CD/O branches/NNS/O in/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O 12/CD/O banking/NN/O subsidiaries/NNS/O ,/,/O five/CD/O branches/NNS/O and/CC/O 12/CD/O representative/JJ/O offices/NNS/O abroad/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O a/DT/O potential/JJ/O suitor/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Luzon/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O team/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O merger/NN/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O working/VBG/O to/TO/O transform/VB/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG into/IN/O an/DT/O efficient/JJ/O bank/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O 1929/CD/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O subsidized/JJ/O credits/NNS/O for/IN/O Spanish/JJ/O exports/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O export/NN/O financing/NN/O was/VBD/O liberalized/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1980s/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O forcing/VBG/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O to/TO/O face/NN/O competition/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O traditional/JJ/O export/NN/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O other/JJ/O developing/VBG/O areas/NNS/O faced/VBD/O a/DT/O sharp/JJ/O decline/NN/O in/IN/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG export/NN/O credit/NN/O portfolio/NN/O plunged/VBD/O from/IN/O 824/CD/O billion/CD/O pesatas/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 7.04/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O as/IN/O of/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 31/CD/O ,/,/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O 522/CD/O billion/CD/O pesetas/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O two/CD/O main/JJ/O pillars/NNS/O of/IN/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG traditional/JJ/O business/NN/O --/:/O wholesale/JJ/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O currency/NN/O trading/NN/O --/:/O also/RB/O began/VBD/O to/TO/O crumble/VB/O under/IN/O the/DT/O weight/NN/O of/IN/O heavy/JJ/O competition/NN/O and/CC/O changing/VBG/O client/NN/O needs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O was/VBD/O hamstrung/JJ/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O face/VB/O the/DT/O challenges/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O changing/VBG/O market/NN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O links/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Until/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Luzon/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O the/DT/O helm/NN/O last/JJ/O November/NNP/O ,/,/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O politicians/NNS/O who/WP/O lacked/VBD/O either/CC/O the/DT/O skills/NNS/O or/CC/O the/DT/O will/NN/O to/TO/O introduce/VB/O innovative/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Luzon/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O moved/VBN/O swiftly/RB/O to/TO/O streamline/VB/O bureaucracy/NN/O ,/,/O cut/VB/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O increase/VB/O capital/NN/O and/CC/O build/VB/O up/RP/O new/JJ/O areas/NNS/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O acknowledged/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBN/O to/TO/O move/VB/O quickly/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Luzon/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O first/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O eliminated/VBD/O 800/CD/O jobs/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O it/PRP/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 'll/MD/O trim/VB/O another/DT/O 1,200/CD/O jobs/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O three/CD/O to/TO/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O employs/VBZ/O 8,000/CD/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O 2,000/CD/O abroad/RB/O ././O
To/TO/O strengthen/VB/O its/PRP$/O capital/NN/O base/NN/O ,/,/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG this/DT/O year/NN/O issued/VBD/O $/$/O 105/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O subordinated/JJ/O debt/NN/O ,/,/O launched/VBD/O two/CD/O rights/NNS/O issues/NNS/O and/CC/O sold/VBD/O stock/NN/O held/VBN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O treasury/NN/O to/TO/O small/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O aggressively/RB/O marketing/VBG/O retail/JJ/O services/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O domestic/JJ/O branches/NNS/O ././O
Though/NNP/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O an/DT/O excess/NN/O of/IN/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O country/NN/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O profitable/JJ/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O aid/VB/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O the/DT/O tough/JJ/O tasks/NNS/O it/PRP/O faces/VBZ/O ahead/RB/O ././O
Expansion/NN/O plans/NNS/O also/RB/O include/VBP/O acquisitions/NNS/O in/IN/O growing/VBG/O foreign/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O interested/VBN/O in/IN/O purchasing/VBG/O banks/NNS/O in/IN/O Morocco/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Portugal/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O retail/JJ/O activities/NNS/O in/IN/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O back/RP/O ././O
Banco/NNP/B-ORG Exterior/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O banks/NNS/O to/TO/O create/VB/O a/DT/O brokerage/NN/O house/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O four/CD/O Spanish/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O underwent/VBD/O sweeping/JJ/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O late/JJ/O start/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O handicap/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O as/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O open/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O market/NN/O to/TO/O foreign/JJ/O competition/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Luzon/NNP/B-PERSON contends/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O experienced/JJ/O team/NN/O he/PRP/O brought/VBD/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O from/IN/O Banco/NNP/B-ORG Bilbao/NNP/I-ORG Vizcaya/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O formerly/RB/O director/NN/O general/JJ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O whip/VB/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O capital/NN/O market/NN/O division/NN/O into/IN/O shape/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O also/RB/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 'll/MD/O use/VB/O its/PRP$/O international/JJ/O network/NN/O to/TO/O channel/VB/O investment/NN/O from/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Zurich/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE into/IN/O the/DT/O Spanish/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O ././O
