Nissan/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG expects/VBZ/O net/JJ/O income/NN/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O 120/CD/O billion/CD/O yen/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O U.S./NNP/O $/$/O 857/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 114.6/CD/O billion/CD/O yen/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Yutaka/NNP/B-PERSON Kume/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kume/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O the/DT/O earnings/NNS/O projection/NN/O for/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O ending/VBG/O next/JJ/O March/NNP/O 31/CD/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O with/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE automotive/JJ/O writers/NNS/O attending/VBG/O the/DT/O Tokyo/NNP/O Motor/NNP/O Show/NNP/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Kume/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O overseas/JJ/O vehicle/NN/O production/NN/O sufficiently/RB/O to/TO/O account/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O outside/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Kume/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG exported/VBD/O slightly/RB/O over/IN/O one/CD/O million/CD/O vehicles/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O produced/VBD/O 570,000/CD/O cars/NNS/O and/CC/O trucks/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O factories/NNS/O in/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O by/IN/O 1992/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O Nissan/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O build/VB/O one/CD/O million/CD/O vehicles/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O outside/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O or/CC/O sufficient/JJ/O to/TO/O equal/VB/O exports/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O By/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1990s/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O producing/VBG/O roughly/RB/O two/CD/O vehicles/NNS/O overseas/RB/O for/IN/O every/DT/O vehicle/NN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O export/VBP/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
That/WDT/O will/MD/O involve/VB/O a/DT/O substantial/JJ/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O overseas/JJ/O manufacturing/NN/O capacity/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O acknowledged/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O provide/VB/O specific/JJ/O details/NNS/O ././O
