Employees/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Globe/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Mail/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Thomson/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG newspaper/NN/O in/IN/O Toronto/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O voted/VBD/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O a/DT/O tentative/JJ/O contract/NN/O agreement/NN/O Saturday/NNP/O ,/,/O averting/VBG/O a/DT/O strike/NN/O at/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leading/JJ/O daily/NN/O ././O
Lorne/NNP/B-PERSON Slotnick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG Ontario/NNP/I-ORG Newspaper/NNP/I-ORG Guild/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O union/NN/O representing/VBG/O the/DT/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Thomson/NNP/B-ORG made/VBD/O significant/JJ/O concessions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O round/NN/O of/IN/O talks/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bargaining/NN/O unit/NN/O voted/VBD/O in/IN/O favor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ././O
