Nicaraguan/JJ/O President/NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Ortega/NNP/I-PERSON may/MD/O have/VB/O accomplished/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O what/WP/O his/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE antagonists/NNS/O have/VBP/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O :/:/O revive/VB/O a/DT/O constituency/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Contra/NNP/B-ORG rebels/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON returned/VBD/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE Saturday/NNP/O night/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O asked/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE humanitarian/JJ/O aid/NN/O be/VB/O diverted/VBN/O to/TO/O disarming/VBG/O and/CC/O demobilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O did/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O comments/NNS/O come/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O was/VBD/O intended/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O showcase/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O came/VBD/O as/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O under/IN/O special/JJ/O international/JJ/O scrutiny/NN/O in/IN/O anticipation/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O planned/JJ/O February/NNP/O elections/NNS/O ././O
Outside/JJ/O observers/NNS/O are/VBP/O gathering/VBG/O in/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O monitor/VB/O the/DT/O registration/NN/O and/CC/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O opposition/NN/O candidates/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O humanitarian/JJ/O assistance/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O pays/VBZ/O for/IN/O supplies/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O food/NN/O and/CC/O clothing/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O amassed/VBN/O along/IN/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O border/NN/O with/IN/O Honduras/NNS/B-GPE ,/,/O replaced/VBD/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O cut/VBN/O off/RP/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O February/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
While/IN/O few/JJ/O lawmakers/NNS/O anticipated/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O humanitarian/JJ/O aid/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O off/RP/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O threat/NN/O practically/RB/O guarantees/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O humanitarian/JJ/O aid/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O continued/VBN/O ././O
Senate/NNP/B-ORG Minority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Dole/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Kan/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O on/IN/O ``/``/O Meet/NNP/O the/NNP/O Press/NNP/O ''/''/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O hope/VB/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O act/NN/O yesterday/NN/O or/CC/O the/DT/O day/NN/O before/IN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O 'd/MD/O have/VB/O unanimous/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O quick/JJ/O action/NN/O on/IN/O remaining/VBG/O humanitarian/JJ/O aid/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Sen./NNP/O Dole/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O hoped/VBD/O for/IN/O unanimous/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O resolution/NN/O he/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O tomorrow/NN/O denouncing/VBG/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O leader/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O renewing/VBG/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O considered/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O question/NN/O ,/,/O rejected/VBN/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O de-emphasized/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O statement/NN/O provides/VBZ/O Contra/NNP/B-ORG supporters/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O press/VB/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O administration/NN/O should/MD/O now/RB/O state/VB/O that/IN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O February/NNP/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O election/NN/O is/VBZ/O voided/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Sandinistas/NNS/O .../:/O they/PRP/O should/MD/O call/VB/O for/IN/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O former/JJ/O Assistant/NNP/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Elliott/NNP/B-PERSON Abrams/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O these/DT/O circumstances/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O they/PRP/O 'd/MD/O win/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Sen./NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O congressional/JJ/O Democrats/NNPS/O intend/VBP/O to/TO/O honor/VB/O the/DT/O March/NNP/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O non-lethal/JJ/O support/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/B-ORG through/IN/O the/DT/O February/NNP/O elections/NNS/O ,/,/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O requires/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/B-ORG not/RB/O initiate/VB/O any/DT/O military/JJ/O action/NN/O ././O
Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG James/NNP/B-PERSON Baker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O accompanied/VBD/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O Friday/NNP/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O reason/NN/O to/TO/O deny/VB/O reports/NNS/O that/IN/O some/DT/O Contras/NNP/B-ORG ambushed/VBD/O some/DT/O Sandinista/NNP/O soldiers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O undermining/VBG/O arguments/NNS/O in/IN/O favor/NN/O of/IN/O ending/VBG/O Contra/NNP/B-ORG aid/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remarks/NNS/O also/RB/O played/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O suspicions/NNS/O of/IN/O some/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O and/CC/O conservatives/NNS/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O searching/VBG/O for/IN/O ways/NNS/O to/TO/O manipulate/VB/O or/CC/O void/VB/O the/DT/O February/NNP/O elections/NNS/O ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O traveling/VBG/O with/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE interpreted/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/VBZ/O wavering/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O sign/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O responding/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O attacks/NNS/O so/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O searching/VBG/O for/IN/O ways/NNS/O to/TO/O strengthen/VB/O his/PRP$/O hand/NN/O prior/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O elections/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Abrams/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O demobilize/VB/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/B-ORG prior/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O elections/NNS/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O any/DT/O pressure/NN/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O fair/JJ/O elections/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O My/PRP$/O sense/NN/O is/VBZ/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O in/IN/O mind/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O excuse/NN/O for/IN/O clamping/VBG/O down/RP/O on/IN/O campaigning/NN/O ''/''/O by/IN/O creating/VBG/O an/DT/O atmosphere/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O military/JJ/O emergency/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
