Federal/JJ/O investigators/NNS/O have/VBP/O identified/VBN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O in/IN/O last/JJ/O July/NNP/O 's/POS/O crash/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG flight/NN/O in/IN/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE :/:/O a/DT/O structural/JJ/O flaw/NN/O that/WDT/O developed/VBD/O during/IN/O the/DT/O making/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O titanium/NN/O engine/NN/O disk/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O several/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Aviation/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Safety/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O suspected/VBN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O metallurgical/JJ/O flaw/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O disk/NN/O led/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O crack/NN/O that/WDT/O ultimately/RB/O caused/VBD/O the/DT/O tail/NN/O engine/NN/O to/TO/O break/VB/O apart/RB/O in/IN/O flight/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O investigators/NNS/O could/MD/O confirm/VB/O their/PRP$/O theory/NN/O only/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O retrieval/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O chunk/NN/O of/IN/O Flight/NNP/O 232/CD/O 's/POS/O tail/NN/O engine/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O cornfield/NN/O near/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Sioux/NNP/I-FAC City/NNP/I-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC in/IN/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O safety/NN/O board/NN/O will/MD/O begin/VB/O four/CD/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O hearings/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O accident/NN/O tomorrow/NN/O in/IN/O Sioux/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O the/DT/O board/NN/O will/MD/O examine/VB/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O UAL/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O should/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O detect/VB/O the/DT/O cracks/NNS/O through/IN/O maintenance/NN/O checks/NNS/O ././O
Anthony/NNP/B-PERSON Broderick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O FAA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O acting/JJ/O executive/NN/O director/NN/O for/IN/O regulatory/JJ/O standards/NNS/O and/CC/O compliance/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O recent/JJ/O tests/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O failed/JJ/O engine/NN/O disk/NN/O indicate/VBP/O that/IN/O a/DT/O flaw/NN/O --/:/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O hard/JJ/O alpha/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O occurred/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O titanium/NN/O during/IN/O its/PRP$/O production/NN/O almost/RB/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O detect/VB/O the/DT/O flaw/NN/O at/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O has/VBZ/O since/IN/O been/VBN/O changed/VBN/O to/TO/O decrease/VB/O the/DT/O chance/NN/O that/IN/O such/JJ/O flaws/NNS/O would/MD/O occur/VB/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O GE/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O FAA/NNP/B-ORG all/RB/O along/RB/O on/IN/O this/DT/O issue/NN/O and/CC/O ``/``/O will/MD/O comply/VB/O fully/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O required/JJ/O inspections/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O also/RB/O pointed/VBD/O out/RP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O recalls/NNS/O will/MD/O have/VB/O no/DT/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O GE/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O engine/NN/O production/NN/O ././O
