Milton/NNP/B-PERSON Petrie/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Petrie/NNP/B-ORG Stores/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O his/PRP$/O 15.2/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Deb/NNP/B-ORG Shops/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O Petrie/NNP/B-ORG Stores/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O will/MD/O take/VB/O place/NN/O tomorrow/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O filing/NN/O said/VBD/O Petrie/NNP/B-ORG Stores/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/O Secaucus/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O purchasing/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Petrie/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Deb/NNP/B-ORG Shops/NNPS/I-ORG stake/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Uhr/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Petrie/NNP/B-PERSON or/CC/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O accumulating/VBG/O Deb/NNP/B-ORG Shops/NNPS/I-ORG stock/NN/O for/IN/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O each/DT/O time/NN/O issuing/VBG/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O regulatory/JJ/O statement/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O no/DT/O discussions/NNS/O currently/RB/O are/VBP/O taking/VBG/O place/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O ././O
