The/DT/O United/NNP/B-GPE Kingdom/NNP/I-GPE reports/NNS/O came/VBD/O from/IN/O Dr./NNP/O Patrick/NNP/B-PERSON Toseland/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O clinical/JJ/O chemistry/NN/O at/IN/O Guy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Hospital/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O telephone/NN/O interview/NN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O Dr./NNP/O Toseland/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O sudden/JJ/O ,/,/O unexplained/JJ/O deaths/NNS/O of/IN/O diabetics/NNS/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O seen/VBN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O was/VBD/O 17/CD/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O just/RB/O two/CD/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ././O
At/IN/O least/JJS/O six/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O deaths/NNS/O occurred/VBD/O among/IN/O relatively/RB/O young/JJ/O diabetics/NNS/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O switched/VBN/O from/IN/O animal/NN/O to/TO/O human/JJ/O insulin/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Solomon/NNP/B-PERSON Sobel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O metabolism/NN/O and/CC/O endrocrine/JJ/O drug/NN/O products/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Food/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O discussed/VBN/O Dr./NNP/O Toseland/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O findings/NNS/O ``/``/O fairly/RB/O intensively/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
While/IN/O there/EX/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O no/DT/O reports/NNS/O of/IN/O similar/JJ/O sudden/JJ/O unexplained/JJ/O deaths/NNS/O among/IN/O diabetics/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Dr./NNP/O Sobel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG plans/NNS/O to/TO/O examine/VB/O Dr./NNP/O Toseland/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O evidence/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O study/NN/O here/RB/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Toseland/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O toxicologist/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O preparing/VBG/O an/DT/O article/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O British/JJ/O forensic/JJ/O medical/JJ/O journal/NN/O raising/VBG/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O deaths/NNS/O may/MD/O have/VB/O occurred/VBN/O after/IN/O human/JJ/O insulin/NN/O blunted/VBD/O critical/JJ/O warning/NN/O signs/NNS/O indicating/VBG/O hypoglycemia/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O low/JJ/O blood/NN/O sugar/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O can/MD/O kill/VB/O diabetics/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O usual/JJ/O warning/NN/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O hypoglycemia/NN/O include/VBP/O sweating/NN/O ,/,/O anxiety/NN/O and/CC/O cramps/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O proper/JJ/O warning/NN/O ,/,/O diabetics/NNS/O can/MD/O easily/RB/O raise/VB/O their/PRP$/O blood/NN/O sugar/NN/O to/TO/O safe/JJ/O levels/NNS/O by/IN/O eating/VBG/O sugar/NN/O or/CC/O sugary/JJ/O food/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O anecdotal/JJ/O data/NN/O certainly/RB/O shows/VBZ/O that/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O were/VBD/O not/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O rapid/JJ/O onset/NN/O of/IN/O hypoglycemia/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Dr./NNP/O Toseland/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Institutes/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Dr./NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Silverman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O diabetes/NN/O program/NN/O branch/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O no/DT/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O unexpected/JJ/O deaths/NNS/O from/IN/O hypoglycemia/NN/O had/VBD/O shown/VBN/O up/RP/O in/IN/O a/DT/O study/NN/O of/IN/O 1,500/CD/O diabetics/NNS/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O under/IN/O way/NN/O at/IN/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O officials/NNS/O conducting/VBG/O the/DT/O study/NN/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O problems/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O hypoglycemia/NN/O unawareness/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O monitoring/VBG/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O closely/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O know/VB/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O slight/JJ/O differences/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O human/JJ/O and/CC/O animal/JJ/O insulins/NNS/O drive/VBP/O down/RP/O blood/NN/O sugar/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Dr./NNP/O Sobel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O enough/JJ/O of/IN/O a/DT/O difference/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O clinically/RB/O significant/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Dr./NNP/O Sobel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Reports/NNS/O of/IN/O Dr./NNP/O Toseland/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O findings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O press/NN/O have/VBP/O triggered/VBN/O widespread/JJ/O concern/NN/O among/IN/O diabetics/NNS/O there/RB/O ././O
Both/DT/O the/DT/B-ORG British/NNP/I-ORG Diabetic/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG Safety/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/I-ORG Medicines/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O equivalent/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG FDA/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O recently/RB/O issued/VBD/O statements/NNS/O noting/VBG/O the/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O hard/JJ/O scientific/JJ/O evidence/NN/O to/TO/O support/VB/O Dr./NNP/O Toseland/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O findings/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Diabetes/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG issued/VBD/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O statement/NN/O urging/VBG/O the/DT/O six/CD/O million/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE diabetics/NNS/O not/RB/O to/TO/O overreact/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O report/NN/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O warning/NN/O symptoms/NNS/O of/IN/O hypoglycemia/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O complex/JJ/O problem/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O unlikely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O due/RB/O simply/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O type/NN/O of/IN/O insulin/NN/O used/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O association/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Lilly/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O building/VBG/O plants/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O insulin/NN/O in/IN/O Indianapolis/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Fagershein/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O its/PRP$/O latest/JJS/O annual/JJ/O report/NN/O ,/,/O Lilly/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Humulin/NNP/O sales/NNS/O have/VBP/O shown/VBN/O ``/``/O excellent/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Lilly/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O seen/VBN/O reports/NNS/O of/IN/O hypoglycemic/JJ/O unawareness/NN/O among/IN/O some/DT/O patients/NNS/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O shift/NN/O from/IN/O animal/JJ/O to/TO/O human/JJ/O insulin/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O had/VBD/O caused/VBN/O any/DT/O deaths/NNS/O ././O
None/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O diabetics/NNS/O were/VBD/O using/VBG/O Lilly/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O insulin/NN/O ././O
