Nicaraguan/JJ/O President/NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Ortega/NNP/I-PERSON may/MD/O have/VB/O accomplished/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O what/WP/O his/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE antagonists/NNS/O have/VBP/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O :/:/O revive/VB/O a/DT/O constituency/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Contra/NNP/B-ORG rebels/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON returned/VBD/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE Saturday/NNP/O night/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O asked/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE humanitarian/JJ/O aid/NN/O be/VB/O diverted/VBN/O to/TO/O disarming/VBG/O and/CC/O demobilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O ././O
Outside/JJ/O observers/NNS/O are/VBP/O gathering/VBG/O in/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O monitor/VB/O the/DT/O registration/NN/O and/CC/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O opposition/NN/O candidates/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O humanitarian/JJ/O assistance/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O pays/VBZ/O for/IN/O supplies/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O food/NN/O and/CC/O clothing/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O amassed/VBN/O along/IN/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O border/NN/O with/IN/O Honduras/NNS/B-GPE ,/,/O replaced/VBD/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O cut/VBN/O off/RP/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O February/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Dole/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O hoped/VBD/O for/IN/O unanimous/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O resolution/NN/O he/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O tomorrow/NN/O denouncing/VBG/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O leader/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O congressional/JJ/O Democrats/NNPS/O intend/VBP/O to/TO/O honor/VB/O the/DT/O March/NNP/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O non-lethal/JJ/O support/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/B-ORG through/IN/O the/DT/O February/NNP/O elections/NNS/O ,/,/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O requires/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/B-ORG not/RB/O initiate/VB/O any/DT/O military/JJ/O action/NN/O ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O traveling/VBG/O with/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE interpreted/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/VBZ/O wavering/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O sign/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O responding/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O attacks/NNS/O so/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O searching/VBG/O for/IN/O ways/NNS/O to/TO/O strengthen/VB/O his/PRP$/O hand/NN/O prior/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O elections/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Abrams/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O demobilize/VB/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/B-ORG prior/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O elections/NNS/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O any/DT/O pressure/NN/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O fair/JJ/O elections/NNS/O ././O
