In/IN/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O letter/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O run/VB/O today/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O journal/NN/O Automotive/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Ron/NNP/B-PERSON Tonkin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Car/NNP/I-ORG Dealers/NNPS/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O dealers/NNS/O should/MD/O cut/VB/O their/PRP$/O inventories/NNS/O to/TO/O no/DT/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O level/NN/O traditionally/RB/O considered/VBN/O desirable/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tonkin/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O feuding/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Big/NNP/O Three/NNP/O since/IN/O he/PRP/O took/VBD/O office/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O with/IN/O half/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O dealers/NNS/O losing/VBG/O money/NN/O or/CC/O breaking/VBG/O even/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O time/NN/O for/IN/O ``/``/O emergency/NN/O action/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE car/NN/O dealers/NNS/O had/VBD/O an/DT/O average/NN/O of/IN/O 59/CD/O days/NNS/O '/POS/O supply/NN/O of/IN/O cars/NNS/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O lots/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Ward/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Automotive/NNP/O Reports/NNPS/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Tonkin/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O dealers/NNS/O should/MD/O slash/VB/O stocks/NNS/O to/TO/O between/IN/O 15/CD/O and/CC/O 30/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O of/IN/O financing/VBG/O inventory/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O message/NN/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O a/DT/O chilly/JJ/O reception/NN/O in/IN/O Detroit/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O Big/NNP/O Three/NNP/O auto/NN/O makers/NNS/O are/VBP/O already/RB/O being/VBG/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O close/VB/O plants/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O soft/JJ/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O reduced/JJ/O dealer/NN/O orders/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O before/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Tonkin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O broadside/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O large/JJ/O dealers/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O cutting/VBG/O inventories/NNS/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG representatives/NNS/O criticized/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Tonkin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O plan/NN/O as/IN/O unworkable/JJ/O ././O
