Wilfred/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Educational/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/O in/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE indicted/VBD/O the/DT/O operator/NN/O of/IN/O cosmetology/NN/O and/CC/O business/NN/O schools/NNS/O for/IN/O mail/NN/O fraud/NN/O ././O
No/DT/O individuals/NNS/O were/VBD/O charged/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O indictment/NN/O ././O
Wilfred/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O ``/``/O vigorously/RB/O defend/VB/O ''/''/O itself/PRP/O against/IN/O the/DT/O charges/NNS/O and/CC/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O charges/NNS/O relate/VBP/O to/TO/O procedures/NNS/O that/WDT/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O since/RB/O changed/VBN/O ././O
Wilfred/NNP/B-ORG closed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE schools/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG composite/JJ/O trading/NN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O Wilfred/NNP/B-ORG fell/VBD/O 6.25/CD/O cents/NNS/O to/TO/O 93.75/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O ././O
