The/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O 1989/CD/O budget/NN/O deficit/NN/O figure/NN/O came/VBD/O out/RP/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O down/IN/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O time/NN/O you/PRP/O hear/VBP/O a/DT/O Member/NNP/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG moan/VB/O about/IN/O the/DT/O deficit/NN/O ,/,/O consider/VB/O what/WP/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
Senator/NNP/B-PERSON Byrd/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Appropriations/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Rep./NNP/O Jamie/NNP/B-PERSON Whitten/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Mississippi/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG Appropriations/NNPS/I-ORG turned/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON request/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O state/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 49.7/CD/O million/CD/O bequest/NN/O ././O
Senator/NNP/O Sasser/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Tennessee/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Appropriations/NNPS/B-ORG subcommittee/NN/O on/IN/O military/JJ/O construction/NN/O ;/:/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O $/$/O 87/CD/O million/CD/O request/NN/O for/IN/O Tennessee/NNP/B-GPE increased/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 109/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Tell/VB/O us/PRP/O about/IN/O spending/NN/O restraint/NN/O ././O
Tell/VB/O us/PRP/O about/IN/O the/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG scandals/NNS/O ././O
Tell/VB/O us/PRP/O what/WDT/O measure/NN/O ,/,/O short/RB/O of/IN/O house/NN/O arrest/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O get/VB/O this/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG under/IN/O control/NN/O ././O
