Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O applied/VBD/O to/TO/O Taiwanese/JJ/O securities/NNS/O officials/NNS/O for/IN/O permission/NN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O brokerage/NN/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Taipei/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Shearson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O application/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O since/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Taiwan/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O June/NNP/O 21/CD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O foreign/JJ/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O to/TO/O do/VB/O business/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O review/VB/O the/DT/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG application/NN/O later/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O rules/NNS/O will/MD/O allow/VB/O investors/NNS/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O foreign/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O directly/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O brokerage/NN/O service/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O directed/VBN/O at/IN/O individual/JJ/O investors/NNS/O who/WP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O foreign/JJ/O and/CC/O domestic/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
