In/IN/O an/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O specialization/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O judiciary/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O bastions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O generalist/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O judge/NN/O must/MD/O jump/VB/O from/IN/O murder/NN/O to/TO/O antitrust/JJ/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O from/IN/O arson/NN/O to/TO/O securities/NNS/O fraud/NN/O ,/,/O without/IN/O missing/VBG/O a/DT/O beat/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O even/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O bench/NN/O ,/,/O specialization/NN/O is/VBZ/O creeping/VBG/O in/RP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O a/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O sharp/JJ/O controversy/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O newest/JJS/O federal/JJ/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Appeals/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O 1982/CD/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O of/IN/O last/JJ/O resort/NN/O for/IN/O most/JJS/O patent/NN/O disputes/NNS/O ././O
Previously/RB/O ,/,/O patent/NN/O cases/NNS/O moved/VBD/O through/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O system/NN/O to/TO/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 12/CD/O circuit/NN/O appeals/NNS/O courts/NNS/O ././O
There/RB/O ,/,/O judges/NNS/O who/WP/O saw/VBD/O few/JJ/O such/JJ/O cases/NNS/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O experience/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O grappled/VBD/O with/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O technical/JJ/O and/CC/O complex/JJ/O disputes/NNS/O imaginable/JJ/O ././O
Some/DT/O patent/NN/O lawyers/NNS/O had/VBD/O hoped/VBN/O that/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O specialty/NN/O court/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O filled/VBN/O with/IN/O experts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O thought/VBD/O otherwise/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O so/RB/O may/MD/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O has/VBZ/O filled/VBN/O four/CD/O vacancies/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG court/NN/O with/IN/O non-patent/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O latter/JJ/O two/CD/O and/CC/O Judge/NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Friedman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 73/CD/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O approaching/VBG/O senior/JJ/O status/NN/O or/CC/O retirement/NN/O ././O
Several/JJ/O organizations/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Industrial/NNP/I-ORG Biotechnical/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Pharmaceutical/NNP/I-ORG Manufacturers/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O have/VB/O asked/VBN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O name/VB/O candidates/NNS/O with/IN/O both/DT/O patent/NN/O and/CC/O scientific/JJ/O backgrounds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O associations/NNS/O would/MD/O like/VB/O the/DT/O court/NN/O to/TO/O include/VB/O between/IN/O three/CD/O and/CC/O six/CD/O judges/NNS/O with/IN/O specialized/JJ/O training/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O associations/NNS/O have/VB/O recommended/VBN/O Dr./NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Lourie/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 54/CD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O patent/NN/O agent/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O doctorate/NN/O in/IN/O organic/JJ/O chemistry/NN/O who/WP/O now/RB/O is/VBZ/O associate/JJ/O general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O with/IN/O SmithKline/NNP/B-ORG Beckman/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Dr./NNP/O Lourie/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG interviewed/VBD/O him/PRP/O last/JJ/O July/NNP/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O effort/NN/O has/VBZ/O received/VBN/O a/DT/O lukewarm/JJ/O response/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O feel/VB/O that/IN/O seats/NNS/O are/VBP/O reserved/VBN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O for/IN/O patent/NN/O lawyers/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Runkel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O soon/RB/O a/DT/O candidate/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O named/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O will/MD/O take/VB/O it/PRP/O into/IN/O consideration/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG view/NN/O is/VBZ/O shared/VBN/O by/IN/O other/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O and/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O one/CD/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O H./NNP/B-PERSON Robert/NNP/I-PERSON Mayer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O civil/JJ/O litigator/NN/O who/WP/O served/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O claims/NNS/O court/NN/O trial/NN/O level/NN/O before/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O appointed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O any/DT/O good/JJ/O lawyer/NN/O should/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O figure/VB/O out/RP/O and/CC/O understand/VB/O patent/NN/O law/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Judge/NNP/O Mayer/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O responsibility/NN/O of/IN/O highly/RB/O paid/VBN/O lawyers/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O who/WP/O argue/VBP/O before/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O make/VB/O us/PRP/O understand/VB/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O complex/JJ/O patent/NN/O litigation/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O the/DT/O Lilly/NNP/B-ORG case/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O broadly/RB/O construed/VBD/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O statute/NN/O to/TO/O grant/VB/O Medtronic/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O medical/JJ/O device/NN/O manufacturer/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O exemption/NN/O to/TO/O infringe/VB/O a/DT/O patent/NN/O under/IN/O certain/JJ/O circumstances/NNS/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Ms./NNP/O Raines/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O The/DT/O judgment/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O confirms/VBZ/O our/PRP$/O concern/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O absence/NN/O of/IN/O patent/NN/O lawyers/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O could/MD/O prove/VB/O troublesome/JJ/O ././O
