The/DT/B-ORG Treasury/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O may/MD/O worsen/VB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O significant/JJ/O improvement/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O its/PRP$/O report/NN/O to/TO/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O international/JJ/O economic/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O any/DT/O improvement/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O broadest/JJS/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O trade/NN/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O account/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O at/IN/O best/JJS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O very/RB/O modest/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O deterioration/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O account/NN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O can/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O excluded/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O statement/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O acknowledgement/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O other/JJ/O groups/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Monetary/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O predicting/VBG/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O ././O
Continued/JJ/O strength/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O was/VBD/O cited/VBN/O as/IN/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O position/NN/O may/MD/O deteriorate/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O liberalized/VBN/O its/PRP$/O exchange/NN/O rate/NN/O system/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
