General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O outside/JJ/O law/NN/O firms/NNS/O the/DT/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O uses/VBZ/O from/IN/O about/RB/O 700/CD/O to/TO/O 200/CD/O within/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
GM/NNP/B-ORG trimmed/VBD/O about/RB/O 40/CD/O firms/NNS/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O approved/JJ/O local/JJ/O counsel/NN/O list/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Pearce/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O add/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O litigation/NN/O staff/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Pearce/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O also/RB/O encouraged/VBN/O his/PRP$/O staff/NN/O to/TO/O work/NN/O more/RBR/O closely/RB/O with/IN/O GM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O technical/JJ/O staffs/NNS/O to/TO/O help/VB/O prevent/VB/O future/JJ/O litigation/NN/O ././O
GM/NNP/B-ORG lawyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O with/IN/O technicians/NNS/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O more/RBR/O uniform/JJ/O welding/NN/O procedures/NNS/O --/:/O the/DT/O way/NN/O a/DT/O vehicle/NN/O is/VBZ/O welded/VBN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O durability/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O also/RB/O monitor/VBP/O suits/NNS/O to/TO/O identify/VB/O specific/JJ/O automobile/NN/O parts/NNS/O that/WDT/O cause/VBP/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O legal/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O necessarily/RB/O mean/VB/O larger/JJR/O firms/NNS/O have/VBP/O an/DT/O advantage/NN/O ;/:/O Mr./NNP/O Pearce/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O GM/NNP/B-ORG works/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O smaller/JJR/O firms/NNS/O it/PRP/O regards/VBZ/O highly/RB/O ././O
FEDERAL/JJ/O PROSECUTORS/NNS/O are/VBP/O concluding/VBG/O fewer/JJR/O criminal/JJ/O cases/NNS/O with/IN/O trials/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O finding/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O study/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG by/IN/O researchers/NNS/O at/IN/O Syracuse/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Burnham/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O authors/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O fewer/JJR/O trials/NNS/O probably/RB/O means/VBZ/O a/DT/O growing/VBG/O number/NN/O of/IN/O plea/NN/O bargains/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O study/NN/O covered/VBD/O 11/CD/O major/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorneys/NNS/O '/POS/O offices/NNS/O --/:/O including/VBG/O those/DT/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Brooklyn/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE --/:/O from/IN/O 1980/CD/O to/TO/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG rejected/VBD/O the/DT/O implication/NN/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O prosecutors/NNS/O are/VBP/O currently/RB/O more/RBR/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O plea/NN/O bargain/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O discrepancy/NN/O is/VBZ/O somewhat/RB/O perplexing/JJ/O in/IN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Syracuse/NNP/B-ORG researchers/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O based/VBD/O their/PRP$/O conclusions/NNS/O on/IN/O government/NN/O statistics/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O finding/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O study/NN/O :/:/O Prosecutors/NNS/O set/VBP/O significantly/RB/O different/JJ/O priorities/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O stressed/VBD/O criminal/JJ/O cases/NNS/O from/IN/O 1980/CD/O to/TO/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O averaging/VBG/O 43/CD/O for/IN/O every/DT/O 100,000/CD/O adults/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O study/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O reporters/NNS/O ,/,/O academic/JJ/O experts/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O raw/JJ/O data/NN/O on/IN/O which/WDT/O to/TO/O base/VB/O further/JJ/O inquiries/NNS/O ././O
IMELDA/NNP/B-PERSON MARCOS/NNP/I-PERSON asks/VBZ/O for/IN/O dismissal/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O kidnapped/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O former/JJ/O first/JJ/O lady/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O asked/VBD/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O dismiss/VB/O an/DT/O indictment/NN/O against/IN/O her/PRP/O ,/,/O claiming/VBG/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O abducted/NN/O from/IN/O her/PRP$/O homeland/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP$/O late/JJ/O husband/NN/O ,/,/O former/JJ/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE President/NNP/O Ferdinand/NNP/B-PERSON Marcos/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O were/VBD/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O embezzling/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O that/DT/O country/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O fraudulently/RB/O concealing/VBG/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O through/IN/O purchases/NNS/O of/IN/O prime/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O attorneys/NNS/O asked/VBD/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON F./NNP/I-PERSON Keenan/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O give/VB/O them/PRP/O access/NN/O to/TO/O all/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE documents/NNS/O about/IN/O her/PRP$/O alleged/JJ/O abduction/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O documents/NNS/O it/PRP/O filed/VBD/O in/IN/O response/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O ``/``/O fanciful/JJ/O --/:/O and/CC/O factually/RB/O unsupported/JJ/O --/:/O claim/NN/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O kidnapped/VBN/O into/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O obtain/VB/O classified/JJ/O material/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O office/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O brought/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE against/IN/O their/PRP$/O will/NN/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O ousted/VBN/O as/IN/O president/NN/O ././O
Lawyers/NNP/O for/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON say/VBP/O that/IN/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O taken/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE against/IN/O her/PRP$/O wishes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O lacks/VBZ/O jurisdiction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
THE/DT/O FEDERAL/JJ/O COURT/NN/O of/IN/O appeals/NNS/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O dismissal/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O 1980/CD/O indictment/NN/O against/IN/O former/JJ/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Crete/NNP/I-ORG owner/NN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Koskotas/NNP/I-PERSON should/MD/O be/VB/O reconsidered/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O indictment/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O sealed/VBN/O and/CC/O apparently/RB/O forgotten/VBN/O by/IN/O investigators/NNS/O until/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O charges/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Koskotas/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O three/CD/O others/NNS/O with/IN/O tax/NN/O fraud/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O violations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O adequately/RB/O consider/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O delay/NN/O would/MD/O actually/RB/O hurt/VB/O the/DT/O chances/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O fair/JJ/O trial/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Koskotas/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O fighting/VBG/O extradition/NN/O proceedings/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O return/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O embezzling/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 250/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Crete/NNP/I-ORG ././O
His/PRP$/O attorney/NN/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
PRO/FW/O BONO/FW/O VOLUNTARISM/NN/O :/:/O In/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O stave/VB/O off/RP/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O require/VB/O all/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE state/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O twenty/CD/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O free/JJ/O legal/JJ/O aid/NN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O state/NN/O bar/NN/O recommended/VBD/O an/DT/O alternative/JJ/O program/NN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O voluntary/JJ/O participation/NN/O in/IN/O pro/FW/O bono/FW/O programs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O bar/NN/O association/NN/O 's/POS/O policy/NN/O making/NN/O body/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Delegate/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O voted/VBD/O Saturday/NNP/O to/TO/O ask/VB/O Chief/NNP/O Judge/NNP/O Sol/NNP/B-PERSON Wachtler/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O give/VB/O the/DT/O bar/NN/O 's/POS/O voluntary/JJ/O program/NN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O prove/VB/O its/PRP$/O effectiveness/NN/O before/IN/O considering/VBG/O mandatory/JJ/O pro/FW/O bono/FW/O ././O
The/DT/O merger/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O formally/RB/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O partners/NNS/O of/IN/O both/DT/O firms/NNS/O but/CC/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O by/IN/O year/NN/O end/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O was/VBD/O filed/VBN/O by/IN/O plaintiffs/NNS/O '/POS/O securities/NNS/O lawyer/NN/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Greenfield/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O trial/NN/O begins/VBZ/O today/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
GE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O vehemently/RB/O denies/VBZ/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O allegations/NNS/O ,/,/O denounced/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Greenfield/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O suit/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O was/VBD/O considering/VBG/O bringing/VBG/O sanctions/NNS/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Greenfield/NNP/B-PERSON for/IN/O making/VBG/O ``/``/O grossly/RB/O inaccurate/JJ/O and/CC/O unsupported/JJ/O allegations/NNS/O ././O
