Southern/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O may/MD/O plead/VB/O guilty/JJ/O this/DT/O week/NN/O to/TO/O charges/NNS/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O illegally/RB/O steered/VBD/O company/NN/O money/NN/O to/TO/O politicians/NNS/O through/IN/O outside/JJ/O vendors/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O individuals/NNS/O close/RB/O to/TO/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O utility/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O investigating/VBG/O whether/IN/O officials/NNS/O at/IN/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG conspired/VBD/O to/TO/O cover/VB/O up/RP/O their/PRP$/O accounting/NN/O for/IN/O spare/JJ/O parts/NNS/O to/TO/O evade/VB/O federal/JJ/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/O has/VBZ/O also/RB/O been/VBN/O investigating/VBG/O whether/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG executives/NNS/O violated/VBD/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Utility/NNP/O Holding/NNP/O Company/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O prohibits/VBZ/O certain/JJ/O utilities/NNS/O from/IN/O making/VBG/O political/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O individuals/NNS/O said/VBD/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O federal/JJ/O prosecutors/NNS/O are/VBP/O considering/VBG/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O under/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O company/NN/O would/MD/O plead/VB/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O two/CD/O felony/NN/O charges/NNS/O and/CC/O pay/VB/O fines/NNS/O totaling/VBG/O between/IN/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Under/IN/O one/CD/O count/NN/O ,/,/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O plead/VB/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O conspiring/VBG/O to/TO/O violate/VB/O the/DT/O Utility/NNP/O Holding/NNP/O Company/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O count/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O would/MD/O plead/VB/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O conspiring/VBG/O to/TO/O evade/VB/O taxes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O guilty/JJ/O pleas/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O solely/RB/O by/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O individuals/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
No/DT/O employee/NN/O or/CC/O vendor/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O involved/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O say/VB/O only/RB/O that/IN/O discussions/NNS/O are/VBP/O continuing/VBG/O between/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O federal/JJ/O prosecutors/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VB/O no/DT/O further/JJ/O developments/NNS/O to/TO/O report/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O at/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O prosecutors/NNS/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
While/IN/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O the/DT/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/O investigations/NNS/O ,/,/O Edward/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Addison/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O defend/VB/O its/PRP$/O tax/NN/O and/CC/O acccounting/NN/O practices/NNS/O if/IN/O any/DT/O charges/NNS/O are/VBP/O brought/VBN/O against/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Morever/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Addison/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O units/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O condone/VB/O illegal/JJ/O political/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O ././O
Neither/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Addison/NNP/B-PERSON nor/CC/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O any/DT/O wrongdoing/NN/O in/IN/O connection/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O inquiries/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O probe/NN/O of/IN/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O attracted/VBN/O considerable/JJ/O attention/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O events/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O befallen/VBN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG executive/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O plane/NN/O crash/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O disappearance/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O company/NN/O vendor/NN/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O key/JJ/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/O witness/NN/O ././O
Witnesses/NNS/O have/VBP/O said/VBN/O the/DT/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/O has/VBZ/O asked/VBN/O numerous/JJ/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O Jacob/NNP/B-PERSON F./NNP/I-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Jake/NN/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Horton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG who/WP/O died/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O plane/NN/O crash/NN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/O morning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O put/VBN/O on/IN/O notice/NN/O that/IN/O an/DT/O audit/NN/O committee/NN/O was/VBD/O recommending/VBG/O his/PRP$/O dismissal/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O invoicing/NN/O irregularities/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O company/NN/O audit/NN/O ././O
Investigators/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O accident/NN/O ,/,/O sabotage/NN/O or/CC/O suicide/NN/O ././O
Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O that/IN/O an/DT/O internal/JJ/O audit/NN/O had/VBD/O disclosed/VBN/O that/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O one/CD/O vendor/NN/O had/VBD/O used/VBN/O false/JJ/O invoices/NNS/O to/TO/O fund/VB/O political/JJ/O causes/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O made/VBN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
