Although/IN/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O white/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O economic/JJ/O factors/NNS/O affected/VBD/O us/PRP/O as/IN/O affects/VBZ/O the/DT/O black/JJ/O people/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Farney/NNP/B-PERSON writes/VBZ/O about/IN/O ././O
Though/NNP/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O been/VBN/O blessed/VBN/O with/IN/O academic/JJ/O degrees/NNS/O and/CC/O some/DT/O success/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O materialistic/JJ/O world/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O never/RB/O forgotten/VBN/O or/CC/O lost/VBN/O contact/NN/O with/IN/O those/DT/O memories/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1930s/CD/O ././O
Most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O land/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Delta/NNP/B-LOC are/VBP/O now/RB/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O second/JJ/O ,/,/O third/JJ/O or/CC/O fourth/JJ/O generations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O families/NNS/O ././O
These/DT/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O families/NNS/O who/WP/O used/VBD/O --/:/O and/CC/O sometime/RB/O abused/VBN/O --/:/O their/PRP$/O sharecroppers/NNS/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O encouragement/NN/O and/CC/O little/JJ/O access/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O education/NN/O or/CC/O training/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O better/JJR/O life/NN/O ././O
Following/VBG/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O one/CD/O family/NN/O with/IN/O mechanized/JJ/O equipment/NN/O could/MD/O farm/VB/O crops/NNS/O formerly/RB/O requiring/VBG/O 20/CD/O families/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O surplus/JJ/O people/NNS/O were/VBD/O dumped/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O mainstream/NN/O of/IN/O society/NN/O with/IN/O no/DT/B-ORG Social/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O no/DT/O skills/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O workplace/NN/O ,/,/O no/DT/O hope/NN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O future/NN/O except/IN/O welfare/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O meantime/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O landowners/NNS/O continue/VBP/O receiving/VBG/O generous/JJ/O subsidies/NNS/O that/WDT/O began/VBD/O during/IN/O New/NNP/O Deal/NNP/O days/NNS/O ././O
Or/CC/O those/DT/O who/WP/O choose/VBP/O not/RB/O to/TO/O farm/NN/O can/MD/O lease/VB/O their/PRP$/O lands/NNS/O and/CC/O crop/NN/O allotments/NNS/O for/IN/O handsome/JJ/O sums/NNS/O ././O
Farmers/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Midwest/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O other/JJ/O areas/NNS/O have/VBP/O suffered/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O those/DT/O along/IN/O the/DT/O Mississippi/NNP/B-LOC continue/VBP/O to/TO/O prosper/VB/O with/IN/O holdings/NNS/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O built/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O sweat/NN/O of/IN/O men/NNS/O and/CC/O women/NNS/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O economic/JJ/O slavery/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O no/RB/O longer/RBR/O needed/VBN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O turned/VBN/O loose/RB/O unprepared/JJ/O to/TO/O build/VB/O lives/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
Denton/NNP/B-PERSON Harris/NNP/I-PERSON
Chairman/NN/O
Metro/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG
Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE
Because/IN/O the/DT/O cycle/NN/O of/IN/O poverty/NN/O along/IN/O the/DT/O lower/JJR/O Mississippi/NNP/B-LOC goes/VBZ/O back/RB/O so/RB/O many/JJ/O generations/NNS/O ,/,/O breaking/VBG/O this/DT/O cycle/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O next/RB/O to/TO/O impossible/JJ/O ././O
Sadly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O cycle/NN/O appears/VBZ/O not/RB/O as/IN/O waves/NNS/O but/CC/O as/IN/O a/DT/O downward/JJ/O spiral/NN/O ././O
Yet/CC/O the/DT/O evidence/NN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O not/RB/O hit/VBN/O bottom/NN/O is/VBZ/O found/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O yet/RB/O helping/VBG/O ourselves/PRP/O ././O
Because/IN/O we/PRP/O refuse/VBP/O to/TO/O face/VB/O the/DT/O tough/JJ/O answers/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O questions/NNS/O continue/VBP/O as/IN/O fodder/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O commissions/NNS/O and/CC/O committees/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O and/CC/O politicians/NNS/O ././O
Does/NNP/O the/DT/O Delta/NNP/B-LOC deserve/VB/O government/NN/O help/NN/O in/IN/O attracting/VBG/O industry/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O residents/NNS/O ,/,/O black/JJ/O and/CC/O white/JJ/O ,/,/O do/VB/O not/RB/O realize/VB/O racism/NN/O alienates/VBZ/O potential/JJ/O employers/NNS/O ?/./O
Delta/NNP/B-LOC problems/NNS/O are/VBP/O difficult/JJ/O ,/,/O not/RB/O impossible/JJ/O ,/,/O to/TO/O solve/VB/O --/:/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O just/RB/O not/RB/O convinced/JJ/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O solve/VB/O them/PRP/O yet/RB/O ././O
Leslie/NNP/B-PERSON Falls/NNP/I-PERSON Humphries/NNP/I-PERSON
Little/NNP/B-GPE Rock/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Ark/NNP/B-GPE ././O
I/PRP/O would/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O issue/VB/O a/DT/O challenge/NN/O to/TO/O corporate/JJ/O America/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O time/NN/O expansion/NN/O plans/NNS/O are/VBP/O mentioned/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O company/NN/O and/CC/O somebody/NN/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Aw/UH/O heck/UH/O ,/,/O guys/NNS/O ,/,/O nobody/NN/O can/MD/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O like/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O I/PRP/O wish/VBP/O you/PRP/O would/MD/O butt/VB/O in/RP/O and/CC/O say/VB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Hold/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O fellas/NNS/O ,/,/O why/WRB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O we/PRP/O compare/VB/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O use/VB/O our/PRP$/O own/JJ/O little/JJ/O Third/NNP/O World/NNP/O country/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O would/MD/O even/RB/O save/VB/O on/IN/O freight/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O mystery/NN/O why/WRB/O the/DT/O Delta/NN/B-LOC originated/VBP/O ``/``/O Singin/VBG/O '/''/O the/DT/O Blues/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Eugene/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Clarke/NNP/I-PERSON IV/NNP/I-PERSON
Hollandale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Miss/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Your/PRP$/O story/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O insult/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O citizens/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Mississippi/NNP/I-LOC Delta/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O you/PRP/O presented/VBN/O exist/VBP/O in/IN/O every/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Poverty/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O two/CD/O blocks/NNS/O from/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O residence/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O ignore/VB/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O of/IN/O poverty/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O now/RB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O gotten/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O hand/NN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O crusade/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O and/CC/O our/PRP$/O Democratic/JJ/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Nobody/NN/O should/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O live/VB/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O poor/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O as/IN/O in/IN/O ``/``/O Sugar/NNP/O Ditch/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O when/WRB/O you/PRP/O travel/VBP/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O problems/NNS/O exist/VBP/O ././O
Then/RB/O maybe/RB/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O stay/VB/O home/RB/O and/CC/O have/VB/O seven/CD/O children/NNS/O and/CC/O watch/VB/O Oprah/NNP/B-PERSON Winfrey/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O like/IN/O Beulah/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O the/DT/O article/NN/O ,/,/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O one/CD/O child/NN/O and/CC/O working/VBG/O constantly/RB/O just/RB/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O above/IN/O water/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O so/RB/O many/JJ/O families/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Dee/NNP/B-PERSON Ann/NNP/I-PERSON Wilson/NNP/I-PERSON
Greenville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Miss/NNP/B-GPE ././O
