Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Jefferson/NNP/I-PERSON sold/VBD/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O decimal/JJ/O system/NN/O for/IN/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O saving/VBG/O Americans/NNPS/O the/DT/O headaches/NNS/O of/IN/O pounds/NNS/O ,/,/O shillings/NNS/O and/CC/O pence/NNS/O ././O
Americans/NNPS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O dislike/VB/O metrics/NNS/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O simply/RB/O ignored/VBD/O them/PRP/O ././O
Scientists/NNS/O felt/VBD/O differently/RB/O ././O
Businessmen/NNS/O took/VBD/O their/PRP$/O cue/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O engineers/NNS/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O the/DT/O public/NN/O is/VBZ/O barely/RB/O aware/JJ/O ,/,/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE industry/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O companies/NNS/O manufacturing/VBG/O or/CC/O selling/VBG/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O metrics/NNS/O routine/JJ/O ././O
General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O uses/VBZ/O metric/JJ/O terms/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O automobile/NN/O bodies/NNS/O and/CC/O power/NN/O trains/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O liquor/NN/O industry/NN/O went/VBD/O metric/JJ/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
New/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O systems/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O around/RB/O until/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O century/NN/O ,/,/O notes/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Tascher/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG metric/JJ/O coordinator/NN/O ././O
Soldiers/NNS/O and/CC/O sailors/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O measured/VBN/O in/IN/O inches/NNS/O and/CC/O pounds/NNS/O ././O
