Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE reached/VBD/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O creditor/NN/O banks/NNS/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O that/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O $/$/O 1.8/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O bank/NN/O debt/NN/O by/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O was/VBD/O announced/VBN/O by/IN/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O President/NNP/O Oscar/NNP/B-PERSON Arias/NNP/I-PERSON Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O as/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Western/NNP/I-LOC Hemisphere/NNP/I-LOC gathered/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Central/JJ/O American/JJ/O nation/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O celebration/NN/O of/IN/O democracy/NN/O ././O
Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE had/VBD/O been/VBN/O negotiating/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O other/JJ/O banks/NNS/O for/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O debt/NN/O plan/NN/O was/VBD/O rushed/VBN/O to/TO/O completion/NN/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O announced/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O had/VBD/O fallen/VBN/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O behind/RB/O in/IN/O interest/NN/O payments/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Monetary/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O approximately/RB/O $/$/O 180/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O support/VB/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O additional/JJ/O funds/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Treasury/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O agreement/NN/O demonstrates/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON debt/NN/O plan/NN/O can/MD/O benefit/VB/O small/JJ/O debtor/NN/O countries/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O big/JJ/O debtors/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE ././O
