Exxon/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O resigning/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Wildlife/NNP/I-ORG Federation/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG corporate/JJ/O advisory/JJ/O panel/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O conservation/NN/O group/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O unfairly/RB/O critical/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Exxon/NNP/O Valdez/NNP/O oil/NN/O spill/NN/O along/IN/O the/DT/O Alaskan/JJ/O coast/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O federation/NN/O said/VBD/O Friday/NNP/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O regrets/VBZ/O the/DT/O resignation/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O issued/VBD/O a/DT/O stinging/JJ/O response/NN/O that/WDT/O called/VBD/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O ``/``/O corporate/JJ/O pariah/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O should/MD/O keep/VB/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O dialogue/NN/O with/IN/O environmentalists/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O federation/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O 5.8/CD/O million/CD/O members/NNS/O nationwide/JJ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O sharpest/JJS/O critics/NNS/O of/IN/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O gallon/NN/O tanker/NN/O spill/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O accused/VBN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O of/IN/O repeatedly/RB/O ignoring/VBG/O requests/NNS/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O and/CC/O discuss/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O March/NNP/O 24/CD/O oil/NN/O spill/VB/O soiled/VBD/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O miles/NNS/O of/IN/O shoreline/NN/O along/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O southern/JJ/O coast/NN/O and/CC/O wreaked/VBD/O havoc/NN/O with/IN/O wildlife/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O fishing/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
Exxon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O charter/JJ/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Corporate/NNP/I-ORG Conservation/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O panel/NN/O of/IN/O executives/NNS/O formed/VBN/O in/IN/O 1982/CD/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Wildlife/NNP/I-ORG Federation/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O foster/VB/O ``/``/O frank/JJ/O and/CC/O open/JJ/O discussions/NNS/O ''/''/O between/IN/O industry/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O federation/NN/O 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O federation/NN/O was/VBD/O among/IN/O the/DT/O plaintiffs/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O against/IN/O Exxon/NN/B-ORG seeking/VBG/O full/JJ/O payment/NN/O of/IN/O environmental/JJ/O recovery/NN/O costs/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O spill/NN/O ././O
