Presidio/NNP/B-ORG Oil/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O signed/VBD/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 163/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Presidio/NN/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O properties/NNS/O are/VBP/O generally/RB/O situated/VBN/O in/IN/O Wyoming/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O North/NNP/B-GPE Dakota/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Louisiana/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Calgary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O non-strategic/JJ/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O focus/VB/O operations/NNS/O on/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O other/JJ/O international/JJ/O areas/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Toronto/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Reichmann/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O properties/NNS/O account/VBP/O for/IN/O about/RB/O 6/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O produce/VBP/O about/RB/O 5,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O 35/CD/O million/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O gas/NN/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O likely/RB/O report/VB/O an/DT/O extraordinary/JJ/O gain/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O offer/VB/O a/DT/O specific/JJ/O estimate/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O close/VB/O by/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 30/CD/O ././O
