Rally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O filed/VBD/O suit/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Delaware/NNP/B-GPE against/IN/O a/DT/O group/NN/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O Burt/NNP/B-PERSON Sugarman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O block/VB/O the/DT/O investors/NNS/O from/IN/O buying/VBG/O more/JJR/O shares/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O ,/,/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O Giant/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sugarman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O owns/VBZ/O about/RB/O 45.2/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Rally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O Securities/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG filings/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O group/NN/O has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O seek/VB/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Rally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sugarman/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O the/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O ``/``/O not/RB/O nice/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O group/NN/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O push/VB/O for/IN/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O removal/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O directors/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O asserts/VBZ/O that/IN/O some/DT/O directors/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O joined/VBN/O forces/NNS/O with/IN/O company/NN/O founder/NN/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Patterson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O have/VB/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O Wendy/NNP/B-ORG 's/VBZ/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O competing/JJ/O hamburger/NN/O chain/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Patterson/NNP/B-PERSON group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O controls/VBZ/O about/RB/O 42/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Rally/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG shares/NNS/O ,/,/O also/RB/O may/MD/O seek/VB/O control/NN/O ././O
Rally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O formed/VBD/O a/DT/O committee/NN/O of/IN/O three/CD/O directors/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O either/CC/O the/DT/O Patterson/NNP/B-PERSON or/CC/O Sugarman/NNP/B-PERSON groups/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O analyze/VB/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O ././O
