Lion/NNP/B-ORG Nathan/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE brewing/NN/O and/CC/O retail/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Friday/NNP/O that/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O ``/``/O committed/JJ/O ''/''/O to/TO/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O whereby/WRB/O Lion/NNP/B-ORG Nathan/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O acquire/VB/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Australian/JJ/O brewing/NN/O assets/NNS/O ././O
SA/NNP/B-ORG Brewing/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O Australian/JJ/O brewer/NN/O ,/,/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O was/VBD/O given/VBN/O approval/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O an/DT/O option/NN/O for/IN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Bell/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Bell/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O acquiring/VBG/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O brewing/NN/O businesses/NNS/O for/IN/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O Australian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 1.9/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
S.A./NNP/B-ORG brewing/NN/I-ORG would/MD/O make/VB/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O offer/NN/O for/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O Bell/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG if/IN/O it/PRP/O exercises/VBZ/O the/DT/O option/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O ././O
Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O brewing/NN/O ,/,/O property/NN/O ,/,/O media/NNS/O and/CC/O resources/NNS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O selling/VBG/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O debts/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Lion/NNP/B-ORG Nathan/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O concluded/VBN/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Bell/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Myers/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Lion/NNP/B-ORG Nathan/NNP/I-ORG ././O
