Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O advertising/NN/O agency/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O strength/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O dominance/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O market/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O setting/VBG/O its/PRP$/O sights/NNS/O on/IN/O overseas/JJ/O expansion/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG acquired/VBD/O 69/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Australian/JJ/O agency/NN/O Fortune/NNP/B-ORG Communication/NNP/I-ORG Holdings/NNS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O 5.9/CD/O million/CD/O Australian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 4.6/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE subsidiaries/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O keep/VBP/O low/JJ/O profiles/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O giant/JJ/O marketing/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O holds/VBZ/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O 4.4/CD/O trillion/CD/O yen/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 30.96/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O advertising/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O advertising/NN/O network/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
What/WP/O is/VBZ/O driving/VBG/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O international/JJ/O expansion/NN/O largely/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O up/RP/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O Japanese/JJ/O clients/NNS/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O grow/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O do/VB/O something/NN/O .../:/O we/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O catch/VB/O up/RP/O with/IN/O demand/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O president/NN/O said/VBD/O acquisition/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O effective/JJ/O method/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O foreign/JJ/O business/NN/O accounted/VBD/O for/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O total/JJ/O billings/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O aiming/VBG/O at/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O near/JJ/O future/NN/O ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O appears/VBZ/O cautious/JJ/O about/IN/O taking/VBG/O the/DT/O big/JJ/O step/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O looked/VBD/O seriously/RB/O at/IN/O Saatchi/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Though/IN/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O has/VBN/O no/DT/O concrete/JJ/O acquisition/NN/O plans/NNS/O or/CC/O deadlines/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O laying/VBG/O the/DT/O groundwork/NN/O for/IN/O international/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O setting/VBG/O up/RP/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O team/NN/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O markets/NNS/O and/CC/O training/VBG/O workers/NNS/O to/TO/O do/VB/O business/NN/O abroad/RB/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBN/O March/NNP/O 31/CD/O ,/,/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG sales/NNS/O rose/VBD/O 19/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 8.9/CD/O billion/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 7.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O net/JJ/O income/NN/O jumped/VBD/O 59/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 102/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 64/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O success/NN/O overseas/RB/O in/IN/O unfamiliar/JJ/O markets/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O trickier/JJR/O than/IN/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O industries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O manufacturers/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ,/,/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O muscle/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE may/MD/O count/VB/O for/IN/O little/RB/O in/IN/O major/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O markets/NNS/O when/WRB/O seeking/VBG/O non-Japanese/JJ/O clients/NNS/O ././O
Thus/RB/O ,/,/O an/DT/O acquisition/NN/O may/MD/O prove/VB/O the/DT/O necessary/JJ/O course/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O are/VBP/O cautious/JJ/O about/IN/O expanding/VBG/O abroad/RB/O because/IN/O client/NN/O relationships/NNS/O are/VBP/O different/JJ/O ././O
Although/IN/O acquiring/VBG/O a/DT/O foreign/JJ/O company/NN/O would/MD/O expand/VB/O Japanese/JJ/O advertising/NN/O agencies/NNS/O '/POS/O business/NN/O to/TO/O foreign/JJ/O clients/NNS/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O clients/NNS/O would/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O expanding/VBG/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O different/JJ/O business/NN/O system/NN/O would/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O hard/JJ/O for/IN/O Dentsu/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O provide/VB/O these/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O services/NNS/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
