First/NNP/B-ORG Tennessee/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O charge/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O its/PRP$/O systems/NNS/O operation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O banking/NN/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O reached/VBD/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O in/IN/O principle/NN/O with/IN/O International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O a/DT/O systems/NNS/O operations/NNS/O contract/NN/O calling/VBG/O for/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O operate/VB/O First/NNP/B-ORG Tennessee/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG computer/NN/O and/CC/O telecommunications/NNS/O functions/NNS/O ././O
Further/RB/O ,/,/O under/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O First/NNP/B-ORG Tennesse/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O the/DT/O software/NN/O that/WDT/O creates/VBZ/O customer/NN/O products/NNS/O and/CC/O sevices/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Because/IN/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O will/MD/O soon/RB/O be/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O desks/NNS/O of/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O tellers/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O customer/NN/O service/NN/O and/CC/O loan/NN/O representatives/NNS/O ,/,/O information/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O instantly/RB/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O help/VB/O customers/NNS/O with/IN/O product/NN/O decisions/NNS/O and/CC/O provide/VB/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O information/NN/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O accounts/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Kelley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O corporate/JJ/O services/NNS/O group/NN/O manager/NN/O at/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Tennessee/NNP/I-ORG ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O about/RB/O 120/CD/O employees/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O affected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ././O
First/NNP/B-ORG Tennessee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O assisted/VBN/O by/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O attempt/VB/O to/TO/O place/VB/O the/DT/O employees/NNS/O within/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O other/JJ/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O Memphis/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O process/NN/O will/MD/O take/VB/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O banking/NN/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O board/NN/O approval/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
