Initial/JJ/O steps/NNS/O were/VBD/O taken/VBN/O at/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O first/JJ/O international/JJ/O environmental/JJ/O conference/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O I/PRP/O attended/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O conference/NN/O ,/,/O held/VBN/O in/IN/O Lower/NNP/B-LOC Silesia/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O was/VBD/O co-sponsored/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Environment/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Rockefeller/NNP/I-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Polish/NNP/O Ecological/NNP/B-ORG Club/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O attended/VBN/O by/IN/O 50/CD/O Poles/NNPS/O from/IN/O government/NN/O and/CC/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O Hungarians/NNPS/O ,/,/O Czechs/NNPS/O ,/,/O Russians/NNPS/O ,/,/O Japanese/NNPS/O and/CC/O Americans/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O conference/NN/O was/VBD/O entitled/VBN/O ``/``/O Economic/NNP/O Mechanisms/NNPS/O for/IN/O Environmental/NNP/O Protection/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O departure/NN/O from/IN/O East/NNP/B-LOC Bloc/NNP/I-LOC usage/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O recognizes/VBZ/O only/RB/O one/CD/O economic/JJ/O mechanism/NN/O --/:/O central/JJ/O planning/NN/O --/:/O to/TO/O direct/VB/O industrial/JJ/O behavior/NN/O ././O
Norms/NNS/O are/VBP/O consistently/RB/O exceeded/VBN/O at/IN/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O nitrogen/NN/O oxide/NN/O monitoring/VBG/O sites/NNS/O and/CC/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O for/IN/O dust/NN/O and/CC/O soot/NN/O emissions/NNS/O ././O
Poland/NNP/B-GPE produces/VBZ/O about/IN/O 20/CD/O times/NNS/O more/JJR/O soot/NN/O and/CC/O five/CD/O times/NNS/O more/RBR/O sulfur/NN/O dioxide/NN/O and/CC/O solid/JJ/O waste/NN/O per/IN/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O gross/JJ/O national/JJ/O product/NN/O than/IN/O does/VBZ/O Western/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Its/PRP$/O mortality/NN/O rate/NN/O for/IN/O males/NNS/O over/IN/O 35/CD/O is/VBZ/O about/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O higher/JJR/O than/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O higher/JJR/O in/IN/O hazard/NN/O areas/NNS/O than/IN/O the/DT/O national/JJ/O average/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O repeatedly/RB/O noted/VBD/O that/DT/O environmental/JJ/O progress/NN/O could/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O secured/VBN/O without/IN/O true/JJ/O ownership/NN/O ,/,/O genuine/JJ/O competition/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O market/NN/O factors/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O risk/NN/O of/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O if/IN/O a/DT/O business/NN/O makes/VBZ/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O revolution/NN/O takes/VBZ/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O conference/NN/O manifestos/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Russians/NNPS/O are/VBP/O talking/VBG/O peace/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Palestinians/NNPS/O are/VBP/O talking/VBG/O elections/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O means/VBZ/O simple/JJ/O ,/,/O clear/JJ/O rules/NNS/O that/WDT/O secure/VBP/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O large/JJ/O blocks/NNS/O of/IN/O reduction/NN/O ,/,/O deferring/VBG/O more/JJR/O complex/JJ/O issues/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O risk/NN/O ././O
East/NNP/B-LOC Bloc/NNP/I-LOC pollution/NN/O data/NNS/O typically/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O state/NN/O secrets/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O participant/NN/O prematurely/RB/O declared/VBD/O that/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O had/VBN/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O market/NN/O in/IN/O goods/NNS/O but/CC/O a/DT/O planned/VBN/O economy/NN/O for/IN/O environmental/JJ/O protection/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE represents/VBZ/O the/DT/O opposite/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Levin/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O head/NN/O of/IN/O EPA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O regulatory/JJ/O reform/NN/O staff/NN/O ,/,/O adapted/VBD/O this/DT/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O November/NNP/O column/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Waste/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ././O
