Designer/NN/O Sandra/NNP/B-PERSON Garratt/NNP/I-PERSON filed/VBD/O for/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 7/CD/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O protection/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O her/PRP$/O cash/NN/O flow/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O cut/VBN/O off/IN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Garratt/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Wall/NNP/B-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG article/NN/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O ././O
Jerell/NNP/B-ORG paid/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Garratt/NNP/B-PERSON royalties/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O Multiples/NNPS/O by/IN/O Sandra/NNP/O Garratt/NNP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O primarily/RB/O through/IN/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Garratt/NNP/B-PERSON sued/VBD/O the/DT/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE apparel/NN/O maker/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O charging/VBG/O that/IN/O Jerell/NNP/B-ORG developed/VBD/O and/CC/O marketed/VBD/O clothing/NN/O lines/NNS/O fashioned/VBN/O after/IN/O her/PRP$/O designs/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O pending/VBG/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Garratt/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O liabilities/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
