Eagle/NNP/B-ORG Clothes/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O operating/VBG/O under/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O reached/VBD/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roth/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O leave/NN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O posts/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O succeeded/VBN/O by/IN/O Geoffrie/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Lurie/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O GDL/NNP/B-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O Eagle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O crisis/NN/O manager/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lurie/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O currently/RB/O co-chief/NN/O executive/NN/O ././O
Arnold/NNP/B-PERSON Levine/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O acting/VBG/O co-chief/NN/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O as/RB/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O board/NN/O member/NN/O ././O
Eagle/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O a/DT/O commitment/NN/O for/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O financing/NN/O from/IN/O Norfolk/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
A/DT/O committee/NN/O representing/VBG/O the/DT/O unsecured/JJ/O creditors/NNS/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O 24/CD/O cents/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ,/,/O Eagle/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O plan/NN/O would/MD/O extend/VB/O the/DT/O period/NN/O under/IN/O which/WDT/O Eagle/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O the/DT/O exclusive/JJ/O right/NN/O to/TO/O file/VB/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O extinguish/VB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O Eagle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O existing/VBG/O capital/NN/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O issue/VB/O new/JJ/O stock/NN/O to/TO/O York/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O sole/JJ/O holder/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O bankruptcy/NN/O court/NN/O hearing/NN/O is/VBZ/O set/VBN/O for/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 3/CD/O on/IN/O these/DT/O accords/NNS/O ././O
Eagle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O management/NN/O retired/VBD/O and/CC/O Biny/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O management/NN/O took/VBD/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
