Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O animal/NN/O health/NN/O and/CC/O nutrition/NN/O products/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O business/NN/O ,/,/O Creations/NNPS/B-PERSON Aromatiques/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Port/NNP/B-GPE Valais/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Woodside/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O division/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Mallinckrodt/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O most/JJS/O recent/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
International/NNP/B-ORG Minerals/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O will/MD/O allow/VB/O Mallinckrodt/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O focus/VB/O its/PRP$/O resources/NNS/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O core/NN/O businesses/NNS/O of/IN/O medical/JJ/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O specialty/NN/O chemicals/NNS/O and/CC/O flavors/NNS/O ././O
