Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Blum/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 41/CD/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O plans/NNS/O at/IN/O Ladenburg/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O name/VB/O a/DT/O co-chairman/NN/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Koenig/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O board/NN/O would/MD/O need/VB/O to/TO/O approve/VB/O any/DT/O appointments/NNS/O or/CC/O title/NN/O changes/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Blum/NNP/B-PERSON added/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O surprised/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Koenig/NNP/B-PERSON resigned/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O his/PRP$/O departure/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O nothing/NN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O desired/VBD/O or/CC/O worked/VBD/O for/IN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Koenig/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O just/RB/O got/VBD/O a/DT/O tremendous/JJ/O offer/NN/O from/IN/O Gruntal/NNP/B-ORG ././O
