Mr./NNP/O McNair/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 62/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O succeeded/VBN/O by/IN/O L.M./NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Bud/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Baker/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 47/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/NN/O credit/NN/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O head/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O administration/NN/O division/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O relinquish/VB/O his/PRP$/O previous/JJ/O positions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O a/DT/O successor/NN/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O named/VBN/O yet/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O continue/VB/O as/IN/O executive/NN/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O North/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE banking/VBG/O operation/NN/O ././O
