-LRB-/-LRB-/O During/IN/O its/PRP$/O centennial/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O report/VB/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O century/NN/O that/DT/O stand/NN/O as/IN/O milestones/NNS/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O business/NN/O history/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
FRANKLIN/NNP/B-ORG NATIONAL/NNP/I-ORG BANK/NNP/I-ORG DIED/VBD/O at/IN/O 3/CD/O p.m./NN/O EDT/NNP/O ,/,/O Oct./NNP/O 8/CD/O ,/,/O 1974/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O promptly/RB/O resurrected/VBN/O under/IN/O new/JJ/O owners/NNS/O to/TO/O shore/VB/O up/RP/O confidence/NN/O in/IN/O other/JJ/O banks/NNS/O during/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O federal/JJ/O insurance/NN/O protected/VBD/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O 631,163/CD/O depositors/NNS/O ././O
Massive/JJ/O withdrawals/NNS/O followed/VBD/O and/CC/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O brief/JJ/O rescue/NN/O attempt/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O political/JJ/O undertones/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O $/$/O 1.77/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG loans/NNS/O ././O
Within/IN/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O many/JJ/O figures/NNS/O were/VBD/O convicted/VBN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O illegal/JJ/O abuse/NN/O of/IN/O Franklin/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O June/NNP/O 1980/CD/O ,/,/O Michele/NNP/B-PERSON Sindona/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O an/DT/O Italian/JJ/O financier/NN/O who/WP/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O 1972/CD/O had/VBD/O bought/VBN/O a/DT/O 22/CD/O %/NN/O block/NN/O of/IN/O Franklin/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O stock/NN/O from/IN/O Loews/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Laurence/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Tisch/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O was/VBD/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O 25/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O after/IN/O being/VBG/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O and/CC/O perjury/NN/O ././O
Included/VBN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O charge/NN/O that/IN/O Sindona/NNP/B-PERSON siphoned/VBD/O $/$/O 45/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O Franklin/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O other/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
During/IN/O 1976/CD/O to/TO/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O other/JJ/O former/JJ/O Franklin/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O either/CC/O pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O or/CC/O were/VBD/O found/VBN/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O violations/NNS/O including/VBG/O phony/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O to/TO/O hide/VB/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O losses/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O happened/VBD/O four/CD/O days/NNS/O after/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O life/NN/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O for/IN/O ordering/VBG/O a/DT/O 1979/CD/O murder/NN/O ././O
Italian/JJ/O magistrates/NNS/O labeled/VBD/O his/PRP$/O death/NN/O a/DT/O suicide/NN/O ././O
