EAST/NNP/B-GPE GERMANY'S/NNP/I-GPE KRENZ/NNP/B-PERSON WARNED/VBD/O against/IN/O further/JJ/O pro-democracy/JJ/O protests/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O reaffirmed/VBD/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE allegiance/NN/O to/TO/O Communist/NNP/O orthodoxy/NN/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O responding/VBG/O to/TO/O complaints/NNS/O from/IN/O opposition/NN/O groups/NNS/O ,/,/O admitted/VBD/O police/NNS/O used/VBD/O excessive/JJ/O force/NN/O in/IN/O dispersing/VBG/O protesters/NNS/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
San/NNP/B-LOC Francisco/NNP/I-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O nine/CD/O people/NNS/O remain/VBP/O missing/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O aftermath/NN/O of/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O death/NN/O toll/NN/O rose/VBD/O to/TO/O 63/CD/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O expressed/VBD/O skepticism/NN/O over/IN/O an/DT/O Israeli/NNP/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O show/VB/O the/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O practice/VB/O terrorism/NN/O ././O
Israel/NNP/B-GPE provided/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O a/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O recent/JJ/O alleged/VBN/O terrorist/JJ/O incidents/NNS/O attributed/VBN/O to/TO/O forces/NNS/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Arafat/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O satisfied/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O incidents/NNS/O constituted/VBD/O terrorism/NN/O ././O
TV/NN/O evangelist/NN/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Bakker/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O 45/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O fined/VBN/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O for/IN/O defrauding/VBG/O followers/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O PTL/NNP/B-ORG ministry/NN/O ././O
Bakker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O immediately/RB/O taken/VBN/O into/IN/O custody/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O convicted/VBN/O Oct./NNP/O 5/CD/O by/IN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O jury/NN/O in/IN/O Charlotte/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O and/CC/O conspiracy/NN/O for/IN/O diverting/VBG/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 3.7/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O ministry/NN/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O personal/JJ/O use/NN/O ././O
Lawmakers/NNS/O in/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE voted/VBD/O to/TO/O deny/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Communist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG its/PRP$/O 100/CD/O guaranteed/VBN/O seats/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/NNP/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O meaning/NN/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O aides/NNS/O might/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O face/VB/O voters/NNS/O ././O
Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O premier/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O visit/VB/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE next/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Arab/NNP/I-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG pledged/VBD/O an/DT/O accord/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O complete/JJ/O Syrian/JJ/O troop/NN/O pullout/NN/O from/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O about/IN/O 70,000/CD/O people/NNS/O marched/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O headquarters/NN/O of/IN/O Christian/NNP/O leader/NN/O Aoun/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O support/VB/O his/PRP$/O rejection/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O peace/NN/O plan/NN/O approved/VBN/O Sunday/NNP/O by/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O legislature/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O plan/NN/O lacked/VBD/O a/DT/O withdrawal/NN/O timetable/NN/O ././O
Pro-Iranian/NNP/O kidnappers/NNS/O renewed/VBD/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O to/TO/O trade/VB/O their/PRP$/O captives/NNS/O in/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 15/CD/O Shiite/NNP/O Moslem/NNP/O comrades/NNS/O jailed/VBN/O in/IN/O Kuwait/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O statement/NN/O by/IN/O Islamic/NNP/B-ORG Jihad/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O holds/VBZ/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O two/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE hostages/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O accompanied/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O photograph/NN/O of/IN/O Associated/NNP/B-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG correspondent/NN/O Terry/NNP/B-PERSON Anderson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O longest/JJS/O held/VBN/O of/IN/O 18/CD/O Western/JJ/O hostages/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O department/NN/O 's/POS/O Office/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Thrift/NNP/I-ORG Supervision/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/DT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O necessarily/RB/O mean/VB/O thrifts/NNS/O are/VBP/O biased/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O conceded/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O data/NNS/O about/IN/O applicants/NNS/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O why/WRB/O blacks/NNS/O are/VBP/O rejected/VBN/O more/RBR/O often/RB/O ././O
Emergency/NN/O crews/NNS/O searched/VBD/O through/IN/O the/DT/O charred/VBN/O rubble/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Phillips/NNP/B-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG plastics/NNS/O plant/NN/O near/IN/O Pasadena/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O explosions/NNS/O Monday/NNP/O killed/VBD/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O two/CD/O people/NNS/O and/CC/O injured/VBD/O 124/CD/O ././O
Company/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O 22/CD/O workers/NNS/O were/VBD/O missing/VBG/O and/CC/O presumed/VBN/O dead/JJ/O ././O
Safety/NN/O authorities/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O immediately/RB/O know/VB/O the/DT/O cause/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O blasts/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O ministers/NNS/O ordered/VBD/O a/DT/O study/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O strategic/JJ/O role/NN/O of/IN/O nuclear/JJ/O arms/NNS/O in/IN/O Western/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC once/IN/O Soviet/NNP/O conventional/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O are/VBP/O reduced/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG scrambled/VBD/O to/TO/O play/VB/O down/IN/O the/DT/O significance/NN/O of/IN/O revised/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O concerning/VBG/O prosecutions/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O racketeering/NN/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O guidelines/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O discourage/VBP/O prosecutors/NNS/O from/IN/O seeking/VBG/O court/NN/O orders/NNS/O seizing/VBG/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O racketeering/NN/O defendants/NNS/O prior/RB/O to/TO/O trial/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O first/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
