The/DT/O internationalization/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O hastened/VBN/O by/IN/O foreign/JJ/O companies/NNS/O '/POS/O acquisitions/NNS/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE producers/NNS/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE brandy/NN/O exports/NNS/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O doubled/VBD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O to/TO/O 360,000/CD/O proof/NN/O gallons/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O standard/JJ/O industry/NN/O measure/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Jobson/NNP/B-ORG Beverage/NNP/I-ORG Alcohol/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O association/NN/O ././O
Exports/NNS/O of/IN/O rum/NN/O surged/VBD/O 54/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 814,000/CD/O proof/NN/O gallons/NNS/O ././O
California/JJ/B-GPE wineries/NNS/O ,/,/O benefiting/VBG/O from/IN/O lowered/VBN/O trade/NN/O barriers/NNS/O and/CC/O federal/JJ/O marketing/NN/O subsidies/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O expanding/VBG/O aggressively/RB/O into/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Great/NNP/B-GPE Britain/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O biggest/JJS/O foreign/JJ/O inroads/NNS/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O bourbon/NN/O ././O
Big/NNP/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE distillers/NNS/O are/VBP/O fiercely/RB/O vying/VBG/O for/IN/O this/DT/O market/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O grew/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 77/CD/O million/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O from/IN/O $/$/O 33/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O government/NN/O figures/NNS/O ././O
Jim/NNP/B-ORG Beam/NNP/I-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O division/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O exporter/NN/O of/IN/O bourbon/NN/O and/CC/O produces/VBZ/O 10/CD/O other/JJ/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O liquor/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O increase/VB/O its/PRP$/O international/JJ/O advertising/NN/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O with/IN/O bourbon/NN/O representing/VBG/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O that/DT/O amount/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O I.W./NNP/O Harper/NNP/O brand/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O bourbon/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Bourbon/NN/O exporters/NNS/O have/VBP/O succeeded/VBN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE where/WRB/O other/JJ/O industries/NNS/O have/VBP/O failed/VBN/O ,/,/O avoiding/VBG/O cultural/JJ/O hitches/NNS/O in/IN/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O distribution/NN/O by/IN/O allying/VBG/O themselves/PRP/O with/IN/O local/JJ/O agents/NNS/O ././O
Jim/NNP/B-ORG Beam/NNP/I-ORG Brands/NNPS/I-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O distribution/NN/O partnership/NN/O with/IN/O Nikka/NNP/B-ORG Whiskey/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O distiller/NN/O ././O
Seagram/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O exports/VBZ/O Four/NNP/O Roses/NNPS/O bourbon/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O link/NN/O with/IN/O Kirin/NNP/B-ORG Brewery/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Some/DT/O bourbon/NN/O makers/NNS/O advertise/VBP/O abroad/RB/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O at/IN/O home/NN/O ././O
Jim/NNP/B-ORG Beam/NNP/I-ORG print/NN/O ads/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O strike/VBP/O different/JJ/O chords/NNS/O in/IN/O different/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ././O
West/NNP/O Germans/NNPS/O get/VBP/O glitz/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O bourbon/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O foreground/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O posh/JJ/O Beverly/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNP/I-GPE hotel/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O background/NN/O ././O
Ads/NNS/O for/IN/O England/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O artsy/JJ/O and/CC/O irreverent/JJ/O ././O
One/CD/O ad/NN/O features/VBZ/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O robot/NN/O carrying/VBG/O a/DT/O voluptuous/JJ/O woman/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O faint/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O tagline/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O only/RB/O asked/VBD/O if/IN/O she/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O a/DT/B-ORG Jim/NNP/I-ORG Beam/NNP/I-ORG ././O
