The/DT/O article/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O replete/JJ/O with/IN/O outrageous/JJ/O distortions/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O observations/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O own/JJ/O loan/NN/O portfolio/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O deep/JJ/O trouble/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O lending/NN/O to/TO/O developing/VBG/O countries/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O not/RB/O so/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O reality/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG finances/NNS/O are/VBP/O rock/NN/O solid/JJ/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O enviably/RB/O low/JJ/O level/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O reality/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG loans/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O linked/VBN/O to/TO/O policy/NN/O improvements/NNS/O for/IN/O 40/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O takes/VBZ/O a/DT/O swipe/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O adjustment/NN/O lending/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O the/DT/O actions/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O development/NN/O agency/NN/O wed/VBN/O to/TO/O central/JJ/O planning/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O the/DT/O concentration/NN/O of/IN/O investment/NN/O decisions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O government/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON alleges/VBZ/O ././O
