International/JJ/O investigators/NNS/O urged/VBD/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O allow/VB/O prosecution/NN/O of/IN/O suspected/VBN/O Nazi/NNP/O war/NN/O criminals/NNS/O who/WP/O took/VBD/O refuge/NN/O there/RB/O after/IN/O 1945/CD/O ././O
Parliament/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
British/JJ/O investigations/NNS/O were/VBD/O prompted/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O 17/CD/O alleged/VBN/O war/NN/O criminals/NNS/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE sent/VBN/O to/TO/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Margaret/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O October/NNP/O 1986/CD/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Simon/NNP/I-ORG Wiesenthal/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O worried/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O convertibility/NN/O of/IN/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O machine/NN/O tools/NNS/O to/TO/O military/JJ/O use/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O at/IN/O Sochaux/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O move/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O assembly/NN/O plant/NN/O at/IN/O Mulhouse/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O strikers/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O whittled/VBN/O down/IN/O to/TO/O 80/CD/O ././O
Striking/VBG/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O began/VBD/O striking/VBG/O five/CD/O diamond/NN/O mines/NNS/O on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O returned/VBN/O to/TO/O work/VB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O union/NN/O and/CC/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG arranged/VBD/O to/TO/O reopen/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O had/VBD/O offered/VBN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O minimum/JJ/O wage/NN/O by/IN/O 18/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O union/NN/O was/VBD/O demanding/VBG/O 26.6/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O People/NNS/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Daily/NNP/I-ORG took/VBD/O note/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O growing/VBG/O problem/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O fraud/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O computers/NNS/O has/VBZ/O mushroomed/VBN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O 10,000/CD/O in/IN/O use/NN/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O 30,000/CD/O miniature/JJ/O models/NNS/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O tourists/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O told/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O care/NN/O when/WRB/O photographing/VBG/O earthquake/NN/O damage/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Travel/NNP/I-ORG Agents/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Tass/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Lenin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O tomb/NN/O in/IN/O Red/NNP/B-FAC Square/NNP/I-FAC will/MD/O be/VB/O closed/VBN/O from/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 10/CD/O to/TO/O Jan./NNP/O 15/CD/O for/IN/O essential/JJ/O maintenance/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O red/JJ/O granite/NN/O mausoleum/NN/O draws/VBZ/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O visitors/NNS/O daily/RB/O ././O
