With/IN/O ballots/NNS/O from/IN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O major/JJ/O cities/NNS/O in/IN/O by/IN/O yesterday/NN/O morning/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Republicans/NNPS/O came/VBD/O away/RP/O with/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O districts/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O many/JJ/O rural/JJ/O districts/NNS/O yet/RB/O to/TO/O report/VB/O ballots/NNS/O ,/,/O election/NN/O officials/NNS/O estimate/VBP/O support/NN/O for/IN/O Christian/NNP/O Democrats/NNPS/O fell/VBD/O an/DT/O average/JJ/O five/CD/O percentage/NN/O points/NNS/O statewide/RB/O ././O
International/JJ/O investigators/NNS/O urged/VBD/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O allow/VB/O prosecution/NN/O of/IN/O suspected/VBN/O Nazi/NNP/O war/NN/O criminals/NNS/O who/WP/O took/VBD/O refuge/NN/O there/RB/O after/IN/O 1945/CD/O ././O
Under/IN/O current/JJ/O law/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O suspects/NNS/O are/VBP/O immune/JJ/O from/IN/O prosecution/NN/O for/IN/O acts/NNS/O committed/VBN/O while/IN/O not/RB/O British/JJ/O citizens/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O careful/JJ/O we/PRP/O could/MD/O become/VB/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O haven/NN/O for/IN/O war/NN/O criminals/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Jeff/NNP/B-PERSON Rooker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O one/CD/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O British/JJ/O politicians/NNS/O attending/VBG/O a/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE conference/NN/O with/IN/O government/NN/O investigators/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Parliament/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
British/JJ/O investigations/NNS/O were/VBD/O prompted/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O 17/CD/O alleged/VBN/O war/NN/O criminals/NNS/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE sent/VBN/O to/TO/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Margaret/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O October/NNP/O 1986/CD/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Simon/NNP/I-ORG Wiesenthal/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O easing/VBG/O tension/NN/O between/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O China/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O again/RB/O take/VB/O back/RB/O illegal/JJ/O immigrants/NNS/O caught/VBD/O crossing/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O colony/NN/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O refused/VBN/O to/TO/O repatriate/VB/O citizens/NNS/O who/WP/O sneaked/VBD/O into/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE illegally/RB/O since/IN/O early/RB/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O colony/NN/O allowed/VBD/O a/DT/O dissident/JJ/O Chinese/JJ/O swimmer/NN/O to/TO/O flee/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
About/IN/O 1,100/CD/O Chinese/NNP/O were/VBD/O awaiting/VBG/O repatriation/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O worried/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O convertibility/NN/O of/IN/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O machine/NN/O tools/NNS/O to/TO/O military/JJ/O use/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Japanese/NNP/I-ORG Fisheries/NNPS/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG criticized/VBD/O moves/NNS/O to/TO/O ban/VB/O the/DT/O practice/NN/O in/IN/O international/JJ/O waters/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O really/RB/O unfortunate/JJ/O for/IN/O human/JJ/O beings/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O swayed/VBN/O by/IN/O emotional/JJ/O discussions/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O association/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O driftnet/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O ``/``/O wall/NN/O of/IN/O death/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O fishing/NN/O ,/,/O fleets/NNS/O lay/VBP/O nets/NNS/O up/IN/O to/TO/O three/CD/O miles/NNS/O long/RB/O that/DT/O trap/NN/O almost/RB/O everything/NN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O path/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O at/IN/O Sochaux/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O move/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O assembly/NN/O plant/NN/O at/IN/O Mulhouse/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O strikers/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O whittled/VBN/O down/RB/O to/TO/O 80/CD/O ././O
About/IN/O 8,000/CD/O National/NNP/B-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Mineworkers/NNPS/I-ORG members/NNS/O resumed/VBD/O their/PRP$/O strike/NN/O against/IN/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG Consolidated/NNP/I-ORG Mines/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG after/IN/O further/JJ/O negotiations/NNS/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O a/DT/O wage/NN/O dispute/NN/O broke/VBD/O down/IN/O ././O
Striking/VBG/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O began/VBD/O striking/VBG/O five/CD/O diamond/NN/O mines/NNS/O on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O returned/VBN/O to/TO/O work/VB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O union/NN/O and/CC/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG arranged/VBD/O to/TO/O reopen/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O had/VBD/O offered/VBN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O minimum/JJ/O wage/NN/O by/IN/O 18/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O union/NN/O was/VBD/O demanding/VBG/O 26.6/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Before/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O parties/NNS/O resumed/VBD/O talks/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG offered/VBD/O 17/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O union/NN/O wanted/VBD/O 37.6/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O People/NNS/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Daily/NNP/I-ORG took/VBD/O note/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O growing/VBG/O problem/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O fraud/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O fraud/NN/O was/VBD/O discovered/VBN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O 1986/CD/O at/IN/O an/DT/O office/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG People/NNPS/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O Shenzhen/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O 15/CD/O major/JJ/O cases/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O found/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O paper/NN/O said/VBD/O ;/:/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O theft/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 235,000/CD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O bank/NN/O in/IN/O Chengdu/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O March/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O computers/NNS/O has/VBZ/O mushroomed/VBN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O 10,000/CD/O in/IN/O use/NN/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O 30,000/CD/O miniature/JJ/O models/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O security/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O management/NN/O controls/NNS/O and/CC/O regulations/NNS/O to/TO/O govern/VB/O their/PRP$/O use/NN/O have/VBP/O not/RB/O kept/VBN/O pace/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG People/NNPS/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Daily/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Besides/IN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O criminals/NNS/O have/VBP/O also/RB/O used/VBN/O computers/NNS/O to/TO/O steal/VB/O secrets/NNS/O and/CC/O intelligence/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O newspaper/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O gave/VBD/O no/DT/O more/JJR/O details/NNS/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O tourists/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O told/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O care/NN/O when/WRB/O photographing/VBG/O earthquake/NN/O damage/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Travel/NNP/I-ORG Agents/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Tass/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Lenin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O tomb/NN/O in/IN/O Red/NNP/B-FAC Square/NNP/I-FAC will/MD/O be/VB/O closed/VBN/O from/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 10/CD/O to/TO/O Jan./NNP/O 15/CD/O for/IN/O essential/JJ/O maintenance/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O red/JJ/O granite/NN/O mausoleum/NN/O draws/VBZ/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O visitors/NNS/O daily/RB/O ././O
