Carlos/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Salvagni/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O pharmaceutical/JJ/O manufacturing/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O assume/VB/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O manufacturing/NN/O in/IN/O Kalamazoo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O effective/JJ/O Nov./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Salvagni/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 53/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O succeeds/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Griffin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 57/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O retiring/VBG/O as/RB/O corporate/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O pharmaceutical/JJ/O manufacturing/NN/O ././O
