He/PRP/O succeeds/VBZ/O Paul/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Montle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 42/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O chairman/NN/O ././O
National/NNP/B-ORG Environmental/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O move/VB/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O from/IN/O Hingham/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O Folcroft/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O site/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O sludge/NN/O dewatering/VBG/O facility/NN/O ././O
National/NNP/B-ORG Environmental/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O formerly/RB/O Yankee/NNP/B-ORG Cos./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O sludge/NN/O treatment/NN/O company/NN/O ././O
