Housing/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Urban/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Kemp/NNP/I-PERSON called/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O lower/VB/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O speech/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Bankers/NNPS/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Kemp/NNP/B-PERSON broke/VBD/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O public/JJ/O silence/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O complained/VBD/O that/IN/O ``/``/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O are/VBP/O too/RB/O high/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O convinced/VBN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O for/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O return/VB/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O historical/JJ/O level/NN/O of/IN/O 4/CD/O %/NN/O or/CC/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O not/RB/O only/RB/O an/DT/O immediate/JJ/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O housing/NN/O starts/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O housing/NN/O stock/NN/O ,/,/O our/PRP$/O industry/NN/O in/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O refurbishing/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O industrial/JJ/O system/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O help/VB/O the/DT/O Third/NNP/O World/NNP/O economies/NNS/O considerably/RB/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O particularly/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O favorable/JJ/O impact/NN/O upon/IN/O our/PRP$/O budget/NN/O deficit/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Kemp/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O inflation/NN/O is/VBZ/O under/IN/O control/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O slowing/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O ease/VB/O credit/NN/O even/RB/O further/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O for/IN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O part/NN/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O avoided/VBN/O expressing/VBG/O those/DT/O views/NNS/O in/IN/O public/NN/O ,/,/O fearing/VBG/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O unnecessarily/RB/O antagonize/VB/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
