The/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O filed/VBD/O a/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O seeking/VBG/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 7.7/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Meredith/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O defrauded/VBD/O the/DT/O government/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O relocation/NN/O services/NNS/O for/IN/O federal/JJ/O employees/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O trial/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Des/NNP/B-GPE Moines/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O Meredith/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O ,/,/O alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O diversified/VBN/O media/NNS/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O relocation/NN/O unit/NN/O cheated/VBD/O the/DT/O government/NN/O by/IN/O misrepresenting/VBG/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O government/NN/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O homes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O contract/NN/O required/VBD/O Meredith/NNP/B-ORG Relocation/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O purchase/VB/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O homes/NNS/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O independent/JJ/O appraisals/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ``/``/O engaged/VBD/O in/IN/O various/JJ/O forms/NNS/O of/IN/O misrepresentation/NN/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/O goal/NN/O of/IN/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O appraised/VBN/O value/NN/O of/IN/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O homes/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O department/NN/O seeks/VBZ/O to/TO/O recover/VB/O $/$/O 7.7/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O costs/NNS/O incurred/VBN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O terminated/VBD/O its/PRP$/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O Meredith/NNP/B-ORG Relocation/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O sought/VBD/O other/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O department/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O seeks/VBZ/O ``/``/O three/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O damages/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O presently/RB/O undetermined/JJ/O ,/,/O plus/CC/O penalties/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Officials/NNS/O with/IN/O Meredith/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O immediate/JJ/O comment/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O ././O
