Ironically/RB/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG attempt/NN/O to/TO/O lead/VB/O industry/NN/O prices/NNS/O higher/RBR/O was/VBD/O reported/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O issue/NN/O as/IN/O your/PRP$/O survey/NN/O showing/VBG/O that/IN/O consumers/NNS/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O confidence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O industry/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Sept./NNP/O 20/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
You/PRP/O quote/VBP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Crandall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O having/VBG/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O discount/NN/O deals/NNS/O for/IN/O big/JJ/O customers/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O dumb/JJ/O ''/''/O because/IN/O ``/``/O you/PRP/O will/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O Detroit/NNP/B-GPE because/IN/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O go/VB/O to/TO/O Detroit/NNP/B-GPE whether/IN/O the/DT/O fare/NN/O is/VBZ/O $/$/O 175/CD/O ,/,/O $/$/O 275/CD/O or/CC/O $/$/O 375/CD/O ././O ''/''/O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Crandall/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O correct/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O of/IN/O all/DT/O people/NNS/O must/MD/O realize/VB/O our/PRP$/O society/NN/O relies/VBZ/O on/IN/O competition/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O prices/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O competitive/JJ/O level/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O settled/VBD/O an/DT/O antitrust/JJ/O suit/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O taped/VBN/O telephone/NN/O conversation/NN/O of/IN/O him/PRP/O proposing/VBG/O to/TO/O Braniff/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O president/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O both/DT/O raise/VBP/O fares/NNS/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Braniff/NNP/B-ORG declined/VBD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
When/WRB/O I/PRP/O asked/VBD/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/O its/PRP$/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O story/NN/O for/IN/O use/NN/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O MBA/NNP/O class/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O I/PRP/O teach/VBP/O business/NN/O ethics/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O respond/VB/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O the/DT/O ethics/NNS/O of/IN/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O leader/NN/O filters/VBZ/O down/IN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O factors/NNS/O that/WDT/O ultimately/RB/O shapes/VBZ/O consumer/NN/O trust/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Arnold/NNP/B-PERSON Celnicker/NNP/I-PERSON Assistant/NNP/O Professor/NNP/O Ohio/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG
