Terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Weyerhaeuser/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O paneling/NN/O business/NN/O employs/VBZ/O about/IN/O 300/CD/O workers/NNS/O at/IN/O two/CD/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O Chesapeake/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Hancock/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Vt/NNP/B-GPE ././O
