With/IN/O reduced/VBN/O exports/NNS/O and/CC/O rising/VBG/O imports/NNS/O ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE trade/NN/O surpluses/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC between/IN/O January/NNP/O and/CC/O September/NNP/O fell/VBD/O sharply/RB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Customs/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
South/NNP/O Korean/NNP/O exports/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE during/IN/O the/DT/O period/NN/O fell/VBD/O 1.6/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 15.06/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O while/IN/O imports/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE soared/VBD/O 26/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 11.56/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O with/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC was/VBD/O pegged/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 414/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O down/IN/O 57/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/IN/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O South/JJ/O Korean/JJ/O exports/NNS/O to/TO/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC dropped/VBD/O 5.3/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.02/CD/O billion/CD/O while/IN/O imports/NNS/O from/IN/O there/RB/O went/VBD/O up/IN/O 17/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 2.61/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
