Mr./NNP/O Lodge/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 48/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O finance/NN/O executive/NN/O at/IN/O Singer/NNP/B-ORG Sewing/NNP/I-ORG Machine/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Celanese/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O succeeds/VBZ/O Francis/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Brophy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 64/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O retire/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
