Staar/NNP/B-ORG Surgical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG board/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O removed/VBN/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Waggoner/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Wolf/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O formerly/RB/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Waggoner/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O dispute/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O since/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O ousted/VBD/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O directors/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O turned/VBD/O down/IN/O the/DT/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O petition/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wolf/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O announcement/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Waggoner/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O Staar/NNP/B-ORG board/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Ford/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wolf/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
