but/CC/O worries/NNS/O about/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
With/IN/O most/JJS/O legislatures/NNS/O adjourned/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O small/JJ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O tallying/VBG/O its/PRP$/O scorecard/NN/O ././O
Five/CD/O states/NNS/O --/:/O Oregon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Rhode/NNP/B-GPE Island/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Wisconsin/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O passed/VBD/O bills/NNS/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O the/DT/O minimum/JJ/O wage/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O measures/NNS/O in/IN/O 19/CD/O other/JJ/O states/NNS/O were/VBD/O defeated/VBN/O ././O
Oregon/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O rate/NN/O will/MD/O rise/VB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 4.75/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O highest/JJS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Jan./NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O 1991/CD/O ././O
Small/JJ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O bracing/VBG/O for/IN/O an/DT/O avalanche/NN/O of/IN/O similar/JJ/O proposals/NNS/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
Only/RB/O two/CD/O states/NNS/O --/:/O Vermont/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O this/DT/O year/NN/O joined/VBD/O five/CD/O others/NNS/O requiring/VBG/O private/JJ/O employers/NNS/O to/TO/O grant/VB/O leaves/NNS/O of/IN/O absence/NN/O to/TO/O employees/NNS/O with/IN/O newborn/JJ/O or/CC/O adopted/VBN/O infants/NNS/O ././O
Similar/JJ/O proposals/NNS/O were/VBD/O defeated/VBN/O in/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 15/CD/O other/JJ/O states/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O just/RB/O a/DT/O matter/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O tide/NN/O turns/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O Midwestern/JJ/O lobbyist/NN/O ././O
Consequently/RB/O ,/,/O small/JJ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O more/RBR/O ``/``/O pro-active/JJ/O ''/''/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O counter/VB/O mandated/VBN/O leaves/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O small/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O are/VBP/O pushing/VBG/O for/IN/O a/DT/O voluntary/JJ/O alternative/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O favor/VBP/O a/DT/O commission/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O develop/VB/O sample/NN/O leave/NN/O policies/NNS/O that/IN/O employers/NNS/O could/MD/O adopt/VB/O ././O
They/PRP/O also/RB/O support/VBP/O a/DT/O tax/NN/O credit/NN/O for/IN/O employers/NNS/O to/TO/O offset/VB/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O hiring/VBG/O and/CC/O training/VBG/O workers/NNS/O who/WP/O temporarily/RB/O replace/VBP/O employees/NNS/O on/IN/O parental/JJ/O leave/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O especially/RB/O close/JJ/O in/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Michigan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O playing/VBG/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O defense/NN/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Midwest/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Northeast/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Buente/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/O NFIB/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Triggering/VBG/O the/DT/O re-examination/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O city/NN/O council/NN/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O preference/NN/O in/IN/O letting/VBG/O city/NN/O contracts/NNS/O to/TO/O suppliers/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O stated/VBN/O policy/NN/O on/IN/O child/NN/O care/NN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O employees/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O preferential/JJ/O treatment/NN/O even/RB/O applies/VBZ/O to/TO/O awarding/VBG/O small/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O under/IN/O $/$/O 25,000/CD/O and/CC/O consulting/VBG/O and/CC/O temporary/JJ/O services/NNS/O --/:/O which/WDT/O often/RB/O go/VBP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O smaller/JJR/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
Council/NN/O member/NN/O Joy/NNP/B-PERSON Picus/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/NN/O advocate/NN/O ,/,/O considers/VBZ/O it/PRP/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O pro-family/NN/O policy/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE a/DT/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O ``/``/O humanizing/VBG/O the/DT/O workplace/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
NOVEMBER/NNP/O BALLOTS/NNS/O will/MD/O contain/VB/O few/JJ/O referendum/NN/O or/CC/O initiative/NN/O issues/NNS/O that/WDT/O especially/RB/O affect/VBP/O small/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O ,/,/O small/JJ/O business/NN/O generally/RB/O opposes/VBZ/O an/DT/O initiative/NN/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O spending/VBG/O on/IN/O children/NNS/O 's/POS/O programs/NNS/O by/IN/O $/$/O 360/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O fearing/VBG/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O 7.8/CD/O %/NN/O sales/NNS/O tax/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O the/DT/O outlays/NNS/O ././O
DIALING/NNP/O DOLLARS/NNPS/O :/:/O
But/CC/O many/JJ/O owners/NNS/O plan/VBP/O to/TO/O practice/VB/O frugality/NN/O --/:/O crossing/VBG/O out/RP/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O code/NN/O and/CC/O writing/VBG/O in/RP/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O one/CD/O until/IN/O their/PRP$/O stock/NN/O runs/VBZ/O out/IN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O He/PRP/O reports/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O up/IN/O slightly/RB/O from/IN/O customers/NNS/O replacing/VBG/O old/JJ/O stock/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Previously/RB/O ,/,/O regulators/NNS/O insisted/VBD/O that/IN/O franchisers/NNS/O pre-register/VB/O such/JJ/O changes/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O --/:/O a/DT/O costly/JJ/O process/NN/O taking/VBG/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O six/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O some/DT/O negotiated/VBN/O sales/NNS/O that/WDT/O meet/VBP/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O tests/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O pre-registered/VBN/O ././O
For/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O franchisers/NNS/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O must/MD/O pre-register/VB/O sales/NNS/O to/TO/O aspiring/VBG/O franchisees/NNS/O who/WP/O qualify/VBP/O as/IN/O ``/``/O sophisticated/JJ/O purchasers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Such/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O must/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O minimum/JJ/O net/JJ/O worth/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O annual/JJ/O income/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O recent/JJ/O experience/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O business/NN/O area/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O franchise/NN/O being/VBG/O sold/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O critics/NNS/O consider/VBP/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O regressive/JJ/O ././O
Lewis/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Rudnick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE lawyer/NN/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O franchisers/NNS/O ,/,/O contends/VBZ/O California/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O narrowly/RB/O limiting/VBG/O --/:/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O expanding/VBG/O --/:/O opportunities/NNS/O for/IN/O negotiating/VBG/O sales/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O argues/VBZ/O California/NNP/B-GPE regulators/NNS/O historically/RB/O have/VBP/O misinterpreted/VBN/O their/PRP$/O law/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O negotiated/VBN/O sales/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O pre-registered/JJ/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O legal/JJ/O all/DT/O along/IN/O ././O
San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE lawyer/NN/O Timothy/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Fine/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O franchisees/NNS/O ,/,/O insists/VBZ/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O cautiousness/NN/O helps/VBZ/O protect/VB/O franchisees/NNS/O from/IN/O crafty/JJ/O sales/NNS/O negotiators/NNS/O who/WP/O push/VBP/O unlawful/JJ/O clauses/NNS/O ././O
SMALL/NNP/O TALK/NNP/O :/:/O
A/DT/O new/JJ/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE law/NN/O frees/VBZ/O store/NN/O owners/NNS/O of/IN/O liability/NN/O if/IN/O a/DT/O customer/NN/O trips/NNS/O or/CC/O otherwise/RB/O gets/VBZ/O hurt/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O restroom/NN/O .../:/O ././O
Only/RB/O 4/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE small/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O surveyed/VBN/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O tested/VBN/O an/DT/O employee/NN/O or/CC/O applicant/NN/O for/IN/O drug/NN/O or/CC/O alcohol/NN/O use/NN/O .../:/O ././O
By/IN/O 52%-36/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O Tennessee/NNP/B-GPE NFIB/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O favor/VBP/O laws/NNS/O to/TO/O limit/VB/O foreign/JJ/O ownership/NN/O of/IN/O land/NN/O and/CC/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
