The/DT/O article/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O replete/JJ/O with/IN/O outrageous/JJ/O distortions/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O observations/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O own/JJ/O loan/NN/O portfolio/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O deep/JJ/O trouble/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O lending/NN/O to/TO/O developing/VBG/O countries/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O not/RB/O so/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O reality/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG finances/NNS/O are/VBP/O rock/NN/O solid/JJ/O ././O
As/IN/O of/IN/O June/NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O --/:/O the/DT/O day/NN/O our/PRP$/O past/NN/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O close/NN/O --/:/O only/RB/O 4.1/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O portfolio/NN/O was/VBD/O affected/VBN/O by/IN/O arrears/NNS/O of/IN/O over/IN/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O enviably/RB/O low/JJ/O level/NN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG follows/VBZ/O a/DT/O prudent/JJ/O provisioning/VBG/O policy/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O set/VBN/O aside/RP/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O against/IN/O possible/JJ/O loan/NN/O losses/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O net/JJ/O income/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O robust/JJ/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O billion/CD/O after/IN/O provisions/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O criticisms/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG lending/NN/O has/VBZ/O done/VBN/O more/JJR/O harm/NN/O than/IN/O good/JJ/O ``/``/O by/IN/O implanting/VBG/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O incentives/NNS/O and/CC/O deflecting/VBG/O energy/NN/O away/RB/O from/IN/O economic/JJ/O development/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Here/RB/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O way/NN/O off/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O reality/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG loans/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O linked/VBN/O to/TO/O policy/NN/O improvements/NNS/O for/IN/O 40/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O and/CC/O large/JJ/O ,/,/O these/DT/O efforts/NNS/O have/VBP/O borne/VBN/O fruit/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O my/PRP$/O home/NN/O region/NN/O ,/,/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O much/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O existing/VBG/O infrastructure/NN/O base/NN/O --/:/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O building/NN/O block/NN/O for/IN/O development/NN/O --/:/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O takes/VBZ/O a/DT/O swipe/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O adjustment/NN/O lending/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O facts/NNS/O on/IN/O this/DT/O type/NN/O of/IN/O lending/NN/O ?/./O
The/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O making/VBG/O adjustment/NN/O loans/NNS/O for/IN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Support/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O private/JJ/O sector/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O longstanding/JJ/O concern/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O helped/VBN/O encourage/VB/O investments/NNS/O by/IN/O entrepreneurs/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Third/NNP/O World/NNP/O through/IN/O its/PRP$/O extensive/JJ/O credit/NN/O operations/NNS/O and/CC/O through/IN/O loans/NNS/O and/CC/O investments/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Most/RBS/O recently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O expanded/VBN/O to/TO/O include/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Multilateral/NNP/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Guarantee/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O stimulate/VB/O direct/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O developing/VBG/O countries/NNS/O by/IN/O offering/VBG/O guarantees/NNS/O against/IN/O noncommercial/JJ/O risk/NN/O and/CC/O advice/NN/O to/TO/O member/NN/O countries/NNS/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O their/PRP$/O business/NN/O climate/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O the/DT/O actions/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O development/NN/O agency/NN/O wed/VBN/O to/TO/O central/JJ/O planning/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O the/DT/O concentration/NN/O of/IN/O investment/NN/O decisions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O government/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON alleges/VBZ/O ././O
