This/DT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O FBI/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O very/RB/O supportive/JJ/O of/IN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O active/JJ/O participant/NN/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O initiative/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O agreed/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O outset/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Initiative/NNP/I-ORG that/IN/O the/DT/O FBI/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O role/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O targeting/VBG/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O drug/NN/O traffickers/NNS/O through/IN/O our/PRP$/O National/NNP/B-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Strategy/NNP/I-ORG ././O
