At/IN/O least/JJS/O 10/CD/O states/NNS/O are/VBP/O resisting/VBG/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG nationwide/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O its/PRP$/O legal/JJ/O troubles/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O some/DT/O might/MD/O instead/RB/O try/VB/O to/TO/O revoke/VB/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O license/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O securities/NNS/O within/IN/O their/PRP$/O borders/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O reluctance/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O states/NNS/O to/TO/O let/VB/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG off/IN/O the/DT/O hook/NN/O could/MD/O hamper/VB/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O attempts/NNS/O to/TO/O polish/VB/O its/PRP$/O image/NN/O after/IN/O its/PRP$/O guilty/JJ/O plea/NN/O to/TO/O six/CD/O felonies/NNS/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O several/JJ/O people/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O discussions/NNS/O ././O
These/DT/O states/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O entering/VBG/O into/IN/O settlements/NNS/O with/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O freely/RB/O anywhere/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE despite/IN/O its/PRP$/O record/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O admitted/VBN/O felon/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O individuals/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O generally/RB/O successful/JJ/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG talks/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O is/VBZ/O meeting/VBG/O resistance/NN/O from/IN/O some/DT/O big/JJ/O states/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Officials/NNS/O in/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O states/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O simply/RB/O accept/VB/O the/DT/O settlements/NNS/O offered/VBN/O by/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O with/IN/O state/NN/O securities/NNS/O regulators/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O criminal/JJ/O guilty/JJ/O plea/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O related/VBN/O civil/JJ/O settlement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG that/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O payment/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 650/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O penalties/NNS/O ././O
Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE District/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/I-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Tennessee/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O less/RBR/O resistant/JJ/O to/TO/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG than/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O six/CD/O states/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O nonetheless/RB/O have/VBP/O refused/VBN/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O so/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O those/DT/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O discussions/NNS/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O any/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O state/NN/O brokerage/NN/O licenses/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O revoked/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O even/RB/O if/IN/O some/DT/O are/VBP/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O securities/NNS/O business/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O directly/RB/O hurt/VBN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O if/IN/O nothing/NN/O else/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O revoked/VBN/O brokerage/NN/O license/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O burden/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O must/MD/O be/VB/O disclosed/VBN/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transactions/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O be/VB/O involved/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O disagree/VBP/O about/IN/O the/DT/O message/NN/O these/DT/O settlements/NNS/O give/VBP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O public/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O internal/JJ/O debate/NN/O about/IN/O that/DT/O specific/JJ/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Susan/NNP/B-PERSON Bryant/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O chief/NN/O securities/NNS/O regulator/NN/O and/CC/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG North/NNP/I-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Administrators/NNPS/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O drafted/VBD/O a/DT/O voluntary/JJ/O settlement/NN/O plan/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O states/NNS/O with/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O question/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O be/VB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O and/CC/O move/VB/O on/IN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O ``/``/O whether/IN/O you/PRP/O should/MD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O simply/RB/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O revoke/VB/O the/DT/O license/NN/O when/WRB/O someone/NN/O is/VBZ/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O felony/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
While/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Bryant/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O state/NN/O went/VBD/O ahead/RB/O and/CC/O accepted/VBN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O settlement/NN/O offer/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 25,000/CD/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O argument/NN/O with/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O different/JJ/O conclusions/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O can/MD/O see/VB/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Similarly/RB/O ,/,/O Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON Rubega/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE director/NN/O of/IN/O securities/NNS/O regulation/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O state/NN/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O received/VBN/O any/DT/O complaints/NNS/O about/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O so/IN/O it/PRP/O really/RB/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O press/VB/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O understand/VBP/O the/DT/O reasons/NNS/O ''/''/O that/IN/O other/JJ/O states/NNS/O are/VBP/O holding/VBG/O out/RP/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O say/VBP/O in/IN/O investment/NN/O banking/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O `/``/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O '/''/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O losing/VBG/O any/DT/O licenses/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Asked/VBD/O about/IN/O states/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O taking/VBG/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O line/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O There/EX/O are/VBP/O states/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O asked/VBN/O for/IN/O additional/JJ/O information/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O providing/VBG/O to/TO/O them/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 2.8/CD/O million/CD/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O paid/VBN/O to/TO/O 26/CD/O states/NNS/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG still/RB/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O out/RP/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 11.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
By/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O have/VB/O another/DT/O three/CD/O to/TO/O four/CD/O settlements/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O rate/NN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O that/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O 30/CD/O to/TO/O 35/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
That/DT/O total/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O important/JJ/O for/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O investment/NN/O bank/NN/O has/VBZ/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O that/IN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O punishment/NN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O create/VB/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O foundation/NN/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O ethical/JJ/O behavior/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O securities/NNS/O industry/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O proviso/NN/O to/TO/O that/DT/O promise/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O a/DT/O minimum/NN/O of/IN/O 35/CD/O states/NNS/O reach/VBP/O settlement/NN/O agreements/NNS/O before/IN/O next/JJ/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O several/JJ/O securities/NNS/O commissioners/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 16/CD/O states/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O either/RB/O close/RB/O to/TO/O settlements/NNS/O with/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O who/WP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O appear/VB/O opposed/VBN/O to/TO/O settling/VBG/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O proposed/VBN/O state/NN/O fines/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O population/NN/O and/CC/O on/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O business/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O asked/VBN/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O $/$/O 300,000/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O refused/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O ruling/VBG/O out/RP/O revoking/VBG/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O brokerage/NN/O license/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O can/MD/O also/RB/O bar/VB/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O adviser/NN/O ././O
State/NN/O officials/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O describe/VB/O their/PRP$/O position/NN/O in/IN/O detail/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O James/NNP/B-PERSON McLelland/NNP/I-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O state/NN/O securities/NNS/O chief/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O really/RB/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O have/VB/O informed/VBN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O that/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O is/VBZ/O really/RB/O not/RB/O sufficient/JJ/O for/IN/O settlement/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE already/RB/O has/VBZ/O issued/VBN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O notice/NN/O of/IN/O intent/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O revoke/VB/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O brokerage/NN/O license/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O states/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O met/VBN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O asked/VBN/O for/IN/O additional/JJ/O information/NN/O about/IN/O investors/NNS/O '/POS/O accounts/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O banking/NN/O department/NN/O spokesman/NN/O added/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O Commissioner/NNP/O Brown/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O feel/VB/O that/DT/O money/NN/O alone/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O here/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Neither/DT/O state/NN/O has/VBZ/O settled/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O officials/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O states/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O discuss/VB/O their/PRP$/O reasons/NNS/O for/IN/O not/RB/O doing/VBG/O so/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O mount/VB/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O legal/JJ/O battle/NN/O in/IN/O each/DT/O state/NN/O if/IN/O its/PRP$/O license/NN/O is/VBZ/O revoked/VBN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O state/NN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O trouble/NN/O with/IN/O some/DT/O states/NNS/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O bad/JJ/O thing/NN/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O process/NN/O should/MD/O point/VB/O out/RP/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O easy/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O firm/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O felony/NN/O to/TO/O immediately/RB/O jump/VB/O back/RB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O retail/JJ/O business/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Ms./NNP/O Bryant/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O somebody/NN/O worried/VBN/O so/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O do/VB/O this/DT/O again/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
These/DT/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O 26/CD/O states/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O commonwealth/NN/O of/IN/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O settled/VBN/O with/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Arkansas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Delaware/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Hawaii/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Idaho/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Indiana/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kentucky/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Maine/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Minnesota/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mississippi/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Mexico/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O North/NNP/B-GPE Dakota/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Oregon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Dakota/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Vermont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wyoming/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ././O
