Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Brady/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Greenspan/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Housing/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Urban/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Kemp/NNP/I-PERSON are/VBP/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON must/MD/O appoint/VB/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O one/NN/O a/DT/O Democrat/NNP/O and/CC/O one/CD/O a/DT/O Republican/NNP/O ././O
An/DT/O administration/NN/O official/NN/O confirmed/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Simmons/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Valley/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Phoenix/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O Republican/NNP/O appointee/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O a/DT/O security/NN/O clearance/NN/O was/VBD/O under/IN/O way/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O appointee/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O determined/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Simmons/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O congressmen/NNS/O 's/POS/O letter/NN/O is/VBZ/O under/IN/O review/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O letter/NN/O ,/,/O dated/VBN/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O cited/VBD/O the/DT/O losses/NNS/O at/IN/O Valley/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O United/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O also/RB/O of/IN/O Phoenix/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Simmons/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O chairman/NN/O for/IN/O 29/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Both/DT/O banks/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O battered/VBN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O have/VBP/O other/JJ/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE banks/NNS/O ,/,/O by/IN/O falling/VBG/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
Valley/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O $/$/O 470/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O problem/NN/O assets/NNS/O as/IN/O of/IN/O June/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O numerous/JJ/O other/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O more/RBR/O qualified/VBN/O for/IN/O this/DT/O important/JJ/O position/NN/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O encourage/VBP/O you/PRP/O to/TO/O give/VB/O them/PRP/O your/PRP$/O thorough/JJ/O consideration/NN/O before/IN/O making/VBG/O this/DT/O key/JJ/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG appointment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O letter/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O able/JJ/O ,/,/O competent/JJ/O management/NN/O available/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Simmons/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O long/JJ/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O both/DT/O Republicans/NNPS/O and/CC/O banking/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O co-chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE campaign/NN/O committee/NN/O in/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O election/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O also/RB/O worked/VBD/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O the/DT/O 1980/CD/O election/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Simmons/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O served/VBD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O committee/NN/O of/IN/O businessmen/NNS/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Seidman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Deposit/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Resolution/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
That/DT/O committee/NN/O determined/VBD/O to/TO/O open/VB/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O banking/NN/O across/IN/O state/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
Arizona/NNP/B-ORG Trend/NNP/I-ORG magazine/NN/O referred/VBD/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Simmons/NNP/B-PERSON this/DT/O year/NN/O as/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 25/CD/O most/RBS/O influential/JJ/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O signed/VBN/O by/IN/O Reps./NNP/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Vento/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Minn./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG RTC/NNP/B-ORG Task/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON McMillen/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Md./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O Kweisi/NNP/B-PERSON Mfume/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Md/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Kanjorski/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Pa/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
