BSB/NNP/B-ORG BANCORP/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Binghamton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O increased/VBD/O its/PRP$/O regular/JJ/O quarterly/JJ/O dividend/NN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 15/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O from/IN/O 10/CD/O cents/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O payable/JJ/O Dec./NNP/O 10/CD/O to/TO/O stock/VB/O of/IN/O record/NN/O Nov./NNP/O 24/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O BSB/NNP/B-ORG earned/VBD/O $/$/O 2/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O up/IN/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.8/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O earlier/RBR/O ././O
BSB/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O 3.1/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ././O
