International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unveiled/VBD/O a/DT/O broad/JJ/O strategy/NN/O to/TO/O tackle/VB/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O problem/NN/O that/IN/O manufacturers/NNS/O face/VBP/O when/WRB/O computerizing/VBG/O their/PRP$/O operations/NNS/O :/:/O Most/JJS/O machines/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O talk/VB/O to/TO/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O unveiled/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 50/CD/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O software/NN/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O integrate/VB/O the/DT/O three/CD/O areas/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O manufacturing/NN/O operation/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O floor/NN/O ,/,/O design/NN/O operations/NNS/O and/CC/O production/NN/O planning/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O aim/NN/O ,/,/O ultimately/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O flow/NN/O of/IN/O information/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O manufacturer/NN/O 's/POS/O main/JJ/O computer/NN/O network/NN/O for/IN/O use/NN/O in/IN/O business/NN/O planning/NN/O ,/,/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Manufacturers/NNS/O have/VBP/O already/RB/O spent/VBN/O so/RB/O heavily/RB/O on/IN/O automation/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O leading/VBG/O revenue/NN/O sources/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O many/JJ/O manufacturers/NNS/O find/VBP/O that/DT/O communication/NN/O between/IN/O different/JJ/O computers/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O rendered/VBN/O nearly/RB/O impossible/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O babel/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O languages/NNS/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O different/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O robots/NNS/O and/CC/O machine/NN/O tools/NNS/O ././O
Consultants/NNS/O have/VBP/O said/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O while/NN/O for/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O pieces/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG strategy/NN/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O into/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O the/DT/O specific/JJ/O products/NNS/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG unveiled/VBD/O will/MD/O generally/RB/O be/VB/O available/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
Sam/NNP/B-PERSON Albert/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O in/IN/O Scarsdale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O developed/VBN/O broad/JJ/O software/NN/O strategies/NNS/O only/RB/O for/IN/O problems/NNS/O that/WDT/O crossed/VBD/O industry/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O this/DT/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O effort/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O industry/NN/O showed/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O getting/VBG/O serious/JJ/O about/IN/O understanding/VBG/O customers/NNS/O '/POS/O problems/NNS/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O selling/VBG/O technology/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O unveil/VB/O similar/JJ/O strategies/NNS/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O industries/NNS/O in/IN/O coming/VBG/O months/NNS/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O push/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O unusual/JJ/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O approach/NN/O to/TO/O marketing/NN/O ././O
Rather/RB/O than/IN/O just/RB/O send/VB/O out/RP/O marketing/NN/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O knock/VB/O on/IN/O customers/NNS/O '/POS/O doors/NNS/O ,/,/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O several/JJ/O hundred/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O manufacturing/VBG/O people/NNS/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O specific/JJ/O needs/NNS/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O manufacturing/VBG/O staff/NN/O also/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O software/NN/O that/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O developed/VBN/O internally/RB/O and/CC/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O form/VB/O teams/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O customer/NN/O to/TO/O jointly/RB/O solve/VB/O manufacturing/NN/O problems/NNS/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O obviously/RB/O bring/VB/O its/PRP$/O expertise/NN/O to/TO/O bear/VB/O on/IN/O problems/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O computer/NN/O manufacturing/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O also/RB/O help/VB/O customers/NNS/O on/IN/O software/NN/O to/TO/O deal/VB/O with/IN/O such/JJ/O things/NNS/O as/IN/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O engineering/VBG/O documents/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O may/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O every/DT/O manufacturing/NN/O problem/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O most/JJS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Conrades/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O top/JJ/O marketing/NN/O official/NN/O ././O
