However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O early/JJ/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O nature/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O projects/NNS/O or/CC/O indicate/VB/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O concluded/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O While/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reuter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O comments/NNS/O please/VBP/O us/PRP/O very/RB/O much/RB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O currently/RB/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O talks/NNS/O in/IN/O progress/NN/O regarding/VBG/O the/DT/O automotive/JJ/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Fiat/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Reuter/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O thinking/VBG/O foremost/RB/O of/IN/O cooperation/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O truck/NN/O sector/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O ``/``/O in/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O run/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O rule/VB/O out/RP/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O also/RB/O come/VB/O a/DT/O bit/NN/O closer/RBR/O in/IN/O personal/JJ/O cars/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Roberto/NNP/B-PERSON Morelli/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE analyst/NN/O for/IN/O County/NNP/B-ORG Natwest/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O right/RB/O now/RB/O ``/``/O the/DT/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O being/VBG/O influenced/VBN/O by/IN/O that/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O news/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O conditional/JJ/O nature/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O mentioned/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reuter/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O by/IN/O the/DT/O uncertainty/NN/O surrounding/VBG/O world/NN/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
