The/DT/O inverse/NN/O trading/NN/O relationship/NN/O between/IN/O bonds/NNS/O and/CC/O stocks/NNS/O was/VBD/O interrupted/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O as/IN/O bonds/NNS/O fell/VBD/O despite/IN/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O decline/NN/O in/IN/O stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O bond/NN/O investors/NNS/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O a/DT/O close/JJ/O watch/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O jittery/JJ/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O early/JJ/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O investors/NNS/O were/VBD/O bidding/VBG/O bond/NN/O prices/NNS/O higher/JJR/O as/IN/O stocks/NNS/O tumbled/VBD/O and/CC/O fears/NNS/O mounted/VBD/O that/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O debacle/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O repeated/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O a/DT/O partial/JJ/O recovery/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Industrial/NNP/O Average/NNP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O down/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 60/CD/O points/NNS/O in/IN/O midmorning/NN/O ,/,/O dashed/VBD/O those/DT/O expectations/NNS/O ././O
Treasury/NN/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O also/RB/O were/VBD/O hurt/VBN/O late/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O offering/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Tennessee/NNP/I-ORG Valley/NNP/I-ORG Authority/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O agency/NN/O debt/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Bond/NN/O investors/NNS/O were/VBD/O hoping/VBG/O that/IN/O stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O would/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Roger/NNP/B-PERSON Early/RB/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O at/IN/O Federated/NNP/B-ORG Investors/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Pittsburgh/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O stocks/NNS/O stabilized/VBD/O ,/,/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O disappointment/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O straight/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O bond/NN/O market/NN/O paid/VBD/O little/JJ/O attention/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG open/JJ/O market/NN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O injected/VBD/O more/JJR/O cash/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O banking/NN/O system/NN/O by/IN/O arranging/VBG/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O repurchase/VBN/O agreements/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O usual/JJ/O pre-noon/NN/O intervention/NN/O period/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O was/VBD/O meant/VBN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O a/DT/O lid/NN/O on/IN/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O investor/NN/O confidence/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O aggressive/JJ/O move/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O needed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O appears/VBZ/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O credit/NN/O conditions/NNS/O further/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O banks/NNS/O charge/VBP/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O on/IN/O overnight/JJ/O loans/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O an/DT/O early/JJ/O signal/NN/O of/IN/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG policy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Macy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O issue/NN/O closed/VBD/O up/RB/O about/IN/O one/CD/O point/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O price/NN/O of/IN/O 97/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O public/JJ/O debt/NN/O offering/VBG/O was/VBD/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O in/IN/O 15/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Strong/JJ/O investor/NN/O demand/NN/O prompted/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O from/IN/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Traders/NNS/O said/VBD/O hedging/VBG/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG pricing/NN/O also/RB/O pressured/VBD/O Treasury/NN/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Underwriters/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O reduced/VBD/O their/PRP$/O market/NN/O risk/NN/O by/IN/O selling/VBG/O Treasurys/NNS/B-ORG to/TO/O cover/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O part/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG -RCB-/-RRB-/O holdings/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O James/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Capra/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O at/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Government/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Refcorp/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O created/VBN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O fund/VB/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O bailout/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O agency/NN/O issue/NN/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O market/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O release/NN/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O economic/JJ/O reports/NNS/O had/VBD/O little/JJ/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O report/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O expanded/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O surprisingly/RB/O wide/JJ/O $/$/O 10.77/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O up/IN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O revised/VBN/O $/$/O 8.24/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O August/NNP/O gap/NN/O was/VBD/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O expanded/VBN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 9.1/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Treasury/NNP/O Securities/NNPS/O
Corporate/NNP/O ,/,/O Other/NNP/O Issues/NNPS/O
The/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O operates/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O electric/JJ/O power/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O corporation/NN/O wholly/RB/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG priced/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O note/NN/O offering/VBG/O to/TO/O yield/VB/O 9.39/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O revival/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O mortgage/NN/O investment/NN/O conduit/NN/O market/NN/O reflected/VBD/O the/DT/O relative/JJ/O calm/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O mortgage/NN/O market/NN/O after/IN/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O volatile/JJ/O trading/NN/O ././O
Dealers/NNS/O noted/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O structure/VB/O new/JJ/O Remics/NNS/O when/WRB/O prices/NNS/O are/VBP/O moving/VBG/O widely/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O Remics/NNS/O priced/VBN/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Loan/NNP/I-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG issue/NN/O underwritten/VBN/O by/IN/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O a/DT/O $/$/O 350/CD/O million/CD/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG deal/NN/O underwritten/VBN/O by/IN/O Greenwich/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Municipals/NNS/O
Prices/NNS/O of/IN/O pre-refunded/JJ/O municipal/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O were/VBD/O capped/VBN/O by/IN/O news/NN/O that/IN/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O agent/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O customer/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O accept/VB/O bids/NNS/O today/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O large/JJ/O lists/NNS/O of/IN/O bonds/NNS/O that/WDT/O include/VBP/O many/JJ/O such/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O lists/NNS/O total/VBP/O $/$/O 654.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Pre-refunded/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O are/VBP/O called/VBN/O at/IN/O their/PRP$/O earliest/JJS/O call/NN/O date/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O escrowed/VBN/O proceeds/NNS/O of/IN/O another/DT/O bond/NN/O issue/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O several/JJ/O new/JJ/O issues/NNS/O were/VBD/O priced/VBN/O ././O
Underwriters/NNS/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG set/VBD/O preliminary/JJ/O pricing/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 144.4/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O California/NNP/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG Financing/NNP/I-ORG Authority/NNP/I-ORG revenue/NN/O bonds/NNS/O for/IN/O Kaiser/NNP/B-ORG Permanente/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Tentative/JJ/O reoffering/NN/O yields/NNS/O were/VBD/O set/VBN/O from/IN/O 6.25/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1993/CD/O to/TO/O 7.227/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 2018/CD/O ././O
As/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O College/NNP/O Savings/NNP/O Plan/NNP/O ,/,/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE offered/VBD/O $/$/O 100.4/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O general/JJ/O obligation/NN/O capital/NN/O appreciation/NN/O bonds/NNS/O priced/VBN/O to/TO/O yield/VB/O to/TO/O maturity/NN/O from/IN/O 6.25/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1994/CD/O to/TO/O 6.90/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 2006/CD/O ,/,/O 2007/CD/O and/CC/O 2009/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG group/NN/O won/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O Oregon/NNP/B-GPE general/JJ/O obligation/NN/O veterans/NNS/O '/POS/O tax/NN/O note/NN/O issue/NN/O due/JJ/O Nov./NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Foreign/NNP/O Bonds/NNPS/O
West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE 7/CD/O %/NN/O bond/NN/O due/JJ/O October/NNP/O 1999/CD/O was/VBD/O at/IN/O 99.95/CD/O late/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O off/IN/O 0.10/CD/O point/NN/O from/IN/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O to/TO/O yield/VB/O 7.01/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
British/JJ/O government/NN/O bonds/NNS/O surged/VBD/O on/RP/O renewed/VBN/O volatility/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O ended/VBD/O weaker/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/O benchmark/NN/O No./NN/O 111/CD/O 4.6/CD/O %/NN/O bond/NN/O due/JJ/O 1998/CD/O ended/VBD/O on/IN/O brokers/NNS/O '/POS/O screens/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O 96/CD/O ,/,/O off/IN/O 0.15/CD/O point/NN/O to/TO/O yield/VB/O 5.27/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
