L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O in/IN/O principle/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG Jewelers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O management/NN/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O executives/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ././O
L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O filed/VBD/O for/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O bankruptcy/NN/O protection/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O working/VBG/O relationship/NN/O with/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Sam/NNP/B-PERSON Merksamer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nationwide/JJ/O jewelry/NN/O chain/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Sanford/NNP/B-PERSON Sigoloff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O both/DT/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
Currently/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Merksamer/NNP/B-PERSON owns/VBZ/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ;/:/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG acquired/VBD/O its/PRP$/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O 1986/CD/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG chain/NN/O had/VBD/O 11/CD/O stores/NNS/O in/IN/O operation/NN/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O 77/CD/O units/NNS/O ,/,/O all/DT/O located/VBN/O in/IN/O shopping/NN/O malls/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O retail/JJ/O leveraged/JJ/O buyouts/NNS/O have/VBP/O failed/VBN/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O jitters/NNS/O among/IN/O suppliers/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG apparently/RB/O wanted/VBD/O assurances/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O delivery/NN/O problems/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBD/O June/NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG Jewelers/NNPS/I-ORG had/VBD/O $/$/O 62/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O revenue/NN/O and/CC/O operating/VBG/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O jewelery/NN/O chain/NN/O was/VBD/O put/VBN/O up/IN/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O those/DT/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O ,/,/O other/JJ/O bidders/NNS/O included/VBD/O Ratners/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Kay/NNP/B-ORG Jewelers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O advising/VBG/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG business/NN/O ././O
Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O retail/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O was/VBD/O founded/VBN/O in/IN/O Sacramento/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O 1929/CD/O by/IN/O two/CD/O brothers/NNS/O ,/,/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Merksamer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O operated/VBD/O as/IN/O DeVon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Jewelers/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O pair/NN/O split/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O in/IN/O half/DT/O ,/,/O with/IN/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O son/NN/O ,/,/O Sam/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O agreeing/VBG/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG Jewelery/NNP/I-ORG name/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG Jewelers/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Tina/NNP/B-PERSON Brozman/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Bankruptcy/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O offer/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O include/VB/O the/DT/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG chain/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O reviewed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sigoloff/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
