Rep./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON Hamilton/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ind/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O Rep./NNP/O Byron/NNP/B-PERSON Dorgan/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.D/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O are/VBP/O backing/VBG/O away/RB/O from/IN/O their/PRP$/O proposal/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O a/DT/O voting/VBG/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG panel/NN/O that/WDT/O sets/VBZ/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Hamilton/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O modified/VBN/O substantially/RB/O to/TO/O call/VB/O for/IN/O two/CD/O meetings/NNS/O each/DT/O year/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O open/JJ/O market/NN/O committee/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Advisers/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O original/JJ/O bill/NN/O was/VBD/O strongly/RB/O opposed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O publicly/RB/O criticized/VBN/O by/IN/O friends/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O undermine/VB/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O independence/NN/O ././O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG critics/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O hailed/VBD/O it/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O overdue/JJ/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O a/DT/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O openness/NN/O and/CC/O democracy/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O setting/NN/O of/IN/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Hamilton/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O meetings/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O ``/``/O improve/VB/O communications/NNS/O and/CC/O perhaps/RB/O coordination/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O branch/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Greenspan/NNP/I-PERSON meets/VBZ/O regularly/RB/O for/IN/O lunch/NN/O with/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Brady/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O talks/VBZ/O frequently/RB/O with/IN/O Budget/NNP/B-ORG Director/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Darman/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Boskin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Advisers/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O ordinarily/RB/O meet/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O membership/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O open/JJ/O market/NN/O committee/NN/O ././O
