The/DT/O days/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O numbered/VBN/O for/IN/O animated/VBN/O shows/NNS/O featuring/VBG/O Alf/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-PERSON Karate/NNP/I-PERSON Kid/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O Chipmunks/NNPS/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O network/NN/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O ``/``/O counterprogram/VB/O ''/''/O with/IN/O shows/NNS/O for/IN/O an/DT/O audience/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O virtually/RB/O ignored/VBN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O period/NN/O :/:/O adults/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O talk/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O revamping/VBG/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O certainly/RB/O heading/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O direction/NN/O of/IN/O less/JJR/O and/CC/O less/JJR/O animation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Cicero/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O finance/NN/O and/CC/O administration/NN/O for/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Cicero/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG president/NN/O Brandon/NNP/B-PERSON Tartikoff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O interviewed/VBN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O options/NNS/O now/RB/O and/CC/O may/MD/O put/VB/O some/DT/O things/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O schedule/NN/O by/IN/O mid-season/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O elaborate/VB/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O feel/VBP/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O audience/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O being/VBG/O served/VBN/O by/IN/O any/DT/O network/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O we/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O lead/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O KCRA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Kueneke/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O need/VB/O cartoons/NNS/O anymore/RB/O ././O
They/PRP/O only/RB/O accounted/VBD/O for/IN/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O best/JJS/O ,/,/O of/IN/O the/DT/O station/NN/O 's/POS/O total/JJ/O revenues/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
An/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O network/NN/O will/MD/O ``/``/O closely/RB/O monitor/VB/O ''/''/O the/DT/O Sacramento/NNP/B-GPE situation/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O station/NN/O to/TO/O defect/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O youthful/JJ/O audience/NN/O for/IN/O Saturday/NNP/O programming/NN/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O longer/RB/O dependent/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O surge/NN/O in/IN/O syndicated/VBN/O children/NNS/O 's/POS/O shows/NNS/O to/TO/O independent/JJ/O stations/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O competition/NN/O from/IN/O videocassettes/NNS/O for/IN/O kids/NNS/O and/CC/O from/IN/O cable/NN/O outlets/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Nickelodeon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Disney/NNP/I-ORG Channel/NNP/I-ORG ././O
NBC/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O on/IN/O previous/JJ/O occasions/NNS/O considered/VBN/O replacing/VBG/O cartoons/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Saturday/NNP/O version/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Today/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ././O
NBC/NNP/B-ORG Productions/NNPS/I-ORG or/CC/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG could/MD/O supply/VB/O the/DT/O network/NN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O Saturday/NNP/O morning/NN/O shows/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O move/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O control/VB/O costs/NNS/O ././O
Animated/JJ/O shows/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O outside/JJ/O production/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O cost/VBD/O the/DT/O network/NN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 300,000/CD/O per/IN/O episode/NN/O ././O
