Rockwell/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Tulsa/NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O signed/VBD/O a/DT/O tentative/JJ/O agreement/NN/O extending/VBG/O its/PRP$/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O provide/VB/O structural/JJ/O parts/NNS/O for/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 747/CD/O jetliners/NNS/O ././O
These/DT/O include/VBP/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O each/DT/O jetliner/NN/O 's/POS/O two/CD/O major/JJ/O bulkheads/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O pressure/NN/O floor/NN/O ,/,/O torque/NN/O box/NN/O ,/,/O fixed/VBN/O leading/VBG/O edges/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O wings/NNS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O aft/JJ/O keel/NN/O beam/NN/O ././O
Rockwell/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O El/NNP/B-GPE Segundo/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O aerospace/NN/O ,/,/O electronics/NNS/O ,/,/O automotive/JJ/O and/CC/O graphics/NNS/O concern/NN/O ././O
