Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Minneapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O signed/VBD/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O development/NN/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O MIPS/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O incorporate/VB/O an/DT/O emerging/VBG/O computing/VBG/O architecture/NN/O in/IN/O future/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O joining/VBG/O MIPS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG follows/VBZ/O several/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O in/IN/O embracing/VBG/O RISC/NNP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O design/NN/O approach/NN/O ././O
Digital/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Tandem/NNP/B-ORG Computers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Group/NNP/B-ORG Bull/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O among/IN/O others/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O similar/JJ/O arrangements/NNS/O with/IN/O MIPs/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O accord/NN/O with/IN/O MIPS/NNP/B-ORG calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O share/VB/O its/PRP$/O expertise/NN/O in/IN/O data/NNS/O storage/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
