US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Percival/NNP/I-PERSON agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O step/VB/O down/IN/O as/IN/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O difference/NN/O of/IN/O opinion/NN/O as/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O future/JJ/O direction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Percival/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O ,/,/O US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Percival/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O employment/NN/O contract/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O act/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O company/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O also/RB/O remain/VB/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ,/,/O US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O serve/VB/O on/IN/O any/DT/O board/NN/O committees/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Percival/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O be/VB/O succeeded/VBN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O interim/JJ/O basis/NN/O by/IN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Kadonada/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O president/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O statement/NN/O ,/,/O US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O bought/VBN/O back/RB/O 112,000/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O transaction/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
