US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Percival/NNP/I-PERSON agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O step/VB/O down/IN/O as/IN/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Percival/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O also/RB/O remain/VB/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ,/,/O US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O serve/VB/O on/IN/O any/DT/O board/NN/O committees/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Percival/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O be/VB/O succeeded/VBN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O interim/JJ/O basis/NN/O by/IN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Kadonada/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O US/NNP/B-ORG Facilities/NNPS/I-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O president/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
