The/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O would/MD/O fall/VB/O ././O
Millions/NNS/O of/IN/O refugees/NNS/O would/MD/O rush/VB/O home/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O resistance/NN/O government/NN/O would/MD/O walk/VB/O into/IN/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Those/DT/O who/WP/O bought/VBD/O that/DT/O illusion/NN/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O bewildered/VBN/O ././O
Soviet/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O support/VB/O their/PRP$/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE clients/NNS/O by/IN/O all/DT/O means/NNS/O necessary/JJ/O --/:/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O fully/RB/O support/VB/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Geneva/NNP/O accords/NNS/O leave/VBP/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE free/JJ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O its/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O in/IN/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O assistance/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O kind/NN/O --/:/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O return/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O ground/NN/O forces/NNS/O --/:/O while/IN/O requiring/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Pakistan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O cut/VB/O off/IN/O aid/NN/O ././O
Gen./NNP/O Gromov/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O said/VBD/O Soviet/JJ/O troops/NNS/O expected/VBD/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O behind/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O military/JJ/O equipment/NN/O and/CC/O installations/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O ././O
Moscow/NNP/B-GPE claims/VBZ/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O all/DT/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O guerrilla/NN/O resistance/NN/O ././O
Complete/JJ/O units/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O trained/VBN/O and/CC/O indoctrinated/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S.S.R./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O other/JJ/O East/NNP/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC nations/NNS/O ;/:/O 30,000/CD/O to/TO/O 40,000/CD/O of/IN/O these/DT/O troops/NNS/O have/VBP/O returned/VBN/O ././O
Cuban/JJ/O military/JJ/O personnel/NNS/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O active/JJ/O in/IN/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE since/IN/O 1979/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O cut/VBD/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O with/IN/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE :/:/O a/DT/O future/JJ/O Iranian/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O Iranian/JJ/O support/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O deal/NN/O was/VBD/O symbolized/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O restoration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Shi'ite/NNP/O Sultan/NNP/O Ali/NNP/B-PERSON Keshtmand/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O the/DT/O Afghan/JJ/O prime/JJ/O ministry/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O heavy/JJ/O outside/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O has/VBZ/O undermined/VBN/O better/JJR/O ,/,/O moderate/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O deal/NN/O fell/VBD/O through/IN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Kandahar/NNP/B-GPE remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O regime/NN/O base/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O resistance/NN/O lacks/VBZ/O not/RB/O only/JJ/O air/NN/O power/NN/O ,/,/O armor/NN/O and/CC/O expertise/NN/O but/CC/O often/RB/O such/JJ/O essentials/NNS/O as/IN/O maps/NNS/O ,/,/O mine/NN/O detectors/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O even/RB/O winter/NN/O gloves/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O took/VBD/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O casualties/NNS/O ;/:/O journalists/NNS/O report/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O faced/VBD/O minefields/NNS/O without/IN/O mine/NN/O detectors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O wonder/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O has/VBZ/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O topple/VB/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O exist/VB/O and/CC/O fight/VB/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
Last/JJ/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O congressional/JJ/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O resumed/VBN/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O months/NNS/O after/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O cut/VBN/O off/IN/O ;/:/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O clear/JJ/O how/WRB/O much/RB/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O sent/VBN/O or/CC/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O arrive/VB/O ././O
Moscow/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE must/MD/O have/VB/O found/VBN/O that/DT/O information/NN/O useful/JJ/O ././O
No/DT/O settlement/NN/O negotiated/VBN/O by/IN/O others/NNS/O can/MD/O force/VB/O the/DT/O Afghan/NNP/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O give/VB/O up/IN/O their/PRP$/O struggle/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O cutoff/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O aid/NN/O would/MD/O merely/RB/O abandon/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O die/VB/O in/IN/O vain/JJ/O ././O
Creation/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O ,/,/O realistic/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE policy/NN/O is/VBZ/O long/RB/O overdue/JJ/O ././O
