HOPES/NNS/O OF/IN/O SIMPLIFYING/VBG/O the/DT/O corporate/JJ/O minimum/JJ/O tax/NN/O before/IN/O 1990/CD/O are/VBP/O weakening/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O method/NN/O of/IN/O calculating/VBG/O the/DT/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O tax/NN/O ,/,/O paid/VBN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O exceeds/VBZ/O tax/NN/O figured/VBN/O the/DT/O regular/JJ/O way/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O due/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O change/NN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O thanks/NNS/O to/TO/O 1986/CD/O 's/POS/O tax/NN/O act/NN/O ././O
Ways/NNS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Means/NNS/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Rostenkowski/NNP/B-PERSON backed/VBD/O a/DT/O simplification/NN/O plan/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pending/VBG/O House/NN/B-ORG tax/NN/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O turns/VBZ/O out/IN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O revenue/NN/O loser/NN/O ././O
Proponents/NNS/O of/IN/O simplification/NN/O fear/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O chances/NNS/O of/IN/O getting/VBG/O it/PRP/O into/IN/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O bill/NN/O are/VBP/O waning/VBG/O ././O
HUGO/NNP/O 'S/POS/O RAVAGES/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O offset/VBN/O by/IN/O immediate/JJ/O claims/NNS/O for/IN/O tax/NN/O refunds/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O lets/VBZ/O victims/NNS/O elect/VB/O to/TO/O deduct/VB/O casualty/NN/O losses/NNS/O on/IN/O either/DT/O 1989/CD/O or/CC/O amended/VBD/O 1988/CD/O returns/NNS/O ,/,/O whichever/WDT/O offers/VBZ/O the/DT/O larger/JJR/O tax/NN/O benefit/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O until/IN/O April/NNP/O 16/CD/O to/TO/O choose/VB/O ././O
A/DT/O loss/NN/O --/:/O after/IN/O insurance/NN/O recoveries/NNS/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O deductible/JJ/O only/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O extent/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O exceeds/VBZ/O $/$/O 100/CD/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O total/JJ/O losses/NNS/O exceed/VBP/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O adjusted/VBN/O gross/JJ/O income/NN/O ;/:/O victims/NNS/O may/MD/O pick/VB/O the/DT/O year/NN/O when/WRB/O income/NN/O is/VBZ/O lower/JJR/O and/CC/O deductions/NNS/O higher/JJR/O ././O
THE/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG DELAYS/VBZ/O several/JJ/O deadlines/NNS/O for/IN/O Hugo/NNP/O 's/POS/O victims/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG denied/VBD/O cost/NN/O deductions/NNS/O because/IN/O few/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O temps/NNS/O got/VBD/O to/TO/O go/VB/O aboard/IN/O ././O
BIGGER/JJR/O THAN/IN/O A/DT/O BREADBOX/NN/O was/VBD/O this/DT/O cash/NN/O hoarder/NN/O 's/POS/O reputation/NN/O for/IN/O honesty/NN/O ././O
People/NNS/O often/RB/O cite/VBP/O frugality/NN/O and/CC/O distrust/NN/O of/IN/O banks/NNS/O to/TO/O justify/VB/O cash/NN/O caches/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Gregory/NNP/B-PERSON Damonne/NNP/I-PERSON Brown/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Fremont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O hardworking/JJ/O ,/,/O reclusive/JJ/O young/JJ/O bachelor/NN/O ,/,/O told/VBD/O that/DT/O story/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Tax/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Brown/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O no/DT/O proof/NN/O ;/:/O but/CC/O testimony/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O mother/NN/O and/CC/O stepmother/NN/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O father/NN/O and/CC/O of/IN/O an/DT/O ex-employer/NN/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O honesty/NN/O and/CC/O habits/NNS/O satisfied/VBD/O a/DT/O judge/NN/O that/IN/O Brown/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O truthful/JJ/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O tale/NN/O of/IN/O gifts/NNS/O was/VBD/O possible/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG offered/VBD/O no/DT/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O hidden/VBN/O sources/NNS/O of/IN/O taxable/JJ/O income/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Shields/NNP/B-PERSON rejected/VBD/O its/PRP$/O claims/NNS/O ././O
