Is/VBZ/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O view/NN/O justified/VBN/O ?/./O
In/IN/O the/DT/O absence/NN/O of/IN/O humans/NNS/O ,/,/O would/MD/O the/DT/O Earth/NN/B-LOC enjoy/VB/O a/DT/O constant/JJ/O climate/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O term/NN/O ?/./O
Clearly/RB/O not/RB/O ././O
About/IN/O 20,000/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O ice/NN/O age/NN/O ended/VBD/O ././O
Enormous/JJ/O ice/NN/O sheets/NNS/O retreated/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O face/NN/O of/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O northern/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Furthermore/RB/O ,/,/O no/DT/O bell/NN/O has/VBZ/O yet/RB/O rung/VBN/O to/TO/O announce/VB/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O immense/JJ/O episode/NN/O of/IN/O natural/JJ/O global/JJ/O warming/NN/O ././O
Jocelyn/NNP/B-PERSON Tomkin/NNP/I-PERSON Astronomy/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG
