SHEARSON/NNP/B-ORG LEHMAN/NNP/I-ORG HUTTON/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG
Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Meador/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 42/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Balcor/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Skokie/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ill./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE investment/NN/O banking/NN/O firm/NN/O ././O
Balcor/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O interests/NNS/O in/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O position/NN/O is/VBZ/O newly/RB/O created/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Meador/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Balcor/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Those/DT/O duties/NNS/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O Van/NNP/B-PERSON Pell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 44/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O an/DT/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
