And/CC/O ,/,/O surprisingly/RB/O ,/,/O little/RB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O whimper/NN/O of/IN/O protest/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O heard/VBN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O Reaganauts/NNS/O once/RB/O breathed/VBD/O fire/NN/O supporting/VBG/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Strategic/NNP/O Defense/NNP/O Initiative/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O programs/NNS/O have/VBP/O arthritis/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Rep./NNP/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Hyde/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O conservative/JJ/O Republican/NNP/O from/IN/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Yet/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O asserts/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O you/PRP/O look/VBP/O around/RB/O .../:/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O `/``/O Who/WP/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O leaders/NNS/O ?/./O
Who/WP/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O carry/VB/O the/DT/O water/NN/O ?/./O '/''/O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O surprising/JJ/O that/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O led/VBN/O a/DT/O crusade/NN/O to/TO/O pump/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/O or/CC/O SDI/NNP/O ././O
Though/IN/O he/PRP/O nominally/RB/O supports/VBZ/O both/DT/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O passionate/JJ/O champion/NN/O of/IN/O either/DT/O cause/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O combination/NN/O of/IN/O factors/NNS/O --/:/O a/DT/O weariness/NN/O among/IN/O some/DT/O conservatives/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O decline/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O perception/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O threat/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O preoccupation/NN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O issues/NNS/O --/:/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O explain/VB/O the/DT/O strange/JJ/O tranquility/NN/O ././O
Above/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O conservative/JJ/O Republicans/NNPS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O championed/VBN/O both/PDT/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/O and/CC/O SDI/NNP/O are/VBP/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O attack/VB/O a/DT/O Republican/JJ/O president/NN/O for/IN/O failing/VBG/O to/TO/O do/VB/O more/RBR/O --/:/O though/IN/O that/DT/O reluctance/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O receding/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O complain/VB/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O say/VB/O something/NN/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O worse/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Rep./NNP/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Burton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O Indiana/NNP/B-GPE Republican/NNP/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O staunch/JJ/O Contra/NNP/O backer/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O like/IN/O kicking/VBG/O your/PRP$/O father/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pants/NNS/O ././O
You/PRP/O hate/VBP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O your/PRP$/O father/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Burton/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O conservatives/NNS/O '/POS/O unhappiness/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O cautious/JJ/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O unsuccessful/JJ/O coup/NN/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O make/VB/O them/PRP/O more/RBR/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O speak/VB/O out/IN/O ././O
Of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O neither/DT/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON nor/CC/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O actually/RB/O abandoned/VBN/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/O or/CC/O SDI/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O struck/VBN/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O with/IN/O congressional/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O nonlethal/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/O until/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE holds/VBZ/O national/JJ/O elections/NNS/O next/IN/O February/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O has/VBZ/O dropped/VBN/O any/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O deal/NN/O with/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG gives/VBZ/O several/JJ/O congressional/JJ/O committees/NNS/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O off/RP/O even/RB/O humanitarian/JJ/O aid/NN/O next/IN/O month/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O the/DT/O committees/NNS/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O let/VB/O aid/NN/O continue/VB/O until/IN/O February/NNP/O ././O
Most/JJS/O analysts/NNS/O think/VBP/O there/EX/O 's/POS/O little/JJ/O prospect/NN/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O fighting/NN/O force/NN/O without/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE arms/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O after/IN/O the/DT/O February/NNP/O election/NN/O their/PRP$/O future/NN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O form/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O murky/JJ/O at/IN/O best/RB/O ././O
Instead/RB/O of/IN/O focusing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Contras/NNPS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O switched/VBN/O to/TO/O urging/VBG/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG --/:/O most/RBS/O recently/RB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG meeting/NN/O yesterday/NN/O --/:/O to/TO/O approve/VB/O financing/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O election/NN/O campaign/NN/O of/IN/O political/JJ/O opponents/NNS/O of/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Sandinista/NNP/O government/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O support/VB/O SDI/NNP/O ,/,/O or/CC/O Star/NNP/O Wars/NNPS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O recently/RB/O lobbied/VBD/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O restore/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O it/PRP/O planned/VBD/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O just/RB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Dick/NNP/B-PERSON Cheney/NNP/I-PERSON gave/VBD/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O speech/NN/O listing/VBG/O ``/``/O compelling/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O push/VB/O ahead/RB/O with/IN/O SDI/NNP/O and/CC/O saying/VBG/O he/PRP/O 'd/MD/O urge/VB/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O veto/VB/O a/DT/O defense/NN/O bill/NN/O with/IN/O ``/``/O inadequate/JJ/O ''/''/O funding/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O strong/JJ/O pitch/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Cheney/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O be/VB/O too/RB/O little/RB/O too/RB/O late/JJ/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O SDI/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O already/RB/O voted/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O deep/JJ/O cut/NN/O in/IN/O funding/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O 's/POS/O backers/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O hard/RB/O pressed/VBN/O to/TO/O head/VB/O off/RP/O some/DT/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O spending/VBG/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O also/RB/O acknowledges/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O pursuing/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O original/JJ/O vision/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O ``/``/O impenetrable/JJ/O shield/NN/O ''/''/O protecting/VBG/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O rather/RB/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O modest/JJ/O version/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O hard/JJ/O down/IN/O the/DT/O road/NN/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O approve/VB/O money/NN/O for/IN/O SDI/NNP/O plans/NNS/O if/IN/O lawmakers/NNS/O fear/VBP/O those/DT/O plans/NNS/O could/MD/O scuttle/VB/O a/DT/O completed/VBN/O treaty/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Gaffney/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG aide/NN/O who/WP/O now/RB/O heads/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Policy/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O charges/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O professions/NNS/O of/IN/O continued/VBN/O commitment/NN/O to/TO/O development/NN/O and/CC/O deployment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O SDI/NNP/O program/NN/O strain/VBP/O credulity/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O proponents/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O shying/VBG/O away/RB/O from/IN/O more/JJR/O drumbeating/NN/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O sense/VBP/O political/JJ/O tides/NNS/O have/VBP/O turned/VBN/O against/IN/O arming/NN/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O rebels/NNS/O or/CC/O boosting/VBG/O spending/NN/O on/IN/O SDI/NNP/O --/:/O particularly/RB/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O public/NN/O perceives/VBZ/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O threat/NN/O is/VBZ/O declining/VBG/O under/IN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O communism/NN/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O beating/VBG/O a/DT/O global/JJ/O retreat/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O conservatives/NNS/O may/MD/O simply/RB/O be/VB/O so/RB/O pleased/VBN/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O anti-communist/JJ/O philosophy/NN/O is/VBZ/O prevailing/VBG/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O fire/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O moment/NN/O to/TO/O push/VB/O controversial/JJ/O programs/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O activists/NNS/O are/VBP/O toiling/VBG/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O the/DT/O profile/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O causes/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O much/JJ/O headway/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O willing/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O the/DT/O tide/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O longtime/NN/O champion/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O programs/NNS/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Republican/NNP/O whip/NN/O Newt/NNP/B-PERSON Gingrich/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O distracted/VBN/O by/IN/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O ethics/NNS/O ,/,/O conservatives/NNS/O note/VBP/O ././O
Other/JJ/O conservative/JJ/O champions/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Wyoming/NNP/B-GPE Republican/NNP/O Sen./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON Wallop/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O longtime/NN/O SDI/NNP/O advocate/NN/O ,/,/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O clout/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG that/IN/O they/PRP/O enjoyed/VBD/O with/IN/O President/NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Above/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O proponents/NNS/O say/VBP/O neither/CC/O the/DT/O Contra/NNP/O nor/CC/O the/DT/O SDI/NNP/O cause/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O pushed/VBN/O much/RB/O further/RB/O without/IN/O more/JJR/O presidential/JJ/O support/NN/O ././O
``/``/O For/IN/O there/EX/O to/TO/O be/VB/O wind/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sails/NNS/O of/IN/O any/DT/O program/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O blowing/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sails/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Rep./NNP/O Burton/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
All/PDT/O this/DT/O causes/VBZ/O Rep./NNP/O Hyde/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O muse/VB/O about/IN/O an/DT/O alternate/JJ/O way/NN/O to/TO/O drum/VB/O up/RP/O more/JJR/O enthusiasm/NN/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O ,/,/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O up/IN/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O for/IN/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O take/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O hustings/NN/O to/TO/O regenerate/VB/O enthusiasm/NN/O for/IN/O SDI/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O congressman/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
