The/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O also/RB/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O any/DT/O future/JJ/O property/NN/O rights/NNS/O issues/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O through/IN/O binding/VBG/O arbitration/NN/O ,/,/O both/DT/O companies/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Linear/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Milpitas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O ``/``/O positive/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O since/IN/O products/NNS/O covered/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O disputed/VBN/O patents/NNS/O account/VBP/O for/IN/O about/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O electronics/NNS/O concern/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O already/RB/O has/VBZ/O paid/VBN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O to/TO/O National/NNP/B-ORG Semiconductor/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Clara/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O will/MD/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O equal/JJ/O installments/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O eight/CD/O quarters/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O payments/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O an/DT/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O coming/VBG/O operating/VBG/O results/NNS/O ,/,/O Linear/NNP/B-ORG added/VBD/O ././O
