Unilab/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Norcross/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ga./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O acquired/VBD/O the/DT/O clinical/JJ/O laboratories/NNS/O of/IN/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O Central/NNP/B-ORG Diagnostic/NNP/I-ORG Laboratory/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O cash/NN/O and/CC/O securities/NNS/O transaction/NN/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 85/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Unilab/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O wholly/RB/O owned/VBN/O MetWest/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O paid/VBD/O $/$/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O cash/NN/O ,/,/O provided/VBN/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O notes/NNS/O and/CC/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O preferred/VBN/O stock/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Central/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O labs/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Western/NNP/I-LOC U.S./NNP/I-LOC ././O
Unilab/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O provides/VBZ/O clinical/JJ/O laboratory/NN/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O competed/VBD/O with/IN/O Central/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Tarzana/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O areas/NNS/O ././O
Beyond/IN/O removing/VBG/O a/DT/O competitor/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O combination/NN/O should/MD/O provide/VB/O ``/``/O synergies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Fred/NNP/B-PERSON Harlow/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Unilab/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/NN/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O will/MD/O hand/VB/O Unilab/NNP/B-ORG new/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Central/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O had/VBN/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O market/NN/O position/NN/O while/IN/O Unilab/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O presence/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O less/RBR/O prominent/JJ/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Harlow/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
