The/DT/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Globe/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O newly/RB/O redesigned/VBN/O pages/NNS/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O ``/``/O crisper/NN/O ''/''/O look/NN/O with/IN/O revamped/VBN/O fixtures/NNS/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O paper/NN/O ``/``/O more/RBR/O consistent/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O easier/JJR/O to/TO/O read/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Maybe/RB/O so/RB/O --/:/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O find/VB/O where/WRB/O your/PRP$/O favorite/JJ/O writer/NN/O went/VBD/O ././O
Beantown/NNP/B-GPE scribes/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O spare/VBP/O no/DT/O invective/NN/O when/WRB/O taking/VBG/O on/RP/O local/JJ/O luminaries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Pee/NNP/I-PERSON Wee/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Dukakis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O or/CC/O New/NNP/B-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG Patriots/NNPS/I-ORG Coach/NNP/O Raymond/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Rev./NNP/I-PERSON Ray/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Berry/NN/I-PERSON ,/,/O yesterday/NN/O poured/VBD/O ridicule/NN/O on/IN/O new/JJ/O drawings/NNS/O of/IN/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG columnists/NNS/O that/WDT/O replaced/VBD/O old/JJ/O photos/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O revamped/VBN/O pages/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O late/JJ/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O ,/,/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG Managing/NNP/O Editor/NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Mulvoy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O bending/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O will/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O troops/NNS/O ,/,/O scrapped/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O drawings/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O no/DT/O pictures/NNS/O or/CC/O drawings/NNS/O of/IN/O any/DT/O kind/NN/O will/MD/O adorn/VB/O the/DT/O columns/NNS/O ././O
Trouble/NN/O was/VBD/O ,/,/O nobody/NN/O thought/VBD/O they/PRP/O looked/VBD/O right/RB/O ././O
Globe/NNP/B-ORG columnist/NN/O Mike/NNP/B-PERSON Barnicle/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O in/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O attack/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O employer/NN/O in/IN/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O --/:/O averred/VBD/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O shadowy/JJ/O countenance/NN/O was/VBD/O so/RB/O bad/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O looked/VBD/O ``/``/O like/IN/O a/DT/O face/NN/O you/PRP/O 'd/MD/O find/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O bottle/NN/O of/IN/O miracle/NN/O elixir/NN/O that/WDT/O promises/VBZ/O to/TO/O do/VB/O away/RB/O with/IN/O diarrhea/NN/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O lifetime/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Barnicle/NNP/B-PERSON reminded/VBD/O readers/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O forgiven/VBN/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O for/IN/O questioning/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 20/CD/O expense/NN/O chit/NN/O he/PRP/O submitted/VBD/O for/IN/O parking/VBG/O his/PRP$/O car/NN/O while/IN/O chasing/VBG/O a/DT/O story/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O thought/VBD/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O drawing/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O a/DT/O cross/NN/O between/IN/O someone/NN/O you/PRP/O 'd/MD/O spot/VB/O whipping/VBG/O open/JJ/O his/PRP$/O trench/NN/O coat/NN/O .../:/O or/CC/O a/DT/O guy/NN/O who/WP/O boasted/VBD/O he/PRP/O 'd/VBD/O been/VBN/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Manson/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON roommate/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O 19/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Barnicle/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O hardly/RB/O kinder/JJR/O to/TO/O the/DT/O renderings/NNS/O of/IN/O colleagues/NNS/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Madden/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O appears/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O pervert/NN/O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O Will/NNP/B-PERSON McDonough/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O looks/VBZ/O as/IN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O drove/VBD/O for/IN/O Abe/NNP/B-PERSON Lincoln/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O or/CC/O Bella/NNP/B-PERSON English/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O ``/``/O little/JJ/O girl/NN/O now/RB/O screams/VBZ/O hysterically/RB/O every/DT/O time/NN/O she/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O a/DT/O newspaper/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Lynn/NNP/B-PERSON Staley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O assistant/NN/O managing/VBG/O editor/NN/O for/IN/O design/NN/O ,/,/O acknowledges/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O visages/NNS/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O on/IN/O the/DT/O low/JJ/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O likeness/NN/O spectrum/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Rival/NNP/O Boston/NNP/B-ORG Herald/NNP/I-ORG columnist/NN/O Howie/NNP/B-PERSON Carr/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O usually/RB/O rails/VBZ/O at/IN/O Statehouse/NN/B-ORG ``/``/O hacks/NNS/O ''/''/O and/CC/O nepotism/NN/O ,/,/O argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O drawings/NNS/O were/VBD/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O hide/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Madden/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O rapidly/RB/O growing/VBG/O forehead/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O the/DT/O facial/JJ/O defects/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O chinless/JJ/O ''/''/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Shaughnessy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG sports/NNS/O columnist/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O think/VB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O you/PRP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O reader/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O save/VB/O on/IN/O Halloween/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Barnicle/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O Instead/RB/O of/IN/O buying/VBG/O masks/NNS/O for/IN/O your/PRP$/O kids/NNS/O ,/,/O just/RB/O cut/VB/O out/RP/O the/DT/O columnists/NNS/O '/POS/O pictures/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
