Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON McKinney/NNP/I-PERSON plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O retire/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O president/NN/O effective/JJ/O Jan./NNP/O 12/CD/O ././O
Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG said/VBD/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O contemplated/VBN/O ''/''/O that/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON McCoy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O assume/VB/O the/DT/O additional/JJ/O position/NN/O of/IN/O president/NN/O upon/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McKinney/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O retirement/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O McKinney/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 50/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Fletcher/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Indianapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O when/WRB/O that/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O merged/VBD/O into/IN/O Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG in/IN/O January/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG board/NN/O ././O
