Early/RB/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O investors/NNS/O scrambled/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O for/IN/O safety/NN/O as/IN/O stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O plummeted/VBD/O and/CC/O fears/NNS/O mounted/VBD/O of/IN/O a/DT/O replay/NN/O of/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O stocks/NNS/O later/RB/O recovered/VBD/O ,/,/O erasing/VBG/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O early/JJ/O declines/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O cut/VBD/O short/RB/O the/DT/O rally/NN/O in/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O and/CC/O depressed/VBN/O prices/NNS/O moderately/RB/O below/IN/O late/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O 's/POS/O levels/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Industrial/NNP/O Average/NNP/O ,/,/O down/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 60.25/CD/O points/NNS/O early/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O finished/VBD/O 18.65/CD/O points/NNS/O lower/JJR/O at/IN/O 2638.73/CD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O clearly/RB/O is/VBZ/O leading/VBG/O the/DT/O bond/NN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Conlon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O at/IN/O Nikko/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O are/VBP/O breathing/VBG/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O sigh/NN/O of/IN/O relief/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O end/VB/O Monday/NNP/O morning/NN/O ''/''/O or/CC/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Gold/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O closely/RB/O watched/VBN/O barometer/NN/O of/IN/O investor/NN/O anxiety/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O little/RB/O changed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O initially/RB/O fell/VBD/O against/IN/O other/JJ/O major/JJ/O currencies/NNS/O on/IN/O news/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O surged/VBD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O to/TO/O $/$/O 10.77/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O later/RB/O rebounded/VBD/O ,/,/O finishing/VBG/O slightly/RB/O higher/JJR/O against/IN/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O although/IN/O slightly/RB/O lower/JJR/O against/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O ././O
Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O sent/VBD/O another/DT/O signal/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O determination/NN/O to/TO/O shore/VB/O up/RP/O investor/NN/O confidence/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG move/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O gesture/NN/O ,/,/O traders/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O appear/VBP/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O their/PRP$/O credit/NN/O grip/NN/O any/RB/O further/RB/O because/IN/O a/DT/O bold/JJ/O move/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O appear/VB/O necessary/JJ/O ,/,/O several/JJ/O investment/NN/O managers/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Although/IN/O stocks/NNS/O have/VBP/O led/VBN/O bonds/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O traders/NNS/O predict/VBP/O that/IN/O relationship/NN/O will/MD/O reverse/VB/O during/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
Nikko/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Conlon/NNP/B-PERSON fears/VBZ/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O wave/NN/O of/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG borrowing/VBG/O early/JJ/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O will/MD/O drive/VB/O down/RB/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bond/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O major/JJ/O market/NN/O activity/NN/O :/:/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bond/NN/O prices/NNS/O fell/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O was/VBD/O mixed/VBN/O ././O
Late/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O rose/VBD/O to/TO/O 142.75/CD/O yen/NN/O from/IN/O 141.80/CD/O yen/NN/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O fell/VBD/O to/TO/O 1.8667/CD/O marks/NNS/O from/IN/O 1.8685/CD/O marks/NNS/O ././O
