According/VBG/O to/TO/O one/CD/O person/NN/O present/JJ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O ,/,/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O new/JJ/O plan/NN/O is/VBZ/O financially/RB/O ``/``/O overly/RB/O optimistic/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Asked/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O consultants/NNS/O '/POS/O reports/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O totally/RB/O disagree/VBP/O ././O ''/''/O
At/IN/O a/DT/O later/JJ/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lorenzo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O exceeding/VBG/O its/PRP$/O goals/NNS/O for/IN/O getting/VBG/O back/NN/O into/IN/O operation/NN/O and/CC/O predicted/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O emerge/VB/O from/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O early/RB/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O operating/VBG/O with/IN/O more/JJR/O service/NN/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O originally/RB/O had/VBD/O scheduled/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O insisted/VBD/O ,/,/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O before/IN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O creditors/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O paid/VBN/O in/IN/O full/JJ/O under/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lorenzo/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O no/DT/O mention/NN/O of/IN/O creditors/NNS/O '/POS/O negative/JJ/O response/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O plan/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O discussing/VBG/O an/DT/O amended/VBN/O plan/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O creditors/NNS/O and/CC/O anticipate/VBP/O filing/VBG/O that/IN/O amended/VBN/O plan/NN/O shortly/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Lorenzo/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O meeting/VBG/O and/CC/O surpassing/VBG/O our/PRP$/O goals/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O after/IN/O selling/VBG/O off/RP/O pieces/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O its/PRP$/O East/NNP/B-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC shuttle/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE hub/NN/O and/CC/O various/JJ/O planes/NNS/O ,/,/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG hit/VBD/O a/DT/O stumbling/VBG/O block/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O South/NNP/O American/NNP/O routes/NNS/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O assets/NNS/O marked/VBN/O for/IN/O disposal/NN/O ././O
Those/DT/O routes/NNS/O ,/,/O valued/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O creditors/NNS/O '/POS/O professionals/NNS/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Eastern/NNP/B-ORG ultimately/RB/O decided/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O and/CC/O operate/VB/O the/DT/O routes/NNS/O itself/PRP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O leave/VB/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O less/JJR/O cash/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O reorganization/NN/O ././O
Those/DT/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O condition/NN/O meant/VBD/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O previously/RB/O presented/VBN/O to/TO/O creditors/NNS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O revamped/VBN/O ././O
Since/IN/O then/RB/O ,/,/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O negotiating/VBG/O with/IN/O creditors/NNS/O over/IN/O revisions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O creditors/NNS/O committee/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O having/VBG/O problems/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O revisions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O committee/NN/O has/VBZ/O two/CD/O groups/NNS/O of/IN/O experts/NNS/O it/PRP/O calls/VBZ/O on/IN/O to/TO/O analyze/VB/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O plans/NNS/O ././O
Both/DT/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O plan/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O work/VB/O ././O
Experts/NNS/O from/IN/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG estimated/VBD/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O miss/VB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O mark/NN/O by/IN/O $/$/O 120/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 135/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O source/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O experts/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expected/VBD/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O issue/VB/O new/JJ/O debt/NN/O to/TO/O cover/VB/O its/PRP$/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O generate/VB/O far/RB/O less/JJR/O cash/NN/O than/IN/O anticipated/VBN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O costs/NNS/O also/RB/O would/MD/O increase/VB/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O maintenance/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O an/DT/O older/JJR/O fleet/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lorenzo/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG President/NNP/O Phil/NNP/B-PERSON Bakes/NNP/I-PERSON presented/VBD/O a/DT/O far/JJ/O rosier/JJR/O assessment/NN/O ././O
Flanked/VBN/O by/IN/O flight/NN/O attendants/NNS/O ,/,/O pilots/NNS/O and/CC/O gate/NN/O agents/NNS/O dressed/VBN/O in/IN/O spiffy/JJ/O new/JJ/O blue/JJ/O uniforms/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O exceeded/VBN/O its/PRP$/O operational/JJ/O goals/NNS/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O filling/VBG/O its/PRP$/O seats/NNS/O ././O
Starting/VBG/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O begin/VB/O flying/VBG/O 775/CD/O flights/NNS/O daily/RB/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O 700/CD/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bakes/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O give/VB/O out/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O daily/JJ/O losses/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O dip/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O cash/NN/O from/IN/O asset/NN/O sales/NNS/O currently/RB/O held/VBN/O in/IN/O escrow/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O accounts/NNS/O hold/VBP/O several/JJ/O hundred/CD/O million/CD/O dollars/NNS/O ,/,/O primarily/RB/O from/IN/O asset/NN/O sales/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O plan/NN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O calls/NNS/O for/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O have/VB/O $/$/O 390/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O cash/NN/O by/IN/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O end/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Lorenzo/NNP/B-PERSON predicted/VBD/O that/DT/O plan/NN/O might/MD/O be/VB/O confirmed/VBN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
As/IN/O to/TO/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O creditors/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lorenzo/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O remarks/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O how/WRB/O they/PRP/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O talks/NNS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O come/VBP/O along/RP/O ././O ''/''/O
However/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O requirement/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O be/VB/O accepted/VBN/O by/IN/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O must/MD/O be/VB/O accepted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Under/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O law/NN/O ,/,/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O exclusive/JJ/O rights/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O certain/JJ/O period/NN/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O deadline/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O extended/VBN/O once/RB/O and/CC/O could/MD/O be/VB/O extended/VBN/O again/RB/O ././O
If/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O get/VB/O creditor/NN/O support/NN/O ,/,/O court/NN/O confirmation/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O plan/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O relatively/RB/O swift/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O creditors/NNS/O are/VBP/O free/JJ/O to/TO/O press/VB/O for/IN/O court/NN/O approval/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O the/DT/O court/NN/O could/MD/O ignore/VB/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O and/CC/O draw/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O any/DT/O event/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O people/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O question/NN/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O will/MD/O act/VB/O by/IN/O January/NNP/O as/IN/O forecast/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lorenzo/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Bakes/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lorenzo/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O pursuing/VBG/O would/MD/O create/VB/O a/DT/O carrier/NN/O 85/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 90/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pre-bankruptcy/NN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O projected/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O operating/VBG/O about/IN/O 1,000/CD/O flights/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O by/IN/O late/JJ/O spring/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O slightly/RB/O fewer/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O 's/POS/O old/JJ/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O 1,050/CD/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
