Bearings/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Cunin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O will/MD/O retire/VB/O as/IN/O an/DT/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O on/IN/O Jan./NNP/O 2/CD/O ././O
George/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON LaMore/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O become/VB/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O upon/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Cunin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O retirement/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O Bearings/NNP/B-ORG director/NN/O since/IN/O 1985/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O appointments/NNS/O are/VBP/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O planned/VBN/O succession/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O bite/VB/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O GM/NNP/B-ORG stall/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O barely/RB/O looked/VBD/O at/IN/O a/DT/O gleaming/VBG/O Cadillac/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O preferring/VBG/O to/TO/O talk/VB/O about/IN/O cooperation/NN/O possibilities/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O meantime/NN/O ,/,/O China/NNP/B-GPE opened/VBD/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O aviation/NN/O show/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O West/NN/O 's/POS/O embargo/NN/O on/IN/O military/JJ/O deals/NNS/O and/CC/O uncertainty/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O stability/NN/O kept/VBD/O many/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O exhibitors/NNS/O away/RB/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O 91/CD/O companies/NNS/O from/IN/O 14/CD/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O displays/NNS/O ,/,/O down/IN/O from/IN/O about/IN/O 260/CD/O firms/NNS/O from/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O countries/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O show/NN/O in/IN/O
Judge/NNP/O Masaaki/NNP/B-PERSON Yoneyama/NNP/I-PERSON told/VBD/O the/DT/O Osaka/NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG Daikin/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ``/``/O responsibility/NN/O is/VBZ/O heavy/JJ/O because/IN/O illegal/JJ/O exports/NNS/O lowered/VBD/O international/JJ/O trust/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
Sale/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O solution/NN/O in/IN/O concentrated/VBN/O form/NN/O to/TO/O Communist/NNP/O countries/NNS/O is/VBZ/O prohibited/VBN/O by/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O law/NN/O and/CC/O by/IN/O international/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O legislative/JJ/O panel/NN/O rejected/VBD/O as/RB/O not/RB/O radical/JJ/O enough/RB/O a/DT/O government/NN/O proposal/NN/O on/IN/O decentralizing/VBG/O economic/JJ/O control/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O newspaper/NN/O Leninskoye/NNP/B-ORG Zamya/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O decided/VBD/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O parcel/VB/O out/RP/O economic/JJ/O powers/NNS/O previously/RB/O exercised/VBN/O by/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O 15/CD/O republics/NNS/O ``/``/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O reflect/VB/O the/DT/O radical/JJ/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O federation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O committee/NN/O gave/VBD/O the/DT/O government/NN/O until/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 15/CD/O to/TO/O revise/VB/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O reflected/VBD/O the/DT/O growing/VBG/O confidence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O revamped/VBN/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Soviet/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O eucalyptus/NN/O plantation/NN/O and/CC/O pulp/NN/O mill/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O covered/VBN/O about/IN/O 175,000/CD/O acres/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Irian/NNP/B-LOC Jaya/NNP/I-LOC region/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O investment/NN/O board/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O opposed/VBN/O by/IN/O some/DT/O environmentalists/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O threat/NN/O to/TO/O Irian/NNP/B-LOC Jaya/NNP/I-LOC 's/POS/I-LOC forests/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O potential/JJ/O source/NN/O of/IN/O social/JJ/O unrest/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O primitive/JJ/O tribes/NNS/O who/WP/O inhabit/VBP/O them/PRP/O ././O
With/IN/O funds/NNS/O of/IN/O 5.56/CD/O billion/CD/O Hong/NNP/O Kong/NNP/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 712/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Yaohan/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O 10/CD/O of/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE top/JJ/O restaurants/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O wholesale/JJ/O market/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O next/IN/O May/NNP/O and/CC/O to/TO/O open/VB/O a/DT/O department/NN/O store/NN/O in/IN/O Bangkok/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O shopping/NN/O centers/NNS/O in/IN/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Seattle/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O December/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O chain/NN/O currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O 90/CD/O retail/JJ/O outlets/NNS/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O seven/CD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O three/CD/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O more/JJR/O scattered/VBN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O globe/NN/O ././O
Major/JJ/O European/JJ/O auction/NN/O houses/NNS/O are/VBP/O turning/VBG/O increasingly/RB/O to/TO/O specialized/VBN/O sales/NNS/O ././O
Christie/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG will/MD/O soon/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Dada/NNP/O and/CC/O Symbolist/NNP/O art/NN/O while/NN/O Sotheby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O luring/VBG/O collectors/NNS/O with/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O Swiss/JJ/O ,/,/O German/JJ/O ,/,/O Spanish/JJ/O ,/,/O Australian/JJ/O and/CC/O Canadian/JJ/O paintings/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Brussels/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Hotel/NNP/B-ORG de/IN/I-ORG Ventes/NNP/I-ORG Horta/NNP/I-ORG auctioned/VBD/O pistols/NNS/O and/CC/O sabers/NNS/O -/:/O along/RB/O with/IN/O paintings/NNS/O and/CC/O jewels/NNS/O ././O
Berlin/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Villa/NNP/B-ORG Grisebach/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O auction/VB/O art/NN/O works/NNS/O with/IN/O pre-sale/JJ/O estimates/NNS/O of/IN/O less/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 1,600/CD/O on/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 25/CD/O ././O
``/``/O Everything/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O between/IN/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Campo/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Stefan/NNP/B-PERSON Campo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O asking/VBG/O clients/NNS/O to/TO/O sign/VB/O protest/NN/O petitions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Then/RB/O there/EX/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O fair/JJ/O competition/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Instead/RB/O of/IN/O banning/VBG/O such/JJ/O shopping/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O confederation/NN/O proposed/VBD/O amending/VBG/O controls/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sure/JJ/O the/DT/O privilege/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O abused/VBN/O .../:/O ././O
British/JJ/O and/CC/O Argentine/JJ/O diplomats/NNS/O opened/VBD/O talks/NNS/O in/IN/O Madrid/NNP/B-GPE aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O restoring/VBG/O ties/NNS/O severed/VBN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O 1982/CD/O war/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Falkland/NNP/I-GPE Islands/NNPS/I-GPE ././O
Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O U.N./NNP/B-ORG representative/NN/O and/CC/O delegation/NN/O head/NN/O Crispin/NNP/B-PERSON Tickell/NNP/I-PERSON called/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O meeting/NN/O ``/``/O good/JJ/O ,/,/O interesting/JJ/O and/CC/O businesslike/JJ/O ././O
