Officials/O of/O the/O Big/O Three/O auto/O makers/O and/O 14/O petroleum/O companies/O said/O they/O are/O setting/O out/O to/O find/O the/O most/O cost/O -/O effective/O fuel/O for/O reducing/O cities/O '/O air/O -/O pollution/O problems/O ,/O with/O no/O bias/O toward/O any/O fuel/O in/O particular/O ./O
However/O ,/O their/O search/O notably/O wo/O n't/O include/O natural/O gas/O or/O pure/O methanol/O --/O the/O two/O front/O -/O running/O alternative/O fuels/O --/O in/O tests/O to/O be/O completed/O by/O next/O summer/O ./O
Environmentalists/O criticized/O the/O program/B-ORG as/O merely/O a/O public/O -/O relations/O attempt/O to/O head/O off/O a/O White/B-ORG House/I-ORG proposal/O to/O require/O a/O million/O cars/O a/O year/O that/O run/O on/O cleaner/O -/O burning/O fuels/O by/O 1997/O ./O
The/O initial/O $/O 11/O million/O research/O program/O will/O conduct/O the/O most/O extensive/O testing/O to/O date/O of/O reformulated/O gasolines/O ,/O said/O Joe/B-PERSON Colucci/I-PERSON ,/O head/O of/O fuels/O and/O lubricants/O at/O General/B-ORG Motors/I-ORG Corp./I-ORG research/O laboratories/O ./O
It/O will/O compare/O 21/O different/O blends/O of/O gasolines/O with/O three/O mixtures/O of/O up/O to/O 85/O %/O methanol/O ./O
A/O second/O phase/O of/O research/O ,/O which/O is/O still/O being/O planned/O ,/O will/O test/O reformulated/O gasolines/O on/O newer/O engine/O technologies/O now/O being/O developed/O for/O use/O in/O 1992/O or/O 1993/O cars/O ./O
There/O was/O no/O cost/O estimate/O for/O the/O second/O phase/O ./O
``/O The/O whole/O idea/O here/O is/O the/O automobile/O and/O oil/O companies/O have/O joint/O customers/O ,/O ''/O said/O Keith/B-PERSON McHenry/I-PERSON ,/O a/O senior/O vice/O president/O of/O technology/O at/O Amoco/B-ORG Corp/I-ORG ./O
The/O Bush/B-PERSON administration/O has/O said/O it/O will/O try/O to/O resurrect/O its/O plan/O when/O the/B-ORG House/I-ORG Energy/I-ORG and/I-ORG Commerce/I-ORG Committee/I-ORG takes/O up/O a/O comprehensive/O clean/O -/O air/O bill/O ./O
