When/WRB/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O announced/VBD/O their/PRP$/O last/JJ/O soldier/NN/O had/VBD/O left/VBN/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O February/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O voices/NNS/O of/IN/O skepticism/NN/O were/VBD/O all/DT/O but/CC/O drowned/VBD/O out/RP/O by/IN/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O chorus/NN/O of/IN/O euphoria/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O '/POS/O Vietnam/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O would/MD/O fall/VB/O ././O
Millions/NNS/O of/IN/O refugees/NNS/O would/MD/O rush/VB/O home/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O resistance/NN/O government/NN/O would/MD/O walk/VB/O into/IN/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Those/DT/O who/WP/O bought/VBD/O that/DT/O illusion/NN/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O bewildered/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O never/RB/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Afghan/JJ/O resistance/NN/O would/MD/O overthrow/VB/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O quickly/RB/O and/CC/O easily/RB/O ././O
Soviet/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O support/VB/O their/PRP$/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE clients/NNS/O by/IN/O all/DT/O means/NNS/O necessary/JJ/O --/:/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O fully/RB/O support/VB/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/O February/NNP/O 1987/CD/O U.N./NNP/B-ORG accords/NNS/O ``/``/O relating/VBG/O to/TO/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE got/VBD/O everything/NN/O it/PRP/O needed/VBD/O to/TO/O consolidate/VB/O permanent/JJ/O control/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Geneva/NNP/O accords/NNS/O leave/VBP/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE free/JJ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O its/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O in/IN/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O assistance/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O kind/NN/O --/:/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O return/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O ground/NN/O forces/NNS/O --/:/O while/IN/O requiring/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Pakistan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O cut/VB/O off/RP/O aid/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O as/RB/O soon/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O accords/NNS/O were/VBD/O signed/VBN/O ,/,/O American/JJ/O officials/NNS/O sharply/RB/O reduced/VBD/O aid/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O February/NNP/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O completed/VBN/O their/PRP$/O pullout/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE cut/VBD/O it/PRP/O further/RB/O ././O
Not/RB/O so/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O ././O
Gen./NNP/O Gromov/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O said/VBD/O Soviet/JJ/O troops/NNS/O expected/VBD/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O behind/RB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O military/JJ/O equipment/NN/O and/CC/O installations/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O the/DT/O troop/NN/O withdrawal/NN/O ,/,/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O poured/VBN/O in/RP/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 200/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O worth/NN/O per/IN/O month/NN/O --/:/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O since/IN/O February/NNP/O ,/,/O equivalent/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O in/IN/O nine/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O early/JJ/O May/NNP/O ,/,/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O delivered/VBN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O 1,000/CD/O trucks/NNS/O ,/,/O about/IN/O 100/CD/O tanks/NNS/O ,/,/O artillery/NN/O and/CC/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O combat/NN/O vehicles/NNS/O ././O
Moscow/NNP/B-GPE claims/VBZ/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O all/DT/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O guerrilla/NN/O resistance/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O Afghan/JJ/O army/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O longer/JJR/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O only/JJ/O military/JJ/O force/NN/O ././O
Complete/JJ/O units/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O trained/VBN/O and/CC/O indoctrinated/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S.S.R./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O other/JJ/O East/NNP/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC nations/NNS/O ;/:/O 30,000/CD/O to/TO/O 40,000/CD/O of/IN/O these/DT/O troops/NNS/O have/VBP/O returned/VBN/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O not/RB/O all/PDT/O these/DT/O forces/NNS/O are/VBP/O committed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O regime/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O dependent/JJ/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
And/CC/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O Afghan/JJ/O children/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O taken/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O hostage/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O behavior/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O families/NNS/O ././O
Since/IN/O 1981/CD/O ,/,/O Indian/JJ/O military/JJ/O advisers/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O assisting/VBG/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O preparation/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O withdrawal/NN/O ,/,/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Delhi/NNP/I-GPE signed/VBD/O two/CD/O agreements/NNS/O for/IN/O several/JJ/O hundred/CD/O newly/RB/O civilian/JJ/O Indian/JJ/O experts/NNS/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O visible/JJ/O Soviet/JJ/O military/JJ/O personnel/NNS/O ././O
Cuban/JJ/O military/JJ/O personnel/NNS/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O active/JJ/O in/IN/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE since/IN/O 1979/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O cut/VBD/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O with/IN/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE :/:/O a/DT/O future/JJ/O Iranian/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O Iranian/JJ/O support/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O deal/NN/O was/VBD/O symbolized/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O restoration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Shi'ite/NNP/O Sultan/NNP/O Ali/NNP/B-PERSON Keshtmand/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O the/DT/O Afghan/JJ/O prime/JJ/O ministry/NN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O serious/JJ/O questions/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O raised/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O claimed/VBN/O withdrawal/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O forces/NNS/O ././O
Before/IN/O his/PRP$/O assassination/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O President/NNP/O Zia/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Pakistan/NNP/B-GPE repeatedly/RB/O stated/VBD/O that/IN/O fresh/JJ/O Soviet/JJ/O troops/NNS/O were/VBD/O being/VBG/O inserted/VBN/O into/IN/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE even/RB/O as/IN/O others/NNS/O were/VBD/O ostentatiously/RB/O withdrawn/VBN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON McCollum/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Fla./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O reports/VBZ/O that/IN/O these/DT/O included/VBD/O 20,000/CD/O to/TO/O 30,000/CD/O Soviet/NNP/O Central/NNP/O Asian/NNP/O KGB/NNP/B-ORG Border/NNP/I-ORG Guards/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O ethnically/RB/O indistinguishable/JJ/O from/IN/O Afghans/NNPS/O and/CC/O wearing/VBG/O unmarked/JJ/O uniforms/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O this/DT/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O aided/VBN/O by/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O ,/,/O European/JJ/O ,/,/O Pakistani/JJ/O and/CC/O Saudi/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O extreme/JJ/O factions/NNS/O --/:/O radical/JJ/O Islamic/JJ/O fanatics/NNS/O with/IN/O leaders/NNS/O whose/WP$/O policies/NNS/O are/VBP/O anathema/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Afghan/JJ/O public/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O heavy/JJ/O outside/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O has/VBZ/O undermined/VBN/O better/JJR/O ,/,/O moderate/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O autumn/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O regime/NN/O garrison/NN/O at/IN/O Kandahar/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O surrender/VB/O the/DT/O city/NN/O to/TO/O resistance/NN/O moderates/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O minute/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O Pakistani/JJ/O officials/NNS/O sent/VBD/O in/RP/O Gulbuddin/NNP/B-PERSON Hekhmatyar/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O hated/VBN/O and/CC/O feared/VBN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O extremists/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O demand/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O surrender/NN/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O forces/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O deal/NN/O fell/VBD/O through/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Kandahar/NNP/B-GPE remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O regime/NN/O base/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O resistance/NN/O lacks/VBZ/O not/RB/O only/JJ/O air/NN/O power/NN/O ,/,/O armor/NN/O and/CC/O expertise/NN/O but/CC/O often/RB/O such/JJ/O essentials/NNS/O as/IN/O maps/NNS/O ,/,/O mine/NN/O detectors/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O even/RB/O winter/NN/O gloves/NNS/O ././O
Experienced/VBN/O resistance/NN/O commanders/NNS/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O use/VB/O guerrilla/NN/O action/NN/O and/CC/O siege/NN/O tactics/NNS/O to/TO/O wear/VB/O down/RP/O the/DT/O regime/NN/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O pressured/JJ/O by/IN/O Pakistan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O ISI/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O channel/NN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O support/NN/O ,/,/O into/IN/O attacking/VBG/O Jalalabad/NNP/B-GPE ././O
They/PRP/O took/VBD/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O casualties/NNS/O ;/:/O journalists/NNS/O report/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O faced/VBD/O minefields/NNS/O without/IN/O mine/NN/O detectors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O wonder/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O has/VBZ/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O topple/VB/O the/DT/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE regime/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O exist/VB/O and/CC/O fight/VB/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
Last/JJ/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O congressional/JJ/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O resumed/VBN/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O months/NNS/O after/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O cut/VBN/O off/IN/O ;/:/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O clear/JJ/O how/WRB/O much/RB/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O sent/VBN/O or/CC/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O arrive/VB/O ././O
For/IN/O months/NNS/O the/DT/O resistance/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O defenseless/JJ/O against/IN/O air/NN/O attack/NN/O ././O
Thus/RB/O far/RB/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O indication/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O re-supplied/VBN/O with/IN/O Stingers/NNPS/O or/CC/O other/JJ/O anti-aircraft/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O indicated/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O press/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O continuation/NN/O of/IN/O aid/NN/O depends/VBZ/O on/IN/O what/WDT/O success/NN/O the/DT/O weakened/VBN/O resistance/NN/O achieves/VBZ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Moscow/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE must/MD/O have/VB/O found/VBN/O that/DT/O information/NN/O useful/JJ/O ././O
For/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE policy/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O incoherent/JJ/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O miscalculation/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O defense/NN/O of/IN/O bureaucratic/JJ/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O turf/NN/O ././O
No/DT/O settlement/NN/O negotiated/VBN/O by/IN/O others/NNS/O can/MD/O force/VB/O the/DT/O Afghan/NNP/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O give/VB/O up/RP/O their/PRP$/O struggle/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O cutoff/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O aid/NN/O would/MD/O merely/RB/O abandon/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O die/VB/O in/IN/O vain/JJ/O ././O
Creation/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O ,/,/O realistic/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE policy/NN/O is/VBZ/O long/RB/O overdue/JJ/O ././O
