President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O veto/VB/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O funding/VBG/O the/DT/O Departments/NNPS/O of/IN/O Labor/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Education/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Health/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Human/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG because/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O of/IN/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O threatened/VBN/O a/DT/O veto/NN/O previously/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O put/VBD/O off/RP/O a/DT/O firm/JJ/O decision/NN/O while/IN/O his/PRP$/O aides/NNS/O and/CC/O legislators/NNS/O searched/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O tighten/VB/O requirements/NNS/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O abortions/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O acceptable/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O president/NN/O ././O
White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/O Secretary/NNP/O Marlin/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzwater/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O negotiations/NNS/O between/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON aides/NNS/O and/CC/O lawmakers/NNS/O ended/VBD/O Monday/NNP/O without/IN/O success/NN/O ././O
Most/JJS/O lawmakers/NNS/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O extremely/RB/O difficult/JJ/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O opponents/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O to/TO/O round/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O votes/NNS/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O override/VB/O the/DT/O veto/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O still/RB/O may/MD/O be/VB/O prolonged/VBN/O debate/NN/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O maneuvering/NN/O that/WDT/O holds/VBZ/O up/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 156.7/CD/O billion/CD/O funding/NN/O bill/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O that/WDT/O began/VBD/O Oct./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O he/PRP/O personally/RB/O approves/VBZ/O of/IN/O abortions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O ,/,/O incest/NN/O and/CC/O danger/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O life/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mother/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O opposed/VBN/O Medicaid/NNP/B-ORG funding/NN/O of/IN/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O poor/JJ/O women/NNS/O who/WP/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O ,/,/O arguing/VBG/O that/IN/O those/DT/O exceptions/NNS/O are/VBP/O enforced/VBN/O so/RB/O loosely/RB/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O open/VBP/O the/DT/O way/NN/O for/IN/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O women/NNS/O ././O
