Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON N./NNP/I-PERSON Wertheimer/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O managing/VBG/O director/NN/O and/CC/O group/NN/O head/NN/O of/IN/O investment/NN/O banking/NN/O in/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wertheimer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 38/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O first/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O industrial/JJ/O group/NN/O in/IN/O investment/NN/O banking/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O succeeds/VBZ/O Everett/NNP/B-PERSON Meyers/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O ././O
