Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Coatedboard/NNP/B-ORG division/NN/O of/IN/O Mead/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Manville/NNP/B-ORG Forest/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Manville/NNP/B-ORG unit/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Manville/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON succeeds/VBZ/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Sherman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O other/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O both/DT/O positions/NNS/O ././O
Manville/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O building/NN/O and/CC/O forest/NN/O products/NNS/O concern/NN/O ././O
