Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Carlucci/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O telecommunications/NNS/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O board/NN/O ,/,/O filling/VBG/O the/DT/O vacancy/NN/O created/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Sobey/NNP/I-PERSON last/JJ/O May/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carlucci/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 59/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O served/VBD/O as/IN/O defense/NN/O secretary/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O January/NNP/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O accepted/VBD/O the/DT/O position/NN/O of/IN/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Carlyle/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O merchant/NN/O banking/NN/O concern/NN/O ././O
