It/PRP/O also/RB/O declined/VBD/O against/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O reach/VB/O its/PRP$/O intraday/NN/O low/JJ/O of/IN/O 1.8435/CD/O marks/NNS/O until/IN/O two/CD/O hours/NNS/O later/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O unit/NN/O stabilized/VBD/O about/IN/O midday/NN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE time/NN/O at/IN/O around/IN/O 1.85/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 141/CD/O yen/NN/O ,/,/O prompting/VBG/O unconfirmed/JJ/O rumors/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O intervened/VBN/O to/TO/O blunt/VB/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O 's/POS/O tumble/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O finished/VBD/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O intraday/NN/O highs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 10.77/CD/O billion/CD/O deficit/NN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O revised/VBN/O July/NNP/O deficit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 8.24/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Economists/NNS/O had/VBD/O expected/VBN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 9.1/CD/O billion/CD/O gap/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O August/NNP/O figure/NN/O reflected/VBD/O a/DT/O 6.4/CD/O %/NN/O rise/NN/O in/IN/O imports/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O 0.2/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O exports/NNS/O ././O
Marc/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Goloven/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O economist/NN/O with/IN/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O while/IN/O the/DT/O figures/NNS/O appear/VBP/O to/TO/O indicate/VB/O a/DT/O sadly/RB/O deteriorating/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O performance/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O still/RB/O enough/RB/O positive/JJ/O news/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O data/NNS/O to/TO/O justify/VB/O buying/VBG/O dollars/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O while/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O gap/NN/O with/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O widened/VBN/O significantly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O with/IN/O Western/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O narrow/VB/O ././O
Sterling/NN/O was/VBD/O unchanged/JJ/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.5753/CD/O ././O
They/PRP/O note/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O is/VBZ/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O the/DT/O upper/JJ/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O presumed/VBN/O target/NN/O zones/NNS/O established/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Group/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Seven/CD/I-ORG trading/NN/O partners/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O injection/NN/O of/IN/O liquidity/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE banking/NN/O system/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O modest/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O anticipate/VB/O significant/JJ/O easing/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG arranged/VBD/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O customer/NN/O repurchase/VBD/O agreements/NNS/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O repurchase/JJ/O agreement/NN/O in/IN/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O injects/VBZ/O capital/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O seen/VBN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O reassure/VB/O the/DT/O finanicial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE central/JJ/O bank/NN/O is/VBZ/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O the/DT/O ample/JJ/O liquidity/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O federal/JJ/O funds/NNS/O rate/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O overnight/JJ/O lending/NN/O rate/NN/O that/IN/O banks/NNS/O charge/VBP/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
Market/NN/O participants/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O post/VB/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O significant/JJ/O gains/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ././O
