The/DT/O post/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O vacant/JJ/O for/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Jelenic/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Ingersoll/NNP/I-PERSON II/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 43/CD/O ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O take/VB/O on/RP/O additional/JJ/O responsibilities/NNS/O as/IN/O editor/NN/O in/IN/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Wilpers/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O editor/NN/O in/IN/O chief/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ingersoll/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O editor/NN/O in/IN/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O recently/RB/O launched/VBN/O daily/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG St./NNP/I-ORG Louis/NNP/I-ORG Sun/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O Jean/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Clifton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 28/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O treasurer/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O ././O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Applebaum/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O after/IN/O less/RBR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O posts/NNS/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Clifton/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O executive/JJ/O financial/JJ/O assistant/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O ././O
