Beantown/NNP/B-GPE scribes/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O spare/VBP/O no/DT/O invective/NN/O when/WRB/O taking/VBG/O on/IN/O local/JJ/O luminaries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Pee/NNP/I-PERSON Wee/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Dukakis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O or/CC/O New/NNP/B-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG Patriots/NNPS/I-ORG Coach/NNP/O Raymond/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Rev./NNP/I-PERSON Ray/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Berry/NN/I-PERSON ,/,/O yesterday/NN/O poured/VBD/O ridicule/NN/O on/IN/O new/JJ/O drawings/NNS/O of/IN/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG columnists/NNS/O that/WDT/O replaced/VBD/O old/JJ/O photos/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O revamped/VBN/O pages/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
Trouble/NN/O was/VBD/O ,/,/O nobody/NN/O thought/VBD/O they/PRP/O looked/VBD/O right/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Barnicle/NNP/B-PERSON reminded/VBD/O readers/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O forgiven/VBN/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O for/IN/O questioning/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 20/CD/O expense/NN/O chit/NN/O he/PRP/O submitted/VBD/O for/IN/O parking/VBG/O his/PRP$/O car/NN/O while/IN/O chasing/VBG/O a/DT/O story/NN/O ././O
Rival/NNP/O Boston/NNP/B-ORG Herald/NNP/I-ORG columnist/NN/O Howie/NNP/B-PERSON Carr/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O usually/RB/O rails/VBZ/O at/IN/O Statehouse/NN/B-ORG ``/``/O hacks/NNS/O ''/''/O and/CC/O nepotism/NN/O ,/,/O argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O drawings/NNS/O were/VBD/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O hide/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Madden/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O rapidly/RB/O growing/VBG/O forehead/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O the/DT/O facial/JJ/O defects/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O chinless/JJ/O ''/''/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Shaughnessy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Globe/NNP/B-ORG sports/NNS/O columnist/NN/O ././O
