Robin/NNP/B-PERSON Honiss/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O elected/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O additional/JJ/O posts/NNS/O of/IN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O New/NNP/B-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG Savings/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ././O
William/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Attridge/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O those/DT/O posts/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O seat/NN/O on/IN/O NESB/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O board/NN/O ././O
NESB/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O also/RB/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O Omnibank/NNP/B-ORG ././O
