Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Tanner/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O company/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O succeeds/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Boudreau/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O for/IN/O personal/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tanner/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Penn/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG National/NNP/B-ORG Southwest/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Boudreau/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O remain/VB/O with/IN/O Penn/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O committee/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O also/RB/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O president/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O subsidiary/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O formed/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O future/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
