Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Rajiv/NNP/B-PERSON Gandhi/NNP/I-PERSON set/VBD/O a/DT/O date/NN/O next/IN/O month/NN/O for/IN/O general/JJ/O elections/NNS/O that/IN/O some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O could/MD/O cost/VB/O him/PRP/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O ruling/VBG/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG I/NN/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Party/NN/I-ORG control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O Indian/JJ/O leader/NN/O could/MD/O retain/VB/O control/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O slim/JJ/O majority/NN/O or/CC/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O rule/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O dominant/JJ/O partner/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O coalition/NN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O parties/NNS/O ././O
Elections/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O large/JJ/O ,/,/O diverse/JJ/O and/CC/O passionate/JJ/O nation/NN/O are/VBP/O always/RB/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O predict/VB/O ././O
Much/RB/O depends/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O loose/JJ/O group/NN/O of/IN/O regional/JJ/O and/CC/O ideological/JJ/O parties/NNS/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON cabinet/NN/O minister/NN/O Vishwanath/NNP/B-PERSON Pratap/NNP/I-PERSON Singh/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O biggest/JJS/O certainty/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O elections/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O for/IN/O or/CC/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O power/NN/O --/:/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O ups/NNS/O and/CC/O downs/NNS/O ,/,/O promises/NNS/O and/CC/O disappointments/NNS/O and/CC/O wide/JJ/O fluctuations/NNS/O in/IN/O popularity/NN/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O four/CD/O days/NNS/O after/IN/O an/DT/O unusual/JJ/O parliamentary/JJ/O defeat/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O ruling/VBG/O party/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O elections/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O lower/JJR/O house/NN/O of/IN/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 22/CD/O and/CC/O 24/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O elections/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O held/VBN/O in/IN/O different/JJ/O states/NNS/O on/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O a/DT/O landslide/NN/O win/NN/O in/IN/O 1984/CD/O in/IN/O polls/NNS/O held/VBN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O mother/NN/O ,/,/O Indira/NNP/B-PERSON Gandhi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON saw/VBD/O his/PRP$/O popularity/NN/O begin/VB/O a/DT/O roller/NN/O coaster/NN/O ride/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O early/JJ/O promises/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O India/NNP/B-GPE a/DT/O modern/JJ/O nation/NN/O remain/VBP/O bogged/VBD/O down/IN/O in/IN/O bloated/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O pledge/NN/O to/TO/O clean/VB/O up/RP/O local/JJ/O administration/NN/O and/CC/O Indian/JJ/O politics/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O party/NN/O ,/,/O went/VBD/O unfulfilled/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O wide/JJ/O feeling/NN/O of/IN/O indignation/NN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Bhabani/NNP/B-PERSON Sen/NNP/I-PERSON Gupta/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Policy/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Delhi/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O judging/VBG/O the/DT/O regime/NN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O petty/JJ/O policeman/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O a/DT/O corrupt/JJ/O revenue/NN/O collector/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O could/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O protest/NN/O against/IN/O an/DT/O administrative/JJ/O failure/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O retains/VBZ/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O push/VB/O through/IN/O major/JJ/O initiatives/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O hobbled/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O thinner/JJR/O majority/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-PERSON Lok/NNP/I-PERSON Sabha/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O or/CC/O lower/JJR/O house/NN/O of/IN/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O 542/CD/O elected/VBN/O and/CC/O two/CD/O appointed/VBN/O seats/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O captured/VBN/O 405/CD/O seats/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O victory/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O history/NN/O of/IN/O Indian/JJ/O democracy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O landslide/NN/O was/VBD/O fueled/VBN/O by/IN/O panic/NN/O that/WDT/O prevailed/VBD/O in/IN/O India/NNP/B-GPE at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O assassinated/VBN/O by/IN/O separatist/JJ/O Sikhs/NNPS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O Indians/NNPS/O feared/VBD/O their/PRP$/O country/NN/O might/MD/O split/VB/O apart/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O three/CD/O general/JJ/O elections/NNS/O ,/,/O similar/JJ/O national/JJ/O issues/NNS/O clinched/VBD/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1971/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG won/VBD/O after/IN/O India/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O victory/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Bangladesh/NNP/O war/NN/O ././O
Most/RBS/O political/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O if/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O opposition/NN/O unites/VBZ/O to/TO/O field/VB/O single/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O in/IN/O most/JJS/O precincts/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O will/MD/O lose/VB/O big/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O if/IN/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O remains/VBZ/O fractured/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O could/MD/O win/VB/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O majority/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O lead/VB/O a/DT/O coalition/NN/O government/NN/O ././O
Chimanbhai/NNP/B-PERSON Mehta/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O parliamentarian/NN/O and/CC/O former/JJ/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON ally/NN/O ,/,/O predicts/VBZ/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O will/MD/O win/VB/O only/RB/O 150/CD/O seats/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O quarter/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O house/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O fields/VBZ/O single/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O in/IN/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O races/NNS/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O will/MD/O struggle/VB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O to/TO/O unite/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O success/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O clear/JJ/O only/RB/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O announces/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O final/JJ/O list/NN/O of/IN/O parliamentary/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O India/NNP/B-GPE signed/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1.4/CD/O billion/CD/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O AB/NNP/B-ORG Bofors/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Nobel/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Sweden/NNP/I-ORG AB/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O 400/CD/O artillery/NN/O pieces/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O contract/NN/O was/VBD/O negotiated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O countries/NNS/O '/POS/O two/CD/O prime/JJ/O ministers/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O free/JJ/O of/IN/O commissions/NNS/O or/CC/O agents/NNS/O '/POS/O costs/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O April/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O evidence/NN/O surfaced/VBD/O that/IN/O commissions/NNS/O were/VBD/O paid/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O opposition/NN/O charged/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O was/VBD/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O bribe/VB/O Indian/JJ/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O allegation/NN/O denied/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O administration/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O statements/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O in/IN/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG subsequently/RB/O were/VBD/O proven/VBN/O wrong/JJ/O by/IN/O documentary/JJ/O evidence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O scandal/NN/O has/VBZ/O faded/VBN/O and/CC/O flared/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O recent/JJ/O disclosures/NNS/O propelled/VBD/O it/PRP/O back/RB/O onto/IN/O the/DT/O front/JJ/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O has/VBZ/O helped/VBN/O galvanize/VB/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O blocked/VBD/O passage/NN/O of/IN/O two/CD/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O bills/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O in/IN/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O that/IN/O such/JJ/O government/NN/O bills/NNS/O were/VBD/O defeated/VBN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O country/NN/O where/WRB/O a/DT/O bribe/NN/O is/VBZ/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O a/DT/O phone/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O job/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O even/RB/O into/IN/O a/DT/O school/NN/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O name/NN/O Bofors/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O a/DT/O potent/JJ/O rallying/NN/O cry/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O illustrates/VBZ/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O disappointment/NN/O many/JJ/O Indians/NNPS/O feel/VBP/O toward/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whom/WP/O they/PRP/O zestfully/RB/O elected/VBD/O and/CC/O enthusiastically/RB/O supported/VBD/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O first/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O power/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O term/NN/O has/VBZ/O produced/VBN/O no/DT/O spectacular/JJ/O failures/NNS/O in/IN/O politics/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O or/CC/O on/IN/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O front/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O chalked/VBN/O up/RP/O some/DT/O successes/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O average/JJ/O Indian/NNP/O had/VBD/O tremendous/JJ/O hope/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O youthful/JJ/O leader/NN/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O promise/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O both/DT/O government/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O ruling/VBG/O party/NN/O more/JJR/O effective/JJ/O and/CC/O less/RBR/O corrupt/JJ/O ././O
His/PRP$/O failures/NNS/O in/IN/O those/DT/O two/CD/O areas/NNS/O deeply/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O sometimes/RB/O bitterly/RB/O ,/,/O disappointed/VBN/O many/JJ/O Indians/NNPS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O like/VB/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Sooraji/NNP/B-PERSON Jath/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O farmer/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O western/JJ/O state/NN/O of/IN/O Gujarat/NN/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG government/NN/O is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O the/DT/O farmers/NNS/O '/POS/O bread/NN/O and/CC/O not/RB/O giving/VBG/O us/PRP/O any/DT/O support/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O well/NN/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O light/NN/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O road/NN/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O tells/VBZ/O us/PRP/O to/TO/O forget/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O greatest/JJS/O thing/NN/O going/VBG/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG I/NN/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Party/NN/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O poor/JJ/O reputation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O unites/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O elections/NNS/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O coherence/NN/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O temporary/JJ/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O lost/VBD/O the/DT/O 1977/CD/O election/NN/O ,/,/O following/VBG/O Mrs./NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O hated/VBN/O emergency/NN/O rule/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O coalition/NN/O took/VBD/O power/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O disintegrated/VBD/O ././O
Many/JJ/O Indians/NNPS/O fear/VBP/O a/DT/O repeat/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O experience/NN/O ././O
March/NNP/O 24/CD/O ,/,/O 1986/CD/O :/:/O
In/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Rajiv/NNP/B-PERSON Gandhi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O then/JJ/O Swedish/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Olof/NNP/B-PERSON Palme/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O imposed/VBD/O the/DT/O condition/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O have/VB/O no/DT/O middlemen/NNS/O ././O
April/NNP/O 16/CD/O ,/,/O 1987/CD/O :/:/O
Swedish/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Radio/NNP/I-ORG reports/VBZ/O that/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O --/:/O nearly/RB/O 3/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O contract/NN/O --/:/O was/VBD/O paid/VBN/O by/IN/O Bofors/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O commissions/NNS/O to/TO/O middlemen/NNS/O ././O
June/NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O 1987/CD/O :/:/O
Sweden/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O National/NNP/B-ORG Audit/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG releases/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O report/NN/O confirming/VBG/O payment/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O unidentified/JJ/O Indians/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O report/NN/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O investigations/NNS/O were/VBD/O severely/RB/O hampered/VBN/O by/IN/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O cooperation/NN/O from/IN/O Bofors/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Bofors/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O names/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O middlemen/NNS/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O jeopardize/VB/O industrial/JJ/O confidentiality/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O report/NN/O containing/VBG/O names/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O middlemen/NNS/O is/VBZ/O withheld/VBN/O by/IN/O officials/NNS/O citing/VBG/O bank/NN/O secrecy/NN/O requirements/NNS/O ././O
Aug./NNP/O 6/CD/O ,/,/O 1987/CD/O :/:/O
Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON tells/VBZ/O the/DT/O Indian/NNP/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ``/``/O .../:/O neither/CC/O I/PRP/O nor/CC/O any/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O family/NN/O has/VBZ/O received/VBN/O any/DT/O consideration/NN/O in/IN/O these/DT/O transactions/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O truth/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Aug./NNP/O 26/CD/O ,/,/O 1987/CD/O :/:/O
Bofors/NNP/B-ORG admits/VBZ/O payments/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 41/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O middlemen/NNS/O ././O
April/NNP/O 22/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O :/:/O
April/NNP/O 26/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O :/:/O
A/DT/O parliamentary/JJ/O investigative/JJ/O committee/NN/O dominated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG I/NN/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG concludes/VBZ/O that/IN/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O no/DT/O middlemen/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O and/CC/O no/DT/O payment/NN/O to/TO/O any/DT/O Indian/JJ/O individual/NN/O or/CC/O company/NN/O ././O
July/NNP/O 18/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O :/:/O
Sept./NNP/O 15/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O :/:/O
Retired/VBN/O army/NN/O Chief/NNP/O of/IN/O Staff/NNP/O Krishnaswami/NNP/B-PERSON Sundarji/NNP/I-PERSON discloses/VBZ/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O suggested/VBD/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O 1987/CD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O cancel/VB/O the/DT/O Bofors/NNP/B-ORG contract/NN/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O Gen./NNP/O Sundarji/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O forced/VBN/O Bofors/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O names/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O middlemen/NNS/O who/WP/O received/VBD/O kickbacks/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O recommendation/NN/O was/VBD/O rejected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
Oct./NNP/O 9./CD/O 1989/CD/O :/:/O
The/DT/O Hindu/NNP/O newspaper/NN/O publishes/VBZ/O the/DT/O withheld/VBN/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Swedish/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Audit/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG report/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O disclosures/NNS/O state/NN/O that/IN/O commissions/NNS/O were/VBD/O paid/VBN/O by/IN/O Bofors/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O an/DT/O Indian/JJ/O agent/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O arms/NNS/O company/NN/O ././O
