Oncor/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Gaithersburg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Md./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O approval/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Food/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O market/VB/O a/DT/O genetic/JJ/O test/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O assist/VB/O in/IN/O diagnosis/NN/O and/CC/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O leukemia/NN/O and/CC/O lymph/NN/O cancer/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Turner/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O test/NN/O initially/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O conjunction/NN/O with/IN/O biopsies/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O tests/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O eventually/RB/O might/MD/O become/VB/O the/DT/O benchmark/NN/O for/IN/O tumor/NN/O analysis/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Turner/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O test/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O shipped/VBN/O in/IN/O 45/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O hospitals/NNS/O and/CC/O clinical/JJ/O laboratories/NNS/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Wyndham/NNP/B-PERSON Wilson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O cancer/NN/O treatment/NN/O specialist/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Cancer/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O test/NN/O is/VBZ/O widely/RB/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O research/NN/O centers/NNS/O but/CC/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O having/VBG/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O impact/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O occasionally/RB/O useful/JJ/O in/IN/O choosing/VBG/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O effective/JJ/O treatment/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O will/MD/O charge/VB/O $/$/O 35/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O test/NN/O and/CC/O projects/VBZ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O test/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O 12/CD/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O marketing/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
