The/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Mercantile/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG fined/VBD/O and/CC/O suspended/VBD/O two/CD/O commodities/NNS/O traders/NNS/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O prearranged/VBN/O trades/NNS/O with/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O that/IN/O allegedly/RB/O cheated/VBD/O a/DT/O customer/NN/O ././O
Merc/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON N./NNP/I-PERSON Roberts/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O disciplined/VBN/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O 's/POS/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O commodities/NNS/O pits/NNS/O from/IN/O July/NNP/O to/TO/O November/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON withheld/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O certain/JJ/O orders/NNS/O in/IN/O cooperation/NN/O with/IN/O another/DT/O trader/NN/O ,/,/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Stein/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG fined/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON $/$/O 15,000/CD/O and/CC/O suspended/VBD/O his/PRP$/O trading/NN/O membership/NN/O for/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Stein/NNP/B-PERSON were/VBD/O ordered/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O restitution/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 35,000/CD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O customer/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stein/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O fined/VBN/O $/$/O 25,000/CD/O and/CC/O suspended/VBN/O for/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Messrs./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Stein/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O disciplinary/JJ/O settlement/NN/O ,/,/O neither/DT/O man/NN/O admitted/VBD/O ,/,/O nor/CC/O denied/VBD/O the/DT/O alleged/VBN/O violations/NNS/O ././O
Neither/DT/O was/VBD/O among/IN/O the/DT/O 46/CD/O traders/NNS/O indicted/VBN/O last/JJ/O August/NNP/O in/IN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O traders/NNS/O at/IN/O both/PDT/O the/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG ././O
