The/DT/O nations/NNS/O of/IN/O southern/JJ/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC know/VBP/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O about/IN/O managing/VBG/O elephants/NNS/O ;/:/O their/PRP$/O herds/NNS/O are/VBP/O thriving/VBG/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O nations/NNS/O of/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC have/VBP/O decided/VBN/O they/PRP/O know/VBP/O better/RB/O ././O
At/IN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O U.N./NNP/B-ORG conference/NN/O in/IN/O Lausanne/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O they/PRP/O imposed/VBD/O a/DT/O global/JJ/O ivory/NN/O ban/NN/O that/WDT/O seeks/VBZ/O to/TO/O overturn/VB/O local/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O Zimbabwean/NNP/O delegate/NN/O argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ban/NN/O would/MD/O ``/``/O guarantee/VB/O the/DT/O extinction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O elephant/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Legitimate/JJ/O ranchers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O an/DT/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O preserving/VBG/O the/DT/O herds/NNS/O ,/,/O would/MD/O go/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ././O
Poachers/NNS/O would/MD/O control/VB/O the/DT/O underground/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O delegates/NNS/O were/VBD/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O craft/VB/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE delegate/NN/O Constance/NNP/B-PERSON Harriman/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O thundered/VBD/O that/DT/O down/RP/O ././O
The/DT/O Greens/NNP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O First/NNP/O World/NNP/O wanted/VBD/O a/DT/O morality/NN/O play/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O a/DT/O negotiation/NN/O ././O
Fortunately/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O nations/NNS/O of/IN/O southern/JJ/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC have/VBP/O n't/RB/O totally/RB/O surrendered/VBN/O their/PRP$/O sovereignty/NN/O ././O
Five/CD/O countries/NNS/O announced/VBD/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O not/RB/O honor/VB/O what/WP/O one/CD/O Zimbabwean/JJ/O delegate/NN/O wryly/RB/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE ''/''/O solution/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O seemed/VBD/O a/DT/O mite/NN/O resentful/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Zimbabwe/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Wildlife/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG described/VBD/O American/JJ/O conservationists/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O fat/JJ/O little/JJ/O puppies/NNS/O from/IN/O urban/JJ/O environments/NNS/O who/WP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O a/DT/O thing/NN/O about/IN/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O fair/JJ/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O all/RB/O fat/JJ/O ././O
