NEWSPAPERS/NNPS/O :/:/O
Media/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O two/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O West/NNP/B-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC weekly/JJ/O newspaper/NN/O chains/NNS/O ,/,/O Golden/NNP/B-ORG West/NNP/I-ORG Publishing/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Highlander/NNP/B-ORG Publications/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O together/RB/O comprise/VBP/O 31/CD/O papers/NNS/O ././O
Media/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O had/VBN/O inquiries/NNS/O from/IN/O potential/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O and/CC/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O a/DT/O sale/NN/O in/IN/O 1989/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O discuss/VB/O a/DT/O price/NN/O ././O
