The/DT/O inquiry/NN/O also/RB/O will/MD/O cover/VB/O the/DT/O actions/NNS/O of/IN/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Keating/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O who/WP/O contributed/VBD/O heavily/RB/O to/TO/O several/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE senators/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Resolution/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O created/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O sick/JJ/O thrifts/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O studied/VBN/O Lincoln/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O examination/NN/O reports/NNS/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O dating/VBG/O back/RB/O to/TO/O 1986/CD/O ././O
When/WRB/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O seized/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O loans/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O $/$/O 250/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O borrowers/NNS/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O buying/VBG/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O from/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 50/CD/O other/JJ/O subsidiaries/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O government/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O step/VB/O in/RB/O until/IN/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O thrift/NN/O officials/NNS/O put/VBD/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG into/IN/O conservatorship/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O day/NN/O after/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG filed/VBD/O for/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O bankruptcy/NN/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O deposits/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O transferred/VBN/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O subsidiaries/NNS/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O under/IN/O the/DT/O jurisdiction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bankruptcy/NN/O court/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O fairly/RB/O clear/JJ/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/O knew/VBD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O that/IN/O regulators/NNS/O were/VBD/O set/VBN/O to/TO/O seize/VB/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Further/JJ/O investigation/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O may/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O further/JJ/O actions/NNS/O against/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O executives/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O including/VBG/O fraud/NN/O actions/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O part/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O filed/VBN/O suit/NN/O alleging/VBG/O that/IN/O regulators/NNS/O unlawfully/RB/O seized/VBD/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O ././O
Leonard/NNP/B-PERSON Bickwit/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O hearings/NNS/O ,/,/O except/IN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O responding/VBG/O comprehensively/RB/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O forums/NNS/O to/TO/O each/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O allegations/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O appropriate/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O treatment/NN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O thrift/NN/O regulators/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O agency/NN/O disbanded/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O law/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O proved/VBN/O embarrassing/VBG/O for/IN/O five/CD/O senators/NNS/O who/WP/O received/VBD/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O campaign/NN/O contributions/NNS/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON DeConcini/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O who/WP/O received/VBD/O $/$/O 48,100/CD/O in/IN/O contributions/NNS/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O phoned/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O request/VB/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O push/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG before/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O seized/VBN/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O lawsuit/NN/O was/VBD/O filed/VBN/O against/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O DeConcini/NNP/B-PERSON returned/VBD/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O contributions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O senator/NN/O 's/POS/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O pushed/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG because/IN/O ``/``/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE jobs/NNS/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O at/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG -RCB-/-RRB-/O were/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Senate/NNP/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Riegle/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Mich/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O has/VBZ/O also/RB/O returned/VBN/O contributions/NNS/O he/PRP/O received/VBD/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/IN/O ././O
Sens./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Glenn/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON McCain/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Cranston/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O also/RB/O received/VBD/O substantial/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O sought/VBD/O to/TO/O intervene/VB/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ././O
House/NNP/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Gonzalez/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O Sen./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON volunteered/VBD/O to/TO/O appear/VB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG committee/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O necessary/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O a/DT/O committee/NN/O staff/NN/O member/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O is/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O closely/RB/O the/DT/O role/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O hearing/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O already/RB/O pumped/VBN/O $/$/O 729/CD/O million/CD/O into/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O liquidity/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O held/VBD/O out/RP/O little/JJ/O hope/NN/O of/IN/O restitution/NN/O for/IN/O purchasers/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 225/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG subordinated/VBD/O debt/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O plans/NNS/O at/IN/O this/DT/O time/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O off/RP/O those/DT/O notes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
