An/DT/O experimental/JJ/O vaccine/NN/O can/MD/O alter/VB/O the/DT/O immune/JJ/O response/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O infected/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O AIDS/NNP/O virus/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O prominent/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE scientist/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O that/DT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O benefit/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O vaccine/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O effectiveness/NN/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O determined/VBN/O until/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O clinical/JJ/O trial/NN/O is/VBZ/O undertaken/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O January/NNP/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Redfield/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O acquired/VBN/O immune/JJ/O deficiency/NN/O syndrome/NN/O research/NN/O at/IN/O Walter/NNP/B-ORG Reed/NNP/I-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Dr./NNP/O Redfield/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O report/NN/O on/IN/O early/JJ/O experiments/NNS/O using/VBG/O an/DT/O AIDS/NNP/O vaccine/NN/O made/VBD/O by/IN/O MicroGeneSys/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Haven/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O came/VBD/O at/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O of/IN/O AIDS/NNP/O vaccine/NN/O researchers/NNS/O in/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE late/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O conventional/JJ/O wisdom/NN/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O modify/VB/O the/DT/O immune/JJ/O response/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O infected/JJ/O individual/NN/O ''/''/O by/IN/O innoculating/VBG/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O synthetic/JJ/O viral/JJ/O proteins/NNS/O ,/,/O Dr./NNP/O Redfield/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O demonstrated/VBN/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O certain/JJ/O volunteers/NNS/O developed/VBD/O kinds/NNS/O of/IN/O antibodies/NNS/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O early/JJ/O AIDS/NNP/O ././O
Other/JJ/O antibodies/NNS/O sparked/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O preparation/NN/O are/VBP/O of/IN/O a/DT/O sort/NN/O rarely/RB/O present/JJ/O in/IN/O large/JJ/O quantities/NNS/O in/IN/O infected/JJ/O or/CC/O ill/JJ/O individuals/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mysteries/NNS/O of/IN/O AIDS/NNP/O remains/VBZ/O why/WRB/O infected/JJ/O people/NNS/O produce/VBP/O large/JJ/O quantities/NNS/O of/IN/O antibodies/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O deteriorate/VBP/O nonetheless/RB/O ././O
