Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O made/VBD/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O watching/VBG/O exchange/NN/O rates/NNS/O carefully/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O sinking/VBG/O pound/NN/O makes/VBZ/O imports/NNS/O more/RBR/O expensive/JJ/O and/CC/O increases/VBZ/O businesses/NNS/O '/POS/O expectations/NNS/O of/IN/O future/JJ/O inflation/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O argued/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O dismissed/VBD/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O imposing/VBG/O direct/JJ/O credit/NN/O controls/NNS/O on/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O financial/JJ/O system/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O speech/NN/O ,/,/O delivered/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Lord/NNP/O Mayor/NNP/O of/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O annual/JJ/O dinner/NN/O at/IN/O Mansion/NNP/B-FAC House/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O came/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O heels/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O grueling/JJ/O period/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE economy/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O 2.9428/CD/O marks/NNS/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE trading/NN/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
Unemployment/NN/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O dropped/VBD/O to/TO/O 1,695,000/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lowest/JJS/O level/NN/O since/IN/O 1980/CD/O ././O
