Gary/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Schantz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 44/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O operating/VBG/O chief/NN/O 's/POS/O post/NN/O is/VBZ/O new/JJ/O ././O
Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Schrager/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 51/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O remains/VBZ/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Schantz/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Acrylic/NNP/B-ORG division/NN/O of/IN/O Polycast/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O board/NN/O expanded/VBD/O to/TO/O six/CD/O members/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O election/NN/O of/IN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Holewinski/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O privately/RB/O placed/VBD/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O warrants/NNS/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 750,000/CD/O ././O
