And/CC/O you/PRP/O thought/VBD/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O reason/NN/O to/TO/O save/VB/O your/PRP$/O canceled/VBN/O checks/NNS/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O prepare/VB/O for/IN/O an/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG audit/NN/O ././O
Reggie/NNP/B-PERSON Jackson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O retired/VBN/O baseball/NN/O star/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O found/VBN/O another/DT/O use/NN/O for/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Jackson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O won/VBD/O the/DT/O nickname/NN/O ``/``/O Mr./NNP/O October/NNP/B-PERSON ''/''/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O exploits/VBZ/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O selling/VBG/O some/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O canceled/VBN/O checks/NNS/O to/TO/O autograph/VB/O collectors/NNS/O through/IN/O a/DT/O dealer/NN/O for/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O each/DT/O ././O
Dealers/NNS/O say/VB/O the/DT/O budding/VBG/O trade/NN/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Jackson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O canceled/VBN/O checks/NNS/O is/VBZ/O unusual/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O of/IN/O any/DT/O living/VBG/O ballplayer/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O ever/RB/O done/VBN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Smalling/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O dealer/NN/O in/IN/O Ames/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O recognized/VBN/O expert/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O of/IN/O baseball/NN/O autographs/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Jackson/NNP/B-PERSON showed/VBD/O up/RP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O affair/NN/O to/TO/O sign/VB/O autographs/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O fee/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
``/``/O For/IN/O someone/NN/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O everything/NN/O else/RB/O --/:/O Reggie/NN/B-PERSON 's/POS/O jersey/NN/O ,/,/O cap/NN/O and/CC/O cards/NNS/O --/:/O his/PRP$/O checks/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O nice/JJ/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Vizas/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O owner/NN/O of/IN/O Bill/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Sports/NNP/I-ORG Collectibles/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O who/WP/O examined/VBD/O the/DT/O checks/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE card/NN/O show/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O these/DT/O players/NNS/O were/VBD/O dead/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O Maybe/RB/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/B-PERSON Ty/NN/I-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON Cobbs/NNS/I-PERSON in/IN/O the/DT/O hobby/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O awhile/RB/O back/RB/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O Babe/NNP/B-PERSON Ruth/NNP/I-PERSON checks/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Smalling/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O thought/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O living/VBG/O player/NN/O selling/VBG/O his/PRP$/O checks/NNS/O rubs/VBZ/O some/DT/O people/NNS/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O way/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Maybe/RB/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O a/DT/O little/RB/O stuffy/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O sell/VB/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O sniffs/VBZ/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Machon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O owner/NN/O of/IN/O Papa/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Sports/NNP/I-ORG Cards/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Menlo/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O Who/WP/O knows/VBZ/O how/WRB/O much/RB/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O worth/JJ/O 100/CD/O years/NNS/O from/IN/O now/RB/O ?/./O ''/''/O
And/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Smalling/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O worth/JJ/O all/DT/O that/DT/O much/JJ/O now/RB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O the/DT/O checks/NNS/O are/VBP/O worth/JJ/O $/$/O 15/CD/O apiece/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Why/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Jackson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O checks/NNS/O available/JJ/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O clear/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O probably/RB/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O done/VBN/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O cash/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O say/VB/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O definitely/RB/O not/RB/O in/IN/O need/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Matt/NNP/B-PERSON Merola/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O agent/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Jackson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O good/JJ/O investments/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Jackson/NNP/B-PERSON probably/RB/O has/VBZ/O opened/VBN/O new/JJ/O checking/VBG/O accounts/NNS/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O
Or/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O he/PRP/O should/MD/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O assume/VB/O those/DT/O accounts/NNS/O are/VBP/O closed/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Smalling/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O accounts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O canceled/VBN/O checks/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O he/PRP/O 'd/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O give/VB/O out/RP/O his/PRP$/O current/JJ/O account/NN/O numbers/NNS/O ././O
