Avondale/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Orleans/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O received/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 23/CD/O million/CD/O contract/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O enlarge/VB/O by/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O the/DT/O capacity/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O auxiliary/JJ/O oiler/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O award/NN/O results/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O exercising/VBG/O of/IN/O an/DT/O option/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O earlier/JJR/O contract/NN/O it/PRP/O awarded/VBD/O Avondale/NNP/B-ORG ././O
