Hoechst/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O stop/VB/O producing/VBG/O fertilizer/NN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O because/IN/O of/IN/O continued/VBN/O losses/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O bleak/JJ/O outlook/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O chemical/NN/O concern/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O close/VB/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O remaining/JJ/O fertilizer/NN/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Oberhausen/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O the/DT/O fall/NN/O of/IN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Hoechst/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O fertilizer/NN/O market/NN/O faces/VBZ/O overcapacity/NN/O in/IN/O Western/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O rising/JJ/O imports/NNS/O from/IN/O East/JJ/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC countries/NNS/O and/CC/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O declining/VBG/O demand/NN/O ././O
