The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG rejected/VBD/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O that/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON sought/VBD/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE flag/NN/O from/IN/O desecration/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O vote/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O 11/CD/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG lawmakers/NNS/O voted/VBD/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O position/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O victory/NN/O for/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O opposed/VBD/O the/DT/O amendment/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O intrusion/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O can/MD/O support/VB/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O flag/NN/O without/IN/O changing/VBG/O the/DT/O American/NNP/O Constitution/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Majority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Mitchell/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Maine/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O defuse/VB/O pressure/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O amendment/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O House/NNP/B-ORG Speaker/NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Foley/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Wash/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O had/VBD/O arranged/VBN/O for/IN/O lawmakers/NNS/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O a/DT/O statute/NN/O barring/VBG/O flag/NN/O desecration/NN/O before/IN/O voting/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O change/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O law/NN/O without/IN/O his/PRP$/O signature/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O only/RB/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O can/MD/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O flag/NN/O adequately/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O June/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG threw/VBD/O out/RP/O the/DT/O conviction/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE man/NN/O who/WP/O set/VBD/O a/DT/O flag/NN/O afire/RB/O during/IN/O a/DT/O 1984/CD/O demonstration/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O engaging/VBG/O in/IN/O political/JJ/O expression/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O protected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O ././O
