Alusuisse/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ;/:/O the/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O hired/VBN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O help/VB/O identify/VB/O bidders/NNS/O ././O
Alusuisse/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Swiss/NNP/B-ORG Aluminium/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Zurich/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O aluminum/NN/O ,/,/O chemicals/NNS/O and/CC/O packaging/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
Consolidated/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O 1988/CD/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O makes/VBZ/O aluminum/NN/O sheet/NN/O and/CC/O foil/NN/O products/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O Hannibal/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Jackson/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tenn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O rolling/NN/O mills/NNS/O and/CC/O recycles/VBZ/O aluminum/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Bens/NNP/B-GPE Run/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O W.Va/NNP/B-GPE ././O
