LEBANESE/JJ/O LAWMAKERS/NNS/O APPROVED/VBD/O a/DT/O peace/NN/O plan/NN/O but/CC/O Aoun/NNP/B-PERSON rejected/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O
As/IN/O rescuers/NNS/O pressed/VBD/O their/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O after/IN/O finding/VBG/O a/DT/O survivor/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O collapsed/VBN/O freeway/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-LOC Francisco/NNP/I-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/O girded/VBD/O for/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O commuters/NNS/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O routes/NNS/O ravaged/VBN/O by/IN/O last/JJ/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O tremor/NN/O ././O
Estimates/NNS/O of/IN/O damage/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O ,/,/O visited/VBN/O Friday/NNP/O by/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O topped/VBD/O $/$/O 5/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O baseball/NN/O commissioner/NN/O announced/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O game/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Giants/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Athletics/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O resume/VB/O until/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
THE/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O IS/VBZ/O REQUIRED/NNP/O to/TO/O notify/VB/O foreign/JJ/O dictators/NNS/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O coup/NN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
Under/IN/O guidelines/NNS/O included/VBN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O exchange/NN/O of/IN/O letters/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG panel/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE must/MD/O inform/VB/O foreign/JJ/O dictators/NNS/O of/IN/O plans/NNS/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O endanger/VB/O their/PRP$/O lives/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O existence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O became/VBD/O known/VBN/O after/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON disclosed/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O seven/CD/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG senators/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O example/NN/O of/IN/O congressional/JJ/O requirements/NNS/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O contends/VBZ/O contribute/VBP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O failure/NN/O of/IN/O covert/JJ/O actions/NNS/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON conceded/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O requirement/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O affect/VB/O a/DT/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O lend/VB/O only/JJ/O minor/JJ/O support/NN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O month/NN/O 's/POS/O failed/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O oust/VB/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O aides/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O shuttle/NN/O Atlantis/NNP/O 's/POS/O crew/NN/O prepared/VBD/O to/TO/O return/VB/O to/TO/O Earth/NNP/B-LOC today/NN/O several/JJ/O hours/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O than/IN/O planned/VBN/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O high/JJ/O winds/NNS/O forecast/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O landing/NN/O site/NN/O at/IN/O Edwards/NNP/O Air/NNP/O Force/NNP/O Base/NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O five/CD/O astronauts/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O stowed/VBD/O gear/NN/O and/CC/O tested/VBD/O the/DT/O spacecraft/NN/O 's/POS/O steering/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O unconcerned/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O touchy/JJ/O weather/NN/O expected/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Mojave/NNP/I-LOC Desert/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Commonwealth/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O issued/VBD/O a/DT/O declaration/NN/O giving/VBG/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE six/CD/O months/NNS/O to/TO/O deliver/VB/O on/IN/O pledges/NNS/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O apartheid/NN/O or/CC/O face/VB/O new/JJ/O reprisals/NNS/O ././O
Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON alone/RB/O dissented/VBD/O ././O
East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE leadership/NN/O vowed/VBD/O swift/JJ/O action/NN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O travel/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O West/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O pledge/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Communist/NNP/O rulers/NNS/O ,/,/O tens/NNS/O of/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O staged/VBD/O marches/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O to/TO/O demand/VB/O democratic/JJ/O freedoms/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Leipzig/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 500/CD/O people/NNS/O met/VBD/O with/IN/O local/JJ/O party/NN/O officials/NNS/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O internal/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG convicted/VBD/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O Alcee/NNP/B-PERSON Hastings/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O eight/CD/O impeachment/NN/O articles/NNS/O ,/,/O removing/VBG/O him/PRP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O bench/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O marked/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE official/NN/O was/VBD/O impeached/VBN/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O a/DT/O jury/NN/O had/VBD/O acquitted/VBN/O him/PRP/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Garcia/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O were/VBD/O found/VBN/O guilty/JJ/O by/IN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O jury/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/O extorting/VBG/O $/$/O 76,000/CD/O from/IN/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O return/NN/O for/IN/O official/JJ/O acts/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE Democrat/NNP/O ././O
Authorities/NNP/O in/IN/O Honduras/NNP/B-GPE launched/VBD/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O cause/NN/O of/IN/O Saturday/NNP/O 's/POS/O crash/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Honduran/JJ/O jetliner/NN/O that/WDT/O killed/VBD/O 132/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 146/CD/O people/NNS/O aboard/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG 727/CD/O ,/,/O en/IN/O route/NN/O to/TO/O Honduras/NNP/B-GPE from/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE via/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O smashed/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O hills/NNS/O outside/IN/O Tegucigalpa/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O it/PRP/O approached/VBD/O the/DT/O capital/NN/B-GPE 's/POS/O airport/NN/O in/IN/O high/JJ/O winds/NNS/O and/CC/O low/JJ/O clouds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O holding/VBG/O what/WP/O an/DT/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Shamir/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O intense/JJ/O telephone/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O in/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O bridge/VB/O differences/NNS/O over/IN/O Mideast/JJ/B-LOC peace/NN/O moves/NNS/O ././O
Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O Contra/NNP/O rebels/NNS/O ambushed/VBD/O two/CD/O trucks/NNS/O carrying/VBG/O troops/NNS/O in/IN/O northern/JJ/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O killing/VBG/O 18/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O soldiers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O incident/NN/O occurred/VBN/O Saturday/NNP/O night/NN/O ././O
Died/VBN/O :/:/O Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON Hayes/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 79/CD/O ,/,/O former/JJ/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Saturday/NNP/O ,/,/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Canaan/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Conn/NNP/B-GPE ././O
