Jurors/NNP/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE cleared/VBD/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON Hershhenson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ;/:/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Pagones/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ;/:/O and/CC/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Vadas/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Dean/NNP/B-PERSON Ciporkin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O engineers/NNS/O with/IN/O Cordis/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Cordis/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O medical/JJ/O devices/NNS/O ,/,/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O plead/VB/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O felony/NN/O and/CC/O misdemeanor/NN/O charges/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O pacemakers/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 5.7/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O fines/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O costs/NNS/O ././O
Cordis/NNP/B-ORG sold/VBD/O its/PRP$/O pacemaker/NN/O operations/NNS/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O to/TO/O Telectronics/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
