Manhattan/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Conway/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O elected/VBN/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O two/CD/O principal/JJ/O insurance/NN/O subsidiaries/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O succeeds/VBZ/O Paul/NNP/B-PERSON P./NNP/I-PERSON Aniskovich/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O other/JJ/O business/NN/O interests/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Conway/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 42/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O elected/VBN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Harry/NNP/B-PERSON Rossi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 69/CD/O ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O remains/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Conway/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O investment/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Union/NNP/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Cincinnati/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Union/NNP/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG bought/VBD/O a/DT/O 54/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O an/DT/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Central/NNP/B-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O accept/VB/O the/DT/O Manhattan/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG presidency/NN/O ././O
