Vickers/NNP/B-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O United/NNP/B-GPE Kingdom/NNP/I-GPE defense/NN/O and/CC/O engineering/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O unit/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE financier/NN/O Ron/NNP/B-PERSON Brierley/NNP/I-PERSON raised/VBD/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O Friday/NNP/O to/TO/O 15.02/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O about/RB/O 14.6/CD/O %/NN/O Thursday/NNP/O and/CC/O from/IN/O 13.7/CD/O %/NN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O latest/JJS/O purchase/NN/O follows/VBZ/O small/JJ/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O holdings/NNS/O made/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O five/CD/O months/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O May/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Brierley/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O stake/NN/O shrank/VBD/O to/TO/O 8.7/CD/O %/NN/O after/IN/O ranging/VBG/O between/IN/O 9/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O 11/CD/O %/NN/O for/IN/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Ron/NNP/B-PERSON Brierley/NNP/I-PERSON clearly/RB/O views/VBZ/O our/PRP$/O company/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O investment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Vickers/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O spokesman/NN/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O speculation/NN/O that/IN/O Industrial/NNP/B-ORG Equity/NNP/I-ORG might/MD/O use/VB/O its/PRP$/O interest/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O platform/NN/O to/TO/O launch/VB/O a/DT/O hostile/JJ/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Vickers/NNP/B-ORG makes/VBZ/O tanks/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE army/NN/O ,/,/O Rolls/NNP/O Royce/NNP/O cars/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O marine/JJ/O and/CC/O medical/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
