I/PRP/O was/VBD/O appalled/VBN/O to/TO/O read/VB/O the/DT/O misstatements/NNS/O of/IN/O facts/NNS/O in/IN/O your/PRP$/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O editorial/NN/O ``/``/O Colombia/NNP/O 's/POS/O Brave/NNP/O Publisher/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
This/DT/O information/NN/O was/VBD/O gleaned/VBN/O from/IN/O your/PRP$/O own/JJ/O news/NN/O stories/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
Past/JJ/O Colombian/JJ/O government/NN/O tolerance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O narcotraficantes/FW/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O lords/NNS/O '/POS/O history/NN/O of/IN/O wiping/VBG/O out/RP/O leftists/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hinterlands/NNS/O ././O
Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Poulin/NNP/I-PERSON Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/I-GPE Calif./NNP/I-GPE
I/PRP/O suggest/VBP/O that/IN/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O other/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE news/NN/O publications/NNS/O of/IN/O like/JJ/O mind/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O should/MD/O put/VB/O its/PRP$/O money/NN/O where/WRB/O its/PRP$/O mouth/NN/O is/VBZ/O :/:/O Lend/VB/O computer/NN/O equipment/NN/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O that/IN/O damaged/VBN/O at/IN/O El/NNP/B-ORG Espectador/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O buy/VB/O ad/NN/O space/NN/O ,/,/O publish/VB/O stories/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O bylines/NNS/O of/IN/O El/NNP/B-ORG Espectador/NNP/I-ORG journalists/NNS/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O an/DT/O arrangement/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O worked/VBN/O out/RP/O to/TO/O ``/``/O sponsor/VB/O ''/''/O El/NNP/B-ORG Espectador/NNP/I-ORG journalists/NNS/O and/CC/O staff/NN/O by/IN/O paying/VBG/O for/IN/O added/VBN/O security/NN/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O exclusive/JJ/O stories/NNS/O ././O
Reward/VB/O El/NNP/B-ORG Espectador/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG courage/NN/O with/IN/O real/JJ/O support/NN/O ././O
Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Evans/NNP/I-PERSON
