When/WRB/O Rune/NNP/B-PERSON Andersson/NNP/I-PERSON set/VBD/O out/RP/O to/TO/O revive/VB/O flagging/JJ/O Swedish/JJ/O conglomerate/NN/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG AB/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O spurned/VBD/O the/DT/O advice/NN/O of/IN/O trendy/JJ/O management/NN/O consultants/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O All/DT/O these/DT/O consultants/NNS/O kept/VBD/O coming/VBG/O around/RP/O telling/VBG/O us/PRP/O we/PRP/O should/MD/O concentrate/VB/O on/IN/O high/JJ/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O electronics/NNS/O or/CC/O biotechnology/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O get/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O mature/JJ/O basic/JJ/O industries/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON recalls/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O going/VBG/O against/IN/O the/DT/O grain/NN/O has/VBZ/O never/RB/O bothered/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Stroking/VBG/O his/PRP$/O trademark/NN/O white/JJ/O goatee/NN/O during/IN/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O diminutive/JJ/O Swede/NN/O quips/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O lucky/JJ/O for/IN/O us/PRP/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O market/NN/O thinks/VBZ/O what/WP/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O doing/VBG/O is/VBZ/O crazy/JJ/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O much/JJ/O competition/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O anxious/JJ/O to/TO/O strengthen/VB/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O balance/NN/O sheet/NN/O ././O
Characteristically/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O waste/VB/O much/JJ/O time/NN/O getting/VBG/O started/VBD/O ././O
On/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG directors/NNS/O announced/VBD/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O spin/VB/O off/RP/O two/CD/O big/JJ/O divisions/NNS/O --/:/O minerals/NNS/O processing/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O building/NN/O and/CC/O distribution/NN/O --/:/O as/RB/O separately/RB/O quoted/VBN/O companies/NNS/O on/IN/O Stockholm/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ././O
At/IN/O current/JJ/O market/NN/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O twin/JJ/O public/JJ/O offerings/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O would/MD/O add/VB/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O Swedish/JJ/O kronor/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 386/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O coffers/NNS/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O board/NN/O had/VBD/O also/RB/O been/VBN/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O approve/VB/O a/DT/O SKr1.5/NNS/O billion/CD/O international/JJ/O offering/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG shares/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O share/NN/O issue/NN/O --/:/O intended/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG better/RBR/O known/VBN/O among/IN/O international/JJ/O investors/NNS/O --/:/O was/VBD/O postponed/VBN/O until/IN/O market/NN/O conditions/NNS/O stabilize/VBP/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O say/VBP/O ././O
Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O internationally/RB/O traded/VBN/O ``/``/O Bfree/NNP/O ''/''/O series/NN/O stock/NN/O plunged/VBD/O SKr29/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 4.48/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O SKr205/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 31.65/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O volatile/JJ/O trading/NN/O Monday/NNP/O in/IN/O Stockholm/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O shares/NNS/O regained/VBD/O SKr20/NNS/O ,/,/O closing/VBG/O at/IN/O SKr225/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O confident/JJ/O that/IN/O taking/VBG/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O public/NN/O will/MD/O help/VB/O erase/VB/O the/DT/O ``/``/O conglomerate/JJ/O stigma/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O held/VBN/O down/RP/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O share/NN/O price/NN/O ././O
Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O remain/VB/O the/DT/O dominant/JJ/O shareholder/NN/O with/IN/O stakes/NNS/O of/IN/O slightly/RB/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O both/DT/O units/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O spinoff/NN/O should/MD/O solve/VB/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O family/NN/O foundation/NN/O set/VBN/O up/RP/O by/IN/O late/JJ/O founder/NN/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Dunker/NNP/I-PERSON controls/VBZ/O 59/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O voting/NN/O shares/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O foundation/NN/O bylaws/NNS/O require/VBP/O the/JJ/O entire/NN/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG stake/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O open/JJ/O market/NN/O if/IN/O control/NN/O drops/VBZ/O below/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O possibility/NN/O had/VBD/O crept/VBN/O closer/RBR/O as/IN/O repeated/VBN/O new/JJ/O share/NN/O offerings/NNS/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O rapid/JJ/O growth/NN/O steadily/RB/O diluted/VBD/O the/DT/O foundation/NN/O 's/POS/O holding/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O growth/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O shopping/NN/O spree/NN/O ,/,/O during/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O bought/VBN/O and/CC/O sold/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 100/CD/O companies/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O additions/NNS/O were/VBD/O barely/RB/O profitable/JJ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O not/RB/O outright/JJ/O loss/NN/O makers/NNS/O ././O
Applying/VBG/O prowess/NN/O gained/VBN/O during/IN/O earlier/JJR/O stints/NNS/O at/IN/O appliance/NN/O maker/NN/O AB/NNP/B-ORG Electrolux/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O loyal/JJ/O lieutenants/NNS/O aggressively/RB/O stripped/VBN/O away/RB/O dead/JJ/O wood/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O got/VBD/O quick/JJ/O results/NNS/O ././O
Between/IN/O 1985/CD/O and/CC/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O sales/NNS/O multipled/VBD/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O times/NNS/O and/CC/O pretax/JJ/O profit/NN/O surged/VBD/O almost/RB/O twelvefold/JJ/O ././O
Many/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O expect/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O owns/VBZ/O 1.7/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O named/VBN/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O new/JJ/O chairman/NN/O when/WRB/O Ernst/NNP/B-PERSON Herslow/NNP/I-PERSON steps/NNS/O down/RB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O promotion/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O alter/VB/O a/DT/O management/NN/O style/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON describes/VBZ/O as/IN/O ``/``/O being/VBG/O the/DT/O driving/VBG/O force/NN/O leading/VBG/O the/DT/O troops/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O managing/VBG/O by/IN/O sitting/VBG/O back/RB/O with/IN/O a/DT/O cigar/NN/O waiting/VBG/O for/IN/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O me/PRP/O ideas/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O boldest/JJS/O move/NN/O yet/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG joined/VBD/O forces/NNS/O with/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Noranda/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O hostile/NN/O takeover/NN/O of/IN/O another/DT/O big/JJ/O Canadian/JJ/O mining/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O Falconbridge/NNP/B-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O certainly/RB/O like/VBP/O what/WP/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O seen/VBN/O so/RB/O far/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG still/RB/O must/MD/O clear/VB/O some/DT/O tough/JJ/O hurdles/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON acknowledges/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O mining/NN/O division/NN/O ``/``/O will/MD/O be/VB/O busy/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O while/NN/O digesting/VBG/O its/PRP$/O recent/JJ/O expansion/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Booming/JJ/O metals/NNS/O prices/NNS/O have/VBP/O fueled/VBN/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O profit/NN/O surge/NN/O ,/,/O raising/VBG/O mining/NN/O 's/POS/O share/NN/O of/IN/O pretax/JJ/O profit/NN/O to/TO/O 68/CD/O %/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O loss/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O ././O
But/CC/O analysts/NNS/O caution/VBP/O an/DT/O expected/VBN/O fall/NN/O in/IN/O metal/NN/O prices/NNS/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O could/MD/O slow/VB/O profit/NN/O growth/NN/O ././O
Mining/NN/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O remain/VB/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O main/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O its/PRP$/O chances/NNS/O of/IN/O success/NN/O will/MD/O likely/RB/O hinge/VB/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O well/RB/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG manages/VBZ/O to/TO/O cooperate/VB/O with/IN/O Noranda/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O Falconbridge/NNP/B-ORG venture/NN/O ././O
Noranda/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG each/DT/O came/VBD/O close/RB/O to/TO/O winning/VBG/O Falconbridge/NNP/B-ORG alone/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O successful/JJ/O joint/NN/O bid/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O Noranda/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O prefer/VB/O to/TO/O break/VB/O up/RP/O Falconbridge/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Swedes/NNS/O --/:/O relatively/RB/O inexperienced/JJ/O in/IN/O international/JJ/O mining/NN/O operations/NNS/O --/:/O could/MD/O have/VB/O problems/NNS/O holding/VBG/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O with/IN/O a/DT/O much/RB/O bigger/JJR/O partner/NN/O like/IN/O Noranda/NNP/B-ORG operating/VBG/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O home/NN/O turf/NN/O ././O
Falconbridge/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O operating/VBG/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O form/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O such/JJ/O partnerships/NNS/O are/VBP/O common/JJ/O in/IN/O mining/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O problems/NNS/O or/CC/O conflict/NN/O of/IN/O interest/NN/O or/CC/O risk/NN/O of/IN/O cheating/VBG/O by/IN/O a/DT/O partner/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O president/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O more/RBR/O important/JJ/O ,/,/O both/DT/O companies/NNS/O share/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O belief/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O coming/JJ/O renaissance/NN/O of/IN/O base/NN/O industries/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O the/DT/O 1980s/CD/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O of/IN/O consumption/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O '90s/CD/O will/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O investment/NN/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Andersson/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O whole/NN/O of/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O the/DT/O industrialized/JJ/O world/NN/O is/VBZ/O suffering/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O breakdown/NN/O in/IN/O infrastructure/NN/O investment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O change/VB/O ././O
And/CC/O investment/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O word/NN/O for/IN/O base/NN/O metals/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O most/JJS/O other/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O Trelleborg/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O ././O
