Ing/NNP/O ././O
An/DT/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O factories/NNS/O are/VBP/O already/RB/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O the/DT/O machine/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O available/JJ/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC by/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O this/DT/O means/VBZ/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Europeans/NNS/O will/MD/O have/VB/O these/DT/O machines/NNS/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O offices/NNS/O before/RB/O Americans/NNS/O do/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Executives/NNS/O at/IN/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O earnings/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O steadily/RB/O sliding/VBG/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O acknowledged/VBN/O that/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O lagged/VBN/O at/IN/O getting/VBG/O new/JJ/O technology/NN/O to/TO/O market/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Davis/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O machines/NNS/O could/MD/O steal/VB/O some/DT/O sales/NNS/O away/RB/O from/IN/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O own/JJ/O minicomputers/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O would/MD/O bring/VB/O new/JJ/O sales/NNS/O among/IN/O professionals/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O engineers/NNS/O ,/,/O stockbrokers/NNS/O and/CC/O medical/JJ/O doctors/NNS/O ././O
Although/IN/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O profits/NNS/O tumbled/VBD/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O restructuring/NN/O last/JJ/O fall/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O introduction/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O products/NNS/O will/MD/O begin/VB/O to/TO/O bear/VB/O fruit/NN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O earnings/NNS/O rebound/NN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O fulfill/VB/O its/PRP$/O promise/NN/O to/TO/O deliver/VB/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O machines/NNS/O by/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
Depending/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O type/NN/O of/IN/O software/NN/O and/CC/O peripherals/NNS/O used/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O machines/NNS/O can/MD/O serve/VB/O either/CC/O as/IN/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O computer/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O network/NN/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O terminals/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O a/DT/O role/NN/O usually/RB/O filled/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O minicomputer/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O technical/JJ/O workstation/NN/O or/CC/O as/IN/O a/DT/O very/RB/O fast/JJ/O personal/JJ/O computer/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O continue/VB/O making/VBG/O its/PRP$/O LSX/NNP/B-ORG minicomputer/NN/O line/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O machines/NNS/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O around/RB/O $/$/O 16,250/CD/O on/IN/O average/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/O Intel/NNP/B-ORG 486/CD/O chip/NN/O can/MD/O process/VB/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O instructions/NNS/O per/IN/O second/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O MIPS/NNP/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Intel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O previous/JJ/O 386/CD/O chip/NN/O could/MD/O handle/VB/O only/RB/O 3/CD/O to/TO/O 6/CD/O MIPS/NNS/O ././O
