The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG rejected/VBD/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O that/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON sought/VBD/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE flag/NN/O from/IN/O desecration/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O vote/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O 11/CD/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG lawmakers/NNS/O voted/VBD/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O position/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O victory/NN/O for/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O opposed/VBD/O the/DT/O amendment/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O intrusion/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O law/NN/O without/IN/O his/PRP$/O signature/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O only/RB/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O can/MD/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O flag/NN/O adequately/RB/O ././O
