Weirton/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Weirton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O W./NNP/B-GPE Va./NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O $/$/O 60.3/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proceeds/NNS/O were/VBD/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O prepay/VB/O the/DT/O remaining/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O note/NN/O outstanding/JJ/O to/TO/O National/NNP/B-ORG Intergroup/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG ././O
