They/PRP/O graze/VBP/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Farmers/NNP/I-ORG Market/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O combination/NN/O gourmet/NN/O food/NN/O court/NN/O and/CC/O grocery/NN/O store/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O a/DT/O pianist/NN/O accompanies/VBZ/O the/DT/O noon/NN/O fashion/NN/O show/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O selection/NN/O of/IN/O dreamy/JJ/O melodies/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O beautiful/JJ/O look/NN/O of/IN/O wool/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O croons/VBZ/O the/DT/O show/NN/O 's/POS/O narrator/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O slightly/RB/O Victorian/JJ/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O influence/NN/O .../:/O ././O ''/''/O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O squat/JJ/O office/NN/O buildings/NNS/O that/WDT/O ring/VBP/O Fashion/NNP/B-FAC Island/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O the/DT/O odds/NNS/O are/VBP/O good/JJ/O that/IN/O someone/NN/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O fleeced/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O like/VB/O these/DT/O industrial/JJ/O parks/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Kacy/NNP/B-PERSON McClelland/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O postal/JJ/O inspector/NN/O who/WP/O specializes/VBZ/O in/IN/O mail/NN/O fraud/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O call/VBP/O them/PRP/O fraud/NN/O farms/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Welcome/UH/O to/TO/O that/DT/O welter/NN/O of/IN/O contradictions/NNS/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE ././O
This/DT/O city/NN/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 70,000/CD/O is/VBZ/O known/VBN/O for/IN/O sunshine/NN/O ,/,/O yachts/NNS/O and/CC/O rich/JJ/O residents/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O fraud/NN/O capital/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O dubbed/VBN/O by/IN/O investigators/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE ``/``/I-GPE Cote/NNP/I-GPE de/IN/I-GPE Fraud/NNP/I-GPE ''/''/I-GPE ././O
Clearly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O existence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O lures/NNS/O the/DT/O latter/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O places/NNS/O renowned/VBN/O for/IN/O breeding/VBG/O bunco/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O the/DT/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE neighborhood/NN/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC ``/``/I-LOC Maggot/NNP/I-LOC Mile/NNP/I-LOC ''/''/I-LOC and/CC/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE flashy/JJ/O strip/NN/O of/IN/O casinos/NNS/O ,/,/O invariably/RB/O offer/VBP/O fast/JJ/O cars/NNS/O ,/,/O high/JJ/O rollers/NNS/O ,/,/O glamorous/JJ/O women/NNS/O and/CC/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O sunshine/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O hear/VB/O much/JJ/O about/IN/O unusual/JJ/O concentrations/NNS/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O in/IN/O Green/NNP/B-GPE Bay/NNP/I-GPE or/CC/O Buffalo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Con/NN/O men/NNS/O hate/VBP/O snow/NN/O ././O
Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE fits/VBZ/O the/DT/O scam/NN/O artists/NNS/O '/POS/O specifications/NNS/O perfectly/RB/O ././O
What/WP/O more/JJR/O could/MD/O a/DT/O con/JJ/O man/NN/O in/IN/O search/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O easy/JJ/O life/NN/O ask/VB/O for/IN/O ?/./O
Nothing/NN/O seems/VBZ/O hard/RB/O here/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O breezes/NNS/O are/VBP/O soft/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O waves/NNS/O lap/VBP/O gently/RB/O and/CC/O the/DT/O palm/NN/O trees/NNS/O sway/VBP/O lazily/RB/O ././O
Nightlife/NN/O is/VBZ/O plentiful/JJ/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O ostentation/NN/O is/VBZ/O appreciated/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O Blondes/NNS/O ,/,/O cocaine/NN/O and/CC/O Corvettes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O mutters/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O McClelland/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O after/IN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O rich/JJ/O image/NN/O of/IN/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE also/RB/O helps/VBZ/O lend/VB/O the/DT/O con/NN/O artists/NNS/O '/POS/O operation/NN/O an/DT/O air/NN/O of/IN/O respectability/NN/O ././O
``/``/O One/CD/O reason/NN/O they/PRP/O use/VBP/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O sounds/VBZ/O swankier/JJR/O than/IN/O most/JJS/O addresses/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Katz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O who/WP/O ,/,/O until/IN/O recently/RB/O ,/,/O headed/VBD/O a/DT/O multi-agency/JJ/O Southern/NNP/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC fraud/NN/O task/NN/O force/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O known/VBN/O in/IN/O Rhode/NNP/B-GPE Island/NNP/I-GPE for/IN/O having/VBG/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O rich/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Because/IN/O only/RB/O a/DT/O fraction/NN/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O are/VBP/O ever/RB/O prosecuted/VBN/O ,/,/O nobody/NN/O really/RB/O knows/VBZ/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O money/NN/O bogus/JJ/O telemarketing/NN/O operators/NNS/O really/RB/O harvest/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O heard/VBN/O that/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O $/$/O 40/CD/O billion/CD/O taken/VBN/O in/RP/O nationwide/JJ/O by/IN/O boiler/NN/O rooms/NNS/O every/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O McClelland/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O true/JJ/O ,/,/O Orange/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O investors/NNS/O range/VBP/O from/IN/O elderly/JJ/O widows/NNS/O to/TO/O affluent/JJ/O professionals/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O one/CD/O ingenious/JJ/O recent/JJ/O example/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE boiler/NN/O room/NN/O ,/,/O prospective/JJ/O investors/NNS/O in/IN/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG were/VBD/O allegedly/RB/O told/VBN/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O precious/JJ/O metals/NNS/O was/VBD/O insured/VBN/O against/IN/O losses/NNS/O ``/``/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O employees/NNS/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O dishonesty/NN/O ,/,/O destruction/NN/O or/CC/O disappearance/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O an/DT/O indictment/NN/O handed/VBD/O up/RP/O by/IN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Thus/RB/O falsely/RB/O reassured/VBN/O ,/,/O investors/NNS/O sent/VBD/O $/$/O 11.4/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE company/NN/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O diverted/VBN/O to/TO/O unauthorized/JJ/O uses/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O indictment/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Jones/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O representing/VBG/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON O./NNP/I-PERSON Kelly/NNP/I-PERSON Sr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O client/NN/O denies/VBZ/O that/IN/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O any/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O defraud/VB/O investors/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O were/VBD/O some/DT/O business/NN/O deals/NNS/O that/WDT/O went/VBD/O bad/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Jones/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O no/DT/O intent/NN/O to/TO/O defraud/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE operations/NNS/O differ/VBP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE boiler/NN/O rooms/NNS/O in/IN/O style/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O in/IN/O dollars/NNS/O ././O
Traditionally/RB/O ,/,/O boiler/NN/O rooms/NNS/O operate/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O cheap/JJ/O ,/,/O since/IN/O few/JJ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O any/DT/O ,/,/O customers/NNS/O ever/RB/O visit/VBP/O their/PRP$/O offices/NNS/O ././O
Indeed/UH/O ,/,/O the/DT/O name/NN/O derives/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O tendency/NN/O among/IN/O telemarketing/NN/O scammers/NNS/O to/TO/O rent/VB/O cheap/JJ/O basement/NN/O space/NN/O ,/,/O near/IN/O the/DT/O boiler/NN/O room/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Katz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O the/DT/O interesting/JJ/O thing/NN/O about/IN/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE operations/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O give/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O the/DT/O indulgence/NN/O of/IN/O beautiful/JJ/O offices/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O plush/JJ/O furnishings/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O we/PRP/O go/VBP/O there/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O quite/RB/O different/JJ/O from/IN/O these/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE places/NNS/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O sandwiches/NNS/O are/VBP/O spread/VBN/O out/RP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O table/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O picking/VBG/O their/PRP$/O noses/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE operators/NNS/O also/RB/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O indulge/VB/O themselves/PRP/O privately/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Valentine/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O five/CD/O counts/NNS/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O drove/VBD/O a/DT/O leased/VBN/O Mercedes/NNS/B-ORG and/CC/O lived/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O expensive/JJ/O home/NN/O on/IN/O Lido/NNP/B-LOC Isle/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O an/DT/O island/NN/O in/IN/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O harbor/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O investigators/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O amazing/JJ/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O that/WDT/O goes/VBZ/O up/IN/O their/PRP$/O nose/NN/O ,/,/O out/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O dog/NN/O track/NN/O or/CC/O to/TO/O the/DT/O tables/NNS/O in/IN/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Katz/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
All/DT/O this/DT/O talk/NN/O of/IN/O boiler/NN/O rooms/NNS/O and/CC/O fraud/NN/O is/VBZ/O unnerving/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O legitimate/JJ/O business/NN/O element/NN/O ././O
Vincent/NNP/B-PERSON M/NNP/I-PERSON Ciavarella/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O regional/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O Property/NNP/B-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O insists/VBZ/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O of/IN/O any/DT/O bogus/JJ/O telemarketers/NNS/O operating/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1.6/CD/O million/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O office/NN/O space/NN/O around/IN/O Fashion/NNP/B-FAC Island/NNP/I-FAC that/IN/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O leases/VBZ/O for/IN/O Irvine/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O owner/NN/O and/CC/O developer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ciavarella/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O rejected/VBN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O prospective/JJ/O tenants/NNS/O who/WP/O provided/VBD/O ``/``/O incomplete/JJ/O ''/''/O financial/JJ/O information/NN/O and/CC/O acknowledges/VBZ/O that/IN/O illegitimate/JJ/O operators/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O easily/RB/O detectable/JJ/O ././O
''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Investigators/NNS/O stress/VBP/O that/IN/O building/NN/O owners/NNS/O are/VBP/O victims/NNS/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O since/IN/O boiler/NN/O rooms/NNS/O often/RB/O leave/VBP/O without/IN/O paying/VBG/O rent/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Luehrs/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Newport/NNP/I-ORG Harbor/NNP/I-ORG Area/NNP/I-ORG Chamber/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O calls/VBZ/O boiler/NN/O rooms/NNS/O a/DT/O ``/``/O negative/JJ/O we/PRP/O wish/VBP/O we/PRP/O could/MD/O get/VB/O rid/VB/O of/IN/O ././O ''/''/O
Actually/RB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O much/JJ/O negative/JJ/O publicity/NN/O about/IN/O this/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O insists/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O except/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O who/WP/O write/VBP/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lancaster/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O deputy/JJ/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Dallas/NNP/B-GPE bureau/NN/O ././O
