Four/CD/O workers/NNS/O at/IN/O GTE/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG headquarters/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O diagnosed/VBN/O as/IN/O having/VBG/O hepatitis/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O city/NN/O health/NN/O officials/NNS/O are/VBP/O investigating/VBG/O whether/IN/O a/DT/O cafeteria/NN/O worker/NN/O may/MD/O have/VB/O exposed/VBN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O GTE/NNP/B-ORG employees/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O viral/JJ/O infection/NN/O ,/,/O company/NN/O and/CC/O city/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O four/CD/O cases/NNS/O were/VBD/O all/DT/O reported/VBN/O to/TO/O GTE/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O medical/JJ/O director/NN/O and/CC/O state/NN/O and/CC/O local/JJ/O health/NN/O authorities/NNS/O ././O
GTE/NNP/B-ORG shut/VBD/O down/RP/O its/PRP$/O cafeteria/NN/O Tuesday/NNP/O afternoon/NN/O after/IN/O testing/NN/O determined/VBD/O that/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O one/CD/O cafeteria/NN/O worker/NN/O employed/VBN/O by/IN/O GTE/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O private/JJ/O food/NN/O vending/VBG/O contractor/NN/O ,/,/O ARA/NNP/B-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O suffering/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O strain/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O virus/NN/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O cafeteria/NN/O remains/VBZ/O closed/JJ/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Andrew/NNP/B-PERSON McBride/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O city/NN/O health/NN/O director/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O staff/NN/O suspects/VBZ/O the/DT/O hepatitis/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O can/MD/O be/VB/O highly/RB/O contagious/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O spread/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O cafeteria/NN/O worker/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O virus/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O exact/JJ/O strain/NN/O of/IN/O hepatitis/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O cafeteria/NN/O worker/NN/O contracted/VBD/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O determined/VBN/O but/CC/O should/MD/O be/VB/O known/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Dr./NNP/B-PERSON McBride/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Hepatitis/NNP/O A/NNP/O ,/,/O considered/VBN/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O dangerous/JJ/O strain/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O virus/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O confirmed/VBN/O in/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O one/CD/O GTE/NNP/B-ORG employee/NN/O ,/,/O company/NN/O and/CC/O city/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
GTE/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O began/VBD/O posting/VBG/O warning/NN/O notices/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O threat/NN/O to/TO/O exposure/NN/O Wednesday/NNP/O morning/NN/O at/IN/O various/JJ/O places/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O GTE/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Mattausch/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
