The/DT/B-ORG Food/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O American/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O recall/VB/O certain/JJ/O generic/JJ/O drugs/NNS/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O Quantum/NNP/B-ORG Pharmics/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O in/IN/O Amityville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Quantum/NNP/B-ORG stopped/VBD/O shipping/VBG/O the/DT/O drugs/NNS/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O following/VBG/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O investigation/NN/O regarding/VBG/O information/NN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O supplied/VBD/O to/TO/O obtain/VB/O three/CD/O drug/NN/O approvals/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG requested/VBD/O the/DT/O recall/NN/O of/IN/O Quantum/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O mioxidil/NN/O tablets/NNS/O ,/,/O chlorazepate/NN/O dipotassium/NN/O tablets/NNS/O and/CC/O meclofenamate/NN/O sodium/NN/O capsules/NNS/O because/IN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O production/NN/O runs/NNS/O submitted/VBN/O for/IN/O testing/NN/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG approval/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O each/DT/O case/NN/O misrepresented/VBD/O as/IN/O much/RB/O larger/JJR/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O actually/RB/O was/VBD/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O recall/VB/O four/CD/O other/JJ/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O trazadone/NN/O ,/,/O doxepin/NN/O ,/,/O diazepam/NN/O and/CC/O lorazapam/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O of/IN/O concerns/NNS/O about/IN/O data/NNS/O submitted/VBN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O original/JJ/O approval/NN/O applications/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG ././O
No/DT/O safety/NN/O problems/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O products/NNS/O are/VBP/O known/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
An/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG spokesperson/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O drugs/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O available/JJ/O under/IN/O other/JJ/O brand/NN/O names/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O suspending/VBG/O production/NN/O and/CC/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O 21/CD/O of/IN/O Quantum/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O generic/JJ/O drug/NN/O products/NNS/O pending/VBG/O the/DT/O completion/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O exhaustive/JJ/O internal/JJ/O audit/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O temporarily/RB/O closed/VBD/O Quantum/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O internal/JJ/O investigation/NN/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ongoing/JJ/O inquiry/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG composite/JJ/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG rose/VBD/O 75/CD/O cents/NNS/O to/TO/O $/$/O 105/CD/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
