``/``/O When/WRB/O elephants/NNS/O start/VB/O fighting/VBG/O ,/,/O ants/NNS/O get/VB/O killed/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Murray/NNP/B-PERSON Riese/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O co-owner/NN/O of/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Restaurants/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE franchisee/NN/O for/IN/O Pizza/NNP/B-ORG Hut/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Roy/NNP/B-ORG Rogers/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O chains/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O hamburger/NN/O and/CC/O pizza/NN/O outlets/NNS/O saturate/VB/O one/CD/O area/NN/O after/IN/O another/DT/O ,/,/O franchisers/NNS/O are/VBP/O struggling/VBG/O desperately/RB/O for/IN/O market/NN/O share/NN/O ,/,/O slashing/VBG/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O stepping/VBG/O up/RP/O costly/JJ/O promotions/NNS/O ././O
Though/NNP/O Charisma/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O are/VBP/O up/IN/O slightly/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Harty/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O profits/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O flat/JJ/O or/CC/O lower/JJR/O ././O
That/WDT/O brought/VBD/O a/DT/O chain/NN/O reaction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O situation/NN/O was/VBD/O further/RB/O aggravated/VBN/O early/RB/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O McDonald/NN/B-ORG 's/VBZ/I-ORG set/VBN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O heat/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O discounting/VBG/O by/IN/O offering/VBG/O coupons/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O some/DT/O franchisees/NNS/O are/VBP/O running/VBG/O hard/RB/O just/RB/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O even/RB/O ,/,/O laying/VBG/O off/RP/O middle/JJ/O managers/NNS/O and/CC/O working/VBG/O harder/RB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O less/JJR/O ././O
Joe/NNP/B-PERSON Mack/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O district/NN/O manager/NN/O for/IN/O Cormack/NNP/B-ORG Enterprises/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Burger/NNP/B-ORG King/NNP/I-ORG operator/NN/O in/IN/O Omaha/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Neb./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O discounting/VBG/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O prevalent/JJ/O that/IN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O have/VB/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O more/JJR/O customers/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O sales/JJ/O level/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O almost/RB/O as/IN/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O doing/VBG/O extra/JJ/O work/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O away/RP/O the/DT/O food/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Alan/NNP/B-PERSON D'Agosto/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Panda/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Inc./NN/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O operator/NN/O of/IN/O Arby/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG restaurants/NNS/O in/IN/O Omaha/NN/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O All/DT/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O doing/VBG/O is/VBZ/O keeping/VBG/O the/DT/O customers/NNS/O coming/VBG/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O increasing/VBG/O sales/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O The/DT/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O overbuilt/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O so/RB/O crowded/VBN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Wendy/NN/B-ORG 's/VBZ/I-ORG in/IN/O Columbus/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O doing/VBG/O well/RB/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O doing/VBG/O well/RB/O at/IN/O someone/NN/O else/RB/O 's/POS/O expense/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Simply/RB/O put/VBN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O enough/JJ/O business/NN/O for/IN/O every/DT/O store/NN/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O ././O
``/``/O McDonald/VB/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG has/VBZ/O also/RB/O been/VBN/O running/VBG/O negative/JJ/O all/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O analyst/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Spokesmen/NNP/O for/IN/O Wendy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG and/CC/O McDonald/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG criticized/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Rohs/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O calculations/NNS/O ././O
Profits/NNS/O of/IN/O franchisees/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O higher/JJR/O since/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1970s/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ././O
Big/JJ/O franchise/NN/O groups/NNS/O ``/``/O can/MD/O ride/VB/O out/IN/O the/DT/O storm/NN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O longer/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Harty/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Burger/NNP/B-ORG King/NNP/I-ORG operator/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O prolonged/VBN/O price/NN/O pressures/NNS/O are/VBP/O driving/VBG/O a/DT/O wedge/NN/O between/IN/O some/DT/O franchisers/NNS/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O franchisees/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Morrissey/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Kentucky/NNP/B-ORG Fried/NNP/I-ORG Chicken/NNP/I-ORG franchisee/NN/O ,/,/O notes/VBZ/O that/IN/O most/JJS/O franchise/NN/O owners/NNS/O must/MD/O absorb/VB/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O expenses/NNS/O without/IN/O any/DT/O cut/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O royalties/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O must/MD/O pay/VB/O franchisers/NNS/O ././O
Franchisees/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O go/VB/O along/RP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O franchiser/NN/O 's/POS/O discounting/VBG/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O courts/NNS/O have/VB/O held/VBN/O that/IN/O antitrust/JJ/O considerations/NNS/O are/VBP/O outweighed/VBN/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O cases/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O consumers/NNS/O from/IN/O deceptive/JJ/O marketing/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O franchisees/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O on/IN/O good/JJ/O terms/NNS/O with/IN/O franchisers/NNS/O ,/,/O routinely/RB/O go/VB/O along/RP/O with/IN/O promotions/NNS/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Riese/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Restaurants/NNP/I-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O resisted/VBD/O on/IN/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O maybe/RB/O you/PRP/O would/MD/O never/RB/O get/VB/O that/DT/O telephone/NN/O call/VB/O about/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O franchise/NN/O ././O
