In/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O humor/NN/O has/VBZ/O long/RB/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O way/NN/O to/TO/O express/VB/O political/JJ/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O laughing/VBG/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O new/JJ/O leader/NN/O Egon/NNP/B-PERSON Krenz/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O contradictory/JJ/O figure/NN/O that/IN/O nobody/NN/O has/VBZ/O even/RB/O come/VBN/O up/RP/O with/IN/O any/DT/O good/JJ/O jokes/NNS/O about/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O clear/JJ/O feelings/NNS/O about/IN/O someone/NN/O before/RB/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O make/VB/O jokes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O an/DT/O East/NNP/O German/NNP/O mother/NN/O of/IN/O two/CD/O who/WP/O loves/VBZ/O swapping/VBG/O political/JJ/O barbs/NNS/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O friends/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O With/IN/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O we/PRP/O just/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O what/WP/O to/TO/O expect/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O appear/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O broad/JJ/O changes/NNS/O either/RB/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE ADN/NNP/B-ORG news/NN/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON spoke/VBD/O to/TO/O Soviet/JJ/O leader/NN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON by/IN/O telephone/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O and/CC/O acknowledged/VBD/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE could/MD/O learn/VB/O from/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O glasnost/NN/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Already/RB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON started/VBD/O overhauling/VBG/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/VBZ/I-GPE heavily/RB/O censored/VBN/O and/CC/O notoriously/RB/O boring/VBG/O news/NN/O media/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O day/NN/O after/RB/O he/PRP/O took/VBD/O office/NN/O ,/,/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O television/NN/O broke/VBD/O into/IN/O regular/JJ/O programming/NN/O to/TO/O launch/VB/O a/DT/O talk/NN/O show/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O viewers/NNS/O call/VBP/O in/RP/O questions/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O panel/NN/O of/IN/O officials/NNS/O to/TO/O answer/VB/O ././O
``/``/O For/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O life/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O sure/JJ/O whether/IN/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O listening/VBG/O to/TO/O our/PRP$/O news/NN/O or/CC/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O television/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Other/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O easing/VBG/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O travel/NN/O for/IN/O East/NNS/O Germans/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O whether/IN/O such/JJ/O moves/NNS/O can/MD/O win/VB/O back/RB/O the/DT/O confidence/NN/O of/IN/O East/NNS/O Germans/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O taken/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O thousands/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O to/TO/O demand/VB/O democratic/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O depends/VBZ/O largely/RB/O on/IN/O whether/IN/O they/PRP/O feel/VBP/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O trust/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
And/CC/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O not/RB/O only/RB/O closely/RB/O identified/VBN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O mentor/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O also/RB/O blamed/VBN/O for/IN/O ordering/VBG/O violent/JJ/O police/NN/O action/NN/O against/IN/O protesters/NNS/O this/DT/O month/NN/O and/CC/O for/IN/O praising/VBG/O China/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O sending/VBG/O tanks/NNS/O against/IN/O student/NN/O demonstrators/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O hope/VBP/O he/PRP/O grows/VBZ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Rainer/NNP/B-PERSON Eppelmann/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Protestant/JJ/O pastor/NN/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O most/RBS/O important/JJ/O thing/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O have/VB/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Although/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O dedicated/VBN/O to/TO/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE conservative/JJ/O vein/NN/O of/IN/O communism/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O much/JJ/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O style/NN/O that/WDT/O sets/VBZ/O him/PRP/O apart/RB/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O party/NN/O comrades/NNS/O ././O
Unlike/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O tended/VBD/O to/TO/O lecture/VB/O people/NNS/O about/IN/O socialist/JJ/O values/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON enjoys/VBZ/O asking/VBG/O questions/NNS/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O first/JJ/O actions/NNS/O as/IN/O leader/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O visit/VB/O a/DT/O gritty/JJ/O machine/NN/O factory/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O outskirts/NNS/O of/IN/O Berlin/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O wander/VB/O among/IN/O the/DT/O workers/NNS/O --/:/O a/FW/O la/FW/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O later/RB/O shown/VBN/O on/IN/O television/NN/O ,/,/O fielding/VBG/O questions/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O one/CD/O point/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O asked/VBD/O a/DT/O worker/NN/O whether/IN/O he/PRP/O thought/VBD/O East/NNS/O Germans/NNS/O were/VBD/O fleeing/VBG/O the/DT/O country/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O restrictive/JJ/O travel/NN/O policies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O worker/NN/O 's/POS/O tart/JJ/O reply/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O just/JJ/O travel/NN/O ././O
People/NNS/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O sense/NN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O ignoring/VBG/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O problems/NNS/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O society/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O exchange/NN/O was/VBD/O all/DT/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O remarkable/JJ/O in/IN/O that/IN/O authorities/NNS/O released/VBD/O television/NN/O footage/NN/O to/TO/O Western/JJ/O news/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O same/JJ/O tendency/NN/O toward/IN/O openness/NN/O impressed/VBD/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O visiting/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE congressmen/NNS/O this/DT/O spring/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Ronnie/NNP/B-PERSON Flippo/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ala./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O delegation/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O particularly/RB/O impressed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ready/JJ/O admission/NN/O that/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE needed/VBD/O to/TO/O change/VB/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O very/RB/O tough/JJ/O man/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O one/CD/O who/WP/O 's/VBZ/O also/RB/O open/JJ/O to/TO/O arguments/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O adds/VBZ/O an/DT/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O Chancellor/NNP/O Helmut/NNP/B-PERSON Kohl/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O another/DT/O side/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Born/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Baltic/JJ/O town/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O area/NN/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O dedicated/VBN/O his/PRP$/O life/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O party/NN/O apparatus/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O moved/VBD/O quickly/RB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O ranks/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O help/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O patron/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O emerged/VBD/O as/IN/O the/DT/O heir/NN/O apparent/JJ/O ././O
Barbara/NNP/B-PERSON Donovan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O expert/NN/O on/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE at/IN/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Munich/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O project/VB/O a/DT/O smooth/JJ/O image/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O she/PRP/O doubts/VBZ/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O true/JJ/O reformer/JJ/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O only/RB/O limited/JJ/O room/NN/O for/IN/O maneuver/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Communist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ruling/NN/O Politburo/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Against/IN/O this/DT/O background/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O East/NNP/O German/NNP/O leader/NN/O must/MD/O move/VB/O quickly/RB/O to/TO/O shore/VB/O up/RP/O his/PRP$/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O standing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O sudden/JJ/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O movement/NN/O ,/,/O together/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O steady/JJ/O outflow/NN/O of/IN/O citizens/NNS/O escaping/VBG/O through/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O plunged/VBN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O into/IN/O its/PRP$/O deepest/JJS/O political/JJ/O crisis/NN/O since/IN/O an/DT/O anti-Soviet/JJ/O workers/NNS/O '/POS/O uprising/NN/O in/IN/O 1953/CD/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O honeymoon/NN/O period/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O Western/JJ/O diplomat/NN/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O sharp/JJ/O and/CC/O quick/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O diplomat/NN/O adds/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O several/JJ/O things/NNS/O going/VBG/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O East/NNP/O German/NNP/O economy/NN/O is/VBZ/O strong/RB/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O East/JJ/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC nations/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O average/JJ/O East/NNS/O Germans/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O puzzle/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Either/NNP/O way/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O with/IN/O how/WRB/O quickly/RB/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O changed/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O doctor/NN/O was/VBD/O among/IN/O dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O milling/VBG/O through/IN/O East/JJ/B-GPE Berlin/JJ/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE Gethsemane/NNP/B-ORG Church/NNP/I-ORG Saturday/NNP/O morning/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O walls/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O church/NN/O are/VBP/O covered/VBN/O with/IN/O leaflets/NNS/O ,/,/O news/NN/O clippings/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O handwritten/JJ/O notes/NNS/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O political/JJ/O opposition/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O come/VB/O here/RB/O to/TO/O read/VB/O the/DT/O walls/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O doctor/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O information/NN/O I/PRP/O still/RB/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Television/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O carried/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O report/NN/O on/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE main/JJ/O wallpaper/NN/O factory/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O production/NN/O ././O
East/NNS/O Germans/NNS/O remember/VBP/O a/DT/O comment/NN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O by/IN/O Kurt/NNP/B-PERSON Hager/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O top/NN/O ideologist/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O just/RB/O because/IN/O a/DT/O neighbor/NN/O hangs/VBZ/O new/JJ/O wallpaper/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O reason/NN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O your/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O whether/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O intended/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O funny/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE shopkeeper/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O But/CC/O everyone/NN/O I/PRP/O know/VBP/O laughed/VBD/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
