Lynch/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Lynch/NNP/B-ORG Telephone/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Western/NNP/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Mexico/NNP/I-ORG Telephone/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O plus/IN/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 24/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O debt/NN/O ././O
Western/NNP/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Mexico/NNP/I-ORG Telephone/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Silver/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O net/JJ/O income/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.9/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O phone/NN/O company/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O service/NN/O area/NN/O of/IN/O 15,000/CD/O square/JJ/O miles/NNS/O in/IN/O southwest/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE Mexico/NNP/I-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O partner/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wireline/JJ/O cellular/JJ/O franchise/NN/O covering/VBG/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O western/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE Mexico/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O represents/VBZ/O Lynch/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O entry/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
