General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O signed/VBD/O a/DT/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O developers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Ocean/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG project/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O phase/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O power/NN/O plant/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O Burrillville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O R.I/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O second/JJ/O portion/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O the/DT/O following/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
GE/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Power/NNP/B-ORG Generation/NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O will/MD/O operate/VB/O and/CC/O maintain/VB/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O upon/IN/O its/PRP$/O completion/NN/O ././O
