Chambers/NNP/B-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Security/NNP/B-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O purchased/VBN/O two/CD/O security/NN/O concerns/NNS/O in/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O will/MD/O add/VB/O $/$/O 2.1/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O ././O
Purchase/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O businesses/NNS/O serving/VBG/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Fort/NNP/B-GPE Lauderdale/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O West/NNP/B-GPE Palm/NNP/I-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Fla./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O by/IN/O Chambers/NNS/B-ORG to/TO/O expand/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O growing/JJ/O security/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
