Lep/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O holds/VBZ/O a/DT/O 62.42/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Profit/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O courses/NNS/O of/IN/O action/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O having/VBG/O ``/``/O active/JJ/O control/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O filing/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Lep/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O course/NN/O of/IN/O action/NN/O may/MD/O include/VB/O acquiring/VBG/O some/DT/O or/CC/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Profit/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O already/RB/O own/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O noted/VBD/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O determined/VBN/O any/DT/O specific/JJ/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O transaction/NN/O ././O
Lep/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O affiliates/NNS/O currently/RB/O control/VBP/O 3,513,072/CD/O Profit/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 62.42/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O filing/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Profit/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Valley/NNP/B-GPE Stream/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O air/NN/O freight/NN/O forwarding/NN/O concern/NN/O ././O
