This/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O story/NN/O about/IN/O suckers/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O are/VBP/O suckers/NNS/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Blodgett/NNP/I-PERSON agrees/VBZ/O --/:/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O know/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O obvious/JJ/O pitch/NN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O lure/NN/O of/IN/O big/JJ/O returns/NNS/O ././O
Everyone/NN/O is/VBZ/O vulnerable/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Harper/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O associate/JJ/O regional/JJ/O administrator/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O owner/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O since/RB/O pleaded/VBN/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O state/NN/O and/CC/O federal/JJ/O fraud/NN/O charges/NNS/O ,/,/O confided/VBD/O to/TO/O investors/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O secret/JJ/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O Amoco/NNP/B-ORG Oil/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O location/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O wells/NNS/O was/VBD/O confidential/JJ/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O civil/JJ/O suit/NN/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O court/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE comptroller/NN/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O adds/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O mystery/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O phoned/VBD/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O updates/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O investment/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O ``/``/O funny/JJ/O things/NNS/O that/WDT/O happened/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O well/RB/O that/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Conservative/JJ/O appearances/NNS/O make/VBP/O people/NNS/O think/VB/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O conservative/JJ/O investment/NN/O ././O
Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Wenz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Phoenix/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O promise/NN/O of/IN/O unrealistic/JJ/O returns/NNS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O him/PRP/O leery/JJ/O ././O
Psychologists/NNS/O say/VB/O isolated/VBN/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O discuss/VB/O their/PRP$/O investments/NNS/O with/IN/O others/NNS/O are/VBP/O particularly/RB/O at/IN/O risk/NN/O for/IN/O fraud/NN/O ././O
Scam/NN/O artists/NNS/O seek/VBP/O out/RP/O such/JJ/O people/NNS/O --/:/O or/CC/O try/VB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O victims/NNS/O isolate/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O ././O
The/VB/O Lyneses/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O of/IN/O Powder/NNP/B-GPE Springs/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Ga./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O have/VBP/O filed/VBN/O suit/NN/O in/IN/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O court/NN/O against/IN/O Stuart/NNP/B-ORG James/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O alleging/VBG/O fraud/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O awaiting/VBG/O an/DT/O arbitration/NN/O proceeding/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O broker/NN/O took/VBD/O them/PRP/O out/RB/O for/IN/O lunch/NN/O frequently/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O urged/VBD/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O refer/VB/O their/PRP$/O friends/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O also/RB/O lost/VBD/O money/NN/O ././O
Experts/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O whatever/WDT/O a/DT/O person/NN/O 's/POS/O particular/JJ/O weak/JJ/O point/NN/O ,/,/O timing/NN/O is/VBZ/O crucial/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O obviously/RB/O also/RB/O more/RBR/O susceptible/JJ/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O need/VBP/O money/NN/O -/:/O retirees/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O their/PRP$/O fixed/JJ/O income/NN/O or/CC/O parents/NNS/O fretting/VBG/O over/IN/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O child/NN/O 's/POS/O college/NN/O expenses/NNS/O ././O
Nick/NNP/B-PERSON Cortese/NNP/I-PERSON thinks/VBZ/O that/IN/O 's/VBZ/O what/WP/O happened/VBD/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O investment/NN/O is/VBZ/O worth/JJ/O about/RB/O $/$/O 130/CD/O today/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Brannigan/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O staff/NN/O reporter/NN/O in/IN/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE bureau/NN/O ././O
