Terry/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Haines/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O formerly/RB/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O elected/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O position/NN/O of/IN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O North/JJ/O American/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O of/IN/O this/DT/O plastics/NNS/O concern/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O Larry/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Kushkin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O North/JJ/O American/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O international/JJ/O automotive/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O another/DT/O new/JJ/O position/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O remains/VBZ/O an/DT/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O new/JJ/O position/NN/O reflects/VBZ/O ``/``/O the/DT/O growing/VBG/O importance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O automotive/JJ/O market/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O A./NNP/B-ORG Schulman/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG high/JJ/O performance/NN/O plastic/NN/O materials/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Gordon/NNP/B-PERSON Trimmer/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O succeed/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Haines/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O Canadian/NNP/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Kushkin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O former/JJ/O position/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O being/VBG/O filled/VBN/O at/IN/O this/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
