The/DT/O most/RBS/O recent/JJ/O OTC/NNP/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O statistics/NNS/O were/VBD/O compiled/VBN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O day/NN/O the/DT/O Nasdaq/NNP/B-ORG composite/JJ/O index/NN/O slid/VBD/O 3/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG tumbled/VBD/O 7/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O it/PRP/O happens/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Nasdaq/NNP/B-ORG composite/NN/O did/VBD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O for/IN/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O initial/JJ/O plunge/NN/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O figures/NNS/O reported/VBN/O by/IN/O brokerage/NN/O and/CC/O securities/NNS/O clearing/NN/O firms/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Dealers/NNP/I-ORG include/VBP/O only/RB/O those/DT/O trades/NNS/O completed/VBN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O settled/VBN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O trades/NNS/O that/WDT/O occurred/VBD/O on/IN/O that/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Gene/NNP/B-PERSON Finn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O economist/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O NASD/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Generally/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O takes/VBZ/O five/CD/O business/NN/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O transfer/VB/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O steps/NNS/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O a/DT/O trade/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O total/JJ/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Nasdaq/NNP/B-ORG stocks/NNS/O as/IN/O of/IN/O mid-October/NNP/O was/VBD/O 237.1/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 223.7/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O but/CC/O well/RB/O below/IN/O the/DT/O record/JJ/O level/NN/O of/IN/O 279/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O established/VBN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ././O
Generally/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O short/JJ/O seller/NN/O expects/VBZ/O a/DT/O fall/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O stock/NN/O 's/POS/O price/NN/O and/CC/O aims/VBZ/O to/TO/O profit/VB/O by/IN/O selling/VBG/O borrowed/VBN/O shares/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O replaced/VBN/O later/RB/O ;/:/O the/DT/O short/JJ/O seller/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O the/DT/O replacement/NN/O shares/NNS/O bought/VBN/O later/RB/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O those/DT/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O sold/VBN/O ././O
Among/IN/O 2,412/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O OTC/NNP/O issues/NNS/O ,/,/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O rose/VBD/O to/TO/O 196.8/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O from/IN/O 185.7/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 2,379/CD/O stocks/NNS/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ././O
Big/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O with/IN/O large/JJ/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O gains/NNS/O as/IN/O of/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O included/VBD/O First/NNP/B-ORG Executive/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Intel/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Campeau/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O LIN/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Short/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Executive/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O insurance/NN/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O rose/VBD/O 55/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 3.8/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Intel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O jumped/VBD/O 42/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Campeau/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O increased/VBD/O 62/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Meritor/NNP/B-ORG Savings/NNP/I-ORG again/RB/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O dubious/JJ/O honor/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O the/DT/O OTC/NNP/O stock/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O position/NN/O on/IN/O Nasdaq/NNP/O ././O
Meritor/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O headed/VBN/O the/DT/O list/NN/O since/IN/O May/NNP/O ././O
First/NNP/B-ORG Executive/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O troubled/VBD/O Valley/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE were/VBD/O next/JJ/O in/IN/O line/NN/O ././O
Short/JJ/O selling/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O necessarily/RB/O bad/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O overall/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
Shorted/JJ/O shares/NNS/O must/MD/O eventually/RB/O be/VB/O replaced/VBN/O through/IN/O buying/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O some/DT/O stocks/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O arbitrage/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O investor/NN/O may/MD/O seek/VB/O to/TO/O profit/VB/O during/IN/O some/DT/O takeover/NN/O situations/NNS/O by/IN/O buying/VBG/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O one/CD/O company/NN/O involved/VBN/O and/CC/O shorting/VBG/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
Two/CD/O big/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O takeover/NN/O activity/NN/O saw/VBD/O their/PRP$/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O surge/NN/O ././O
Short/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O depositary/JJ/O receipts/NNS/O of/IN/O Jaguar/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O target/NN/O of/IN/O both/DT/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O doubled/VBD/O ././O
Short/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O 1,327/CD/O non-NMS/JJ/B-ORG securities/NNS/O totaled/VBD/O 40.3/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O almost/RB/O 38/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O in/IN/O 1,310/CD/O issues/NNS/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O October/NNP/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O represents/VBZ/O 1.04/CD/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O average/JJ/O daily/JJ/O trading/NN/O volume/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O smaller/JJR/O stocks/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O reporting/NN/O period/NN/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O 0.94/CD/O day/NN/O a/DT/O month/NN/O ago/RB/O ././O
Among/IN/O bigger/JJR/O OTC/NNP/O stocks/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O figures/NNS/O represent/VBP/O 2.05/CD/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O average/JJ/O daily/JJ/O volume/NN/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O 2.14/CD/O days/NNS/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O adjacent/JJ/O tables/NNS/O show/VBP/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O a/DT/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O position/NN/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 50,000/CD/O shares/NNS/O existed/VBD/O as/IN/O of/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O or/CC/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O short/JJ/O position/NN/O change/NN/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 25,000/CD/O shares/NNS/O since/IN/O Sept./NNP/O 15/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O see/VB/O accompanying/JJ/O tables/NNS/O --/:/O WSJ/NNP/O Oct./NNP/O 25/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
