Israel/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O launched/VBN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O prove/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Palestine/NNP/I-ORG Liberation/NNP/I-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O practice/VB/O terrorism/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O thus/RB/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O break/VB/O off/RP/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O buying/VBG/O the/DT/O Israeli/JJ/O argument/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Arafat/NNP/B-PERSON publicly/RB/O renounced/VBD/O terrorism/NN/O Dec./NNP/O 15/CD/O ,/,/O satisfying/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE precondition/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O direct/JJ/O ``/``/O dialogue/NN/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG ././O
A/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE counterterrorism/NN/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O experts/NNS/O are/VBP/O studying/VBG/O the/DT/O Israeli/JJ/O list/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O independent/JJ/O evidence/NN/O linking/VBG/O Fatah/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O any/DT/O acts/NNS/O of/IN/O terrorism/NN/O since/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 15/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O specific/JJ/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG group/NN/O that/WDT/O Mr./NNP/O Arafat/NNP/B-PERSON heads/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O So/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O this/DT/O list/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O change/VB/O our/PRP$/O view/NN/O ././O
Israel/NNP/B-GPE wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O end/VB/O the/DT/O dialogue/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O our/PRP$/O analysts/NNS/O take/VBP/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O view/NN/O than/IN/O theirs/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Israeli/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Yitzhak/NNP/B-PERSON Shamir/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O top/JJ/O adviser/NN/O on/IN/O counterterrorism/NN/O ,/,/O Yigal/NNP/B-PERSON Carmon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O here/RB/O Monday/NNP/O to/TO/O present/VB/O the/DT/O report/NN/O to/TO/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O reporters/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carmon/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O also/RB/O presented/VBD/O the/DT/O list/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O to/TO/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Brown/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Ambassador/NNP/O to/TO/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Separately/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Israeli/JJ/O government/NN/O had/VBD/O provided/VBN/O its/PRP$/O correspondent/NN/O in/IN/O Jerusalem/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O different/JJ/O documents/NNS/O that/IN/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O prove/VB/O the/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O conducting/VBG/O terrorism/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O occupied/JJ/O Arab/JJ/O territories/NNS/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O seen/VBN/O copies/NNS/O of/IN/O those/DT/O papers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O the/DT/O dialogue/NN/O was/VBD/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O that/IN/O Arafat/NNP/B-PERSON or/CC/O the/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O stop/VB/O terrorism/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O continued/JJ/O terrorism/NN/O ,/,/O what/WP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O logical/JJ/O conclusion/NN/O ?/./O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Carmon/NNP/B-PERSON asked/VBD/O ././O
Israel/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O long/RB/O claimed/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Arafat/NNP/B-PERSON never/RB/O meant/VBD/O to/TO/O renounce/VB/O terrorism/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O lieutenants/NNS/O reserved/VBD/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O press/VB/O ``/``/O armed/JJ/O struggle/NN/O ''/''/O against/IN/O the/DT/O Jewish/JJ/O state/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O Jerusalem/NNP/B-GPE says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O backing/VBG/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O contention/NN/O with/IN/O detailed/JJ/O accounts/NNS/O of/IN/O alleged/JJ/O terrorist/JJ/O acts/NNS/O and/CC/O plans/NNS/O linked/VBN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Arafat/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
It/PRP/O blames/VBZ/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O these/DT/O on/IN/O Fatah/NN/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O accusations/NNS/O come/VBP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O delicate/JJ/O time/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O about/RP/O talks/NNS/O between/IN/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Palestinian/JJ/O representatives/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O letter/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O from/IN/O Israeli/NNP/O Foreign/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Moshe/NNP/B-PERSON Arens/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O restating/VBG/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O previous/JJ/O objection/NN/O to/TO/O negotiating/VBG/O with/IN/O any/DT/O Palestinian/NNP/O tied/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Deciding/VBG/O what/WP/O constitutes/VBZ/O ``/``/O terrorism/NN/O ''/''/O can/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O legalistic/JJ/O exercise/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE defines/VBZ/O it/PRP/O as/IN/O ``/``/O premediated/JJ/O ,/,/O politically/RB/O motivated/JJ/O violence/NN/O perpetrated/VBN/O against/IN/O noncombatant/JJ/O targets/NNS/O by/IN/O subnational/JJ/O groups/NNS/O or/CC/O clandestine/JJ/O state/NN/O agents/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
To/TO/O meet/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE criteria/NNS/O ,/,/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE contended/VBD/O it/PRP/O only/RB/O listed/VBD/O incidents/NNS/O that/WDT/O involved/VBD/O civilians/NNS/O and/CC/O occurred/VBD/O inside/IN/O its/PRP$/O pre-1967/JJ/O borders/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O report/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O incidents/NNS/O Jerusalem/NNP/B-GPE attributes/VBZ/O to/TO/O Fatah/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O bombs/NNS/O and/CC/O Molotov/NNP/O cocktails/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O say/VB/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O satisfied/VBN/O these/DT/O incidents/NNS/O constitute/VBP/O terrorism/NN/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O offshoots/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O intifadah/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Palestinian/JJ/O rebellion/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O occupied/JJ/O territories/NNS/B-LOC ,/,/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O classify/VB/O as/IN/O terrorism/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O presented/VBN/O convincing/JJ/O evidence/NN/O these/DT/O acts/NNS/O were/VBD/O ordered/VBN/O by/IN/O Fatah/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O by/IN/O any/DT/O group/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Arafat/NNP/B-PERSON controls/VBZ/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE terrorism/NN/O experts/NNS/O also/RB/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O highly/RB/O uncertain/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O veracity/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O separate/JJ/O documents/NNS/O leaked/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Some/DT/O supporters/NNS/O of/IN/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE say/NNP/O U.S./VBP/B-GPE policy/NN/O on/IN/O Palestinian/JJ/O terrorism/NN/O is/VBZ/O colored/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O intense/JJ/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O the/DT/O dialogue/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG ././O
But/CC/O State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O accuse/VBP/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O leaking/VBG/O questionable/JJ/O claims/NNS/O to/TO/O embarrass/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
