Directors/NNS/O of/IN/O Bergen/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Den/NNP/B-ORG Norske/NNP/I-ORG Creditbank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O two/CD/O of/IN/O Norway/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leading/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O announced/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O formal/JJ/O merger/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O merger/NN/O would/MD/O create/VB/O Scandinavia/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O seventh/JJ/O largest/JJS/O bank/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O combined/JJ/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O 210/CD/O billion/CD/O Norwegian/JJ/O kroner/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 30.3/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
The/DT/O banks/NNS/O said/VBD/O an/DT/O application/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O concession/NN/O to/TO/O merge/VB/O into/IN/O one/CD/O entity/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O Den/NNP/B-ORG Norske/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG AS/IN/I-ORG was/VBD/O sent/VBN/O Monday/NNP/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O boards/NNS/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O statement/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/JJ/O merger/NN/O agreement/NN/O was/VBD/O considered/VBN/O in/IN/O separate/JJ/O board/NN/O meetings/NNS/O in/IN/O Oslo/NNP/B-GPE Monday/NNP/O ././O
They/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O submitted/VBN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O respective/JJ/O supervisory/JJ/O boards/NNS/O next/IN/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
Extraordinary/JJ/O general/JJ/O meetings/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O held/VBN/O Nov./NNP/O 28/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O decide/VB/O the/DT/O share/NN/O exchange/NN/O ratio/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O merger/NN/O requires/VBZ/O the/DT/O approval/NN/O of/IN/O Norwegian/JJ/O authorities/NNS/O ././O
