He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O argued/VBN/O that/IN/O such/JJ/O presidential/JJ/O power/NN/O is/VBZ/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O rein/VB/O in/RP/O congressional/JJ/O spending/NN/O ././O
Such/PDT/O an/DT/O assertion/NN/O most/RBS/O likely/RB/O would/MD/O bring/VB/O about/RP/O a/DT/O court/NN/O challenge/NN/O from/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG that/WDT/O would/MD/O clarify/VB/O whether/IN/O a/DT/O president/NN/O already/RB/O has/VBZ/O such/JJ/O power/NN/O ././O
White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O Marlin/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzwater/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O confirming/VBG/O comments/NNS/O made/VBN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O by/IN/O Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Quayle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O ``/``/O interested/JJ/O ''/''/O in/IN/O finding/VBG/O a/DT/O suitable/JJ/O test/NN/O case/NN/O ././O
