The/DT/O investment/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O through/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O raise/VB/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Paxus/NN/B-ORG to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O over/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O not/RB/O go/VB/O beyond/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Paxus/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O several/JJ/O ``/``/O well/RB/O developed/JJ/O product/NN/O and/CC/O services/NNS/O relationships/NNS/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE computer/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O these/DT/O links/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O earns/VBZ/O about/RB/O half/PDT/O its/PRP$/O revenue/NN/O overseas/RB/O and/CC/O plans/VBZ/O further/JJ/O expansion/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O majority/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Paxus/NNP/B-ORG currently/RB/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O NZI/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O diluted/VBN/O to/TO/O slightly/RB/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O after/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG acquires/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O interest/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O requires/VBZ/O approval/NN/O from/IN/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Foreign/NNP/B-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Review/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O National/NNP/B-ORG Companies/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O from/IN/O shareholders/NNS/O of/IN/O Paxus/NNP/B-ORG ././O
