The/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Showtime/NNP/B-ORG stake/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O direct/JJ/O slap/NN/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O face/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O one/CD/O senior/JJ/O Time/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O how/WRB/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O cable/NN/O operator/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O the/DT/O weaker/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O networks/NNS/O is/VBZ/O anti-competitive/JJ/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O stronger/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O networks/NNS/O is/VBZ/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O second/RB/O largest/JJS/O ''/''/O cable/NN/O operator/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Kern/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O since/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O merger/NN/O with/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O relations/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O strained/JJ/O ././O
Each/DT/O company/NN/O worries/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O is/VBZ/O becoming/VBG/O too/RB/O powerful/JJ/O and/CC/O too/RB/O vertically/RB/O integrated/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Manhattan/NNP/B-ORG Cable/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O launch/VB/O Showtime/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 1/CD/O to/TO/O over/IN/O 230,000/CD/O subscribers/NNS/O ././O
Showtime/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O also/RB/O accused/VBN/O HBO/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O locking/VBG/O up/RP/O the/DT/O lion/NN/O 's/POS/O share/NN/O of/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O movies/NNS/O by/IN/O signing/VBG/O exclusive/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O with/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O studios/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Showtime/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O continued/VBN/O to/TO/O sign/VB/O new/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O with/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE studios/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O yesterday/NN/O announced/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O buy/VB/O movies/NNS/O from/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O non-exclusive/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O with/IN/O HBO/NNP/B-ORG ././O
