Medieval/JJ/O philosophers/NNS/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O the/DT/O sensible/JJ/O belief/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O more/RBR/O perfect/JJ/O to/TO/O exist/VB/O than/IN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O exist/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O to/TO/O exist/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O matter/NN/O of/IN/O necessity/NN/O was/VBD/O most/RBS/O perfect/JJ/O of/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
His/PRP$/O credentials/NNS/O are/VBP/O excellent/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O task/NN/O ././O
Star/JJ/O lecturer/NN/O at/IN/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O author/NN/O of/IN/O numerous/JJ/O popular/JJ/O books/NNS/O on/IN/O science/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O scourge/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O creationist/JJ/O lobby/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gould/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O perhaps/RB/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/VBZ/O most/RBS/O eminent/JJ/O evolutionary/JJ/O theorist/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O argument/NN/O turns/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O discovery/NN/O in/IN/O 1909/CD/O of/IN/O an/DT/O amazing/JJ/O fossil/NN/O quarry/NN/O high/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O Rockies/NNPS/B-LOC called/VBN/O the/DT/B-LOC Burgess/NNP/I-LOC Shale/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Such/PDT/O an/DT/O embarrassment/NN/O of/IN/O riches/NNS/O was/VBD/O inconceivable/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O discovered/VBD/O the/DT/B-LOC Burgess/NNP/I-LOC Shale/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O one/CD/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Doolittle/NNP/I-PERSON Walcott/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O received/JJ/O Darwinian/JJ/O wisdom/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O animals/NNS/O living/VBG/O so/RB/O long/RB/O ago/RB/O must/MD/O be/VB/O simple/JJ/O in/IN/O design/NN/O ,/,/O limited/JJ/O in/IN/O scope/NN/O and/CC/O ancestral/JJ/O to/TO/O contemporary/JJ/O species/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O until/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1970s/CD/O that/IN/O Cambridge/NNP/B-GPE Prof./NNP/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON Whittington/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O two/CD/O sharp/JJ/O graduate/JJ/O students/NNS/O began/VBD/O to/TO/O publish/VB/O a/DT/O reinterpretation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Burgess/NNP/I-LOC Shale/NNP/I-LOC ././O
One/CD/O was/VBD/O so/RB/O fantastic/JJ/O in/IN/O appearance/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O dubbed/VBN/O Hallucigenia/NNP/O ././O
A/DT/O good/JJ/O deal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O is/VBZ/O boring/JJ/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O the/DT/O endless/JJ/O allusions/NNS/O to/TO/O high/JJ/O and/CC/O pop/JJ/O culture/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O frequent/JJ/O jokes/NNS/O festooning/VBG/O the/DT/O text/NN/O ././O
Interest/NN/O picks/VBZ/O up/RP/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Gould/NNP/B-PERSON gets/VBZ/O around/IN/O to/TO/O discussing/VBG/O the/DT/O meaning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Burgess/NNP/B-LOC oddities/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O theory/NN/O of/IN/O evolution/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O vast/JJ/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O wiped/VBN/O out/RP/O by/IN/O a/DT/O succession/NN/O of/IN/O environmental/JJ/O upheavals/NNS/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O too/RB/O sudden/JJ/O and/CC/O catastrophic/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O normal/JJ/O rules/NNS/O of/IN/O natural/JJ/O selection/NN/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O ././O
Our/PRP$/O mammalian/JJ/O forerunners/NNS/O lucked/VBD/O out/RP/O through/IN/O the/DT/O extraterrestrial/JJ/O impact/NN/O that/WDT/O did/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O dinosaurs/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O small/JJ/O ,/,/O not/RB/O smart/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O ,/,/O by/IN/O contrast/NN/O ,/,/O can/MD/O not/RB/O help/VB/O feeling/NN/O that/IN/O if/IN/O some/DT/O other/JJ/O curiosity/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Burgess/NNP/I-LOC Shale/NNP/I-LOC had/VBD/O survived/VBN/O instead/RB/O ,/,/O beings/NNS/O at/IN/O once/RB/O wiser/JJR/O and/CC/O less/RBR/O boorish/JJ/O than/IN/O Homo/NN/O sapiens/JJ/O might/MD/O have/VB/O eventually/RB/O gained/VBN/O earthly/JJ/O dominion/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Holt/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O columnist/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Literary/NNP/I-ORG Review/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
