What/WP/O defeated/VBD/O General/NNP/O Aoun/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O not/RB/O only/RB/O the/DT/O weight/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Syrian/JJ/O army/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O weight/NN/O of/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O history/NN/O was/VBD/O also/RB/O against/IN/O him/PRP/O ;/:/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O history/NN/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O in/IN/O danger/NN/O of/IN/O repeating/VBG/O ././O
Like/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O however/RB/O unfairly/RB/O ,/,/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O regarded/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Arab/JJ/O world/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O colonial/JJ/O aberration/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O best/JJS/O hope/NN/O of/IN/O acceptance/NN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O neighbours/NNS/O lies/VBZ/O in/IN/O reaching/VBG/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Palestinians/NNPS/O ././O
Like/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O remade/VB/O by/IN/O demography/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Greater/NNP/B-GPE Israel/NNP/I-GPE more/JJR/O than/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O children/NNS/O under/IN/O six/CD/O are/VBP/O Muslims/NNPS/O ././O
Within/IN/O 25/CD/O years/NNS/O Jews/NNPS/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O be/VB/O the/DT/O minority/NN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O neither/CC/O share/VB/O power/NN/O with/IN/O all/PDT/O these/DT/O Arabs/NNS/O nor/CC/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O present/JJ/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O redraw/VB/O its/PRP$/O borders/NNS/O closer/RBR/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O pre-1967/JJ/O Jewish/JJ/O heartland/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O not/RB/O choosing/VBG/O one/CD/O of/IN/O these/DT/O options/NNS/O ,/,/O Israelis/NNPS/O will/MD/O condemn/VB/O themselves/PRP/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Maronites/NNPS/O did/VBD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O perpetual/JJ/O war/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Muslims/NNPS/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O midst/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O so/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O internal/JJ/O erosion/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O state/NN/O ././O
Unlike/IN/O the/DT/O Maronites/NNPS/O ,/,/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Jews/NNPS/O will/MD/O not/RB/O let/VB/O themselves/PRP/O become/VB/O the/DT/O weakest/JJS/O force/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O system/NN/O of/IN/O private/JJ/O armies/NNS/O ;/:/O Jerusalem/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O become/VB/O Belfast/NNP/B-GPE before/IN/O it/PRP/O becomes/VBZ/O Beirut/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O a/DT/O consolation/NN/O to/TO/O draw/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O failure/NN/O of/IN/O General/NNP/O Aoun/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
