``/``/O Lifestyles/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Rich/NNP/O and/CC/O Famous/NNP/O ''/''/O may/MD/O be/VB/O visiting/VBG/O some/DT/O new/JJ/O venues/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O near/JJ/O future/NN/O ././O
Judge/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/I-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Maximum/NNP/I-PERSON Bob/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON Potter/NNP/I-PERSON sentenced/VBN/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Bakker/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O 45/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O big/JJ/O house/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O a/DT/O Beverly/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNP/I-GPE judge/NN/O tucked/VBD/O away/RP/O Zsa/NNP/B-PERSON Zsa/NNP/I-PERSON Gabor/NNP/I-PERSON for/IN/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O plus/CC/O 120/CD/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O work/NN/O with/IN/O homeless/JJ/O women/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bakker/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O sin/NN/O but/CC/O not/RB/O fraud/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O can/MD/O only/RB/O wonder/VB/O who/WP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O lost/JJ/O soul/NN/O chosen/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Celebrity/NNP/O Convict/NNP/O ././O
