Wang/NNP/B-ORG Laboratories/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O $/$/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O reached/VBN/O agreements/NNS/O in/IN/O principle/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 187/CD/O million/CD/O shortly/RB/O ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Miller/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O annual/JJ/O meeting/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O reached/VBN/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O major/JJ/O financial/JJ/O firm/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O for/IN/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O its/PRP$/O domestic/JJ/O equipment/NN/O lease/NN/O portfolio/NN/O and/CC/O that/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG Credit/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O a/DT/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O European/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O unit/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 37/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/DT/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O already/RB/O sold/VBN/O some/DT/O $/$/O 12/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O miscellaneous/JJ/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O disclosed/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O $/$/O 13/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O Compaq/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Stirling/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Scotland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O plant/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON repeated/VBD/O that/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O he/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O another/DT/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O to/TO/O repay/VB/O debt/NN/O and/CC/O reduce/VB/O interest/NN/O costs/NNS/O at/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O minincomputer/JJR/O maker/NN/O in/IN/O Lowell/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass/NNP/B-GPE ././O
