The/DT/O text/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O new/JJ/O policy/NN/O ''/''/O guidelines/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Criminal/NNP/I-ORG Division/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O reprinted/VBN/O nearby/RB/O ././O
Justice/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O a/DT/O replay/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O tactics/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O amounts/VBZ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O extraordinary/JJ/O repudiation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tenure/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE mayoral/JJ/O candidate/NN/O and/CC/O former/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O Rudolph/NNP/B-PERSON Giuliani/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O more/RBR/O inclined/JJ/O to/TO/O gathering/VBG/O scalps/NNS/O than/IN/O understanding/VBG/O markets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O guidelines/NNS/O limit/VBP/O the/DT/O pretrial/JJ/O forfeitures/NNS/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O RICOed/JJ/O defendants/NNS/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O investors/NNS/O ,/,/O clients/NNS/O ,/,/O bankers/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O into/IN/O liquidation/NN/O before/IN/O trial/NN/O when/WRB/O investors/NNS/O yanked/VBD/O their/PRP$/O funds/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O demanded/VBD/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O pre-trial/JJ/O asset/NN/O forfeiture/NN/O ././O
Prosecutors/NNS/O wanted/VBD/O $/$/O 23.8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O forfeiture/NN/O for/IN/O alleged/JJ/O tax/NN/O fraud/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O $/$/O 400,000/CD/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG therefore/RB/O agreed/VBD/O instead/RB/O to/TO/O an/DT/O arrangement/NN/O allowing/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O plea/VB/O to/TO/O charges/NNS/O ``/``/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O to/TO/O dispute/VB/O ''/''/O because/IN/O of/IN/O RICO/NNP/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O plea/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Milken/NNP/B-PERSON loose/JJ/O ././O
Justice/NN/B-ORG has/VBZ/O finally/RB/O recognized/VBN/O its/PRP$/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O abuses/NNS/O ,/,/O thanks/NNS/O largely/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O demands/NNS/O for/IN/O reform/NN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON diGenova/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O salvage/VB/O RICO/NNP/O for/IN/O real/JJ/O criminals/NNS/O ././O
No/DT/O prosecutorial/JJ/O guidelines/NNS/O ,/,/O observed/JJ/O or/CC/O unobserved/JJ/O ,/,/O limit/VBP/O civil/JJ/O RICO/NNP/O cases/NNS/O by/IN/O plaintiffs/NNS/O for/IN/O damages/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O suspect/VBP/O that/IN/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O some/DT/O day/NN/O agree/VB/O that/IN/O only/RB/O the/DT/O complete/JJ/O repeal/NN/O of/IN/O RICO/NNP/O can/MD/O guarantee/VB/O an/DT/O end/NN/O to/TO/O injustices/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O name/NN/O ././O
