The/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE brewing/NN/O and/CC/O retail/JJ/O concern/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O terms/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O is/VBZ/O effective/JJ/O Jan./NNP/O 1/CD/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O approval/NN/O from/IN/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Foreign/NNP/B-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Review/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Cadbury/NNP/B-ORG Schweppes/NNP/I-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O held/VBN/O the/DT/O Australian/JJ/O Pepsi/NNP/B-ORG franchise/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Lion/NNP/B-ORG Nathan/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O PepsiCola/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O PepsiCo/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O why/WRB/O Cadbury/NNP/B-ORG Schweppes/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O no/RB/O longer/RBR/O hold/VB/O the/DT/O franchise/NN/O ././O
