Northeast/NNP/B-ORG Utilities/NNP/I-ORG raised/VBD/O its/PRP$/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O Public/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Hampshire/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O operating/VBG/O under/IN/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O protection/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O $/$/O 2.25/CD/O billion/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.85/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Northeast/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O raised/VBN/O bid/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O supported/VBN/O by/IN/O PS/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Hampshire/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/O official/JJ/O shareholder/NN/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O prelude/NN/O to/TO/O what/WP/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O round/NN/O of/IN/O higher/JJR/O bids/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O groups/NNS/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O utility/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O $/$/O 2.25/CD/O billion/CD/O value/NN/O claimed/VBN/O by/IN/O Northeast/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Hartford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O yet/RB/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O other/JJ/O bidding/VBG/O groups/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O their/PRP$/O offers/NNS/O tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O date/NN/O set/VBN/O for/IN/O revised/JJ/O offers/NNS/O by/IN/O a/DT/O bankruptcy/NN/O court/NN/O judge/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O hearing/NN/O is/VBZ/O set/VBN/O for/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 15/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O participants/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O a/DT/O resolution/NN/O until/IN/O July/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Northeast/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O previous/JJ/O offer/NN/O had/VBD/O proposed/VBN/O that/IN/O equity/NN/O holders/NNS/O receive/VB/O just/RB/O $/$/O 165/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O previous/JJ/O proposal/NN/O had/VBD/O conditioned/VBN/O rate/NN/O limits/NNS/O on/IN/O Seabrook/NNP/B-FAC operations/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O contingencies/NNS/O ././O
Wilbur/NNP/B-PERSON Ross/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O financial/JJ/O adviser/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O equity/NN/O holders/NNS/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Given/VBN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O strong/JJ/O bargaining/NN/O position/NN/O .../:/O we/PRP/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O NU/NNP/B-ORG plan/NN/O provides/VBZ/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O recovery/NN/O available/JJ/O ''/''/O to/TO/O PS/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Hampshire/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG equity/NN/O holders/NNS/O ././O
Officials/NNP/O of/IN/O PS/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Hampshire/NNP/I-ORG could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O filed/VBN/O an/DT/O internal/JJ/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O it/PRP/O valued/VBD/O at/IN/O $/$/O 2.2/CD/O billion/CD/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O require/VB/O 5.5/CD/O %/NN/O rate/NN/O increases/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O plan/NN/O would/MD/O leave/VB/O existing/JJ/O preferred/JJ/O shareholders/NNS/O with/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O a/DT/O 41/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O and/CC/O give/VB/O common/JJ/O shareholders/NNS/O as/RB/O little/JJ/O as/IN/O 13/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
New/NNP/B-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Westborough/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O proposed/VBN/O buying/VBG/O the/DT/O company/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O require/VB/O rate/NN/O increases/NNS/O of/IN/O only/RB/O 4.8/CD/O %/NN/O annually/RB/O for/IN/O seven/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O favored/VBN/O that/DT/O plan/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O bidder/NN/O is/VBZ/O United/NNP/B-ORG Illuminating/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Haven/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 2.2/CD/O billion/CD/O and/CC/O and/CC/O a/DT/O proposal/NN/O for/IN/O seven/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O 5.5/CD/O %/NN/O rate/NN/O increases/NNS/O ././O
