He/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O likely/RB/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O mulitiplier/JJ/O effect/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O stimulating/VBG/O further/JJ/O trade/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O countries/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hotels/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O the/DT/B-ORG Sheraton/NNP/I-ORG Moscow/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O have/VB/O 450/CD/O rooms/NNS/O and/CC/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O an/DT/O estimated/JJ/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O build/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O Russian/JJ/O tavern/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O English/JJ/O pub/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O discotheque/NN/O and/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O and/CC/O Italian/JJ/O restaurants/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Sheraton/NNP/B-ORG announcement/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O hotel/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O in/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O second/JJ/O hotel/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O the/DT/B-ORG Budapest/NNP/I-ORG Hotel/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O constructed/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O site/NN/O even/RB/O closer/RBR/O to/TO/O Red/NNP/B-FAC Square/NNP/I-FAC ././O
Details/NNS/O about/IN/O its/PRP$/O size/NN/O and/CC/O cost/NN/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O been/VBN/O determined/VBN/O ././O
Sheraton/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O ITT/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O hotels/NNS/O ;/:/O Pan/NNP/B-PERSON American/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Pan/NNP/B-ORG Am/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O owners/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O Mossoviet/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O city/NN/O governing/NN/O body/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O national/JJ/O airline/NN/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O account/VBP/O for/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1,000/CD/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O Soviet/JJ/O joint/NN/O ventures/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O announced/VBN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O began/VBD/O encouraging/JJ/O such/JJ/O undertakings/NNS/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Sheraton/NNP/I-ORG Moscow/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O charge/VB/O about/RB/O $/$/O 140/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 150/CD/O a/DT/O day/NN/O for/IN/O each/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O rooms/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O accept/VB/O payment/NN/O only/RB/O in/IN/O currencies/NNS/O that/WDT/O can/MD/O be/VB/O traded/VBN/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O exchange/NN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Sheraton/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O ././O
