Axa/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O also/RB/O maintain/VB/O Farmers/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O manages/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bebear/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O his/PRP$/O remarks/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O breakfast/NN/O meeting/NN/O with/IN/O reporters/NNS/O here/RB/O yesterday/NN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O tour/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O rally/VB/O support/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/JJ/O acquisition/NN/O ././O
Axa/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Farmers/NNP/B-ORG from/IN/O Sir/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O investment/NN/O vehicle/NN/O ,/,/O Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG Investments/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O $/$/O 4.5/CD/O billion/CD/O plus/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Any/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Farmers/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O the/DT/O approval/NN/O of/IN/O insurance/NN/O commissioners/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O nine/CD/O states/NNS/O where/WRB/O Farmers/NNP/B-ORG operates/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Bebear/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O trip/NN/O will/MD/O take/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O Idaho/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE after/IN/O his/PRP$/O stay/NN/O here/RB/O ;/:/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O meet/VB/O with/IN/O insurance/NN/O regulators/NNS/O ,/,/O legislators/NNS/O ,/,/O industry/NN/O excutives/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O press/NN/O ././O
Hearings/NNS/O on/IN/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O acquisition/NN/O application/NN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O set/VBN/O for/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 13/CD/O in/IN/O Idaho/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Nov./NNP/O 20/CD/O in/IN/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Nov./NNP/O 24/CD/O and/CC/O Dec./NNP/O 4/CD/O in/IN/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Dec./NNP/O 11/CD/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O ;/:/O and/CC/O Jan./VB/O 8/CD/O in/IN/O Oregon/NN/B-GPE ././O
Hearings/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O been/VBN/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O insurance/NN/O commissioner/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O hold/VB/O hearings/NNS/O on/IN/O acquisition/NN/O applications/NNS/O ././O
Farmers/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O quick/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O to/TO/O point/VB/O out/RP/O the/DT/O many/JJ/O negative/JJ/O aspects/NNS/O it/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O in/IN/O having/VBG/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O its/PRP$/O parent/NN/O ././O
Those/DT/O credits/NNS/O result/VBP/O because/IN/O of/IN/O taxes/NNS/O that/WDT/O Farmers/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O management/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O paid/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O have/VBP/O ``/``/O proved/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O very/RB/O important/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O exchanges/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Farmers/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bebear/NNP/B-PERSON contended/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O cost/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O exchanges/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O revised/JJ/O structure/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O about/RB/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O described/VBD/O as/IN/O ``/``/O peanuts/NNS/O ././O
