Mobil/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O preparing/VBG/O to/TO/O slash/VB/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O force/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O possibly/RB/O as/RB/O soon/RB/O as/IN/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O individuals/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O strategy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cuts/NNS/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O known/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O centered/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O exploration/NN/O and/CC/O production/NN/O division/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O locating/VBG/O oil/NN/O reserves/NNS/O ,/,/O drilling/VBG/O wells/NNS/O and/CC/O pumping/VBG/O crude/JJ/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O ././O
Employees/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O been/VBN/O notified/VBN/O ././O
Sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O meetings/NNS/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O reductions/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O Friday/NNP/O at/IN/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG offices/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Orleans/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ././O
This/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O round/NN/O of/IN/O cuts/NNS/O by/IN/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O along/RB/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O oil/NN/O producers/NNS/O and/CC/O refiners/NNS/O reduced/VBD/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O force/NN/O by/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1980s/NNS/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O industrywide/JJ/O shakeout/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O company/NN/O spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O reached/VBN/O at/IN/O his/PRP$/O home/NN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O only/RB/O say/VB/O that/IN/O there/EX/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O announcement/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O reduction/NN/O program/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
Individuals/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strategy/NN/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O reducing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE work/NN/O force/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O declining/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE output/NN/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O domestic/JJ/O exploration/NN/O and/CC/O production/NN/O operations/NNS/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 16/CD/O million/CD/O loss/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O comparable/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O operations/NNS/O earned/VBD/O $/$/O 234/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Industrywide/RB/O ,/,/O oil/NN/O production/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O fell/VBD/O by/IN/O 500,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O to/TO/O 7.7/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O eight/CD/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Daily/JJ/O output/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O decline/VB/O by/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O another/DT/O 500,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O were/VBD/O dismayed/JJ/O that/IN/O a/DT/O reference/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O cutbacks/NNS/O was/VBD/O included/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O earnings/NNS/O report/NN/O before/IN/O workers/NNS/O were/VBD/O notified/VBN/O ././O
One/CD/O Mobil/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O charge/NN/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O action/NN/O indicates/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O substantial/JJ/O ''/''/O number/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O involved/VBN/O ././O
Some/DT/O will/MD/O likely/RB/O be/VB/O offered/VBN/O severance/NN/O packages/NNS/O while/IN/O others/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O transferred/VBN/O to/TO/O overseas/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ././O
