When/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG Trinity/NNP/I-ORG Repertory/NNP/I-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG named/VBD/O Anne/NNP/B-PERSON Bogart/NNP/I-PERSON its/PRP$/O artistic/JJ/O director/NN/O last/JJ/O spring/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O theatrical/JJ/O cognoscenti/NNS/O arched/VBD/O a/DT/O collective/JJ/O eyebrow/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O acclaimed/JJ/O creator/NN/O of/IN/O deconstructed/JJ/O dramatic/JJ/O collages/NNS/O that/VBP/O tear/VB/O into/IN/O such/JJ/O sacred/JJ/O texts/NNS/O as/IN/O Rodgers/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Hammerstein/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O South/NNP/O Pacific/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O decidedly/RB/O downtown/JJ/O ././O
Trinity/NNP/B-ORG Rep/NNP/I-ORG meanwhile/RB/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O oldest/JJS/O and/CC/O most/RBS/O respected/JJ/O regional/JJ/O theaters/NNS/O ,/,/O still/RB/O hosting/VBG/O an/DT/O annual/JJ/O ``/``/O A/NNP/O Christmas/NNP/O Carol/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
How/WRB/O would/MD/O this/DT/O bastion/NN/O of/IN/O traditional/JJ/O values/NNS/O fare/VB/O in/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O iconoclastic/JJ/O hands/NNS/O ?/./O
She/PRP/O held/VBD/O her/PRP$/O fire/NN/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O first/JJ/O production/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Trinity/NN/B-ORG earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O season/NN/O ././O
Hers/JJ/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O hand/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O test/VB/O the/DT/O mettle/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O audiences/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O initially/RB/O studied/VBD/O and/CC/O directed/VBD/O in/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O cites/VBZ/O such/JJ/O European/JJ/O directors/NNS/O as/IN/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Stein/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Giorgio/NNP/B-PERSON Strehler/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Ariane/NNP/B-PERSON Mnouchkine/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O influences/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O tends/VBZ/O to/TO/O stage/VB/O her/PRP$/O productions/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Brechtian/JJ/O rigor/NN/O --/:/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O text/NN/O demands/VBZ/O it/PRP/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ././O
And/CC/O Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O considered/VBN/O the/DT/O father/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O socialist/JJ/O realism/NN/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O write/VB/O plays/NNS/O that/WDT/O easily/RB/O lend/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O to/TO/O deliberately/RB/O antirealistic/JJ/O distancing/NN/O techniques/NNS/O ././O
Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O a/DT/O loyal/JJ/O if/IN/O occasionally/RB/O ambivalent/JJ/O proletarian/JJ/O writer/NN/O committed/VBN/O to/TO/O enlightening/VBG/O the/DT/O masses/NNS/O with/IN/O plain/JJ/O speaking/NN/O rooted/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O slightly/RB/O sour/JJ/O version/NN/O of/IN/O Chekhovian/JJ/O humanism/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O ``/``/O Summerfolk/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O penned/VBN/O in/IN/O 1904/CD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O sequel/NN/O to/TO/O Chekhov/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Cherry/NNP/O Orchard/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O lawn/NN/O party/NN/O of/IN/O Russian/JJ/O yuppies/NNS/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O exhausting/JJ/O ideological/JJ/O fight/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O finish/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O allrightniks/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O reformers/NNS/O ././O
Along/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O there/EX/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O romantic/JJ/O dalliances/NNS/O ././O
Wisely/RB/O Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O kept/VBN/O Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O time/NN/O and/CC/O place/NN/O intact/JJ/O ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O absence/NN/O of/IN/O samovars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O a/DT/O tendency/NN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O the/DT/O furniture/NN/O upside/RB/O down/RB/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O production/NN/O is/VBZ/O rich/JJ/O in/IN/O Russian/JJ/O ennui/NN/O voiced/VBN/O by/IN/O languorous/JJ/O folk/NN/O sporting/VBG/O beige/JJ/O linen/NN/O and/CC/O rumpled/JJ/O cotton/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O boaters/NNS/O and/CC/O fishing/NN/O poles/NNS/O aplenty/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O beyond/IN/O this/DT/O decorative/JJ/O nod/NN/O to/TO/O tradition/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O company/NN/O head/VBP/O off/IN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O stylistic/JJ/O direction/NN/O that/IN/O all/RB/O but/RB/O transforms/VBZ/O Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O naturalistic/JJ/O drama/NN/O into/IN/O something/NN/O akin/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O well/RB/O ,/,/O farce/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O director/NN/O 's/POS/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O force/VB/O some/DT/O Brechtian/JJ/O distance/NN/O between/IN/O her/PRP$/O actors/NNS/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O characters/NNS/O frequently/RB/O backfires/VBZ/O with/IN/O performances/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O unduly/RB/O mannered/JJ/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O do/VBP/O the/DT/O actors/NNS/O stand/VB/O outside/IN/O their/PRP$/O characters/NNS/O and/CC/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O at/IN/O odds/NNS/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O often/RB/O literally/RB/O stand/VBP/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O heads/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Talk/NN/O hurts/VBZ/O from/IN/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O spurts/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O one/CD/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O clash/NN/O of/IN/O ideologies/NNS/O survives/VBZ/O this/DT/O treatment/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O nuance/NN/O and/CC/O richness/NN/O of/IN/O Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O individual/JJ/O characters/NNS/O have/VBP/O vanished/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O scuffle/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O humor/NN/O that/IN/O Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O text/NN/O provides/VBZ/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O repainted/VBN/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O broad/JJ/O strokes/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O particularly/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O lesser/JJR/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ensemble/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O it/PRP/O looks/VBZ/O and/CC/O sounds/VBZ/O forced/JJ/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O better/RBR/O with/IN/O music/NN/O than/IN/O with/IN/O words/NNS/O when/WRB/O she/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O ,/,/O as/IN/O she/PRP/O so/RB/O often/RB/O does/VBZ/O want/VB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O express/VB/O herself/PRP/O through/IN/O Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O helpless/JJ/O play/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O Gorky/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Helpern/NNP/B-PERSON provided/VBD/O an/DT/O aural/JJ/O collage/NN/O of/IN/O Debussy/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Rachmaninoff/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O less/RBR/O a/DT/O score/NN/O than/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O character/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O distinct/JJ/O point/NN/O of/IN/O view/NN/O ././O
Like/IN/O Brecht/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O indeed/RB/O Ezra/NNP/B-PERSON Pound/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O her/PRP$/O intent/NN/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O manipulative/JJ/O staging/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O classics/NNS/O is/VBZ/O simply/RB/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O new/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O during/IN/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O post-production/JJ/O audience/NN/O discussion/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O director/NN/O explained/VBD/O that/IN/O her/PRP$/O fondest/JJS/O artistic/JJ/O wish/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O find/VB/O a/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O play/VB/O ``/``/O Somewhere/NNP/O Over/NNP/O the/NNP/O Rainbow/NNP/O ''/''/O so/IN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O song/NN/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O original/JJ/O beauty/NN/O comes/VBZ/O through/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O surmounting/VBG/O the/DT/O cliche/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O danger/NN/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O courting/VBG/O here/RB/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O obfuscation/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O rejuvenation/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O vision/NN/O so/RB/O at/IN/O odds/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O playwright/NN/O 's/POS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O points/NNS/O of/IN/O view/NN/O nullify/VBP/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O illuminate/VB/O ,/,/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Bogart/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O cast/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O and/CC/O parcel/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O ././O
Ed/NNP/B-PERSON Shea/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Barbara/NNP/B-PERSON Orson/NNP/I-PERSON never/RB/O find/VBP/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O love/NN/O affair/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O foolish/JJ/O ,/,/O idealistic/JJ/O young/JJ/O Vass/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O tirelessly/RB/O humanitarian/JJ/O doctor/NN/O Maria/NNP/B-PERSON Lvovna/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Better/RBR/O to/TO/O look/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O corners/NNS/O for/IN/O performances/NNS/O that/WDT/O inspire/VBP/O or/CC/O amuse/VBP/O ././O
Janice/NNP/B-PERSON Duclos/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O possessing/VBG/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O evening/NN/O 's/POS/O more/RBR/O impressive/JJ/O vocal/JJ/O instruments/NNS/O ,/,/O brings/VBZ/O an/DT/O unsuspected/JJ/O comedic/JJ/O touch/NN/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O role/NN/O of/IN/O Olga/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O everybody/NN/O 's/POS/O favorite/JJ/O mom/NN/O ././O
Marni/NNP/B-PERSON Rice/NNP/I-PERSON plays/VBZ/O the/DT/O maid/NN/O with/IN/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O edge/NN/O as/IN/O to/TO/O steal/VB/O her/PRP/O two/CD/O scenes/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O Trinity/NNP/B-ORG Rep/NNP/I-ORG newcomer/NN/O ,/,/O Jonathan/NNP/B-PERSON Fried/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/I-PERSON Zamislov/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O paralegal/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O actor/NN/O to/TO/O watch/VB/O ,/,/O whether/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O hamming/VBG/O it/PRP/O up/RP/O while/IN/O conducting/VBG/O the/DT/O chamber/NN/O musicians/NNS/O or/CC/O seducing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O neighbor/NN/O 's/POS/O wife/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Becca/NNP/B-PERSON Lish/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O by/IN/O licking/VBG/O her/PRP$/O bosom/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON Vries/NNP/I-PERSON writes/VBZ/O frequently/RB/O about/IN/O theater/NN/O ././O
