A/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O apple/NN/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O Fuji/NNP/O is/VBZ/O cropping/VBG/O up/RP/O in/IN/O orchards/NNS/O the/DT/O way/NN/O Hondas/NNPS/O did/VBD/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE roads/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O fruit/NN/O visionaries/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O Fuji/NNP/O could/MD/O someday/RB/O tumble/VB/O the/DT/O Red/NNP/O Delicious/NNP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O top/NN/O of/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O apple/NN/O heap/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O certainly/RB/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O there/RB/O on/IN/O looks/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O more/JJR/O sugar/NN/O ``/``/O than/IN/O any/DT/O apple/NN/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O ever/RB/O tested/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Duane/NNP/B-PERSON Greene/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Massachusetts/NNP/I-ORG pomologist/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O apple/NN/O scholar/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O shelf/NN/O life/NN/O and/CC/O ``/``/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O fool/VB/O the/DT/O public/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Grady/NNP/B-PERSON Auvil/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O Orondo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wash./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O grower/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O planting/VBG/O Fujis/NNPS/O and/CC/O spreading/VBG/O the/DT/O good/JJ/O word/NN/O about/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Auvil/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O razor/NN/O sharp/JJ/O at/IN/O 83/CD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O picked/VBN/O and/CC/O packed/VBN/O a/DT/O zillion/NN|CD/O pecks/NNS/O of/IN/O apples/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O 65/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O did/VBD/O ,/,/O shaking/VBG/O the/DT/O apple/NN/O establishment/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O roots/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Delicious/NNP/O hegemony/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O end/VB/O anytime/RB/O soon/RB/O ././O
New/JJ/O apple/NN/O trees/NNS/O grow/VBP/O slowly/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Red/NNP/O Delicious/NNP/O is/VBZ/O almost/RB/O as/RB/O entrenched/JJ/O as/IN/O mom/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O roots/NNS/O are/VBP/O patriotic/JJ/O --/:/O with/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O trees/NNS/O appearing/VBG/O in/IN/O 1872/CD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O orchard/NN/O near/IN/O Peru/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O exact/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O good/JJ/O Delicious/NNP/O can/MD/O indeed/RB/O be/VB/O delicious/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O scare/NN/O over/IN/O Alar/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O growth/NN/O regulator/NN/O that/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O apples/NNS/O redder/JJR/O and/CC/O crunchier/JJR/O but/CC/O may/MD/O be/VB/O carcinogenic/JJ/O ,/,/O made/VBD/O consumers/NNS/O shy/VB/O away/RP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Delicious/NNP/O ,/,/O though/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O less/RBR/O affected/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O McIntosh/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O glut/NN/O and/CC/O consequent/JJ/O lower/JJR/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O combined/VBN/O with/IN/O cancer/NN/O fears/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O very/RB/O serious/JJ/O blow/NN/O to/TO/O growers/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O may/MD/O be/VB/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Broderick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Sterling/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O grower/NN/O ././O
Supermarkets/NNS/O are/VBP/O getting/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O variety/NN/O act/NN/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O
They/PRP/O still/RB/O buy/VBP/O apples/NNS/O mainly/RB/O for/IN/O big/JJ/O ,/,/O red/JJ/O good/JJ/O looks/NNS/O --/:/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O why/WRB/O so/RB/O many/JJ/O taste/VBP/O like/IN/O woodchucks/NNS/O '/POS/O punching/NN/O bags/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fuji/NNP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O product/NN/O of/IN/O meticulous/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O pomological/JJ/O engineering/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O fostered/VBD/O it/PRP/O 50/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O at/IN/O a/DT/O government/NN/O research/NN/O orchard/NN/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O researchers/NNS/O have/VBP/O bred/VBN/O dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O strains/NNS/O of/IN/O Fujis/NNPS/O to/TO/O hone/VB/O its/PRP$/O color/NN/O ,/,/O taste/NN/O and/CC/O shelf/NN/O life/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Department/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Agriculture/NNP/I-ORG estimates/VBZ/O that/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O Americans/NNPS/O will/MD/O eat/VB/O about/RB/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O more/RBR/O fresh/JJ/O apples/NNS/O per/IN/O capita/NN/O than/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fuji/NNP/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O small/JJ/O potatoes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O sold/VBN/O mainly/RB/O in/IN/O fruit/NN/O boutiques/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Auvil/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE grower/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O sell/VB/O Fujis/NNPS/O to/TO/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE buyers/NNS/O at/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O a/DT/O box/NN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O them/PRP/O ././O
Washington/NNP/B-GPE Red/NNP/O Delicious/NNP/O ,/,/O by/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O wholesaling/VBG/O for/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O a/DT/O box/NN/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Auvil/NNP/B-PERSON sees/VBZ/O Fujis/NNPS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O striking/VBG/O a/DT/O blow/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O perversion/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE apples/NNS/O by/IN/O supermarkets/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O do/VBP/O deserve/VB/O respect/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O --/:/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O almost/RB/O a/DT/O year/NN/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O probably/RB/O equal/JJ/O to/TO/O about/RB/O 106/CD/O in/IN/O human/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fuji/NNP/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sure/JJ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O blemishes/NNS/O too/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O ripens/VBZ/O later/RB/O than/IN/O most/JJS/O apples/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O growing/VBG/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE areas/NNS/O with/IN/O chilly/JJ/O autumns/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O tricky/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Broderick/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE grower/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O big/JJ/O boss/NN/O ''/''/O at/IN/O a/DT/O supermarket/NN/O chain/NN/O even/RB/O rejected/VBD/O his/PRP$/O Red/NNP/O Delicious/NNP/O recently/RB/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O waxed/VBN/O and/CC/O brushed/VBN/O for/IN/O extra/JJ/O shine/NN/O ././O
