--/:/O ``/``/O Arms/NNS/O Control/NN/O Reality/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Nov./NNP/O 20/CD/O ,/,/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O of/IN/O some/RB/O 20/CD/O Journal/NNP/B-ORG editorials/NNS/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O Krasnoyarsk/NNP/B-GPE violated/VBD/O the/DT/O ABM/NNP/O treaty/NN/O ././O
--/:/O ``/``/O Whether/IN/O the/DT/O installation/NN/O is/VBZ/O for/IN/O early/JJ/O warning/NN/O or/CC/O space/NN/O track/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O clearly/RB/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O deployed/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O lawmakers/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Thus/RB/O we/PRP/O judge/VBP/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O not/RB/O a/DT/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ABM/NNP/O treaty/NN/O at/IN/O this/DT/O time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O delegation/NN/O included/VBD/O a/DT/O reporter/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O aides/NNS/O to/TO/O Sen./NNP/O Edward/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Kennedy/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Rep./NNP/O Les/NNP/B-PERSON AuCoin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O Natural/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG staff/NN/O members/NN/O ././O
--/:/O The/DT/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG Post/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Sept./NNP/O 9/CD/O ,/,/O 1987/CD/O ././O
--/:/O The/DT/O U.S.S.R./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O unprecedented/JJ/O unilateral/JJ/O measures/NNS/O of/IN/O openness/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O giving/VBG/O American/JJ/O representatives/NNS/O a/DT/O possibility/NN/O to/TO/O inspect/VB/O the/DT/O building/NN/O site/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Krasnoyarsk/NNP/B-GPE radar/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O radar/NN/O vans/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O areas/NNS/O of/IN/O Gomel/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O so/RB/O as/IN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O for/IN/O themselves/PRP/O that/IN/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O violations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ABM/NNP/O treaty/NN/O of/IN/O 1972/CD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
--/:/O The/DT/O construction/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O station/NN/O equal/JJ/O in/IN/O size/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Egyptian/JJ/O pyramids/NNS/O constituted/VBD/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O say/VBP/O it/PRP/O directly/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O clear/JJ/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O ABM/NNP/O ././O
--/:/O Eduard/NNP/B-PERSON Shevardnadze/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Oct./NNP/O 23/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O ././O
We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O happy/JJ/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O guess/VBP/O ,/,/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O confirmation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Krasnoyarsk/NNP/B-GPE violation/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O ,/,/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O after/IN/O we/PRP/O started/VBD/O writing/VBG/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O even/RB/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O apologists/NNS/O will/MD/O now/RB/O accede/VB/O ././O
Without/IN/O question/NN/O ,/,/O something/NN/O intriguing/JJ/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O on/RP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O chambers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Politburo/NNP/B-ORG ././O
As/IN/O it/PRP/O bids/VBZ/O for/IN/O new/JJ/O agreements/NNS/O ,/,/O new/JJ/O loans/NNS/O and/CC/O indeed/RB/O admission/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O civilized/JJ/O world/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O recognized/VBN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O credibility/NN/O problem/NN/O ././O
So/RB/O after/IN/O 70/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O confessing/VBG/O the/DT/O obvious/JJ/O ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O believed/VBN/O about/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O enough/RB/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O believed/VBN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O start/VB/O telling/VBG/O the/DT/O truth/NN/O about/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O totally/RB/O obvious/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O has/VBZ/O never/RB/O waivered/VBN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O assessment/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O incident/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O accident/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O biological/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O facility/NN/O there/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O hence/RB/O a/DT/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1972/CD/O Biological/NNP/O Weapons/NNP/O Convention/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O recently/RB/O issued/VBN/O ``/``/O Soviet/JJ/O Military/JJ/O Power/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O though/IN/O in/IN/O general/JJ/O adopting/VBG/O a/DT/O softer/JJR/O line/NN/O ,/,/O repeated/VBD/O the/DT/O Sverdlovsk/NNP/B-GPE assessment/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O was/VBD/O detailed/VBN/O in/IN/O Congressional/JJ/B-ORG testimony/NN/O this/DT/O past/JJ/O February/NNP/O :/:/O An/DT/O explosion/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Microbiology/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Virology/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Sverdlovsk/NNP/B-GPE released/VBD/O anthrax/NN/O germs/NNS/O that/WDT/O caused/VBD/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O deaths/NNS/O ././O
Since/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Shevardnadze/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O not/RB/O address/NN/O this/DT/O topic/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Soviet/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE official/JJ/O position/NN/O remains/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O anthrax/NN/O deaths/NNS/O were/VBD/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O tainted/JJ/O meat/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O doubt/VBP/O this/DT/O claim/NN/O just/RB/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O doubted/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Shevardnadze/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O assurance/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O that/IN/O Krasnoyarsk/NNP/B-GPE did/VBD/O n't/RB/O violate/VB/O the/DT/O ABM/NNP/O treaty/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O '/POS/O explanation/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O anthrax/NN/O came/VBD/O from/IN/O one/CD/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O animal/NN/O feed/NN/O made/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O bones/NNS/O of/IN/O cattle/NNS/O that/WDT/O grazed/VBD/O on/IN/O soil/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O naturally/RB/O infected/VBN/O with/IN/O anthrax/NN/O spores/NNS/O ././O
Harvard/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Matthew/NNP/B-PERSON Meselson/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O who/WP/O we/PRP/O read/VBP/O has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O something/NN/O called/VBN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O scientific/JJ/O community/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O that/IN/O ``/``/O yellow/JJ/O rain/NN/O ''/''/O attacks/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Laotian/JJ/O Hmong/NNPS/O were/VBD/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O the/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O fecal/JJ/O showers/NNS/O by/IN/O giant/JJ/O bees/NNS/O --/:/O found/VBD/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O anthrax/NN/O scenario/NN/O ``/``/O completely/RB/O plausible/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
And/CC/O we/PRP/O certainly/RB/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O believe/VB/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON or/CC/O any/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O emissaries/NNS/O yet/RB/O deserve/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O take/VB/O their/PRP$/O word/NN/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O 's/POS/O Sverdlovsk/NNP/B-GPE complaint/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O with/IN/O Krasnoyarsk/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O mere/JJ/O political/JJ/O posturing/NN/O ././O
Biological/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O violations/NNS/O have/VBP/O figured/VBN/O little/RB/O in/IN/O political/JJ/O debate/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O indeed/RB/O have/VBP/O not/RB/O been/VBN/O pressed/VBN/O vigorously/RB/O enough/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O stated/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE position/NN/O is/VBZ/O detailed/JJ/O and/CC/O specific/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O of/IN/O biological/JJ/O warfare/NN/O is/VBZ/O profoundly/RB/O chilling/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O set/VB/O in/IN/O motion/NN/O a/DT/O process/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O acknowledge/VB/O that/DT/O Sverdlovsk/NNP/B-GPE violated/VBD/O the/DT/O 1972/CD/O agreement/NN/O or/CC/O ,/,/O alternatively/RB/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O give/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE specialists/NNS/O reasonable/JJ/O confidence/NN/O that/IN/O this/DT/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O wholly/RB/O civilian/JJ/O accident/NN/O ././O
Until/IN/O that/DT/O happens/VBZ/O ,/,/O glasnost/FW/O can/MD/O not/RB/O begin/VB/O to/TO/O deserve/VB/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O credibility/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Shevardnadze/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O bidding/VBG/O for/IN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O confessions/NNS/O on/IN/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
