The/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O submitting/VBG/O a/DT/O ``/``/O comprehensive/JJ/O ''/''/O proposal/NN/O for/IN/O overhauling/VBG/O agricultural/JJ/O trade/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O help/VB/O break/VB/O an/DT/O impasse/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O round/NN/O of/IN/O multilateral/JJ/O trade/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O considerable/JJ/O flexibility/NN/O in/IN/O determining/VBG/O how/WRB/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O these/DT/O goals/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O achieved/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE plan/NN/O also/RB/O would/MD/O ease/VB/O the/DT/O transition/NN/O to/TO/O freer/JJR/O agriculture/NN/O trade/NN/O by/IN/O allowing/VBG/O some/DT/O countries/NNS/O to/TO/O convert/VB/O non-tariff/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O into/IN/O tariffs/NNS/O that/WDT/O ,/,/O together/RB/O with/IN/O existing/JJ/O tariffs/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O would/MD/O be/VB/O phased/VBN/O out/RP/O over/IN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Trade/NNP/B-ORG Representative/NNP/O Carla/NNP/B-PERSON Hills/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O along/IN/O with/IN/O Agriculture/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Clayton/NNP/B-PERSON Yeutter/NNP/I-PERSON unveiled/VBD/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O confident/JJ/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O gain/VB/O considerable/JJ/O support/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trading/NN/O partners/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O submitting/VBG/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O today/NN/O in/IN/O Geneva/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O initiative/NN/O will/MD/O spur/VB/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Agreement/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG Tariffs/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O reach/VB/O agreement/NN/O on/IN/O new/JJ/O trade/NN/O rules/NNS/O before/IN/O their/PRP$/O current/JJ/O negotiating/NN/O round/NN/O concludes/VBZ/O in/IN/O December/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Another/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE proposal/NN/O filed/VBN/O Monday/NNP/O urges/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ``/``/O fair/JJ/O play/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O services/NNS/O trade/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O predictable/JJ/O and/CC/O clear/JJ/O rules/NNS/O and/CC/O equality/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O and/CC/O domestic/JJ/O service/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE package/NN/O makes/VBZ/O clear/JJ/O there/EX/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O transition/NN/O period/NN/O during/IN/O which/WDT/O GATT/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O could/MD/O use/VB/O a/DT/O combination/NN/O of/IN/O tariffs/NNS/O and/CC/O quotas/NNS/O to/TO/O cushion/VB/O their/PRP$/O farmers/NNS/O from/IN/O foreign/JJ/O competition/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O says/VBZ/O countries/NNS/O could/MD/O temporarily/RB/O raise/VB/O tariffs/NNS/O on/IN/O certain/JJ/O products/NNS/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O experience/VBP/O an/DT/O unusually/RB/O heavy/JJ/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O imports/NNS/O ././O
Instead/RB/O of/IN/O proposing/VBG/O a/DT/O complete/JJ/O elimination/NN/O of/IN/O farm/NN/O subsidies/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O earlier/JJR/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE proposal/NN/O did/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O package/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O elimination/NN/O of/IN/O only/RB/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O tradedistorting/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ././O
Less/RBR/O objectionable/JJ/O ones/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O subject/JJ/O only/RB/O to/TO/O some/DT/O restraints/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O relatively/RB/O minor/JJ/O trade/NN/O impact/NN/O ''/''/O would/MD/O be/VB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O under/IN/O certain/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE plan/NN/O also/RB/O would/MD/O establish/VB/O procedures/NNS/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O countries/NNS/O from/IN/O using/VBG/O health/NN/O and/CC/O sanitation/NN/O rules/NNS/O to/TO/O impede/VB/O trade/NN/O arbitrarily/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE contends/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O justified/VBN/O on/IN/O health/NN/O grounds/NNS/O ././O
To/TO/O encourage/VB/O more/JJR/O competition/NN/O among/IN/O exporting/VBG/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O proposing/VBG/O that/IN/O export/NN/O subsidies/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O tax/NN/O incentives/NNS/O for/IN/O exporters/NNS/O ,/,/O be/VB/O phased/VBN/O out/RP/O in/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
