Falcon/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O about/RB/O 54,000/CD/O subscribers/NNS/O from/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Carolina/NNP/I-ORG Cable/NNP/I-ORG TV/NN/I-ORG Limited/NNP/I-ORG Partnership/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O roughly/RB/O $/$/O 2,000/CD/O a/DT/O subscriber/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O subscribers/NNS/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O 52/CD/O different/JJ/O communities/NNS/O in/IN/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Alabama/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Mississippi/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Completion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O early/RB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Falcon/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O composite/JJ/O trading/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Falcon/NNP/B-ORG closed/VBD/O at/IN/O $/$/O 20/CD/O ,/,/O unchanged/JJ/O ././O
