Boeing/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Trans/NNP/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Airways/NNP/I-ORG ordered/VBD/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O 737/CD/O jetliners/NNS/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 450/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O 300/CD/O and/CC/O 400/CD/O series/NN/O aircraft/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O powered/VBN/O by/IN/O engines/NNS/O jointly/RB/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Snecma/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Currently/NNP/O ,/,/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O backlog/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 80/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O production/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O slowed/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O strike/NN/O of/IN/O 55,000/CD/O machinists/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O entered/VBD/O its/PRP$/O 22nd/JJ/O day/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O mediator/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O rekindle/VB/O talks/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O strikers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O rejected/VBN/O a/DT/O pay/NN/O raise/NN/O offer/NN/O of/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O over/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
