The/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O control/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O law/NN/O that/IN/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Sentelle/NNP/I-PERSON recently/RB/O called/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O monster/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Needless/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O talking/VBG/O about/IN/O RICO/NNP/O ././O
With/IN/O its/PRP$/O recently/RB/O revised/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O for/IN/O RICO/NNP/O ,/,/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O currently/RB/O holds/VBZ/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O incentives/NNS/O for/IN/O abuse/NN/O by/IN/O prosecutors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O text/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O new/JJ/O policy/NN/O ''/''/O guidelines/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Criminal/NNP/I-ORG Division/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O reprinted/VBN/O nearby/RB/O ././O
Justice/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O a/DT/O replay/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O tactics/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O amounts/VBZ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O extraordinary/JJ/O repudiation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tenure/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE mayoral/JJ/O candidate/NN/O and/CC/O former/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O Rudolph/NNP/B-PERSON Giuliani/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O more/RBR/O inclined/JJ/O to/TO/O gathering/VBG/O scalps/NNS/O than/IN/O understanding/VBG/O markets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O guidelines/NNS/O limit/VBP/O the/DT/O pretrial/JJ/O forfeitures/NNS/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O RICOed/JJ/O defendants/NNS/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O investors/NNS/O ,/,/O clients/NNS/O ,/,/O bankers/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O forfeiture/NN/O memo/NN/O cited/VBD/O ``/``/O considerable/JJ/O criticism/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O perception/NN/O that/IN/O pre-trial/JJ/O freezing/NN/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O is/VBZ/O tantamount/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O seizure/NN/O of/IN/O property/NN/O without/IN/O due/JJ/O process/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O told/VBD/O prosecutors/NNS/O not/RB/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O forfeitures/NNS/O if/IN/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O less/RBR/O intrusive/JJ/O ''/''/O alternatives/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O forfeitures/NNS/O ``/``/O disproportionate/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O defendant/NN/O 's/POS/O crime/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O into/IN/O liquidation/NN/O before/IN/O trial/NN/O when/WRB/O investors/NNS/O yanked/VBD/O their/PRP$/O funds/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O demanded/VBD/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O pre-trial/JJ/O asset/NN/O forfeiture/NN/O ././O
Prosecutors/NNS/O wanted/VBD/O $/$/O 23.8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O forfeiture/NN/O for/IN/O alleged/JJ/O tax/NN/O fraud/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O $/$/O 400,000/CD/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG therefore/RB/O agreed/VBD/O instead/RB/O to/TO/O an/DT/O arrangement/NN/O allowing/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O plea/VB/O to/TO/O charges/NNS/O ``/``/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O to/TO/O dispute/VB/O ''/''/O because/IN/O of/IN/O RICO/NNP/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O plea/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Milken/NNP/B-PERSON loose/JJ/O ././O
So/RB/O after/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O prosecutorial/JJ/O hoopla/NN/O no/DT/O one/NN/O has/VBZ/O established/VBN/O what/WP/O ,/,/O if/IN/O anything/NN/O ,/,/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O wrong/RB/O ././O
So/RB/O two/CD/O cheers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O rules/NNS/O ././O
Justice/NN/B-ORG has/VBZ/O finally/RB/O recognized/VBN/O its/PRP$/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O abuses/NNS/O ,/,/O thanks/NNS/O largely/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O demands/NNS/O for/IN/O reform/NN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON diGenova/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O salvage/VB/O RICO/NNP/O for/IN/O real/JJ/O criminals/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O prosecutorial/JJ/O guidelines/NNS/O are/VBP/O effective/JJ/O only/RB/O if/IN/O someone/NN/O at/IN/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O and/CC/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O supervise/VB/O hyperactive/JJ/O prosecutors/NNS/O ././O
Judge/NNP/O Sentelle/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O of/IN/O the/DT/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O made/VBD/O this/DT/O point/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O Cato/NNP/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG conference/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O remarkable/JJ/O speech/NN/O titled/VBN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O RICO/NNP/O :/:/O The/DT/O Monster/NN/O That/WDT/O Ate/VBD/O Jurisprudence/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O ours/PRP/O is/VBZ/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ``/``/O a/DT/O government/NN/O of/IN/O laws/NNS/O not/RB/O of/IN/O men/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O yet/RB/O RICO/NNP/O defenders/NNS/O ``/``/O tell/VBP/O us/PRP/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O should/MD/O rely/VB/O on/IN/O prosecutorial/JJ/O discretion/NN/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O against/IN/O overbreadth/NN/O of/IN/O RICO/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
No/DT/O prosecutorial/JJ/O guidelines/NNS/O ,/,/O observed/JJ/O or/CC/O unobserved/JJ/O ,/,/O limit/VBP/O civil/JJ/O RICO/NNP/O cases/NNS/O by/IN/O plaintiffs/NNS/O for/IN/O damages/NNS/O ././O
Justice/NNP/O should/MD/O review/VB/O these/DT/O cases/NNS/O to/TO/O see/VB/O what/WP/O other/JJ/O prosecutorial/JJ/O abuses/NNS/O may/MD/O have/VB/O occurred/VBN/O ././O
We/PRP/O suspect/VBP/O that/IN/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O some/DT/O day/NN/O agree/VB/O that/IN/O only/RB/O the/DT/O complete/JJ/O repeal/NN/O of/IN/O RICO/NNP/O can/MD/O guarantee/VB/O an/DT/O end/NN/O to/TO/O injustices/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O name/NN/O ././O
