The/DT/O budget/NN/O impact/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O greater/JJR/O still/RB/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O forced/VBD/O a/DT/O confrontation/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Appropriations/NNP/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG leadership/NN/O and/CC/O Budget/NNP/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Leon/NNP/B-PERSON Panetta/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O California/NNP/B-GPE district/NN/O was/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
Going/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O well/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O chamber/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Panetta/NNP/B-PERSON demanded/VBD/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O counted/VBN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O prominent/JJ/O role/NN/O put/VBD/O him/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O awkward/JJ/O position/NN/O of/IN/O challenging/VBG/O the/DT/O very/JJ/O committee/NN/O members/NNS/O on/IN/O whom/WP/O his/PRP$/O state/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O most/RBS/O dependent/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O months/NNS/O ahead/RB/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O come/VB/O to/TO/O this/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG asking/VBG/O for/IN/O any/DT/O handout/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VB/O not/RB/O intend/VB/O to/TO/O hide/VB/O these/DT/O costs/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O funds/NNS/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O billion/CD/O appropriated/VBN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O recovery/NN/O from/IN/O Hugo/NNP/O ,/,/O bringing/VBG/O the/DT/O total/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O disasters/NNS/O to/TO/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O unanticipated/JJ/O spending/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O appropriations/NNS/O set/VBD/O in/IN/O motion/NN/O spending/NN/O that/WDT/O adds/VBZ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O already/RB/O grim/JJ/O budget/NN/O picture/NN/O for/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1991/CD/O ././O
Within/IN/O the/DT/O appropriations/NNS/O process/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O is/VBZ/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O difficult/JJ/O since/IN/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O counted/VBN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O share/NN/O of/IN/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O allocated/VBN/O to/TO/O those/DT/O subcommittees/NNS/O that/WDT/O recently/RB/O have/VBP/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O greatest/JJS/O difficulty/NN/O in/IN/O staying/VBG/O within/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O underlying/JJ/O bill/NN/O approved/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O is/VBZ/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O operating/VBG/O past/IN/O midnight/NN/O tonight/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O this/DT/O urgency/NN/O has/VBZ/O contributed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O speed/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O ,/,/O critics/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O mistakes/NNS/O --/:/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O accompanied/VBN/O the/DT/O package/NN/O of/IN/O disaster/NN/O assistance/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O hastily/RB/O drafted/VBN/O measure/NN/O could/MD/O hurt/VB/O California/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O requiring/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O put/VB/O up/RP/O more/JJR/O matching/JJ/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O emergency/NN/O highway/NN/O assistance/NN/O than/IN/O otherwise/RB/O would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O delegation/NN/O is/VBZ/O fearful/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O funding/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O counted/VBN/O against/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O $/$/O 185/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O highway/NN/O funds/NNS/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O expect/VB/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O normal/JJ/O allocation/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O price/NN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE real/JJ/O estate/NN/O puts/VBZ/O the/DT/O state/NN/O at/IN/O odds/NNS/O with/IN/O federal/JJ/O regulations/NNS/O more/RBR/O attuned/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O national/JJ/O average/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O disaster/NN/O loans/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O small/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O and/CC/O homeowners/NNS/O ,/,/O offer/VBP/O credit/NN/O as/RB/O low/JJ/O as/IN/O 4/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O some/DT/O cases/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE delegation/NN/O finds/VBZ/O itself/PRP/O asking/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O cap/NN/O per/IN/O household/NN/O be/VB/O lifted/VBN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 100,000/CD/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O the/DT/O hard/JJ/O hit/NN/O but/CC/O often/RB/O wealthy/JJ/O Marina/NNP/B-LOC district/NN/I-LOC ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O some/DT/O modifications/NNS/O today/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O both/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG appear/VBP/O most/RBS/O anxious/JJ/O to/TO/O speed/VB/O final/JJ/O approval/NN/O before/IN/O tonight/NN/O 's/POS/O deadline/NN/O ././O
Administration/NNP/O pressure/NN/O discourages/VBZ/O any/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O add/VB/O to/TO/O total/JJ/O funding/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG changes/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O largely/RB/O technical/JJ/O --/:/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O highway/NN/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O lifting/VBG/O the/DT/O ceiling/NN/O on/IN/O total/JJ/O Small/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG loans/NNS/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.8/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O the/DT/O increased/JJ/O activity/NN/O expected/VBN/O ././O
An/DT/O estimated/JJ/O $/$/O 25.8/CD/O million/CD/O is/VBZ/O allocated/VBN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O work/NN/O in/IN/O Oman/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O all/DT/O funding/NN/O is/VBZ/O cut/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O projects/NNS/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE are/VBP/O cut/VBN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 13.6/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O sixth/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O request/NN/O ././O
Closer/RBR/O to/TO/O home/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O negotiators/NNS/O were/VBD/O more/RBR/O generous/JJ/O ././O
An/DT/O estimated/JJ/O $/$/O 38.9/CD/O million/CD/O was/VBD/O set/VBN/O aside/RB/O for/IN/O military/JJ/O installations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O home/NN/O state/NN/O of/IN/O North/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE Rep./NNP/O W.G./NNP/B-PERSON Hefner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O $/$/O 70.2/CD/O million/CD/O would/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O projects/NNS/O in/IN/O Tennessee/NNP/B-GPE represented/VBN/O by/IN/O his/PRP$/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG counterpart/NN/O and/CC/O fellow/JJ/O Democrat/NNP/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Sasser/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Texas/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O California/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O traditionally/RB/O powerful/JJ/O within/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O equally/RB/O striking/JJ/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O dominance/NN/O of/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O West/NNP/B-GPE Virginia/NNP/I-GPE because/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O power/NN/O elsewhere/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O appropriations/NNS/O process/NN/O ././O
Senate/NNP/B-ORG Appropriations/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Byrd/NNP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O W.Va/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O even/RB/O added/VBD/O report/NN/O language/NN/O listing/VBG/O $/$/O 49.4/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O projects/NNS/O he/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
No/DT/O individual/NN/O illustrated/VBD/O this/DT/O mix/NN/O of/IN/O power/NN/O more/RBR/O yesterday/NN/O than/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Inouye/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Hawaii/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O who/WP/O chairs/VBZ/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG defense/NN/O subcommittee/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O insistent/JJ/O on/IN/O setting/VBG/O aside/RP/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O carry/VB/O out/RP/O base/NN/O closings/NNS/O ordered/VBN/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O gave/VBD/O ground/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Inouye/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O projects/NNS/O ,/,/O ranging/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O parking/NN/O garage/NN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O a/DT/O land/NN/O transfer/NN/O in/IN/O Hawaii/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O a/DT/O provision/NN/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O the/DT/O Makwah/NNP/O Indian/NNP/O Tribe/NNP/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O tribe/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O poorest/JJS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Pacific/NNP/I-LOC Northwest/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Mr./NNP/O Inouye/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O chairs/VBZ/O the/DT/O select/JJ/O committee/NN/O on/IN/O Indian/NNP/B-ORG Affairs/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O used/VBD/O his/PRP$/O power/NN/O to/TO/O move/VB/O $/$/O 400,000/CD/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Indian/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O assist/VB/O in/IN/O renovating/VBG/O a/DT/O decommissoned/JJ/O base/NN/O to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O a/DT/O drug/NN/O and/CC/O alcohol/NN/O rehabilitation/NN/O center/NN/O ././O
