Murata/NNP/B-ORG Mfg./NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O establishing/VBG/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O produce/VB/O electric/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O ceramic/JJ/O condensers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE maker/NN/O of/IN/O ceramic/JJ/O capacitors/NNS/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O purchased/VBD/O a/DT/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Plymouth/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O a/DT/O purchase/NN/O price/NN/O or/CC/O capitalization/NN/O figures/NNS/O ././O
Production/NN/O is/VBZ/O slated/VBN/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O ././O
Murata/NNP/B-ORG expects/VBZ/O sales/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O yen/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
