The/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O correction/NN/O of/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O grim/JJ/O reminder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Oct./NNP/O 19/CD/O ,/,/O 1987/CD/O market/NN/O collapse/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O just/RB/O what/WP/O happened/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O October/NNP/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O situation/NN/O was/VBD/O like/IN/O that/DT/O of/IN/O a/DT/O skier/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O thrown/VBN/O slightly/RB/O off/IN/O balance/NN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O unexpected/JJ/O bump/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O slope/NN/O ././O
Unable/JJ/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O his/PRP$/O accelerating/VBG/O descent/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O crashes/VBZ/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O doubtful/JJ/O ,/,/O though/IN/O ,/,/O whether/IN/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O do/VBP/O any/DT/O real/JJ/O good/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O availability/NN/O of/IN/O timely/JJ/O assistance/NN/O --/:/O of/IN/O a/DT/O backstop/NN/O --/:/O can/MD/O help/VB/O markets/NNS/O retain/VB/O their/PRP$/O resilience/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O assumed/VBN/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O government/NN/O securities/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O mean/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG does/VBZ/O not/RB/O already/RB/O play/VB/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O indirect/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O lent/VBD/O money/NN/O to/TO/O banks/NNS/O and/CC/O encouraged/VBD/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O funds/NNS/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O brokerage/NN/O houses/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O ,/,/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O ,/,/O lent/VBD/O money/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O customers/NNS/O --/:/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O recognize/VB/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O a/DT/O profit/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O turmoil/NN/O and/CC/O buy/VB/O shares/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O power/NN/O to/TO/O set/VB/O margin/NN/O requirements/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O certainly/RB/O not/RB/O too/RB/O big/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O handle/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O daily/JJ/O volume/NN/O for/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/O is/VBZ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 110/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O $/$/O 13/CD/O billion/CD/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG injected/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O markets/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O enough/JJ/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O stocks/NNS/O traded/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O typical/JJ/O day/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O role/NN/O ought/MD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O very/RB/O ambitious/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O should/MD/O seek/VB/O only/RB/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O the/DT/O functioning/NN/O of/IN/O markets/NNS/O --/:/O not/RB/O to/TO/O prop/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG or/CC/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG averages/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O particular/JJ/O level/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O guard/VB/O against/IN/O systemic/JJ/O risk/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O against/IN/O the/DT/O risks/NNS/O inherent/JJ/O in/IN/O individual/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O inappropriate/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O or/CC/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O or/CC/O sell/VB/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNPS/I-ORG shares/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O increased/VBN/O demand/NN/O would/MD/O normalize/VB/O trading/NN/O and/CC/O stabilize/VB/O prices/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O eliminate/VB/O the/DT/O cause/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O panic/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O treat/VB/O the/DT/O symptom/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O liquidity/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Disorderly/JJ/O market/NN/O conditions/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O observed/VBN/O quite/RB/O frequently/RB/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O exchange/NN/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1960s/NNS/O and/CC/O 1970s/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O recall/VB/O any/DT/O disorder/NN/O in/IN/O currency/NN/O markets/NNS/O since/IN/O the/DT/O 1974/CD/O guidelines/NNS/O were/VBD/O adopted/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Heller/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O now/RB/O at/IN/O VISA/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O governor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG from/IN/O 1986/CD/O until/IN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O adapted/VBN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O speech/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Commonwealth/NNP/I-ORG Club/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ././O
