Toni/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON pulls/VBZ/O a/DT/O tape/NN/O measure/NN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O front/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O was/VBD/O once/RB/O a/DT/O stately/JJ/O Victorian/JJ/O home/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O deep/JJ/O trench/NN/O now/RB/O runs/VBZ/O along/IN/O its/PRP$/O north/NN/O wall/NN/O ,/,/O exposed/VBN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O house/NN/O lurched/VBD/O two/CD/O feet/NNS/O off/IN/O its/PRP$/O foundation/NN/O during/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O side/NN/O porch/NN/O was/VBD/O ripped/VBN/O away/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O chimney/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O pile/NN/O of/IN/O bricks/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O front/JJ/O lawn/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O remainder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O house/NN/O leans/VBZ/O precariously/RB/O against/IN/O a/DT/O sturdy/JJ/O oak/NN/O tree/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O move/NN/O almost/RB/O incessantly/RB/O since/IN/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O an/DT/O army/NN/O of/IN/O adjusters/NNS/O ,/,/O employed/VBN/O by/IN/O major/JJ/O insurers/NNS/O ,/,/O invaded/VBD/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O policyholders/NNS/O sift/VB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O rubble/NN/O and/CC/O restore/VB/O some/DT/O order/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O lives/NNS/O ././O
Equipped/VBN/O with/IN/O cellular/JJ/O telephones/NNS/O ,/,/O laptop/NN/O computers/NNS/O ,/,/O calculators/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O pack/NN/O of/IN/O blank/JJ/O checks/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O parcel/VBP/O out/RP/O money/NN/O so/IN/O their/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O can/MD/O find/VB/O temporary/JJ/O living/NN/O quarters/NNS/O ,/,/O buy/VB/O food/NN/O ,/,/O replace/VB/O lost/VBN/O clothing/NN/O ,/,/O repair/VB/O broken/JJ/O water/NN/O heaters/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O replaster/VB/O walls/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O will/MD/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O demolish/VB/O unstable/JJ/O buildings/NNS/O and/CC/O clear/VB/O sites/NNS/O for/IN/O future/JJ/O construction/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O adjusters/NNS/O are/VBP/O authorized/VBN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O checks/NNS/O for/IN/O amounts/NNS/O up/RB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 100,000/CD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O spot/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O flinch/VB/O at/IN/O writing/VBG/O them/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O my/PRP$/O job/NN/O --/:/O get/VB/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O policyholders/NNS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O entitled/VBN/O to/TO/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Schaeffer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O claims/NNS/O supervisor/NN/O who/WP/O flew/VBD/O in/RB/O from/IN/O Aetna/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O Bridgeport/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O office/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Victorian/JJ/O house/NN/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O inspecting/VBG/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O deemed/VBN/O unsafe/JJ/O by/IN/O town/NN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
She/PRP/O snaps/VBZ/O photos/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O buckled/JJ/O floors/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O plaster/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O fallen/VBN/O away/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O walls/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O she/PRP/O works/VBZ/O inside/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O tenant/NN/O returns/VBZ/O with/IN/O several/JJ/O friends/NNS/O to/TO/O collect/VB/O furniture/NN/O and/CC/O clothing/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O friends/NNS/O sweeps/VBZ/O broken/JJ/O dishes/NNS/O and/CC/O shattered/JJ/O glass/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O countertop/NN/O and/CC/O starts/VBZ/O to/TO/O pack/VB/O what/WP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O salvaged/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O kitchen/NN/O ././O
Others/NNS/O grab/VBP/O books/NNS/O ,/,/O records/NNS/O ,/,/O photo/NN/O albums/NNS/O ,/,/O sofas/NNS/O and/CC/O chairs/NNS/O ,/,/O working/VBG/O frantically/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fear/NN/O that/IN/O an/DT/O aftershock/NN/O will/MD/O jolt/VB/O the/DT/O house/NN/O again/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O owners/NNS/O ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Margie/NNP/B-PERSON Hammack/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O are/VBP/O luckier/JJR/O than/IN/O many/JJ/O others/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON insisted/VBD/O on/IN/O buying/VBG/O earthquake/NN/O insurance/NN/O for/IN/O this/DT/O house/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O converted/VBN/O into/IN/O apartments/NNS/O ././O
Only/RB/O about/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE home/NN/O and/CC/O business/NN/O owners/NNS/O carried/VBD/O earthquake/NN/O coverage/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Hammacks/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O own/JJ/O home/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Gatos/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O suffered/VBD/O comparatively/RB/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O works/VBZ/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O office/NN/O in/IN/O Walnut/NNP/B-GPE Creek/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC suburb/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O awed/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O 's/POS/O destructive/JJ/O force/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O really/RB/O brings/VBZ/O you/PRP/O down/RP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O human/JJ/O level/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O suffering/NN/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O through/IN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O ././O
If/IN/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O do/VB/O your/PRP$/O job/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
For/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O insurers/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE earthquake/NN/O hit/VBD/O when/WRB/O resources/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O already/RB/O were/VBD/O stretched/VBN/O ././O
Most/RBS/O companies/NNS/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O sort/VB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O wreckage/NN/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Carolinas/NNPS/B-GPE last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Aetna/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O nearly/RB/O 3,000/CD/O adjusters/NNS/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O deployed/VBN/O about/IN/O 750/CD/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O Charlotte/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Columbia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Charleston/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Adjusters/NNS/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC say/VBP/O the/DT/O insurer/NN/O will/MD/O still/RB/O be/VB/O processing/VBG/O claims/NNS/O from/IN/O that/DT/O storm/NN/O through/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O rocked/VBD/O northern/JJ/O California/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG senior/JJ/O claims/NNS/O executives/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O were/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O Hartford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O headquarters/NN/O for/IN/O additional/JJ/O training/NN/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O major/JJ/O catastrophes/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O earthquakes/NNS/O ././O
Since/IN/O commercial/JJ/O airline/NN/O flights/NNS/O were/VBD/O disrupted/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O chartered/VBD/O three/CD/O planes/NNS/O to/TO/O fly/VB/O these/DT/O executives/NNS/O back/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-LOC West/NNP/I-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O bring/VB/O along/RB/O portable/JJ/O computers/NNS/O ,/,/O cellular/JJ/O phones/NNS/O and/CC/O some/DT/O claims/NNS/O adjusters/NNS/O ././O
Because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O difficulty/NN/O of/IN/O assessing/VBG/O the/DT/O damages/NNS/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG pulled/VBD/O together/RB/O a/DT/O team/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O most/RBS/O experienced/JJ/O claims/NNS/O adjusters/NNS/O from/IN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O so/RB/O ,/,/O few/JJ/O had/VBD/O ever/RB/O dealt/VBN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O adjusters/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Singer/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O in/IN/O Charleston/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O nearly/RB/O four/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O returned/VBD/O home/RB/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O packed/VBD/O a/DT/O bag/NN/O with/IN/O fresh/JJ/O clothes/NNS/O and/CC/O reported/VBD/O for/IN/O duty/NN/O Friday/NNP/O in/IN/O Walnut/NNP/B-GPE Creek/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Offices/NNS/O were/VBD/O set/VBN/O up/RP/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O instances/NNS/O ,/,/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG knew/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O probably/RB/O be/VB/O shelling/VBG/O out/RP/O big/JJ/O bucks/NNS/O ,/,/O even/RB/O before/IN/O a/DT/O client/NN/O called/VBD/O or/CC/O faxed/VBD/O in/RP/O a/DT/O claim/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O at/IN/O Walnut/NNP/B-GPE Creek/NNP/I-GPE office/NN/O learned/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Amfac/NNP/I-ORG Hotel/NNP/I-ORG near/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE airport/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O insured/VBN/O by/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O badly/RB/O damaged/VBN/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O saw/VBD/O it/PRP/O on/IN/O network/NN/O television/NN/O news/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O secret/NN/O to/TO/O being/VBG/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O adjuster/NN/O is/VBZ/O counting/VBG/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Gerardo/NNP/B-PERSON Rodriguez/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG adjuster/NN/O from/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Ana/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O count/VB/O everything/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Adjusters/NNS/O must/MD/O count/VB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O bathrooms/NNS/O ,/,/O balconies/NNS/O ,/,/O fireplaces/NNS/O ,/,/O chimneys/NNS/O ,/,/O microwaves/NNS/O and/CC/O dishwashers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O must/MD/O also/RB/O assign/VB/O a/DT/O price/NN/O to/TO/O each/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O items/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O to/TO/O floors/NNS/O ,/,/O wallcoverings/NNS/O ,/,/O roofing/NN/O and/CC/O siding/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O come/VB/O up/RB/O with/IN/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O value/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O house/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O do/VB/O that/DT/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O must/MD/O think/VB/O in/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O sheetrock/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O square/NN/O foot/NN/O ,/,/O carpeting/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O square/NN/O yard/NN/O ,/,/O wallpaper/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O roll/NN/O ,/,/O molding/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O linear/JJ/O foot/NN/O ././O
Sometimes/RB/O repairs/NNS/O are/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O question/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG adjuster/NN/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Schaeffer/NNP/I-PERSON visited/VBD/O a/DT/O retired/JJ/O couple/NN/O in/IN/O Oakland/NN/B-GPE last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O found/VBD/O them/PRP/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O a/DT/O mobile/JJ/O home/NN/O parked/VBN/O in/IN/O front/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O yard/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Schaeffer/NNP/B-PERSON presented/VBD/O the/DT/O couple/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O check/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 151,000/CD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O them/PRP/O build/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O home/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O neighborhood/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O adjusters/NNS/O employed/VBN/O by/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O insurers/NNS/O have/VBP/O some/DT/O experience/NN/O with/IN/O construction/NN/O work/NN/O or/CC/O carpentry/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O such/JJ/O skills/NNS/O were/VBD/O alien/JJ/O to/TO/O Toni/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
A/DT/O friend/NN/O mentioned/VBD/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O might/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O look/VB/O into/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O at/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O if/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O job/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O constantly/RB/O challenge/VB/O her/PRP/O ././O
She/PRP/O signed/VBD/O up/RB/O ,/,/O starting/VBG/O as/IN/O an/DT/O ``/``/O inside/JJ/O ''/''/O adjuster/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O settles/VBZ/O minor/JJ/O claims/NNS/O and/CC/O does/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O by/IN/O phone/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O year/NN/O later/RB/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O moved/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O commercial/JJ/O property/NN/O claims/NNS/O division/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O spent/VBD/O a/DT/O month/NN/O at/IN/O an/DT/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG school/NN/O in/IN/O Gettysburg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O learning/VBG/O all/DT/O about/IN/O the/DT/O construction/NN/O trade/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O masonry/NN/O ,/,/O plumbing/NN/O and/CC/O electrical/JJ/O wiring/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O was/VBD/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O three/CD/O months/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Aetna/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Hartford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O immersed/VBN/O in/IN/O learning/VBG/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O read/VB/O and/CC/O interpret/VB/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O has/VBZ/O some/DT/O perils/NNS/O ././O
Recently/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O contractor/NN/O saved/VBD/O her/PRP/O from/IN/O falling/VBG/O three/CD/O stories/NNS/O as/IN/O she/PRP/O investigated/VBD/O what/WP/O remained/VBD/O of/IN/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O Victorian/JJ/O house/NN/O torched/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O arsonist/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O owe/VBP/O that/DT/O contractor/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O really/RB/O do/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
As/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON stands/VBZ/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON house/NN/O after/IN/O winding/VBG/O up/RP/O her/PRP$/O chores/NNS/O there/EX/O ,/,/O the/DT/O house/NN/O begins/VBZ/O to/TO/O creak/VB/O and/CC/O sway/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O ground/NN/O shakes/VBZ/O underneath/IN/O her/PRP/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O aftershock/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 2,000/CD/O since/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O makes/VBZ/O her/PRP/O uneasy/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O she/PRP/O prepares/VBZ/O a/DT/O $/$/O 10,000/CD/O check/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Hammacks/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O cover/VB/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O demolishing/VBG/O the/DT/O house/NN/O and/CC/O clearing/VBG/O away/RB/O the/DT/O debris/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O jumps/VBZ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O slightest/JJS/O noise/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O further/JJ/O reflection/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O admits/VBZ/O that/IN/O venturing/VBG/O inside/IN/O the/DT/O Hammacks/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O house/NN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O day/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O ``/``/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O idea/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
During/IN/O her/PRP$/O second/JJ/O meeting/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Hammacks/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON reviews/VBZ/O exactly/RB/O what/WP/O their/PRP$/O policy/NN/O covers/VBZ/O ././O
They/PRP/O would/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O retrieve/VB/O some/DT/O appliances/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O floor/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O wonder/VBP/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O safe/JJ/O to/TO/O venture/VB/O inside/RB/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON tells/VBZ/O them/PRP/O that/IN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O appliances/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O salvaged/VBN/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O policy/NN/O covers/VBZ/O the/DT/O replacement/NN/O cost/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O eager/JJ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O what/WP/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O house/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O come/VB/O down/RP/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O will/MD/O I/PRP/O get/VB/O that/DT/O check/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O million/CD/O dollars/NNS/O ?/./O ''/''/O he/PRP/O jokes/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O adjuster/NN/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O completed/VBN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O calculations/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O talking/VBG/O policy/NN/O limits/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O this/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O suddenly/RB/O dawns/VBZ/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O rebuilding/VBG/O the/DT/O house/NN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Gatos/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O affluent/JJ/O community/NN/O in/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Clara/NNP/I-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O may/MD/O cost/VB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O policy/NN/O will/MD/O pay/VB/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O can/MD/O lose/VB/O money/NN/O on/IN/O this/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O And/CC/O you/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O me/PRP/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O earthquake/NN/O insurance/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mrs./NNP/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O reaching/VBG/O across/IN/O the/DT/O table/NN/O and/CC/O gently/RB/O tapping/VBG/O his/PRP$/O hand/NN/O ././O
Earthquake/NN/O insurance/NN/O costs/VBZ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 4/CD/O annually/RB/O for/IN/O every/DT/O $/$/O 1,000/CD/O of/IN/O value/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O high/JJ/O deductibles/NNS/O mean/VBP/O it/PRP/O generally/RB/O pays/VBZ/O only/RB/O when/WRB/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O catastrophe/NN/O ././O
So/RB/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O Californians/NNPS/O believe/VBP/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O get/VB/O by/RP/O without/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Even/RB/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON herself/PRP/O made/VBD/O that/DT/O assumption/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O always/RB/O knew/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O `/``/O Big/JJ/O One/NN/O '/''/O was/VBD/O coming/VBG/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O during/IN/O my/PRP$/O lifetime/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Now/RB/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O thinking/VBG/O of/IN/O contacting/VBG/O her/PRP$/O own/JJ/O insurance/NN/O agent/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O just/RB/O a/DT/O work/NN/O experience/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O lives/VBZ/O in/IN/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O community/NN/O hit/VBN/O hard/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O hot/JJ/O water/NN/O for/IN/O five/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O sister/NN/O ,/,/O Cynthia/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O wishes/VBZ/O Toni/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O job/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O worry/VBP/O about/IN/O her/PRP/O out/RB/O there/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Cynthia/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Last/JJ/O Sunday/NNP/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON finally/RB/O got/VBD/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O water/VB/O her/PRP$/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O stopped/VBD/O abruptly/RB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O realized/VBD/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O waste/VB/O this/DT/O water/NN/O when/WRB/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O Watsonville/NNP/B-GPE who/WP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O fresh/JJ/O water/NN/O to/TO/O drink/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O played/VBN/O any/DT/O music/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O hit/VB/O ,/,/O out/IN/O of/IN/O respect/NN/O for/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O died/VBD/O on/IN/O Interstate/NNP/B-FAC 880/CD/I-FAC where/WRB/O the/DT/O roadway/NN/O collapsed/VBD/O ././O
