Analysts/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O move/NN/O could/MD/O presage/VB/O even/RB/O harsher/JJR/O action/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O any/DT/O move/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O to/TO/O take/VB/O over/RP/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG management/NN/O could/MD/O threaten/VB/O its/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O its/PRP$/O national/JJ/O television/NN/O network/NN/O under/IN/O Australian/JJ/O broadcast/NN/O license/NN/O rules/NNS/O ././O
That/IN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O substantially/RB/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O television/NN/O assets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O appointment/NN/O of/IN/O Peat/NNP/B-ORG Marwick/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O that/WDT/O specializes/VBZ/O in/IN/O advising/VBG/O troubled/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O came/VBD/O about/RP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O round/NN/O of/IN/O meetings/NNS/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Skase/NNP/I-PERSON with/IN/O bank/NN/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Skase/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O solvent/JJ/O and/CC/O with/IN/O the/DT/O continued/JJ/O support/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O bankers/NNS/O is/VBZ/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O its/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O commitments/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O faltered/VBD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O its/PRP$/O offer/NN/O to/TO/O US$/$/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O following/VBG/O a/DT/O counterbid/NN/O from/IN/O Rupert/NNP/B-PERSON Murdoch/NNP/I-PERSON ;/:/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O fell/VBD/O apart/RP/O altogether/RB/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG owes/VBZ/O creditors/NNS/O around/IN/O A$/$/O 1.2/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
