AGIP/NNP/B-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Libya/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Franco/NNP/B-PERSON Reviglio/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ENI/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O ,/,/O looks/VBZ/O for/IN/O sweeping/JJ/O structural/JJ/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O industry/NN/O --/:/O he/PRP/O calls/VBZ/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O ``/``/O revolution/NN/O ''/''/O requiring/VBG/O huge/JJ/O investments/NNS/O --/:/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O environmental/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O examine/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE environmental/JJ/O trends/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O often/RB/O followed/VBN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
ENI/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O what/WP/O 's/VBZ/O coming/VBG/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O prepares/VBZ/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O some/DT/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O on/IN/O upgrading/VBG/O its/PRP$/O refineries/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O go/VB/O for/IN/O work/NN/O ranging/VBG/O from/IN/O refinery/NN/O modification/NN/O to/TO/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O distribution/NN/O system/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O way/NN/O service/NN/O stations/NNS/O pump/VBP/O fuel/NN/O into/IN/O cars/NNS/O ././O
Alaska/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Arctic/NNP/B-LOC National/NNP/I-LOC Wildlife/NNP/I-LOC Refuge/NNP/I-LOC alone/RB/O is/VBZ/O thought/VBN/O to/TO/O hide/VB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O three/CD/O billion/CD/O barrels/NNS/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O huge/JJ/O production/NN/O system/NN/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sea/NN/O off/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Barbara/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O ashore/RB/O is/VBZ/O sitting/VBG/O idle/JJ/O ././O
