Toni/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON pulls/VBZ/O a/DT/O tape/NN/O measure/NN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O front/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O was/VBD/O once/RB/O a/DT/O stately/JJ/O Victorian/JJ/O home/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O deep/JJ/O trench/NN/O now/RB/O runs/VBZ/O along/IN/O its/PRP$/O north/NN/O wall/NN/O ,/,/O exposed/VBN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O house/NN/O lurched/VBD/O two/CD/O feet/NNS/O off/IN/O its/PRP$/O foundation/NN/O during/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O side/NN/O porch/NN/O was/VBD/O ripped/VBN/O away/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O chimney/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O pile/NN/O of/IN/O bricks/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O front/JJ/O lawn/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O remainder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O house/NN/O leans/VBZ/O precariously/RB/O against/IN/O a/DT/O sturdy/JJ/O oak/NN/O tree/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O move/NN/O almost/RB/O incessantly/RB/O since/IN/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O an/DT/O army/NN/O of/IN/O adjusters/NNS/O ,/,/O employed/VBN/O by/IN/O major/JJ/O insurers/NNS/O ,/,/O invaded/VBD/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O policyholders/NNS/O sift/VB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O rubble/NN/O and/CC/O restore/VB/O some/DT/O order/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O lives/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O will/MD/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O demolish/VB/O unstable/JJ/O buildings/NNS/O and/CC/O clear/VB/O sites/NNS/O for/IN/O future/JJ/O construction/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O adjusters/NNS/O are/VBP/O authorized/VBN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O checks/NNS/O for/IN/O amounts/NNS/O up/RB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 100,000/CD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O spot/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O flinch/VB/O at/IN/O writing/VBG/O them/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O Victorian/JJ/O house/NN/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O inspecting/VBG/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O deemed/VBN/O unsafe/JJ/O by/IN/O town/NN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
She/PRP/O snaps/VBZ/O photos/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O buckled/JJ/O floors/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O plaster/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O fallen/VBN/O away/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O walls/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O friends/NNS/O sweeps/VBZ/O broken/JJ/O dishes/NNS/O and/CC/O shattered/JJ/O glass/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O countertop/NN/O and/CC/O starts/VBZ/O to/TO/O pack/VB/O what/WP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O salvaged/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O kitchen/NN/O ././O
Others/NNS/O grab/VBP/O books/NNS/O ,/,/O records/NNS/O ,/,/O photo/NN/O albums/NNS/O ,/,/O sofas/NNS/O and/CC/O chairs/NNS/O ,/,/O working/VBG/O frantically/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fear/NN/O that/IN/O an/DT/O aftershock/NN/O will/MD/O jolt/VB/O the/DT/O house/NN/O again/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O owners/NNS/O ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Margie/NNP/B-PERSON Hammack/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O are/VBP/O luckier/JJR/O than/IN/O many/JJ/O others/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON insisted/VBD/O on/IN/O buying/VBG/O earthquake/NN/O insurance/NN/O for/IN/O this/DT/O house/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O converted/VBN/O into/IN/O apartments/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Hammacks/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O own/JJ/O home/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Gatos/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O suffered/VBD/O comparatively/RB/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O works/VBZ/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O office/NN/O in/IN/O Walnut/NNP/B-GPE Creek/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC suburb/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O awed/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O 's/POS/O destructive/JJ/O force/NN/O ././O
Aetna/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O nearly/RB/O 3,000/CD/O adjusters/NNS/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O deployed/VBN/O about/IN/O 750/CD/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O Charlotte/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Columbia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Charleston/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Adjusters/NNS/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC say/VBP/O the/DT/O insurer/NN/O will/MD/O still/RB/O be/VB/O processing/VBG/O claims/NNS/O from/IN/O that/DT/O storm/NN/O through/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
Some/DT/O adjusters/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Singer/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O in/IN/O Charleston/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O nearly/RB/O four/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O returned/VBD/O home/RB/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O packed/VBD/O a/DT/O bag/NN/O with/IN/O fresh/JJ/O clothes/NNS/O and/CC/O reported/VBD/O for/IN/O duty/NN/O Friday/NNP/O in/IN/O Walnut/NNP/B-GPE Creek/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Offices/NNS/O were/VBD/O set/VBN/O up/RB/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Adjusters/NNS/O must/MD/O count/VB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O bathrooms/NNS/O ,/,/O balconies/NNS/O ,/,/O fireplaces/NNS/O ,/,/O chimneys/NNS/O ,/,/O microwaves/NNS/O and/CC/O dishwashers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Schaeffer/NNP/B-PERSON presented/VBD/O the/DT/O couple/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O check/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 151,000/CD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O them/PRP/O build/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O home/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O neighborhood/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O adjusters/NNS/O employed/VBN/O by/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O insurers/NNS/O have/VBP/O some/DT/O experience/NN/O with/IN/O construction/NN/O work/NN/O or/CC/O carpentry/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O friend/NN/O mentioned/VBD/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O might/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O look/VB/O into/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O at/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O if/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O job/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O constantly/RB/O challenge/VB/O her/PRP/O ././O
She/PRP/O signed/VBD/O up/RB/O ,/,/O starting/VBG/O as/IN/O an/DT/O ``/``/O inside/JJ/O ''/''/O adjuster/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O settles/VBZ/O minor/JJ/O claims/NNS/O and/CC/O does/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O by/IN/O phone/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O year/NN/O later/RB/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O moved/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O commercial/JJ/O property/NN/O claims/NNS/O division/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O spent/VBD/O a/DT/O month/NN/O at/IN/O an/DT/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG school/NN/O in/IN/O Gettysburg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O learning/VBG/O all/DT/O about/IN/O the/DT/O construction/NN/O trade/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O masonry/NN/O ,/,/O plumbing/NN/O and/CC/O electrical/JJ/O wiring/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O was/VBD/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O three/CD/O months/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Aetna/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Hartford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O immersed/VBN/O in/IN/O learning/VBG/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O read/VB/O and/CC/O interpret/VB/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O has/VBZ/O some/DT/O perils/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O really/RB/O do/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O ground/NN/O shakes/VBZ/O underneath/IN/O her/PRP/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O aftershock/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 2,000/CD/O since/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O makes/VBZ/O her/PRP/O uneasy/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O she/PRP/O prepares/VBZ/O a/DT/O $/$/O 10,000/CD/O check/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Hammacks/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O cover/VB/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O demolishing/VBG/O the/DT/O house/NN/O and/CC/O clearing/VBG/O away/RB/O the/DT/O debris/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O jumps/VBZ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O slightest/JJS/O noise/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O would/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O retrieve/VB/O some/DT/O appliances/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O floor/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O wonder/VBP/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O safe/JJ/O to/TO/O venture/VB/O inside/RB/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON tells/VBZ/O them/PRP/O that/IN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O appliances/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O salvaged/VBN/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O policy/NN/O covers/VBZ/O the/DT/O replacement/NN/O cost/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O eager/JJ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O what/WP/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O house/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O come/VB/O down/RP/O ././O
It/PRP/O suddenly/RB/O dawns/VBZ/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hammack/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O rebuilding/VBG/O the/DT/O house/NN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Gatos/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O affluent/JJ/O community/NN/O in/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Clara/NNP/I-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O may/MD/O cost/VB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O Aetna/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O policy/NN/O will/MD/O pay/VB/O ././O
Earthquake/NN/O insurance/NN/O costs/VBZ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 4/CD/O annually/RB/O for/IN/O every/DT/O $/$/O 1,000/CD/O of/IN/O value/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O high/JJ/O deductibles/NNS/O mean/VBP/O it/PRP/O generally/RB/O pays/VBZ/O only/RB/O when/WRB/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O catastrophe/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O lives/VBZ/O in/IN/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O community/NN/O hit/VBN/O hard/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O hot/JJ/O water/NN/O for/IN/O five/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O sister/NN/O ,/,/O Cynthia/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O wishes/VBZ/O Toni/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O job/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O Sunday/NNP/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON finally/RB/O got/VBD/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O water/VB/O her/PRP$/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O stopped/VBD/O abruptly/RB/O ././O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O played/VBN/O any/DT/O music/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O hit/VB/O ,/,/O out/IN/O of/IN/O respect/NN/O for/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O died/VBD/O on/IN/O Interstate/NNP/B-FAC 880/CD/I-FAC where/WRB/O the/DT/O roadway/NN/O collapsed/VBD/O ././O
