When/WRB/O the/DT/O going/VBG/O gets/VBZ/O tough/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O tough/JJ/O to/TO/O trade/VB/O stocks/NNS/O in/IN/O continental/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O troubling/JJ/O conclusion/NN/O reached/VBN/O by/IN/O many/JJ/O international/JJ/O investors/NNS/O and/CC/O money/NN/O managers/NNS/O angry/JJ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O malfunctions/NNS/O on/IN/O Continental/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O during/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O global/JJ/O market/NN/O turbulence/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O market/NN/O volatility/NN/O has/VBZ/O underscored/VBN/O the/DT/O shortcomings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O many/JJ/O European/JJ/O exchanges/NNS/O trade/VBP/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O saying/VBG/O London/NNP/B-ORG covered/VBD/O itself/PRP/O in/IN/O glory/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O week/NN/O have/VBP/O certainly/RB/O exposed/VBN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O weaknesses/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Stewart/NNP/B-PERSON Gilchrist/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Scottish/NNP/B-ORG Amicable/NNP/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Managers/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Glasgow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Scotland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O manages/VBZ/O about/IN/O #/#/O 6/CD/O billion/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 9.63/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O institutional/JJ/O money/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O events/NNS/O strengthen/VBP/O London/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O hand/NN/O in/IN/O becoming/VBG/O the/DT/O center/NN/O for/IN/O trading/VBG/O European/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Gilchrist/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
London/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O some/DT/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O
Some/DT/O dealers/NNS/O say/VBP/O other/JJ/O traders/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O picking/VBG/O up/RP/O their/PRP$/O phones/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O London/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O problems/NNS/O were/VBD/O nothing/NN/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Continent/NN/O 's/POS/O ././O
For/IN/O 48/CD/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O no/DT/O one/CD/O had/VBD/O any/DT/O idea/NN/O precisely/RB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O his/PRP$/O securities/NNS/O were/VBD/O worth/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Belgian/JJ/O computer/NN/O system/NN/O finally/RB/O was/VBD/O repaired/VBN/O and/CC/O restarted/VBN/O on/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O of/IN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O aid/NN/O of/IN/O Toronto/NNP/B-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O who/WP/O developed/VBD/O the/DT/O system/NN/O ././O
Exchange/NN/O officials/NNS/O extended/VBD/O trading/NN/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O 75/CD/O minutes/NNS/O on/IN/O Monday/NNP/O and/CC/O 65/CD/O minutes/NNS/O on/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O to/TO/O clear/VB/O up/RP/O order/NN/O backlogs/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O by/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O big/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O had/VBD/O switched/VBN/O business/NN/O to/TO/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O Belgium/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O closed/VBN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE closed/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O stuck/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O nightmare/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Susan/NNP/B-PERSON Noble/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O manager/NN/O at/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-ORG Fleming/NNP/I-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG International/NNP/B-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O worrying/JJ/O that/IN/O these/DT/O markets/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O cope/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
On/IN/O Manic/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O German/JJ/O shares/NNS/O traded/VBN/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE more/RBR/O than/IN/O tripled/VBD/O to/TO/O 2.2/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O French/JJ/O shares/NNS/O rose/VBD/O 48/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O By/IN/O comparison/NN/O ,/,/O German/JJ/O domestic/JJ/O stock/NN/O volume/NN/O in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE only/RB/O doubled/VBD/O that/DT/O day/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
The/DT/O switch/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O during/IN/O such/JJ/O turbulent/JJ/O times/NNS/O is/VBZ/O significant/JJ/O ././O
For/IN/O one/CD/O thing/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O affected/JJ/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O enormous/JJ/O --/:/O the/DT/O European/JJ/O stock/NN/O markets/NNS/O account/VBP/O for/IN/O some/DT/O 22.5/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O global/JJ/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O capitalization/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O value/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.175/CD/O trillion/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Stanley/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Continental/JJ/O markets/NNS/O alone/RB/O contribute/VBP/O about/IN/O 14.3/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O estimated/VBN/O world/NN/O market/NN/O capitalization/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 9.671/CD/O trillion/CD/O ././O
Though/IN/O the/DT/O widely/RB/O traded/VBN/O shares/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O quoted/VBN/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE account/NN/O for/IN/O only/RB/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O totals/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O closely/RB/O watched/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O often/RB/O viewed/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O barometer/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O markets/NNS/O generally/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O switch/NN/O to/TO/O London/NNP/B-ORG underscores/VBZ/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O market/NN/O by/IN/O 1992/CD/O ,/,/O European/JJ/O stock/NN/O trading/NN/O remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O highly/RB/O fragmented/JJ/O and/CC/O very/RB/O localized/JJ/O activity/NN/O ././O
Against/IN/O this/DT/O backdrop/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O thing/NN/O that/WDT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O likely/RB/O to/TO/O result/VB/O from/IN/O 1992/CD/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O European/JJ/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O firms/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O often/RB/O have/VBP/O acquired/VBN/O a/DT/O local/JJ/O brokerage/NN/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O calling/VBG/O the/DT/O shots/NNS/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O comes/VBZ/O to/TO/O deciding/VBG/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O market/NN/O to/TO/O transact/VB/O a/DT/O trade/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O senior/JJ/O officials/NNS/O of/IN/O two/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE securities/NNS/O houses/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O switched/VBD/O trades/NNS/O in/IN/O European/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O unwind/VB/O positions/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Continent/NN/O ././O
Meantime/RB/O ,/,/O brokers/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Continent/NN/O are/VBP/O worried/JJ/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O much/RB/O happier/JJR/O if/IN/O this/DT/O volume/NN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O in/IN/O German/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O were/VBD/O in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE rather/RB/O than/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Dieter/NNP/B-PERSON Bauernfeind/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O equity/NN/O sales/NNS/O at/IN/O Dresdner/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O acknowledges/VBZ/O that/IN/O spreads/NNS/O ``/``/O were/VBD/O too/RB/O wide/JJ/O and/CC/O volumes/NNS/O too/RB/O light/JJ/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O extreme/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O on/IN/O Manic/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
Already/RB/O the/DT/O Germans/NNPS/O appear/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O acting/VBG/O ;/:/O at/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O meeting/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O decline/NN/O ,/,/O directors/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Frankfurt/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG voted/VBD/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O their/PRP$/O trading/NN/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O although/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O decided/VBN/O when/WRB/O or/CC/O by/IN/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE exchange/NN/O official/NN/O ,/,/O acknowledging/VBG/O the/DT/O brokers/NNS/O '/POS/O anxieties/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O market/NN/O still/RB/O feels/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O functioned/VBD/O OK/UH/O during/IN/O this/DT/O crash/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Dutch/NNPS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O some/DT/O trading/NN/O problems/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O insufficient/JJ/O computer/NN/O capacity/NN/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O new/JJ/O equipment/NN/O to/TO/O solve/VB/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O installed/VBN/O within/IN/O a/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O a/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Brussels/NNP/I-ORG Bourse/NNP/I-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O Nobody/NN/O around/IN/O here/RB/O will/MD/O tell/VB/O you/PRP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O happy/JJ/O the/DT/O system/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O work/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O just/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O those/DT/O things/NNS/O that/WDT/O happened/VBD/O ././O
Investors/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O assured/VBN/O now/RB/O that/IN/O this/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O problem/NN/O can/MD/O never/RB/O occur/VB/O again/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O for/IN/O others/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O pledges/NNS/O echo/VBP/O the/DT/O promises/NNS/O made/VBN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O stock/NN/O crash/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O similar/JJ/O problems/NNS/O led/VBD/O many/JJ/O markets/NNS/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O systems/NNS/O that/WDT/O performed/VBD/O so/RB/O badly/RB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O all/DT/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O invested/VBD/O huge/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O either/RB/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O buy/VB/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O machines/NNS/O or/CC/O they/PRP/O wasted/VBD/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Fleming/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Ms./NNP/O Noble/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
