The/DT/O McLean/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O company/NN/O modifies/VBZ/O computers/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O sensitive/JJ/O military/JJ/O data/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O unfriendly/JJ/O hands/NNS/O ././O
Iverson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O earnings/NNS/O plunged/VBD/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.2/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O troubles/NNS/O continued/VBN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O profit/NN/O plunged/VBD/O 81/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 302,000/CD/O ././O
Iverson/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O small/JJ/O defense/NN/O contractors/NNS/O besieged/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O slowdown/NN/O in/IN/O defense/NN/O spending/NN/O ././O
Companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O only/RB/O recently/RB/O were/VBD/O thriving/JJ/O find/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O scrambling/VBG/O to/TO/O survive/VB/O ././O
More/RBR/O venturesome/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O are/VBP/O applying/VBG/O their/PRP$/O skills/NNS/O in/IN/O commercial/JJ/O fields/NNS/O ././O
ERC/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O provides/VBZ/O professional/JJ/O and/CC/O technical/JJ/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O military/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O refining/VBG/O its/PRP$/O defense/NN/O niche/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O retreating/VBG/O from/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
UNC/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O Annapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Md./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O contractor/NN/O that/WDT/O earned/VBD/O $/$/O 23.8/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 400.4/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O gone/VBN/O even/RB/O further/RBR/O in/IN/O realigning/VBG/O its/PRP$/O military/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
UNC/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O is/VBZ/O selling/VBG/O new/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O if/IN/O needed/VBN/O ,/,/O directly/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O through/IN/O a/DT/O prime/JJ/O contractor/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O taking/VBG/O over/RP/O the/DT/O maintenance/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG aircraft/NN/O with/IN/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O fewer/JJR/O people/NNS/O than/IN/O the/DT/O military/NN/O used/VBD/O ././O
Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Iverson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O hopes/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O can/MD/O eventually/RB/O get/VB/O up/RB/O to/TO/O half/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O commercial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Iverson/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O 5,000/CD/O potential/JJ/O customers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O software/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O area/NN/O alone/RB/O ././O
QuesTech/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Falls/NNP/B-GPE Church/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O acquired/VBN/O some/DT/O companies/NNS/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O partnership/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Williamsburg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Shell/NNP/B-ORG Oil/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG recently/RB/O patented/VBD/O a/DT/O process/NN/O for/IN/O producing/VBG/O plastic/NN/O food/NN/O containers/NNS/O that/WDT/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O melt/VB/O in/IN/O microwave/NN/O ovens/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Salvatori/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O know/VB/O ././O
Some/DT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O cutting/VBG/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O hoping/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O ././O
Telos/NNP/B-ORG responded/VBD/O by/IN/O combining/VBG/O three/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O five/CD/O divisions/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O expenses/NNS/O and/CC/O ``/``/O bring/VB/O more/JJR/O focus/NN/O to/TO/O potentially/RB/O fewer/JJR/O bidding/NN/O opportunities/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Lin/NNP/B-PERSON Conger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Telos/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O controlling/VBG/O shareholder/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O closing/NN/O contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O $/$/O 3.4/CD/O million/CD/O loss/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ended/VBN/O July/NNP/O 31/CD/O --/:/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O quarterly/JJ/O loss/NN/O since/IN/O 1974/CD/O ././O
