Exxon/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O move/VB/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O from/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 300/CD/O employees/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O midtown/JJ/O headquarters/NN/O building/NN/O --/:/O including/VBG/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O senior/JJ/O management/NN/O --/:/O were/VBD/O unaware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O until/IN/O informed/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O morning/NN/O meeting/NN/O by/IN/O Chairman/NNP/O Lawrence/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Rawl/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O shift/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O affect/VB/O operations/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O pullout/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O embarrassment/NN/O to/TO/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE officials/NNS/O ,/,/O coming/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O high/JJ/O office/NN/O building/NN/O vacancy/NN/O rates/NNS/O and/CC/O departures/NNS/O by/IN/O other/JJ/O major/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O dismayed/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O do/VB/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O now/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON Grayson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE deputy/NN/O mayor/NN/O for/IN/O finance/NN/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O development/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE welcomed/VBD/O the/DT/O move/NN/O ././O
City/NN/O officials/NNS/O there/EX/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O were/VBD/O aware/JJ/O that/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O company/NN/O was/VBD/O moving/VBG/O in/RP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O negotiations/NNS/O had/VBD/O all/DT/O been/VBN/O conducted/VBN/O through/IN/O a/DT/O law/NN/O firm/NN/O and/CC/O under/IN/O the/DT/O code/NN/O name/NN/O ``/``/O Everglades/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O When/WRB/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O told/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O beyond/IN/O all/DT/O expectations/NNS/O ;/:/O what/WP/O a/DT/O coup/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Tom/NNP/B-PERSON Lewis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-ORG Partnership/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O development/NN/O affiliate/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O Chamber/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O its/PRP$/O economy/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O slump/NN/O ././O
Until/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O is/VBZ/O completed/VBN/O ,/,/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O rent/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O existing/VBG/O office/NN/O tower/NN/O ././O
Las/NNP/B-FAC Colinas/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O once/RB/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ranch/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O sprawling/VBG/O complex/NN/O of/IN/O office/NN/O buildings/NNS/O ,/,/O homes/NNS/O and/CC/O recreational/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O developers/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O struggling/VBG/O to/TO/O populate/VB/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
Exxon/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O less/JJR/O to/TO/O run/VB/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O at/IN/O Las/NNP/B-FAC Colinas/NNP/I-FAC than/IN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O save/VB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O during/IN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O interim/NN/O location/NN/O ,/,/O sources/NNS/O say/VBP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O likely/RB/O pay/VB/O rent/VB/O of/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 15/CD/O per/IN/O square/JJ/O foot/NN/O ././O
Owners/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE say/VBP/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O asking/VBG/O $/$/O 50/CD/O per/IN/O square/JJ/O foot/NN/O for/IN/O rent/NN/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O the/DT/O space/NN/O that/IN/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O vacating/VBG/O ././O
In/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O taxes/NNS/O and/CC/O development/NN/O costs/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O lower/JJR/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
