European/JJ/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG employers/NNS/O fear/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG EC/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG plans/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O charter/NN/O of/IN/O fundamental/JJ/O social/JJ/O rights/NNS/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O danger/NN/O to/TO/O industrial/JJ/O competitiveness/NN/O ././O
Unice/NNP/B-ORG --/:/O an/DT/O acronym/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Industrial/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Employers/NNPS/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG Confederations/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O fears/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O will/MD/O force/VB/O EC/NNP/B-ORG countries/NNS/O to/TO/O adopt/VB/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O pattern/NN/O in/IN/O labor/NN/O relations/NNS/O ././O
Workers/NNS/O and/CC/O management/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Tyszkiewicz/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O would/MD/O lose/VB/O the/DT/O ``/``/O flexibility/NN/O and/CC/O diversity/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O so/RB/O far/RB/O allowed/VBN/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O adapt/VB/O to/TO/O local/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O and/CC/O traditions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O British/JJ/O government/NN/O also/RB/O strongly/RB/O opposes/VBZ/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O form/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O argues/VBZ/O ,/,/O as/RB/O does/VBZ/O Unice/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O that/IN/O labor/NN/O relations/NNS/O are/VBP/O best/RB/O left/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O regulated/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O national/JJ/O level/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tyszkiewicz/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O would/MD/O put/VB/O poorer/JJR/O EC/NNP/B-ORG countries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Portugal/NNP/B-GPE at/IN/O a/DT/O disadvantage/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O force/VB/O these/DT/O countries/NNS/O to/TO/O introduce/VB/O minimum/JJ/O standards/NNS/O for/IN/O pay/NN/O and/CC/O working/NN/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O provide/VB/O for/IN/O collective/JJ/O bargaining/NN/O and/CC/O worker/NN/O ``/``/O participation/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O major/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O warned/VBD/O ,/,/O would/MD/O prevent/VB/O these/DT/O countries/NNS/O from/IN/O bridging/VBG/O the/DT/O difference/NN/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O richer/JJR/O EC/NNP/B-ORG brethren/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O charter/NN/O would/MD/O just/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O restricted/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O workers/NNS/O '/POS/O fundamental/JJ/O rights/NNS/O ,/,/O without/IN/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O impose/VB/O any/DT/O norms/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O key/JJ/O provision/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O would/MD/O give/VB/O the/DT/O commission/NN/B-ORG a/DT/O mandate/NN/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O an/DT/O ``/``/O action/NN/O program/NN/O ''/''/O detailing/VBG/O on/IN/O what/WDT/O points/NNS/O EC/NNP/B-ORG member/NN/O states/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O comply/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O goals/NNS/O set/VBN/O out/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O provision/NN/O lies/VBZ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O and/CC/O Unice/NNP/B-ORG fears/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O social/JJ/O engineering/NN/O ''/''/O by/IN/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O possible/JJ/O political/JJ/O solution/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O would/MD/O be/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O to/TO/O present/VB/O the/DT/O action/NN/O program/NN/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O November/NNP/O ,/,/O before/IN/O the/DT/O adoption/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O summit/NN/O of/IN/O EC/NNP/B-ORG governments/NNS/O on/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 8/CD/O and/CC/O 9/CD/O ././O
This/DT/O would/MD/O leave/VB/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE free/JJ/O to/TO/O adopt/VB/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O after/IN/O having/VBG/O rebutted/VBN/O the/DT/O action/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O charter/NN/O was/VBD/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG EC/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O Sept./NNP/O 21/CD/O ././O
France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Socialist/JJ/O government/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O currently/RB/O holds/VBZ/O the/DT/O council/NN/O 's/POS/O rotating/VBG/O presidency/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O committed/VBN/O to/TO/O having/VBG/O the/DT/O charter/NN/O adopted/VBN/O by/IN/O all/DT/O 12/CD/O EC/NNP/B-ORG states/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O --/:/O the/DT/O bicentennial/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O French/JJ/O revolution/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O ``/``/O Universal/NNP/O Declaration/NNP/O of/IN/O Human/NNP/O Rights/NNPS/O ././O
