But/CC/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O question/NN/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sikes/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O extraordinarily/RB/O cautious/JJ/O man/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O continue/VB/O pushing/VBG/O deregulation/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O face/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O great/JJ/O political/JJ/O pressure/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O means/VBZ/O that/IN/O Sikes/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O serious/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O deregulation/NN/O of/IN/O long/JJ/O distance/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Grubman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O telecommunications/NN/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O attended/VBD/O the/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG meeting/NN/O ././O
``/``/O All/PDT/O the/DT/O commissioners/NNS/O were/VBD/O in/IN/O amazing/JJ/O agreement/NN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O to/TO/O re-examine/VB/O regulation/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O for/IN/O only/RB/O having/VBG/O been/VBN/O together/RB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O again/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
United/NNP/B-ORG Telecommunications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG US/PRP/B-ORG Sprint/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O obviously/RB/O disappointed/JJ/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG decision/NN/O on/IN/O Tariff/NN/O 12/CD/O ././O
US/PRP/B-ORG Sprint/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O was/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O petition/VB/O the/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG decision/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O will/MD/O find/VB/O it/PRP/O unlawful/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O US/PRP/B-ORG Sprint/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
Julie/NNP/B-PERSON Amparano/NNP/I-PERSON Lopez/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
