In/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Exxon/NNP/O Valdez/NNP/O spill/NN/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O ,/,/O new/JJ/O governmental/JJ/O drilling/NN/O bans/NNS/O are/VBP/O sharply/RB/O curtailing/VBG/O exploration/NN/O in/IN/O promising/JJ/O locations/NNS/O offshore/RB/O and/CC/O in/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O stream/NN/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O growing/VBG/O heavier/RBR/O ././O
So/RB/O the/DT/O scramble/NN/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O for/IN/O lighter/JJR/O crudes/NNS/O globally/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O for/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
And/CC/O some/DT/O oil/NN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O lock/VB/O in/RP/O future/JJ/O supplies/NNS/O ././O
AGIP/NNP/B-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Libya/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Franco/NNP/B-PERSON Reviglio/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ENI/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O ,/,/O looks/VBZ/O for/IN/O sweeping/JJ/O structural/JJ/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O industry/NN/O --/:/O he/PRP/O calls/VBZ/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O ``/``/O revolution/NN/O ''/''/O requiring/VBG/O huge/JJ/O investments/NNS/O --/:/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O environmental/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O examine/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE environmental/JJ/O trends/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O often/RB/O followed/VBN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
ENI/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O what/WP/O 's/VBZ/O coming/VBG/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O prepares/VBZ/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O some/DT/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O on/IN/O upgrading/VBG/O its/PRP$/O refineries/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O go/VB/O for/IN/O work/NN/O ranging/VBG/O from/IN/O refinery/NN/O modification/NN/O to/TO/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O distribution/NN/O system/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O way/NN/O service/NN/O stations/NNS/O pump/VBP/O fuel/NN/O into/IN/O cars/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O search/NN/O for/IN/O oil/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O headed/VBN/O toward/IN/O environmentally/RB/O sensitive/JJ/O areas/NNS/O believed/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O vast/JJ/O reserves/NNS/O ././O
Alaska/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Arctic/NNP/B-LOC National/NNP/I-LOC Wildlife/NNP/I-LOC Refuge/NNP/I-LOC alone/RB/O is/VBZ/O thought/VBN/O to/TO/O hide/VB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O three/CD/O billion/CD/O barrels/NNS/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O ././O
Until/IN/O the/DT/O tanker/NN/O spill/NN/O ,/,/O Big/NNP/O Oil/NNP/O was/VBD/O slowly/RB/O convincing/JJ/O authorities/NNS/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O safely/RB/O produce/VB/O from/IN/O such/JJ/O places/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O the/DT/O wildlife/NN/O refuge/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O closed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O possibly/RB/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O ././O
Similarly/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O Chevron/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O pump/VB/O oil/NN/O found/VBN/O off/IN/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE coast/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O huge/JJ/O production/NN/O system/NN/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sea/NN/O off/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Barbara/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O ashore/RB/O is/VBZ/O sitting/VBG/O idle/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O push/NN/O for/IN/O cleaner/JJR/O fuels/NNS/O is/VBZ/O increasing/VBG/O the/DT/O attractiveness/NN/O of/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O ././O
More/JJR/O than/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O domestic/JJ/O drilling/NN/O now/RB/O under/IN/O way/NN/O is/VBZ/O for/IN/O gas/NN/O ,/,/O partly/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O that/DT/O demand/NN/O will/MD/O rise/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O fuel/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O cleaner/JJR/O to/TO/O burn/VB/O than/IN/O either/DT/O oil/NN/O or/CC/O coal/NN/O ././O
Santa/NNP/B-ORG Fe/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O Kuwait/NNP/B-GPE -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O Santa/NNP/B-ORG Fe/NNP/I-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG unit/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O stepping/VBG/O up/RP/O development/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O well/NN/O off/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE '/POS/O Matagorda/NNP/B-GPE Island/NNP/I-GPE where/WRB/O it/PRP/O found/VBD/O gas/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O could/MD/O have/VB/O sat/VBN/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O longer/RBR/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O impetus/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O gas/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O marketplace/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Poole/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O scout/NN/O for/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-ORG Fe/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O get/VB/O it/PRP/O on/IN/O line/NN/O as/RB/O soon/RB/O as/IN/O possible/RB/O now/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
