Albert/NNP/B-PERSON Engelken/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON had/VBD/O never/RB/O met/VBN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O for/IN/O 38/CD/O years/NNS/O their/PRP$/O lives/NNS/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O intertwined/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O peculiar/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O sports/NNS/O world/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O one/CD/O recent/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O became/VBD/O much/RB/O closer/JJR/O ././O
He/PRP/O often/RB/O groans/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O at/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O clutter/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O sports/NNS/O stories/NNS/O about/IN/O drugs/NNS/O ,/,/O alcohol/NN/O ,/,/O gambling/NN/O and/CC/O some/DT/O player/NN/O 's/POS/O lament/NN/O ``/``/O about/IN/O the/DT/O miserly/JJ/O millions/NNS/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O offered/VBN/O to/TO/O play/VB/O the/DT/O game/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
His/PRP$/O morning/NN/O paper/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG Post/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O even/RB/O carries/VBZ/O a/DT/O sports/NNS/O column/NN/O called/VBN/O ``/``/O Jurisprudence/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O recounts/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O arrests/NNS/O and/CC/O convictions/NNS/O of/IN/O players/NNS/O and/CC/O team/NN/O managers/NNS/O ././O
Like/IN/O many/JJ/O sports/NNS/O buffs/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O turned/VBN/O cynic/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O his/PRP$/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O story/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O hero/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O era/NN/O of/IN/O sports/NNS/O anti-heroes/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O about/IN/O what/WP/O Babe/NNP/B-PERSON Ruth/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON reminds/VBZ/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O once/RB/O called/VBD/O ``/``/O the/DT/O only/RB/O real/JJ/O game/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
To/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O story/NN/O ``/``/O about/IN/O love/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O blessed/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O wife/NN/O who/WP/O still/RB/O thinks/VBZ/O her/PRP/O slightly/RB/O eccentric/JJ/O husband/NN/O 's/POS/O 50th/JJ/O birthday/NN/O deserves/VBZ/O the/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O present/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
To/TO/O understand/VB/O what/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON means/VBZ/O ,/,/O one/PRP/O must/MD/O go/VB/O back/RB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O sunny/JJ/O October/NNP/O afternoon/NN/O in/IN/O 1951/CD/O at/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE Polo/NNP/B-FAC Grounds/NNPS/I-FAC stadium/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O argued/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O dramatic/JJ/O moment/NN/O in/IN/O baseball/NN/O history/NN/O was/VBD/O played/VBN/O out/RP/O ././O
Baseball/NN/O fans/NNS/O throughout/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE had/VBD/O sweated/VBN/O out/RP/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O summer/NN/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O teams/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O now/RB/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O come/VBN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O :/:/O a/DT/O battle/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O National/NNP/B-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG pennant/NN/O --/:/O down/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O inning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O game/NN/O ,/,/O no/RB/O less/RB/O ././O
Some/DT/O 34,320/CD/O fans/NNS/O jammed/VBD/O the/DT/O stands/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O shouted/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O top/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O lungs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Giants/NNPS/B-ORG scored/VBD/O once/RB/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O runners/NNS/O on/IN/O second/JJ/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Whitey/NNP/B-PERSON Lockman/NNP/I-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O third/JJ/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Clint/NNP/B-PERSON Hartung/NNP/I-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/O as/IN/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON advanced/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O plate/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O history/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Thomson/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O a/DT/O called/VBN/O strike/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON recounts/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O tension/NN/O mounted/VBD/O as/IN/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Branca/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O again/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O mound/NN/O ,/,/O stared/VBD/O down/RP/O the/DT/O batter/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O wound/VBD/O up/RB/O and/CC/O let/VB/O loose/VB/O a/DT/O fastball/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O pitch/NN/O sailed/VBD/O toward/IN/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON high/RB/O and/CC/O inside/RB/O and/CC/O then/RB/O ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O crack/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bat/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O sent/VBN/O rocketing/VBG/O back/RB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O lower/JJR/O leftfield/NN/O stands/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Giants/NNS/B-ORG fans/NNS/O went/VBD/O into/IN/O euphoria/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
And/CC/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O made/VBN/O a/DT/O legend/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O an/DT/O older/JJR/O baseball/NN/O fan/NN/O alive/JJ/O who/WP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O clearly/RB/O remember/VB/O that/IN/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON homer/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O tell/VB/O you/PRP/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O heard/VBD/O the/DT/O famous/JJ/O Russ/NNP/B-PERSON Hodges/NNP/I-PERSON radio/NN/O broadcast/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O one/NN/O that/WDT/O concluded/VBD/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hodges/NNP/B-PERSON shouting/VBG/O ,/,/O over/RB/O and/CC/O over/RB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Giants/NNPS/B-ORG win/VBP/O the/DT/O pennant/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Giants/NNPS/B-ORG win/VBP/O the/DT/O pennant/NN/O !/./O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON moved/VBD/O south/RB/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O took/VBD/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O enduring/VBG/O memories/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O homer/NN/O of/IN/O 1951/CD/O ././O
When/WRB/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Betsy/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O came/VBD/O down/IN/O the/DT/O aisle/NN/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O wedding/NN/O day/NN/O in/IN/O 1966/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON --/:/O no/DT/O slouch/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O romantic/JJ/O front/NN/O --/:/O gave/VBD/O her/PRP/O the/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O compliment/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O look/VBP/O prettier/JJR/O than/IN/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON home/NN/O run/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O couple/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O dog/NN/O ,/,/O Homer/NNP/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Great/JJ/O Event/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O unwitting/JJ/O friends/NNS/O assumed/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O namesake/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O poet/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sister/NN/O ,/,/O Martha/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O born/VBN/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O home/NN/O run/NN/O ,/,/O reached/VBD/O her/PRP/O 25th/JJ/O birthday/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON wrote/VBD/O his/PRP$/O sports/NNS/O hero/NN/O to/TO/O tell/VB/O him/PRP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O coincidence/NN/O of/IN/O events/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Thomson/NNP/B-PERSON sent/VBD/O off/RP/O a/DT/O card/NN/O to/TO/O Martha/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O like/IN/O 25/CD/O years/NNS/O since/IN/O I/PRP/O hit/VBP/O that/DT/O home/NN/O run/VB/O to/TO/O celebrate/VB/O your/PRP$/O birth/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O it/PRP/O read/VBD/O ././O
Martha/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O pleased/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O nowhere/RB/O near/RB/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O family/NN/O license/NN/O plate/NN/O reads/VBZ/O ``/``/O ENG/NNP/O 23/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O three/CD/O letters/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O family/NN/O name/NN/O and/CC/O --/:/O no/DT/O surprise/NN/O here/RB/O --/:/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON uniform/JJ/O number/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O 40th/JJ/O birthday/NN/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O bought/VBD/O a/DT/O book/NN/O detailing/VBG/O the/DT/O big/JJ/O homer/NN/O and/CC/O sent/VBD/O it/PRP/O off/RP/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Thomson/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O be/VB/O autographed/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O could/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O better/JJR/O ?/./O ''/''/O asks/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Betsy/NNP/B-PERSON Engelken/NNP/I-PERSON asked/VBD/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O question/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O was/VBD/O about/IN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O 50/CD/O ././O
She/PRP/O had/VBD/O an/DT/O idea/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O scheduled/VBN/O a/DT/O stop/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC New/NNP/I-FAC Jersey/NNP/I-FAC Turnpike/NNP/I-FAC to/TO/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O told/VBD/O her/PRP/O husband/NN/O ,/,/O pick/VB/O up/RP/O some/DT/O papers/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O neighbor/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O papers/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O handed/VBN/O over/RP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O bank/NN/O of/IN/O telephone/NN/O booths/NNS/O just/RB/O off/IN/O Exit/NN/B-FAC 10/CD/I-FAC ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O sounded/VBD/O like/IN/O something/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Ian/NNP/B-PERSON Fleming/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON recalls/VBZ/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O appointed/JJ/O exit/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O family/NN/O pulled/VBD/O over/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mrs./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON went/VBD/O to/TO/O get/VB/O her/PRP$/O papers/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON turned/VBD/O off/RP/O the/DT/O motor/NN/O and/CC/O rolled/VBD/O down/RP/O the/DT/O window/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O crouched/VBD/O down/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O car/NN/O window/NN/O and/CC/O addressed/VBD/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O favorite/JJ/O nickname/NN/O :/:/O
``/``/O Bertie/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Happy/JJ/O 50th/JJ/O Birthday/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O And/CC/O there/EX/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O recalls/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O hero/NN/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O youth/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O one/CD/O person/NN/O in/IN/O history/NN/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O most/RBS/O like/VB/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O ././O
Keep/VB/O your/PRP$/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Jeffersons/NNPS/I-PERSON ,/,/O or/CC/O St./NNP/O Augustines/NNPS/B-PERSON or/CC/O Michelangelos/NNPS/B-PERSON ;/:/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O take/VB/O baseball/NN/O 's/POS/O Flying/NNP/O Scot/NNP/O without/IN/O hesitation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
They/PRP/O talked/VBD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O home/NN/O run/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O thought/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O upper/JJ/O deck/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O now/RB/O 66/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O talked/VBD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O aftermath/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O never/RB/O thought/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O become/VB/O so/RB/O momentous/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON remarked/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O says/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O was/VBD/O overwhelmed/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O thing/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O worth/JJ/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O just/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O look/NN/O on/IN/O Albert/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O face/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O spent/VBD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O at/IN/O Exit/NN/B-FAC 10/CD/I-FAC ,/,/O rehashing/VBG/O the/DT/O event/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O fulfilling/VBG/O the/DT/O lifelong/JJ/O dream/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O young/JJ/O boy/NN/O now/RB/O turned/VBN/O 50/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
His/PRP$/O hero/NN/O signed/VBD/O photographs/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O homer/NN/O and/CC/O diplomatically/RB/O called/VBD/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Branca/NNP/I-PERSON ``/``/O a/DT/O very/RB/O fine/JJ/O pitcher/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON asked/VBD/O him/PRP/O why/WRB/O he/PRP/O took/VBD/O time/NN/O off/RP/O from/IN/O work/NN/O for/IN/O somebody/NN/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O know/VB/O ,/,/O Bobby/NNP/B-PERSON Thomson/NNP/I-PERSON replied/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O know/VBP/O ,/,/O Albert/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O chance/NN/O in/IN/O life/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O somebody/NN/O this/DT/O happy/JJ/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O an/DT/O obligation/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
His/PRP$/O mail/NN/O regularly/RB/O recalls/VBZ/O ``/``/O my/PRP$/O one/CD/O event/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O growing/VBG/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O letters/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Thomson/NNP/B-PERSON usually/RB/O sends/VBZ/O an/DT/O autographed/JJ/O photo/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O polite/JJ/O note/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O rarely/RB/O arranges/VBZ/O a/DT/O rendezvous/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O Betsy/NNP/B-PERSON Engelken/NNP/I-PERSON wrote/VBD/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O she/PRP/O could/MD/O stop/VB/O near/IN/O his/PRP$/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE home/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seemed/VBD/O different/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O feeling/NN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O for/IN/O me/PRP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O that/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O thought/VBD/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O got/VBD/O back/RB/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O trip/NN/O up/RB/O north/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON wrote/VBD/O it/PRP/O all/DT/O down/RP/O ,/,/O just/RB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O no/DT/O detail/NN/O was/VBD/O missed/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O On/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O home/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O his/PRP$/O notes/NNS/O recall/VBP/O ,/,/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O took/VBD/O concentrated/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O that/DT/O car/NN/O pointed/VBD/O south/RB/O ././O
My/PRP$/O mind/NN/O was/VBD/O miles/NNS/O north/RB/O at/IN/O a/DT/O place/NN/O called/VBD/O Coogan/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/I-LOC Bluff/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O where/WRB/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O sports/NNS/O hero/NN/O had/VBD/O captured/VBN/O the/DT/O imagination/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O kid/NN/O who/WP/O never/RB/O fully/RB/O grew/VBD/O up/RB/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O richer/JJR/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O Take/VB/O heart/NN/O ,/,/O sports/NNS/O fans/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O wrote/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Real/JJ/O heroes/NNS/O exist/VBP/O ././O
You/PRP/O might/MD/O not/RB/O find/VB/O one/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O `/``/O Jurisprudence/NN/O '/''/O column/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O who/WP/O knows/VBZ/O ?/./O
You/PRP/O might/MD/O meet/VB/O up/RP/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O at/IN/O that/DT/O bank/NN/O of/IN/O telephone/NN/O booths/NNS/O just/RB/O off/IN/O Exit/NN/B-FAC 10/CD/I-FAC of/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC New/NNP/I-FAC Jersey/NNP/I-FAC Turnpike/NNP/I-FAC ././O
