He/PRP/O will/MD/O succeed/VB/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Harrington/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O retired/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Crestmont/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O conducting/VBG/O a/DT/O search/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Crestmont/NNP/B-ORG since/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O general/JJ/O partner/NN/O of/IN/O Seidman/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O 9.89/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Crestmont/NNP/B-ORG ././O
