Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Brady/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O grant/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG the/DT/O power/NN/O to/TO/O close/VB/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O periods/NNS/O of/IN/O crisis/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON contended/VBD/O that/DT/O discretionary/JJ/O power/NN/O could/MD/O have/VB/O an/DT/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O if/IN/O rumors/NNS/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O circulate/VB/O about/IN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O exchanges/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O closed/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O already/RB/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O power/NN/O to/TO/O close/VB/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O asked/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Working/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNPS/I-ORG to/TO/O determine/VB/O whether/IN/O futures/NNS/O margins/NNS/O are/VBP/O too/RB/O low/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O noted/VBD/O that/IN/O some/DT/O minimum/NN/O margin/NN/O requirements/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O reduced/VBN/O to/TO/O levels/NNS/O below/IN/O those/DT/O before/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
Margins/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O an/DT/O investor/NN/O needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O put/VB/O up/RB/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O or/CC/O sell/VB/O a/DT/O futures/NNS/O contract/NN/O ././O
Margins/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O futures/NNS/O exchanges/NNS/O typically/RB/O are/VBP/O raised/VBN/O and/CC/O lowered/VBN/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O market/NN/O volatility/NN/O ././O
Margins/NNS/O were/VBD/O raised/VBN/O or/CC/O lowered/VBN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O times/NNS/O since/IN/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O Oct./NNP/O 19/CD/O ,/,/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O former/JJ/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O executive/NN/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O an/DT/O opinion/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O controversy/NN/O surrounding/VBG/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O recently/RB/O become/VBN/O a/DT/O larger/JJR/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O blamed/VBN/O for/IN/O accelerating/VBG/O the/DT/O drop/NN/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
That/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O proposed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O require/VB/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O positions/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O holding/VBG/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O mandate/VB/O large/JJ/O traders/NNS/O '/POS/O reporting/NN/O of/IN/O program/NN/O or/CC/O block/NN/O trades/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O improve/VB/O clearing/VBG/O and/CC/O settlement/NN/O of/IN/O trades/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O futures/NNS/O and/CC/O stock/NN/O markets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O also/RB/O would/MD/O give/VB/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG the/DT/O power/NN/O to/TO/O close/VB/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O discretion/NN/O that/IN/O former/JJ/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Ruder/NNP/I-PERSON wanted/VBD/O but/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O ././O
