The/DT/O McLean/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O company/NN/O modifies/VBZ/O computers/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O sensitive/JJ/O military/JJ/O data/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O unfriendly/JJ/O hands/NNS/O ././O
From/IN/O 1984/CD/O to/TO/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O earnings/NNS/O soared/VBD/O six-fold/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.8/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O on/IN/O a/DT/O seven-fold/JJ/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O $/$/O 44.1/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O ran/VBD/O into/IN/O a/DT/O buzz/NN/O saw/NN/O :/:/O a/DT/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG spending/NN/O freeze/NN/O ././O
Iverson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O earnings/NNS/O plunged/VBD/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.2/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O troubles/NNS/O continued/VBN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O profit/NN/O plunged/VBD/O 81/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 302,000/CD/O ././O
Iverson/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O small/JJ/O defense/NN/O contractors/NNS/O besieged/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O slowdown/NN/O in/IN/O defense/NN/O spending/NN/O ././O
Companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O only/RB/O recently/RB/O were/VBD/O thriving/JJ/O find/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O scrambling/VBG/O to/TO/O survive/VB/O ././O
As/IN/O their/PRP$/O varied/JJ/O strategies/NNS/O suggest/VBP/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O one/CD/O way/NN/O to/TO/O respond/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O disaster/NN/O --/:/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O too/RB/O soon/RB/O to/TO/O tell/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O will/MD/O pay/VB/O off/RP/O ././O
For/IN/O many/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O instinctive/JJ/O first/JJ/O response/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O costs/NNS/O ././O
More/RBR/O venturesome/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O are/VBP/O applying/VBG/O their/PRP$/O skills/NNS/O in/IN/O commercial/JJ/O fields/NNS/O ././O
ERC/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O provides/VBZ/O professional/JJ/O and/CC/O technical/JJ/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O military/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O refining/VBG/O its/PRP$/O defense/NN/O niche/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O retreating/VBG/O from/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
After/IN/O quadrupling/VBG/O annual/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O over/IN/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O $/$/O 6.8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Fairfax/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O company/NN/O ,/,/O posted/VBD/O a/DT/O 23/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O earnings/NNS/O for/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O belief/NN/O that/DT/O development/NN/O of/IN/O advanced/JJ/O military/JJ/O technology/NN/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O a/DT/O top/JJ/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG priority/NN/O ,/,/O ERC/NNP/B-ORG last/JJ/O year/NN/O acquired/VBD/O W.J./NNP/B-ORG Schafer/NNP/I-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O technical/JJ/O and/CC/O scientific/JJ/O analysis/NN/O company/NN/O with/IN/O contracts/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Strategic/NNP/O Defense/NNP/O Initiative/NNP/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O SDI/NNP/O anti-missile/JJ/O program/NN/O recently/RB/O awarded/VBD/O W.J./NNP/B-PERSON Schafer/NNP/I-PERSON two/CD/O contracts/NNS/O totaling/VBG/O $/$/O 13.4/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O ERC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O founder/NN/O ,/,/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Aalseth/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O bought/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ``/``/O more/JJR/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O technology/NN/O than/IN/O its/PRP$/O customer/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
UNC/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O Annapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Md./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O contractor/NN/O that/WDT/O earned/VBD/O $/$/O 23.8/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 400.4/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O gone/VBN/O even/RB/O further/RBR/O in/IN/O realigning/VBG/O its/PRP$/O military/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O orders/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O aircraft/NN/O and/CC/O submarine/NN/O parts/NNS/O dwindled/VBD/O ,/,/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O steady/JJ/O growth/NN/O ended/VBD/O with/IN/O a/DT/O 69/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O income/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O hit/VBD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O strategy/NN/O :/:/O If/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O so/RB/O intent/JJ/O on/IN/O saving/VBG/O money/NN/O ,/,/O why/WRB/O not/RB/O make/VB/O money/NN/O off/IN/O that/DT/O trend/NN/O ?/./O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O current/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O :/:/O repairing/VBG/O old/JJ/O parts/NNS/O at/IN/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O replacing/VBG/O them/PRP/O ././O
UNC/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O is/VBZ/O selling/VBG/O new/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O if/IN/O needed/VBN/O ,/,/O directly/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O through/IN/O a/DT/O prime/JJ/O contractor/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O taking/VBG/O over/RP/O the/DT/O maintenance/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG aircraft/NN/O with/IN/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O fewer/JJR/O people/NNS/O than/IN/O the/DT/O military/NN/O used/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O another/DT/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O tiny/JJ/O Iverson/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O its/PRP$/O growth/NN/O by/IN/O braving/VBG/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O world/NN/O of/IN/O commercial/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Iverson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O hopes/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O can/MD/O eventually/RB/O get/VB/O up/RB/O to/TO/O half/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O commercial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Earlier/RB/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Iverson/NNP/B-PERSON agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O exclusive/JJ/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O software/NN/O system/NN/O developed/VBN/O by/IN/O Visher/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Salt/NNP/B-GPE Lake/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Iverson/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O 5,000/CD/O potential/JJ/O customers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O software/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O area/NN/O alone/RB/O ././O
QuesTech/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Falls/NNP/B-GPE Church/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O acquired/VBN/O some/DT/O companies/NNS/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O transfer/VB/O its/PRP$/O skill/NN/O at/IN/O designing/VBG/O military/JJ/O equipment/NN/O to/TO/O commercial/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O partnership/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Williamsburg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Shell/NNP/B-ORG Oil/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG recently/RB/O patented/VBD/O a/DT/O process/NN/O for/IN/O producing/VBG/O plastic/NN/O food/NN/O containers/NNS/O that/WDT/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O melt/VB/O in/IN/O microwave/NN/O ovens/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O imagination/NN/O and/CC/O talent/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O engineers/NNS/O and/CC/O come/VB/O up/RB/O with/IN/O new/JJ/O processes/NNS/O for/IN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Vincent/NNP/B-PERSON Salvatori/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O QuesTech/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O branch/VB/O out/RP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O difficult/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O defense/NN/O contractor/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Salvatori/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O know/VB/O ././O
Instead/RB/O of/IN/O helping/VBG/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O defense/NN/O spending/NN/O slowdown/NN/O ,/,/O Dynamic/NNP/B-ORG Engineering/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O troubled/JJ/O subsidiary/NN/O that/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O wind/NN/O tunnels/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O space/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O QuesTech/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O $/$/O 3.3/CD/O million/CD/O loss/NN/O on/IN/O $/$/O 55.6/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O revenue/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O January/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Salvatori/NNP/B-PERSON sold/VBD/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O our/PRP$/O first/JJ/O acquisition/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O mistake/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O cutting/VBG/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O hoping/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O ././O
Following/VBG/O a/DT/O tripling/VBG/O of/IN/O earnings/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.9/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O on/IN/O a/DT/O doubling/VBG/O of/IN/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O $/$/O 116/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O over/IN/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O earnings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O fiscal/JJ/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O ended/VBD/O June/NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O plunged/VBD/O 90/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 45,000/CD/O ././O
Telos/NNP/B-ORG responded/VBD/O by/IN/O combining/VBG/O three/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O five/CD/O divisions/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O expenses/NNS/O and/CC/O ``/``/O bring/VB/O more/JJR/O focus/NN/O to/TO/O potentially/RB/O fewer/JJR/O bidding/NN/O opportunities/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Lin/NNP/B-PERSON Conger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Telos/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O controlling/VBG/O shareholder/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O evident/JJ/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O entering/VBG/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O competitive/JJ/O era/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O closing/NN/O contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O $/$/O 3.4/CD/O million/CD/O loss/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ended/VBN/O July/NNP/O 31/CD/O --/:/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O quarterly/JJ/O loss/NN/O since/IN/O 1974/CD/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O ordnance/NN/O business/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O hurt/VBN/O very/RB/O badly/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O slowdown/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Arch/NNP/B-PERSON Scurlock/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O TransTechnology/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O business/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O making/VBG/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O pyrotechnic/JJ/O devices/NNS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O ././O
