The/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG challenged/VBD/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O on/IN/O routes/NNS/O and/CC/O fares/NNS/O between/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O two/CD/O largest/JJS/O airlines/NNS/O on/IN/O antitrust/JJ/O grounds/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O notified/VBN/O so/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O begin/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O Brussels/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O modify/VB/O the/DT/O pact/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O shared/VBD/O results/NNS/O from/IN/O this/DT/O route/NN/O swap/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O followed/VBD/O rules/NNS/O on/IN/O ticket/NN/O pricing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG EC/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG decided/VBD/O that/IN/O such/JJ/O an/DT/O accord/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O benefit/VB/O consumers/NNS/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O merit/VB/O an/DT/O exemption/NN/O from/IN/O antitrust/JJ/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O airlines/NNS/O presented/VBD/O it/PRP/O as/IN/O offering/VBG/O consumers/NNS/O more/JJR/O choice/NN/O and/CC/O better/JJR/O flight/NN/O connections/NNS/O ././O
