How/WRB/O did/VBD/O this/DT/O happen/VB/O ?/./O
But/CC/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O grimly/RB/O ironic/JJ/O twist/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG loss/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O regard/VBP/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O largely/RB/O phony/JJ/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O ``/``/O long/JJ/O term/NN/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O nonetheless/RB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O salon/NN/O topic/NN/O all/DT/O around/IN/O the/DT/O Beltway/NNP/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/O issue/NN/O of/IN/O seeking/VBG/O relief/NN/O from/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O raised/VBN/O to/TO/O Delbert/NNP/B-PERSON Staley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Nynex/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Staley/NNP/B-PERSON replied/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O Legislation/NN/O tends/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O compromised/VBN/O ././O
I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O take/VB/O a/DT/O shot/NN/O at/IN/O getting/VBG/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O done/VBN/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O through/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O ,/,/O through/IN/O Justice/NN/B-ORG and/CC/O through/IN/O state/NN/O and/CC/O federal/JJ/O regulatory/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O see/VBP/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O a/DT/O last/JJ/O resort/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O reality/NN/O of/IN/O life/NN/O in/IN/O modern/JJ/O America/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O wreck/VB/O something/NN/O that/WDT/O works/VBZ/O ,/,/O let/VB/O it/PRP/O fall/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
