Some/DT/O conservatives/NNS/O say/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O the/DT/O trip/NN/O ,/,/O during/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O participate/VB/O in/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE celebration/NN/O of/IN/O 100/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O democracy/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O critics/NNS/O object/VBP/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O participation/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O that/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O President/NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Ortega/NNP/I-PERSON among/IN/O the/DT/O guests/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Windsor/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O connected/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O Heritage/NNP/B-ORG Foundation/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O fears/VBZ/O the/DT/O gathering/NN/O of/IN/O 18/CD/O leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O from/IN/O Central/JJ/O American/JJ/O nations/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O force/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O to/TO/O explain/VB/O and/CC/O redeem/VB/O himself/PRP/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O charges/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE failed/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O aid/VB/O the/DT/O removal/NN/O of/IN/O Panamanian/JJ/O dictator/NN/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Noriega/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O said/VBD/O improvements/NNS/O in/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE economic/JJ/O condition/NN/O warrant/VBP/O the/DT/O cut/NN/O in/IN/O aid/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O country/NN/O uses/VBZ/O mainly/RB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O payments/NNS/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O $/$/O 4.5/CD/O billion/CD/O foreign/JJ/O debt/NN/O ././O
Democrats/NNP/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE deserves/VBZ/O more/JJR/O assistance/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O reason/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O attending/VBG/O the/DT/O celebration/NN/O this/DT/O weekend/NN/O :/:/O to/TO/O reward/VB/O the/DT/O country/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O stability/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O region/NN/O wracked/VBN/O with/IN/O turmoil/NN/O and/CC/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O peace/NN/O in/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Lawmakers/NNS/O in/IN/O both/DT/O houses/NNS/O support/VBP/O the/DT/O higher/JJR/O level/NN/O ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O defend/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O trip/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O also/RB/O made/VBD/O clear/JJ/O its/PRP$/O continuing/VBG/O distate/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O leftist/JJ/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O government/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O endorsing/VBG/O a/DT/O package/NN/O of/IN/O electoral/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O opposition/NN/O ,/,/O renewing/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O embargo/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O and/CC/O continuing/VBG/O to/TO/O complain/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O supports/VBZ/O rebel/NN/O groups/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O also/RB/O insist/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O use/VB/O the/DT/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O highlight/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O initiatives/NNS/O for/IN/O pushing/VBG/O democracy/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ,/,/O fighting/VBG/O illegal/JJ/O drugs/NNS/O and/CC/O assisting/VBG/O the/DT/O less/RBR/O developed/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ././O
