Misunderstanding/VBG/O conversations/NNS/O with/IN/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Tomsho/NNP/B-PERSON argued/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Redford/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O environmental/JJ/O views/NNS/O are/VBP/O at/IN/O odds/NNS/O with/IN/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE residents/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O may/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O true/JJ/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O times/NNS/O have/VBP/O changed/VBN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O in/IN/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Redford/NNP/B-PERSON no/RB/O longer/RB/O stands/VBZ/O out/RP/O as/IN/O an/DT/O extremist/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O changed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O those/DT/O around/IN/O him/PRP/O have/VBP/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O views/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O protection/NN/O of/IN/O wilderness/NN/O areas/NNS/O ,/,/O rivers/NNS/O and/CC/O canyons/NNS/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O embraced/VBN/O by/IN/O mainstream/JJ/O ,/,/O conservative/JJ/O Utahans/NNPS/O ././O
Recently/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O 60/CD/O environmental/JJ/O and/CC/O outdoor/JJ/O groups/NNS/O representing/VBG/O such/JJ/O divergent/JJ/O points/NNS/O of/IN/O view/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Sierra/NNP/I-ORG Club/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Women/NNP/I-ORG Voters/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Rifle/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG joined/VBD/O together/RB/O to/TO/O request/VB/O a/DT/O reassessment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O environmentally/RB/O unsound/JJ/O Central/NNP/B-ORG Utah/NNP/I-ORG Project/NNP/I-ORG ././O
While/IN/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O not/RB/O yet/RB/O a/DT/O haven/NN/O for/IN/O environmentalism/NN/O ,/,/O public/JJ/O views/NNS/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O have/VBP/O significantly/RB/O improved/VBN/O ././O
In/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O conservative/JJ/O ,/,/O Republican/JJ/O states/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O nation/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O greening/NN/O of/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Redford/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON neighbors/NNS/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O story/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Tomsho/NNP/B-PERSON missed/VBD/O ././O
Sammye/NNP/B-PERSON Meadows/NNP/I-PERSON Sam/NNP/B-PERSON Rushforth/NNP/I-PERSON Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Bryner/NNP/I-PERSON Heber/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE
If/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Redford/NNP/B-PERSON wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O accepted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O of/IN/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O should/MD/O have/VB/O taken/VBN/O an/DT/O advisory/JJ/O role/NN/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O forcing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O personal/JJ/O preferences/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O excellent/JJ/O environmental/JJ/O actor/NN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Vranian/NNP/I-PERSON M.B.A./NNP/O Student/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Colorado/NNP/I-ORG Boulder/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Colo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Redford/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O like/VB/O it/PRP/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O like/IN/O a/DT/O braking/VBG/O system/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O runaway/JJ/O truck/NN/O ,/,/O kind/RB/O of/IN/O slowing/VBG/O it/PRP/O down/RP/O into/IN/O control/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O rich/JJ/O ,/,/O famous/JJ/O and/CC/O intelligent/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O time/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O something/NN/O that/IN/O not/RB/O even/RB/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O will/MD/O do/VB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Redford/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O slowing/VBG/O down/RP/O a/DT/O mindless/JJ/O ,/,/O speeding/JJ/O maniac/NN/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O progress/NN/O of/IN/O mankind/NN/O ././O
Ron/NNP/B-PERSON Dyer/NNP/I-PERSON
