Mr./NNP/O Pissocra/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 56/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O 10/CD/O banks/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Eastern/JJ/O region/NN/O ././O
Dan/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Hartwell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 41/CD/O ,/,/O executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG One/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Dover/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Dover/NNP/B-GPE bank/NN/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Pissocra/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
No/DT/O one/NN/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Hartwell/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
