General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O temporarily/RB/O idle/VB/O its/PRP$/O Arlington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O assembly/NN/O plant/NN/O for/IN/O one/CD/O week/NN/O beginning/NN/O Monday/NNP/O because/IN/O of/IN/O slow/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O closing/NN/O will/MD/O affect/VB/O about/IN/O 3,000/CD/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O eliminate/VB/O production/NN/O of/IN/O 700/CD/O cars/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O assembly/NN/O plant/NN/O builds/VBZ/O the/DT/O Cadillac/NNP/B-ORG DeVille/NNP/O ,/,/O Chevrolet/NNP/B-ORG Caprice/NNP/O and/CC/O Oldsmobile/NNP/B-ORG Cutlass/NNP/O Ciera/NNP/O Wagon/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O plant/NN/O builds/VBZ/O chassis/NNS/O for/IN/O recreational/JJ/O vehicles/NNS/O and/CC/O about/IN/O 450/CD/O workers/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O affected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O closing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O No./NN/O 1/CD/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O scheduled/VBD/O overtime/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O Janesville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wis./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O assembly/NN/O plant/NN/O ,/,/O manufacturer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Chevrolet/NNP/B-ORG Cavalier/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O nine/CD/O major/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE auto/NN/O makers/NNS/O plan/VBP/O to/TO/O build/VB/O 147,121/CD/O vehicles/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O down/RB/O 9.6/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O 162,767/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O 2.5/CD/O %/NN/O higher/JJR/O than/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O 143,534/CD/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG slated/VBD/O overtime/NN/O again/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O Wixom/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Wayne/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mo./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Norfolk/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O assembly/NN/O plants/NNS/O ././O
Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG scheduled/VBD/O overtime/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O St./NNP/B-FAC Louis/NNP/I-FAC Assembly/NNP/I-FAC Plant/NNP/I-FAC No./NN/I-FAC 2/CD/I-FAC ,/,/O Newark/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Del./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Sterling/NNP/B-GPE Heights/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O assembly/NN/O plants/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O build/VBP/O extended/JJ/O minivans/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Dodge/NNP/B-ORG Spirit/NNP/O ,/,/O Acclaim/NNP/O ,/,/O Shadow/NNP/O and/CC/O Sundance/NNP/O ././O
d/LS/O -/:/O Percentage/NN/O change/NN/O is/VBZ/O greater/JJR/O than/IN/O 999/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
e/LS/O -/:/O Estimated/VBN/O ././O
f/LS/O -/:/O Includes/VBZ/O Chevrolet/NNP/B-ORG Prizm/NNP/O and/CC/O Toyota/NNP/B-ORG Corolla/NNP/O ././O
r/LS/O -/:/O Revised/VBN/O ././O
