Exxon/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O move/VB/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O from/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O shift/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O affect/VB/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O its/PRP$/O economy/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O slump/NN/O ././O
Las/NNP/B-FAC Colinas/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O once/RB/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ranch/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O sprawling/VBG/O complex/NN/O of/IN/O office/NN/O buildings/NNS/O ,/,/O homes/NNS/O and/CC/O recreational/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O developers/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O struggling/VBG/O to/TO/O populate/VB/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
Exxon/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O less/JJR/O to/TO/O run/VB/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O at/IN/O Las/NNP/B-FAC Colinas/NNP/I-FAC than/IN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O save/VB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O during/IN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O interim/NN/O location/NN/O ,/,/O sources/NNS/O say/VBP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O likely/RB/O pay/VB/O rent/VB/O of/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 15/CD/O per/IN/O square/JJ/O foot/NN/O ././O
Owners/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE say/VBP/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O asking/VBG/O $/$/O 50/CD/O per/IN/O square/JJ/O foot/NN/O for/IN/O rent/NN/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O the/DT/O space/NN/O that/IN/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O vacating/VBG/O ././O
