Unless/IN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O happens/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON ././O
Like/IN/O other/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O banks/NNS/O establishing/VBG/O a/DT/O presence/NN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O family/NN/O describes/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O move/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O calculated/JJ/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O outlet/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O economy/NN/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O integration/NN/O of/IN/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG markets/VBZ/O after/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Yet/CC/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON do/VBP/O n't/RB/O deny/VB/O an/DT/O emotional/JJ/O element/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O original/JJ/O bank/NN/O in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE closed/VBD/O in/IN/O 1901/CD/O after/IN/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O Wilhelm/NNP/B-PERSON Carl/NNP/I-PERSON von/NNP/I-PERSON Rothschild/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O banking/NN/O activities/NNS/O focused/VBD/O on/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Baron/NNP/O Elie/NNP/B-PERSON de/FW/I-PERSON Rothschild/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O elder/JJR/O spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O explains/VBZ/O that/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 19th/JJ/O century/NN/O ,/,/O Berlin/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O replaced/VBN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O financial/JJ/O center/NN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O the/DT/O chief/JJ/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O closure/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O rooted/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O family/NN/O tradition/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O allow/VB/O a/DT/O bank/NN/O to/TO/O bear/VB/O the/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON name/NN/O without/IN/O a/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O its/PRP$/O management/NN/O ././O
Much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O mystique/NN/O remained/VBD/O ././O
Although/IN/O its/PRP$/O palatial/JJ/O residence/NN/O was/VBD/O destroyed/VBN/O by/IN/O bombs/NNS/O during/IN/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON '/POS/O place/NN/O in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNPS/B-GPE 's/POS/O history/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O recalled/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O park/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O street/NN/O bearing/VBG/O the/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON name/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O long/JJ/O absence/NN/O is/VBZ/O understandable/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O family/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O Allied/JJ/B-ORG countries/NNS/O during/IN/O both/DT/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O I/NNP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O period/NN/O of/IN/O economic/JJ/O strife/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1920s/NN/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Third/NNP/I-ORG Reich/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON were/VBD/O a/DT/O target/NN/O of/IN/O Nazi/JJ/O propaganda/NN/O against/IN/O Jewish/JJ/O financiers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O persecution/NN/O pursued/VBD/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON across/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC as/IN/O the/DT/O Nazis/NNPS/O grabbed/VBD/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O confiscating/VBG/O the/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O property/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O ././O
American/JJ/O journalist/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Shirer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O book/NN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Rise/NN/O and/CC/O Fall/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Third/NNP/O Reich/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O wrote/VBD/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O in/IN/O Vienna/NNP/B-GPE he/PRP/O had/VBD/O witnessed/VBN/O ``/``/O squads/NNS/O of/IN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Nazi/JJ/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O SS/NNP/B-ORG men/NNS/O carting/VBG/O off/RP/O silver/NN/O ,/,/O tapestries/NNS/O ,/,/O paintings/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O loot/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON palace/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O the/DT/O immediate/JJ/O postwar/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON concentrated/VBD/O on/IN/O rebuilding/VBG/O their/PRP$/O other/JJ/O European/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O delaying/VBG/O their/PRP$/O return/NN/O to/TO/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O competition/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O greatly/RB/O concerned/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O surprising/JJ/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O come/VBN/O to/TO/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O time/NN/O for/IN/O 1992/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O bring/VBP/O an/DT/O interesting/JJ/O tradition/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O market/NN/O really/RB/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O stood/VBN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O head/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O banker/NN/O at/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Big/JJ/O Three/CD/O banks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O return/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O modest/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O representative/JJ/O office/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O one/CD/O manager/NN/O and/CC/O two/CD/O assistants/NNS/O --/:/O none/NN/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O --/:/O will/MD/O carry/VB/O out/RP/O no/DT/O banking/VBG/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O left/VBD/O his/PRP$/O job/NN/O as/IN/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE office/NN/O because/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O When/WRB/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON called/VBD/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O resist/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Each/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON bank/NN/O is/VBZ/O linked/VBN/O by/IN/O family/NN/O ties/NNS/O and/CC/O cross-ownership/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O March/NNP/O ,/,/O N/NNP/B-ORG M/NNP/I-ORG Rothschild/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Rothschild/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Zurich/NNP/B-GPE showed/VBD/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O #/#/O 4.1/CD/O billion/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 6.51/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O 1.26/CD/O billion/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 774/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O respectively/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE bank/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O publish/VB/O that/DT/O figure/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON banks/NNS/O are/VBP/O focusing/VBG/O on/IN/O mergers/NNS/O and/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O as/IN/O European/JJ/O industry/NN/O restructures/VBZ/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Yet/RB/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O limited/JJ/O resources/NNS/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O niche/NN/O player/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Obviously/RB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O quantitative/JJ/O limitations/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O assistance/NN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O provide/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O concedes/VBZ/O Baron/NNP/O David/NNP/B-PERSON de/FW/I-PERSON Rothschild/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O feel/VBP/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O some/DT/O cards/NNS/O to/TO/O play/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON hope/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O history/NN/O in/IN/O private/JJ/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O aura/NN/O of/IN/O exclusivity/NN/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O private/JJ/O and/CC/O institutional/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ././O
As/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Zurich/NNP/B-GPE bank/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O minimum/NN/O investment/NN/O for/IN/O individuals/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O high/JJ/O :/:/O about/IN/O a/DT/O million/CD/O German/JJ/O marks/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 538,000/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O three/CD/O times/NNS/O what/WP/O many/JJ/O other/JJ/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O investment/NN/O banks/NNS/O require/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O make/VB/O exceptions/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O smiling/VBG/O Baron/NNP/O Elie/NNP/B-PERSON de/FW/I-PERSON Rothschild/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O especially/RB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O very/RB/O young/JJ/O and/CC/O have/VB/O very/RB/O rich/JJ/O parents/NNS/O ././O
