When/WRB/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON travels/VBZ/O to/TO/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE today/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O 'll/MD/O go/VB/O with/IN/O little/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O fanfare/NN/O that/WDT/O accompanies/VBZ/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O foreign/JJ/O travels/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O conservatives/NNS/O say/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O the/DT/O trip/NN/O ,/,/O during/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O participate/VB/O in/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE celebration/NN/O of/IN/O 100/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O democracy/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O critics/NNS/O object/VBP/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O participation/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O that/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O President/NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Ortega/NNP/I-PERSON among/IN/O the/DT/O guests/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O argue/VBP/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O help/VB/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O standing/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O by/IN/O trumpeting/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE commitment/NN/O to/TO/O democracy/NN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O month/NN/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O administration/NN/O played/VBD/O an/DT/O ineffectual/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O failed/VBN/O coup/NN/O attempt/NN/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O do/VB/O more/JJR/O damage/NN/O than/IN/O good/JJ/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O legitimize/VB/O people/NNS/O like/IN/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Ortega/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Curtin/NNP/B-PERSON Windsor/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O served/VBD/O as/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ambassador/NN/O to/TO/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE during/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Windsor/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O connected/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O Heritage/NNP/B-ORG Foundation/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O fears/VBZ/O the/DT/O gathering/NN/O of/IN/O 18/CD/O leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O from/IN/O Central/JJ/O American/JJ/O nations/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O force/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O to/TO/O explain/VB/O and/CC/O redeem/VB/O himself/PRP/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O charges/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE failed/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O aid/VB/O the/DT/O removal/NN/O of/IN/O Panamanian/JJ/O dictator/NN/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Noriega/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O liberal/JJ/O and/CC/O moderate/JJ/O Democrats/NNPS/O note/VBP/O the/DT/O irony/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O joining/VBG/O a/DT/O celebration/NN/O of/IN/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O democracy/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O his/PRP$/O administration/NN/O has/VBZ/O sought/VBN/O sharp/JJ/O cuts/NNS/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O tiny/JJ/O country/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O said/VBD/O improvements/NNS/O in/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE economic/JJ/O condition/NN/O warrant/VBP/O the/DT/O cut/NN/O in/IN/O aid/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O country/NN/O uses/VBZ/O mainly/RB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O payments/NNS/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O $/$/O 4.5/CD/O billion/CD/O foreign/JJ/O debt/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O officials/NNS/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O coffee/NN/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O combined/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O continuing/VBG/O struggle/NN/O to/TO/O reinvigorate/VB/O its/PRP$/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O make/VBP/O the/DT/O support/NN/O as/RB/O necessary/JJ/O as/IN/O ever/RB/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O crossing/VBG/O the/DT/O river/NN/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O need/VBP/O a/DT/O little/RB/O more/JJR/O help/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O side/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Rodrigo/NNP/B-PERSON Sotela/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O economic/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O specialist/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O Embassy/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Democrats/NNP/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE deserves/VBZ/O more/JJR/O assistance/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O reason/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O attending/VBG/O the/DT/O celebration/NN/O this/DT/O weekend/NN/O :/:/O to/TO/O reward/VB/O the/DT/O country/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O stability/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O region/NN/O wracked/VBN/O with/IN/O turmoil/NN/O and/CC/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O peace/NN/O in/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O peace/NN/O efforts/NNS/O by/IN/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O President/NNP/O Oscar/NNP/B-PERSON Arias/NNP/I-PERSON have/VBP/O n't/RB/O always/RB/O helped/VBN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O cause/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O going/VBG/O there/RB/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O helpful/JJ/O sign/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Sen./NNP/O Terry/NNP/B-PERSON Sanford/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.C/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG who/WP/O pushed/VBD/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE about/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O aid/NN/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Lawmakers/NNS/O in/IN/O both/DT/O houses/NNS/O support/VBP/O the/DT/O higher/JJR/O level/NN/O ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O defend/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O trip/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O they/PRP/O acknowledge/VBP/O the/DT/O president/NN/O will/MD/O attend/VB/O several/JJ/O meals/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O working/NN/O session/NN/O also/RB/O attended/VBD/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O they/PRP/O insist/VBP/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O extending/VBG/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O leader/NN/O any/DT/O special/JJ/O courtesies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O also/RB/O made/VBD/O clear/JJ/O its/PRP$/O continuing/VBG/O distate/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O leftist/JJ/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O government/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O endorsing/VBG/O a/DT/O package/NN/O of/IN/O electoral/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O opposition/NN/O ,/,/O renewing/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O embargo/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O and/CC/O continuing/VBG/O to/TO/O complain/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O supports/VBZ/O rebel/NN/O groups/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O also/RB/O insist/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O use/VB/O the/DT/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O highlight/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O initiatives/NNS/O for/IN/O pushing/VBG/O democracy/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ,/,/O fighting/VBG/O illegal/JJ/O drugs/NNS/O and/CC/O assisting/VBG/O the/DT/O less/RBR/O developed/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Let/VB/O me/PRP/O say/VB/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O symbolic/JJ/O component/NN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O trip/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG James/NNP/B-PERSON Baker/NNP/I-PERSON told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O any/DT/O formal/JJ/O resolutions/NNS/O or/CC/O communiques/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O we/PRP/O still/RB/O see/VB/O this/DT/O as/IN/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O many/JJ/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O very/RB/O important/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
