S.A./NNP/B-ORG Brewing/NNP/I-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG began/VBD/O laying/VBG/O the/DT/O groundwork/NN/O to/TO/O launch/VB/O a/DT/O rival/JJ/O offer/NN/O for/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Australian/JJ/O brewing/NN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Such/JJ/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O could/MD/O torpedo/VB/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O by/IN/O Lion/NNP/B-ORG Nathan/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O acquire/VB/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O brewing/NN/O interests/NNS/O ././O
Australia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O National/NNP/B-ORG Companies/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O allow/VB/O S.A./NNP/B-ORG Brewing/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O acquire/VB/O an/DT/O option/NN/O on/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Bell/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O acquiring/VBG/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG brewing/NN/O businesses/NNS/O for/IN/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O Australian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 1.93/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O brewing/NN/O ,/,/O property/NN/O ,/,/O media/NNS/O and/CC/O resources/NNS/O concern/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O financier/NN/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Bond/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O selling/VBG/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O an/DT/O A$/$/O 6.9/CD/O billion/CD/O debt/NN/O ././O
