The/DT/O original/JJ/O bank/NN/O in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE closed/VBD/O in/IN/O 1901/CD/O after/IN/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O Wilhelm/NNP/B-PERSON Carl/NNP/I-PERSON von/NNP/I-PERSON Rothschild/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O banking/NN/O activities/NNS/O focused/VBD/O on/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Baron/NNP/O Elie/NNP/B-PERSON de/FW/I-PERSON Rothschild/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O elder/JJR/O spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O explains/VBZ/O that/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 19th/JJ/O century/NN/O ,/,/O Berlin/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O replaced/VBN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O financial/JJ/O center/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O long/JJ/O absence/NN/O is/VBZ/O understandable/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O family/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O Allied/JJ/B-ORG countries/NNS/O during/IN/O both/DT/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O I/NNP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O period/NN/O of/IN/O economic/JJ/O strife/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1920s/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O persecution/NN/O pursued/VBD/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON across/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC as/IN/O the/DT/O Nazis/NNPS/O grabbed/VBD/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O confiscating/VBG/O the/DT/O family/NN/O 's/POS/O property/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O return/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O modest/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O representative/JJ/O office/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O one/CD/O manager/NN/O and/CC/O two/CD/O assistants/NNS/O --/:/O none/NN/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O --/:/O will/MD/O carry/VB/O out/RP/O no/DT/O banking/VBG/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
Each/DT/O Rothschild/NNP/B-PERSON bank/NN/O is/VBZ/O linked/VBN/O by/IN/O family/NN/O ties/NNS/O and/CC/O cross-ownership/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE bank/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O publish/VB/O that/DT/O figure/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Rothschilds/NNPS/B-PERSON hope/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O history/NN/O in/IN/O private/JJ/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O aura/NN/O of/IN/O exclusivity/NN/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O private/JJ/O and/CC/O institutional/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ././O
