The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O filed/VBD/O a/DT/O criminal/JJ/O complaint/NN/O against/IN/O six/CD/O bank/NN/O employees/NNS/O charging/VBG/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O conspiracy/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O scheme/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O apparently/RB/O was/VBD/O capable/JJ/O of/IN/O handling/VBG/O millions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O by/IN/O funneling/VBG/O cash/NN/O through/IN/O fictitious/JJ/O bank/NN/O accounts/NNS/O ././O
Two/CD/O other/JJ/O men/NNS/O also/RB/O were/VBD/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O participating/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O operation/NN/O ././O
Walter/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Fisher/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O auditor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O Security/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O no/DT/O bank/NN/O funds/NNS/O were/VBD/O at/IN/O risk/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O investigation/NN/O ././O
Arrested/VBN/O were/VBD/O Jose/NNP/B-PERSON O./NNP/I-PERSON Lopez/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 27/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Whittier/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O vault/NN/O supervisor/NN/O ;/:/O Carlos/NNP/B-PERSON O./NNP/I-PERSON Huerta/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 29/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O La/NNP/B-GPE Puente/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O Luis/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Arroyo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 36/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O Ignacio/NNP/B-PERSON Rojas/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 32/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Baldwin/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O Doris/NNP/B-PERSON Moreno/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 37/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Bell/NNP/B-GPE Gardens/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O and/CC/O Ana/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Azucena/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 27/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Huntington/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Geno/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Apicella/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 27/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Terrell/NNP/B-PERSON N./NNP/I-PERSON Madison/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 27/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Hawthorne/NN/B-GPE ,/,/O were/VBD/O also/RB/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O participating/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O conspiracy/NN/O ././O
Each/DT/O defendant/NN/O faces/VBZ/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O sentence/NN/O of/IN/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O in/IN/O fines/NNS/O ././O
