It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O more/JJR/O drug/NN/O users/NNS/O than/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O people/NNS/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O tax/NN/O base/NN/O is/VBZ/O shrinking/VBG/O ,/,/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O budget/NN/O deficit/NN/O looms/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O city/NN/O faces/VBZ/O contract/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O all/DT/O major/JJ/O municipal/JJ/O unions/NNS/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O dust/NN/O and/CC/O dirt/NN/O settle/VBP/O in/IN/O an/DT/O extra-nasty/JJ/O mayoral/JJ/O race/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O man/NN/O most/RBS/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O custody/NN/O of/IN/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O career/NN/O politician/NN/O named/VBN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Dinkins/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Running/VBG/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O and/CC/O most/RBS/O ornery/JJ/O city/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O no/DT/O treat/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON knows/VBZ/O what/WP/O to/TO/O expect/VB/O from/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O hits/VBZ/O the/DT/O home/NN/O stretch/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O voters/NNS/O still/RB/O have/VBP/O very/RB/O little/JJ/O idea/NN/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O expect/VB/O from/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
After/IN/O 25/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O city/NN/O politics/NNS/O ,/,/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Dinkins/NNP/I-PERSON remains/VBZ/O an/DT/O enigma/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O widely/RB/O described/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O man/NN/O with/IN/O deep/JJ/O convictions/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O few/JJ/O major/JJ/O political/JJ/O programs/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O call/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
Asked/VBN/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O greatest/JJS/O achievement/NN/O in/IN/O public/JJ/O life/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O first/RB/O speaks/VBZ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O staff/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O election/NN/O day/NN/O nears/VBZ/O ,/,/O even/RB/O some/DT/O supporters/NNS/O wonder/VBP/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O do/VB/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O wins/VBZ/O the/DT/O mayoralty/NN/O on/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 7/CD/O ././O
They/PRP/O wonder/VBP/O whether/IN/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O firm/JJ/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O longtime/JJ/O allies/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O union/NN/O leaders/NNS/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O cronies/NNS/O who/WP/O may/MD/O seek/VB/O a/DT/O place/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O trough/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O stumbled/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O over/IN/O his/PRP$/O campaign/NN/O 's/POS/O payments/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O black/JJ/O activist/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O convicted/VBN/O kidnapper/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O over/IN/O his/PRP$/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O stock/NN/O sale/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O son/NN/O ././O
Polls/NNS/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O recorded/VBN/O some/DT/O slippage/NN/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O support/NN/O among/IN/O Jewish/JJ/O voters/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O citywide/JJ/O projections/NNS/O now/RB/O put/VB/O his/PRP$/O lead/NN/O at/IN/O between/IN/O four/CD/O and/CC/O 20/CD/O percentage/NN/O points/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O with/IN/O reporters/NNS/O and/CC/O editors/NNS/O of/IN/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON appears/VBZ/O quite/RB/O confident/JJ/O of/IN/O victory/NN/O and/CC/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O the/DT/O mayoralty/NN/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O think/VBP/O I/PRP/O will/MD/O give/VB/O away/RP/O the/DT/O store/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O I/PRP/O can/MD/O assure/VB/O you/PRP/O I/PRP/O will/MD/O not/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O aware/JJ/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O real/JJ/O budgetary/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O city/NN/O is/VBZ/O full/JJ/O of/IN/O aging/VBG/O bridges/NNS/O ,/,/O water/NN/O mains/NNS/O and/CC/O roadways/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O need/NN/O of/IN/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O worth/JJ/O of/IN/O repair/NN/O ././O
Renewed/VBN/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O drugs/NNS/O and/CC/O crime/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O costly/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O city/NN/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O tax/NN/O revenues/NNS/O are/VBP/O lagging/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O after/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O of/IN/O explosive/JJ/O job/NN/O growth/NN/O on/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O period/NN/O of/IN/O contraction/NN/O is/VBZ/O under/IN/O way/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Koch/NNP/B-PERSON already/RB/O has/VBZ/O announced/VBN/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O drop/VB/O 3,200/CD/O jobs/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O payroll/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/DT/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O enough/RB/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE State/NNP/I-GPE Comptroller/NNP/O Edward/NNP/B-PERSON Regan/NNP/I-PERSON predicts/VBZ/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O budget/NN/O gap/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O next/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O gap/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O grow/VB/O if/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O face/VB/O a/DT/O mess/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O City/NNP/B-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Andrew/NNP/B-PERSON Stein/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O His/PRP$/O supporters/NNS/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O venal/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O their/PRP$/O solution/NN/O to/TO/O everything/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O money/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
By/RB/O and/CC/O large/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O finessed/VBN/O the/DT/O touchy/JJ/O question/NN/O of/IN/O whose/WP$/O ox/NN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O gore/VB/O ././O
Instead/RB/O of/IN/O focusing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O future/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O himself/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O unifier/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O city/NN/O recently/RB/O touched/VBN/O by/IN/O racial/JJ/O violence/NN/O and/CC/O as/IN/O a/DT/O soothing/JJ/O antidote/NN/O to/TO/O 12/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O commotion/NN/O generated/VBN/O by/IN/O Mayor/NNP/O Koch/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
No/DT/O doubt/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O calming/JJ/O influence/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O avuncular/JJ/O figure/NN/O who/WP/O remembers/VBZ/O the/DT/O birthdays/NNS/O of/IN/O colleagues/NNS/O '/POS/O children/NNS/O ,/,/O opens/VBZ/O doors/NNS/O for/IN/O women/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O almost/RB/O never/RB/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O bad/JJ/O word/NN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O about/IN/O anybody/NN/O ././O
Rather/RB/O than/IN/O scaring/VBG/O off/RP/O white/JJ/O voters/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O many/JJ/O predicted/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON attracted/VBD/O many/JJ/O whites/NNS/O precisely/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O reputation/NN/O for/IN/O having/VBG/O a/DT/O cool/JJ/O head/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O story/NN/O about/IN/O how/WRB/O he/PRP/O mishandled/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O son/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O media/NNS/O company/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O his/PRP$/O political/JJ/O patron/NN/O Percy/NNP/B-PERSON Sutton/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O fester/VB/O a/DT/O full/JJ/O week/NN/O before/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON faced/VBD/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O canceled/VBN/O numerous/JJ/O campaign/NN/O appointments/NNS/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O largely/RB/O inaccessible/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O until/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O story/NN/O broke/VBD/O ././O
Critics/NNS/O have/VBP/O said/VBN/O the/DT/O payment/NN/O looked/VBD/O like/IN/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON camp/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Carson/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O stop/VB/O leading/VBG/O confrontational/JJ/O demonstrations/NNS/O protesting/VBG/O the/DT/O Bensonhurst/NNP/B-LOC murder/NN/O --/:/O protests/VBZ/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O may/MD/O have/VB/O feared/VBN/O could/MD/O cause/VB/O some/DT/O white/JJ/O voters/NNS/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O black/JJ/O candidate/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O has/VBZ/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O allay/VB/O Jewish/JJ/O voters/NNS/O '/POS/O fears/NNS/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O association/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Rev./NNP/O Jesse/NNP/B-PERSON Jackson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O few/JJ/O local/JJ/O non-Jewish/JJ/O politicians/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O as/RB/O vocal/NN/O for/IN/O Jewish/JJ/O causes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O ././O
These/DT/O campaign/NN/O problems/NNS/O have/VBP/O echoed/VBN/O difficulties/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O run/VBN/O into/IN/O before/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O former/JJ/O U.S./NNP/O Marine/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON got/VBD/O off/RB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O quick/JJ/O start/NN/O in/IN/O politics/NNS/O ,/,/O joining/VBG/O a/DT/O local/JJ/O Democratic/JJ/O political/JJ/O club/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1950s/NNS/O ,/,/O linking/VBG/O up/RP/O with/IN/O black/JJ/O urban/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Rangel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Basil/NNP/B-PERSON Paterson/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Sutton/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O getting/VBG/O himself/PRP/O elected/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O state/NN/O assembly/NN/O in/IN/O 1965/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O his/PRP$/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O deputy/JJ/O mayor/NN/O under/IN/O Mayor/NNP/O Abraham/NNP/B-PERSON Beame/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O boosted/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sutton/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O squandered/VBN/O because/RB/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O failure/NN/O --/:/O still/RB/O largely/RB/O unexplained/JJ/O --/:/O to/TO/O file/VB/O income/NN/O tax/NN/O returns/NNS/O for/IN/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O running/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O always/RB/O thought/VBD/O of/IN/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O thing/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O always/RB/O be/VB/O done/VBN/O tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O O'Dwyer/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O now/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sutton/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O media/NNS/O company/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
The/DT/O debt/NN/O rose/VBD/O further/RBR/O in/IN/O 1977/CD/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Sutton/NNP/B-PERSON resigned/VBD/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O as/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE borough/NN/O president/NN/O to/TO/O run/VB/O for/IN/O mayor/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sutton/NNP/B-PERSON recalls/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O When/WRB/O I/PRP/O left/VBD/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O sat/VBD/O down/RB/O with/IN/O Charlie/NNP/B-PERSON -LCB-/-LRB-/I-PERSON Rangel/NNP/I-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON ,/,/O Basil/NNP/B-PERSON -LCB-/-LRB-/I-PERSON Paterson/NNP/I-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON and/CC/O David/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O David/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O `/``/O Who/WP/O will/MD/O run/VB/O for/IN/O borough/NN/O president/NN/O ?/./O '/''/O And/CC/O I/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O `/``/O You/PRP/O will/MD/O ././O '/''/O ''/''/O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Garth/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mayor/NNP/O Koch/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O longtime/JJ/O media/NNS/O adviser/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O He/PRP/O really/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O personification/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O patronage/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O guy/NN/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O personally/RB/O decent/JJ/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O forget/VB/O that/DT/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON lost/VBD/O twice/RB/O by/IN/O wide/JJ/O margins/NNS/O before/IN/O finally/RB/O getting/VBG/O elected/VBN/O borough/NN/O president/NN/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ././O
Colleagues/NNS/O today/NN/O recall/VBP/O with/IN/O some/DT/O humor/NN/O how/WRB/O meetings/NNS/O would/MD/O crawl/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O morning/NN/O hours/NNS/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O march/VB/O his/PRP$/O staff/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O board/NN/O meetings/NNS/O and/CC/O into/IN/O his/PRP$/O private/JJ/O office/NN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O ,/,/O en/FW/O masse/FW/O ,/,/O certain/JJ/O controversial/JJ/O proposals/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O taught/VBD/O me/PRP/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O drink/VB/O herbal/JJ/O tea/NN/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O coffee/NN/O at/IN/O 3/CD/O a.m./RB/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 'll/MD/O give/VB/O him/PRP/O that/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Deputy/NNP/O Mayor/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Esnard/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Often/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O procrastination/NN/O prevented/VBD/O him/PRP/O from/IN/O having/VBG/O a/DT/O say/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O things/NNS/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O ,/,/O critics/NNS/O claim/VBP/O ././O
But/CC/O board/NN/O members/NNS/O say/VBP/O he/PRP/O took/VBD/O so/RB/O long/JJ/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O vote/VB/O that/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O he/PRP/O decided/VBD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O late/JJ/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O draw/VB/O other/JJ/O members/NNS/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O one/CD/O city/NN/O official/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O Everybody/NN/O else/RB/O had/VBD/O brought/VBN/O in/RP/O the/DT/O wagons/NNS/O and/CC/O made/VBN/O their/PRP$/O deal/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O got/VBN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O more/JJR/O done/VBN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O made/VBD/O up/RP/O his/PRP$/O mind/NN/O faster/RBR/O ././O ''/''/O
One/CD/O Board/NN/B-ORG member/NN/O ,/,/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE Borough/NNP/I-GPE President/NNP/O Ferdinand/NNP/B-PERSON Ferrer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O said/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O so/RB/O impatient/JJ/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O behavior/NN/O at/IN/O many/JJ/O meetings/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O withheld/VBD/O his/PRP$/O support/NN/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O mayoral/JJ/O effort/NN/O until/IN/O late/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O primary/JJ/O campaign/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O had/VBD/O some/DT/O problem/NN/O from/IN/O time/NN/O to/TO/O time/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O length/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O take/VB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O up/RP/O his/PRP$/O mind/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Ferrer/NNP/B-PERSON admits/VBZ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O maintains/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O delay/VB/O his/PRP$/O support/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O backs/VBZ/O the/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O candidate/NN/O enthusiastically/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O campaign/NN/O manager/NN/O and/CC/O former/JJ/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O staff/NN/O ,/,/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Lynch/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O denies/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE borough/NN/O president/NN/O has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O too/RB/O long/JJ/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O important/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O some/DT/O occasions/NNS/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O discussed/VBN/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O run/VBN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O familiar/JJ/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O trouble/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O supporters/NNS/O were/VBD/O stunned/JJ/O this/DT/O summer/NN/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON suggested/VBD/O weakening/VBG/O the/DT/O law/NN/O forbidding/VBG/O public/JJ/O employees/NNS/O to/TO/O go/VB/O on/IN/O strike/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O withdrew/VBD/O the/DT/O remark/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O he/PRP/O later/RB/O sided/VBD/O with/IN/O striking/JJ/O hospital/NN/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O allies/NNS/O cringed/VBD/O a/DT/O little/RB/O more/RBR/O ,/,/O concerned/JJ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O setting/VBG/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O tone/NN/O for/IN/O coming/VBG/O contract/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O city/NN/O employees/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O announcement/NN/O was/VBD/O roundly/RB/O criticized/VBN/O by/IN/O Mayor/NNP/O Koch/NNP/B-PERSON --/:/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O endorsed/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON --/:/O because/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O faces/VBZ/O a/DT/O garbage/NN/O crisis/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O spent/VBN/O $/$/O 5/CD/O million/CD/O planning/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O incinerator/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O scrapped/VBN/O under/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O his/PRP$/O public/JJ/O statements/NNS/O have/VBP/O at/IN/O times/NNS/O been/VBN/O confusing/VBG/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O position/NN/O papers/NNS/O have/VBP/O more/RBR/O consistently/RB/O reflected/VBN/O anti-development/JJ/O sentiment/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O favors/VBZ/O a/DT/O form/NN/O of/IN/O commercial/JJ/O rent/NN/O control/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O community/NN/O believes/VBZ/O would/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O more/RBR/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O labor/NN/O shortage/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O proposes/VBZ/O linking/VBG/O city/NN/O subsidies/NNS/O to/TO/O businesses/NNS/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O record/NN/O of/IN/O hiring/VBG/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE residents/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O an/DT/O untrained/JJ/O local/JJ/O labor/NN/O pool/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O experts/NNS/O believe/VBP/O ,/,/O that/DT/O policy/NN/O could/MD/O drive/VB/O businesses/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O he/PRP/O favors/VBZ/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O cooperative/JJ/O approach/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O neighboring/VBG/O states/NNS/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O the/DT/O battle/NN/O over/IN/O companies/NNS/O thinking/VBG/O of/IN/O moving/VBG/O employees/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O planks/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O bother/VB/O the/DT/O business/NN/O community/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O draws/VBZ/O significant/JJ/O support/NN/O ././O
Steven/NNP/B-PERSON Spinola/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Real/NNP/I-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O economic/JJ/O development/NN/O program/NN/O is/VBZ/O shortsighted/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O comes/VBZ/O down/RB/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O reasonable/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O inner/JJ/O circle/NN/O of/IN/O advisers/NNS/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O include/VB/O both/DT/O ideologues/NNS/O and/CC/O pragmatists/NNS/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O voters/NNS/O with/IN/O little/JJ/O clue/NN/O as/IN/O to/TO/O who/WP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O influential/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O key/JJ/O man/NN/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lynch/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON campaign/NN/O hit/VBD/O tough/JJ/O times/NNS/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Andrew/NNP/B-PERSON Cuomo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O politically/RB/O seasoned/JJ/O son/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE governor/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O said/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O active/JJ/O role/NN/O on/IN/O strategy/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O close/JJ/O ally/NN/O is/VBZ/O Ruth/NNP/B-PERSON Messinger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE city/NN/O councilwoman/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O whose/WP$/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O commercial/JJ/O rent/NN/O control/NN/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O made/VBN/O their/PRP$/O way/NN/O into/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O position/NN/O papers/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O she/PRP/O remains/VBZ/O influential/JJ/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O some/DT/O suggest/VBP/O she/PRP/O will/MD/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O mayoralty/NN/O may/MD/O take/VB/O on/RP/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O anti-development/JJ/O flavor/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O business/NN/O leaders/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O also/RB/O believe/VB/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O place/VB/O significant/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O deputy/JJ/O mayor/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O administrative/JJ/O background/NN/O ././O
Names/NNS/O of/IN/O possible/JJ/O deputies/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O surfaced/VBN/O include/VBP/O former/JJ/O mayoral/JJ/O candidate/NN/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Ravitch/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O schools/NNS/O chancellor/NN/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Macchiarola/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Messrs./NNPS/O Leventhal/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Gliedman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Having/VBG/O attained/VBN/O positions/NNS/O of/IN/O real/JJ/O influence/NN/O or/CC/O wealth/NN/O ,/,/O these/DT/O men/NNS/O constitute/VBP/O the/DT/O Old/NNP/O Guard/NNP/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE black/JJ/O politics/NNS/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O less/RBR/O confrontational/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O younger/JJR/O ,/,/O more/RBR/O activist/JJ/O black/JJ/O political/JJ/O community/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O based/VBN/O largely/RB/O in/IN/O Brooklyn/NNP/B-GPE ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Part/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O strength/NN/O is/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O the/DT/O support/NN/O of/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/O Brooklyn/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Harlem/NNP/B-LOC factions/NNS/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
``/``/O We/PRP/O know/VBP/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O potholes/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O out/RB/O there/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Paterson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O former/JJ/O law/NN/O partner/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O think/VBP/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O sidetrack/VB/O David/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O determination/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O best/RBS/O possible/JJ/O mayor/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O obligations/NNS/O to/TO/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O making/VBG/O a/DT/O sad/JJ/O mistake/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Adds/VBZ/O Ms./NNP/O Messinger/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O the/DT/O borough/NN/O president/NN/O 's/POS/O job/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O vacating/VBG/O ,/,/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O remember/VB/O David/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O pragmatist/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O pragmatism/NN/O often/RB/O comes/VBZ/O across/RB/O more/RBR/O as/IN/O an/DT/O insider/NN/O 's/POS/O determination/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O upset/VB/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O apple/NN/O cart/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O aback/RB/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O when/WRB/O asked/VBD/O whether/IN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O mayor/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O on/IN/O reforming/VBG/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O ``/``/O fiefdoms/NNS/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O perpetuate/VBP/O the/DT/O monumental/JJ/O ineffectiveness/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE school/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O will/MD/O sit/VB/O down/RB/O and/CC/O talk/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O out/RP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O take/VB/O on/RP/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O system/NN/O ?/./O Uh-uh/UH/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O with/IN/O a/DT/O shake/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O head/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O many/JJ/O doubts/NNS/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O candidacy/NN/O ,/,/O white/JJ/O New/NNPS/O Yorkers/NNPS/O --/:/O who/WP/O gave/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 30/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O votes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O primary/NN/O --/:/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O desert/VB/O in/IN/O sufficient/JJ/O numbers/NNS/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O the/DT/O election/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Giuliani/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O former/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O prosecuted/VBD/O targets/NNS/O ranging/VBG/O from/IN/O Mafia/NNP/B-ORG dons/NNS/O to/TO/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O executives/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O succeeded/VBN/O in/IN/O raising/VBG/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ethical/JJ/O standards/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O so/RB/O far/RB/O has/VBZ/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O generate/VB/O excitement/NN/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O candidacy/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O Republican/NNP/O in/IN/O an/DT/O overwhelmingly/RB/O Democratic/JJ/O city/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Giuliani/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O an/DT/O inherent/JJ/O handicap/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Giuliani/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O finding/VBG/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O many/JJ/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O public/JJ/O life/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O built/VBN/O up/RP/O considerable/JJ/O good/JJ/O will/NN/O that/WDT/O so/RB/O far/RB/O has/VBZ/O led/VBN/O many/JJ/O voters/NNS/O to/TO/O overlook/VB/O certain/JJ/O failings/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O bottom/JJ/O line/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O very/RB/O genuine/JJ/O and/CC/O decent/JJ/O guy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON Hoenlein/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Jewish/JJ/O community/NN/O leader/NN/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O David/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O be/VB/O judged/VBN/O for/IN/O being/VBG/O David/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
