George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON disclosed/VBD/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O by/IN/O reading/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG senators/NNS/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O of/IN/O shifting/VBG/O blame/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE fiasco/NN/O to/TO/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O policy/NN/O was/VBD/O contained/VBN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O exchange/NN/O of/IN/O letters/NNS/O last/JJ/O October/NNP/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG intelligence/NN/O committee/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O National/NNP/B-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Staff/NN/O lawyers/NNS/O for/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O were/VBD/O busy/JJ/O agreeing/VBG/O with/IN/O one/NN/O another/DT/O about/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE could/MD/O not/RB/O do/VB/O to/TO/O oust/VB/O the/DT/O Panamanian/JJ/O thug/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O simply/RB/O got/VBD/O carried/VBN/O away/RB/O with/IN/O interpreting/VBG/O what/WP/O the/DT/O executive/NN/O order/NN/O banning/VBG/O assassinations/NNS/O really/RB/O meant/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O ironic/JJ/O that/IN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Boren/NNP/I-PERSON should/MD/O be/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O mire/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O former/JJ/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE governor/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O thoughtful/JJ/O defender/NN/O of/IN/O presidential/JJ/O powers/NNS/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O rare/JJ/O Democratic/JJ/O hawk/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O senator/NN/O most/JJS/O like/IN/O Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON Vandenberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG senator/NN/O from/IN/O Michigan/NNP/B-GPE who/WP/O worked/VBD/O to/TO/O forge/VB/O a/DT/O bipartisan/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1940s/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O committee/NN/O rejected/VBD/O a/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O support/VB/O a/DT/O coup/NN/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Ohio/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O Howard/NNP/B-PERSON Metzenbaum/NNP/I-PERSON refused/VBD/O to/TO/O support/VB/O any/DT/O plan/NN/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O get/VB/O people/NNS/O hurt/JJ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O charming/JJ/O notion/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O power/NN/O ././O
Maine/NNP/B-GPE Republican/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Cohen/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O might/MD/O violate/VB/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O ban/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O influenced/VBD/O the/DT/O failed/VBN/O coup/NN/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O concede/VB/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O mistakes/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O confusing/VBG/O consensus/NN/O on/IN/O general/JJ/O principles/NNS/O with/IN/O agreement/NN/O on/IN/O specific/JJ/O actions/NNS/O ././O
Elliott/NNP/B-PERSON Abrams/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O veteran/NN/O of/IN/O intelligence/NN/O committee/NN/O debates/NNS/O ,/,/O doubts/NNS/O that/WDT/O even/RB/O Grenada/NNP/O or/CC/O the/DT/O Libyan/JJ/O raid/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O taken/VBN/O place/NN/O if/IN/O ``/``/O consensus/NN/O ''/''/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O required/VBN/O ././O
Vandenberg/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Rayburn/NNP/B-PERSON were/VBD/O wise/JJ/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O specific/JJ/O operations/NNS/O to/TO/O presidents/NNS/O ;/:/O modern/JJ/O senators/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON notwithstanding/IN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O less/RBR/O modest/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG committee/NN/O has/VBZ/O what/WP/O amounts/VBZ/O to/TO/O veto/NN/O power/NN/O over/IN/O every/DT/O covert/JJ/O action/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON even/RB/O spies/VBZ/O a/DT/O silver/JJ/O lining/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O figures/VBZ/O the/DT/O episode/NN/O will/MD/O help/VB/O ``/``/O clarify/VB/O any/DT/O ambiguities/NNS/O ''/''/O between/IN/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O and/CC/O administration/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O reply/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Metzenbaums/NNPS/B-PERSON and/CC/O Cohens/NNPS/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O abolish/VB/O these/DT/O oversight/NN/O committees/NNS/O because/IN/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O seen/VBN/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O abuses/NNS/O of/IN/O executive/NN/O power/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O ././O
Americans/NNPS/O may/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O so/RB/O lucky/JJ/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O
