Analysts/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O move/NN/O could/MD/O presage/VB/O even/RB/O harsher/JJR/O action/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O appointment/NN/O of/IN/O Peat/NNP/B-ORG Marwick/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O that/WDT/O specializes/VBZ/O in/IN/O advising/VBG/O troubled/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O came/VBD/O about/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O round/NN/O of/IN/O meetings/NNS/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Skase/NNP/I-PERSON with/IN/O bank/NN/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG owes/VBZ/O creditors/NNS/O around/IN/O A$/$/O 1.2/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
