The/DT/O surprise/NN/O resignation/NN/O yesterday/NN/O of/IN/O British/NNP/O Chancellor/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Exchequer/NNP/O Nigel/NNP/B-PERSON Lawson/NNP/I-PERSON sent/VBD/O sterling/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O tailspin/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O by/IN/O creating/VBG/O uncertainties/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O direction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O also/RB/O firmed/VBN/O against/IN/O other/JJ/O currencies/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O back/NN/O of/IN/O sterling/NN/O 's/POS/O tumble/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O market/NN/O participants/NNS/O switched/VBD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O pounds/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O resignation/NN/O shocked/VBD/O many/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O ,/,/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O recurring/VBG/O speculation/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O rift/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O chancellor/NN/O and/CC/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Margaret/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Everyone/NN/O was/VBD/O extremely/RB/O long/JJ/O on/IN/O sterling/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Beale/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Sterling/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.5765/CD/O ,/,/O sharply/RB/O down/RB/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.6145/CD/O late/JJ/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Foley/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Lloyds/NNP/B-ORG noted/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O replacement/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Major/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O take/VB/O time/NN/O to/TO/O establish/VB/O his/PRP$/O credibility/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O meantime/NN/O ,/,/O sterling/NN/O could/MD/O trend/VB/O downward/RB/O in/IN/O volatile/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Chandross/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O economist/NN/O at/IN/O Lloyds/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O also/RB/O noted/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O 's/POS/O sharp/JJ/O decline/NN/O is/VBZ/O pegged/VBN/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O uncertainty/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O than/IN/O a/DT/O vision/NN/O of/IN/O altered/JJ/O United/NNP/B-GPE Kingdom/NNP/I-GPE economic/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O pound/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 1.6143/CD/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE prior/RB/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O announcement/NN/O ,/,/O sank/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O two/CD/O cents/NNS/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.5930/CD/O ,/,/O prompting/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O buy/VB/O pounds/NNS/O for/IN/O dollars/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O move/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O only/RB/O proved/VBD/O a/DT/O stopgap/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O 's/POS/O slide/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG intervened/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O time/NN/O at/IN/O around/IN/O $/$/O 1.5825/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE traders/NNS/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE GNP/NNP/O rose/VBD/O at/IN/O an/DT/O annual/JJ/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O 2.5/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O implicit/JJ/O price/NN/O deflator/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O inflation/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O down/RB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O 2.9/CD/O %/NN/O annual/JJ/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O quarter/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O 4.6/CD/O %/NN/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O gain/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O closed/VBD/O prior/RB/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O announcement/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O close/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O since/IN/O August/NNP/O 3/CD/O ././O
