Bankers/NNPS/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG won/VBD/O permission/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O move/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O private/JJ/O placement/NN/O department/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O fledgling/JJ/O securities/NNS/O subsidiary/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O seemingly/RB/O mundane/JJ/O action/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O opposed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Industry/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O trade/NN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O important/JJ/O implications/NNS/O for/IN/O banks/NNS/O '/POS/O recent/JJ/O entry/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O underwriting/NN/O of/IN/O corporate/JJ/O securities/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O action/NN/O increases/VBZ/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O publicly/RB/O registered/VBN/O securities/NNS/O that/IN/O banks/NNS/O '/POS/O securities/NNS/O affiliates/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O underwrite/VB/O ././O
Several/JJ/O other/JJ/O banks/NNS/O have/VBP/O similar/JJ/O applications/NNS/O pending/JJ/O ././O
Securities/NNS/O firms/NNS/O have/VBP/O challenged/VBN/O those/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG approvals/NNS/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O they/PRP/O violate/VBP/O federal/JJ/O laws/NNS/O separating/VBG/O the/DT/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O securities/NNS/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG limited/VBD/O the/DT/O revenue/NN/O that/WDT/O banks/NNS/O could/MD/O earn/VB/O from/IN/O these/DT/O new/JJ/O underwriting/NN/O activities/NNS/O to/TO/O no/DT/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O revenue/NN/O earned/VBN/O from/IN/O other/JJ/O securities/NNS/O activities/NNS/O long/RB/O open/RB/O to/TO/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O dealing/VBG/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Treasurys/NNPS/O ././O
For/IN/O some/DT/O banks/NNS/O that/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O ceiling/NN/O created/VBD/O problems/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O by/IN/O allowing/VBG/O BT/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O handle/VB/O private/JJ/O placements/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG boosted/VBD/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O underwriting/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O can/MD/O do/VB/O ././O
Private/JJ/O placements/NNS/O involve/VBP/O debt/NN/O and/CC/O equity/NN/O securities/NNS/O ,/,/O typically/RB/O in/IN/O denominations/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O institutional/JJ/O investors/NNS/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O registered/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Bankers/NNP/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O placed/VBD/O $/$/O 10/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O corporate/JJ/O debt/NN/O and/CC/O equities/NNS/O privately/RB/O ././O
