Half/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O polled/VBN/O see/VBP/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O trending/VBG/O lower/JJR/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O three/CD/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O others/NNS/O forecast/VBP/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O rebound/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/O Year/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O month/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O survey/NN/O predicted/VBD/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O 1.8690/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 139.75/CD/O yen/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O October/NNP/O ././O
Sterling/NN/O was/VBD/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.5805/CD/O ,/,/O down/RB/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.5820/CD/O late/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O average/NN/O of/IN/O estimates/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 10/CD/O economists/NNS/O polled/VBN/O puts/VBZ/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O around/IN/O 1.8200/CD/O marks/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O November/NNP/O and/CC/O at/IN/O 141.33/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
Those/DT/O with/IN/O a/DT/O bullish/JJ/O view/NN/O see/VBP/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O trading/VBG/O up/RB/O near/IN/O 1.9000/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 145/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O bears/NNS/O see/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE currency/NN/O trading/VBG/O around/IN/O 1.7600/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 138/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O polled/VBN/O predict/VBP/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O will/MD/O slip/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG eases/VBZ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O rate/NN/O banks/NNS/O charge/VBP/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O on/IN/O overnight/JJ/O loans/NNS/O ;/:/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG influences/VBZ/O the/DT/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O adding/VBG/O or/CC/O draining/VBG/O reserves/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O banking/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O discount/NN/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O currently/RB/O 7/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O rate/NN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG charges/VBZ/O member/NN/O banks/NNS/O for/IN/O loans/NNS/O ,/,/O using/VBG/O government/NN/O securities/NNS/O as/IN/O collateral/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O drop/NN/O marked/VBD/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O monthly/JJ/O tumble/NN/O since/IN/O a/DT/O 19/CD/O %/NN/O slide/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O 1982/CD/O ././O
Several/JJ/O other/JJ/O European/JJ/O central/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O notably/RB/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O followed/VBD/O the/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O Bundesbank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O lead/NN/O by/IN/O raising/VBG/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O key/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O discount/NN/O rate/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O base/JJ/O rate/NN/O on/IN/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O commercial/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Tomoshige/NNP/B-PERSON Kakita/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O deputy/NN/O manager/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O treasury/NN/O department/NN/O of/IN/O Mitsui/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O suggested/VBD/O that/IN/O uncertainty/NN/O about/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE stocks/NNS/O and/CC/O bonds/NNS/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O Japanese/JJ/O investors/NNS/O leery/JJ/O of/IN/O holding/VBG/O those/DT/O securities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O near/JJ/O term/NN/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O damping/VBG/O dollar/NN/O demand/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O contended/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O ease/VB/O rates/NNS/O further/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O predicted/VBD/O Bundesbank/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O will/MD/O relax/VB/O key/JJ/O rates/NNS/O in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON Zapfel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O trader/NN/O at/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O took/VBD/O an/DT/O opposite/JJ/O stance/NN/O ././O
West/JJ/O German/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O unchanged/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O predicted/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O will/MD/O skid/VB/O below/IN/O 1.80/CD/O marks/NNS/O to/TO/O around/IN/O 1.78/CD/O marks/NNS/O this/DT/O month/NN/O and/CC/O 1.75/CD/O marks/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O beginning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Owen/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Kleinwort/NNP/B-ORG Benson/NNP/I-ORG suggested/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O chancellor/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Major/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O will/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O line/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O autumn/NN/O statement/NN/O later/RB/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O helping/VBG/O to/TO/O underpin/VB/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O ././O
Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Hill/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Hastings/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Erik/NNP/B-PERSON Kirschbaum/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Caitlin/NNP/B-PERSON Randall/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Appell/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
