Intelogic/NNP/B-ORG Trace/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O exploring/VBG/O alternatives/NNS/O to/TO/O maximize/VB/O shareholder/NN/O value/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O possible/JJ/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Any/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Intelogic/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O have/VB/O an/DT/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O battle/NN/O between/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Edelman/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE attorney/NN/O Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Ackerman/NNP/I-PERSON for/IN/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Datapoint/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Intelogic/NNP/B-ORG holds/VBZ/O 27.5/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Datapoint/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Edelman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O ``/``/O has/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O with/IN/O Marty/NNP/B-PERSON Ackerman/NNP/I-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Ackerman/NNP/B-PERSON contended/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O direct/JJ/O response/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Datapoint/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Intelogic/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O spun/VBN/O off/RP/O from/IN/O Datapoint/NNP/B-ORG four/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O shortly/RB/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Edelman/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Datapoint/NNP/B-ORG ././O
