Gillette/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O planning/VBG/O to/TO/O restructure/VB/O its/PRP$/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O subsidiary/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O Gillette/NNP/B-ORG South/NNP/I-ORG Africa/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O sell/VB/O manufacturing/NN/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O Springs/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O business/NN/O in/IN/O toiletries/NNS/O and/CC/O plastic/NN/O bags/NNS/O to/TO/O Twins/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceuticals/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O affiliate/NN/O of/IN/O Anglo/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O company/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O not/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O final/JJ/O agreement/NN/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O been/VBN/O signed/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O moves/NNS/O will/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O material/JJ/O effect/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Gillette/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Gillette/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O continued/JJ/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE ``/``/O enables/VBZ/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O meaningful/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O to/TO/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O society/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O the/DT/O lives/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O employees/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O the/DT/O communities/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O operates/VBZ/O ././O ''/''/O
Gillette/NNP/B-ORG South/NNP/I-ORG Africa/NNP/I-ORG employs/VBZ/O about/RB/O 250/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
About/RB/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O work/NN/O force/NN/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O with/IN/O Gillette/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O transfer/VB/O to/TO/O Twins/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceuticals/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
