Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O collapse/NN/O may/MD/O cost/VB/O taxpayers/NNS/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O estimates/NNS/O ,/,/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O expensive/JJ/O thrift/NN/O failure/NN/O in/IN/O history/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O evidence/NN/O pointed/VBD/O to/TO/O wrongdoing/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O allege/VB/O any/DT/O specific/JJ/O violation/NN/O ././O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Newsom/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O official/NN/O who/WP/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O examined/VBD/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O also/RB/O saw/VBD/O evidence/NN/O that/IN/O crimes/NNS/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O committed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O later/RB/O brought/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O billion/CD/O fraud/NN/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O complained/VBN/O that/IN/O regulators/NNS/O waited/VBD/O far/RB/O too/RB/O long/RB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O ignoring/VBG/O a/DT/O recommendation/NN/O from/IN/O regional/JJ/O officials/NNS/O to/TO/O place/VB/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG into/IN/O receivership/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O failed/VBD/O ././O
State/NN/O thrift/NN/O examiner/NN/O Eugene/NNP/B-PERSON Stelzer/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O found/VBD/O the/DT/O chief/JJ/O federal/JJ/O examiner/NN/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON Scott/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O be/VB/O totally/RB/O uninterested/JJ/O in/IN/O one/CD/O allegedly/RB/O fraudulent/JJ/O series/NN/O of/IN/O transactions/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bickwit/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O paper/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O donated/VBN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O a/DT/O charitable/JJ/O organization/NN/O that/WDT/O sells/VBZ/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O recycling/VBG/O ././O
