West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE will/MD/O repeal/VB/O the/DT/O unpopular/JJ/O turnover/NN/O tax/NN/O on/IN/O securities/NNS/O transactions/NNS/O as/IN/O of/IN/O Jan./NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O Economics/NNP/B-ORG Minister/NNP/O Helmut/NNP/B-PERSON Haussmann/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O announcement/NN/O follows/VBZ/O several/JJ/O comments/NNS/O by/IN/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O will/MD/O speed/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O repeal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O originally/RB/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O start/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O single/JJ/O internal/JJ/O market/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O tax/NN/O has/VBZ/O raised/VBN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O one/CD/O billion/CD/O marks/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 545.3/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O annually/RB/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O abolish/VB/O the/DT/O levy/NN/O for/IN/O budgetary/JJ/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Haussmann/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O specify/VB/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O revenue/NN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O will/MD/O lose/VB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O disappears/VBZ/O ././O
