Those/DT/O two/CD/O groups/NNS/O have/VBP/O recently/RB/O been/VBN/O leading/VBG/O the/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O stocks/NNS/O setting/VBG/O new/JJ/O highs/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/POS/O as/IN/O if/IN/O investors/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O betting/VBG/O that/IN/O something/NN/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O go/VB/O wrong/JJ/O --/:/O even/RB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O what/WP/O ././O
Inventories/NNS/O are/VBP/O creeping/VBG/O up/RB/O ;/:/O car/NN/O inventories/NNS/O are/VBP/O already/RB/O high/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O big/JJ/O auto/NN/O makers/NNS/O are/VBP/O idling/VBG/O plants/NNS/O ././O
Takeover/NN/O fever/NN/O has/VBZ/O cooled/VBN/O ,/,/O removing/VBG/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O horse/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O cart/NN/O ././O
Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O unsettled/JJ/O political/JJ/O scene/NN/O also/RB/O worries/VBZ/O some/DT/O investors/NNS/O ././O
Utilities/NNS/B-ORG are/VBP/O a/DT/O classic/JJ/O example/NN/O :/:/O Even/RB/O in/IN/O recessions/NNS/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O use/VB/O electric/JJ/O power/NN/O ,/,/O water/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O fairly/RB/O steady/JJ/O rate/NN/O ././O
Such/JJ/O defensive/NN/O issues/NNS/O as/IN/O food/NN/O ,/,/O tobacco/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O drug/NN/O stocks/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O favor/NN/O for/IN/O some/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Gold/NN/O stocks/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O cheap/JJ/O on/IN/O this/DT/O basis/NN/O ,/,/O either/RB/O ,/,/O with/IN/O many/JJ/O selling/VBG/O for/IN/O 20/CD/O times/NNS/O earnings/NNS/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O just/RB/O what/WP/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON Granville/NNP/I-PERSON expects/VBZ/O ././O
One/CD/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O gloom/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O weekly/JJ/O tally/NN/O he/PRP/O keeps/VBZ/O of/IN/O stocks/NNS/O within/IN/O a/DT/O point/NN/O of/IN/O hitting/VBG/O new/JJ/O highs/NNS/O or/CC/O lows/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stovall/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O an/DT/O actual/JJ/O recession/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O favors/VBZ/O FPL/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Florida/NNP/B-ORG Progress/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O TECO/NNP/B-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Wisconsin/NNP/B-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Dominion/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O appeal/NN/O of/IN/O gold/NN/O issues/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Stovall/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O ``/``/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O a/DT/O counter/JJ/O group/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O favorites/NNS/O are/VBP/O American/NNP/B-ORG Barrick/NNP/I-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Echo/NNP/B-ORG Bay/NNP/I-ORG Mines/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Coeur/NNP/B-ORG d'Alene/NNP/I-ORG Mines/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Abby/NNP/B-PERSON Cohen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O strategist/NN/O for/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O also/RB/O thinks/VBZ/O it/PRP/O makes/VBZ/O sense/NN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O some/DT/O money/NN/O in/IN/O both/CC/O utilities/NNS/O and/CC/O gold/NN/O ././O
