No/DT/O way/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O appears/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O thing/NN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O learning/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG story/NN/O is/VBZ/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O enlarge/VB/O its/PRP$/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O honey/NN/O pot/NN/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O special/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O that/DT/O at/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O deepening/VBG/O the/DT/O taxpayer/NN/O 's/POS/O exposure/NN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O loans/NNS/O going/VBG/O sour/JJ/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O idle/JJ/O fear/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O the/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG lost/VBD/O $/$/O 4.2/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O loan/NN/O defaults/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O higher/JJR/O mortgage/NN/O ceiling/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O the/DT/O starter/JJ/O kit/NN/O for/IN/O what/WP/O Senator/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Cranston/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Majority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Mitchell/NNP/I-PERSON have/VBP/O in/IN/O mind/NN/O for/IN/O housing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O begin/VB/O hearings/NNS/O next/IN/O week/NN/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O proposal/NN/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O existing/VBG/O federal/JJ/O housing/NN/O programs/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O formula/NN/O for/IN/O ensuring/VBG/O even/RB/O more/JJR/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG red/JJ/O ink/NN/O ././O
Because/IN/O a/DT/O purchaser/NN/O can/MD/O use/VB/O an/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG loan/NN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O all/DT/O points/NNS/O and/CC/O closing/NN/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O wind/VB/O up/RP/O lending/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O house/NN/O is/VBZ/O worth/IN/O ././O
If/IN/O housing/NN/O prices/NNS/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O borrowers/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O better/JJR/O off/RP/O walking/VBG/O away/RB/O from/IN/O their/PRP$/O homes/NNS/O and/CC/O leaving/VBG/O taxpayers/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O losses/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O sounds/VBZ/O like/IN/O a/DT/O formula/NN/O for/IN/O ensuring/VBG/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O dragged/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG tar/NN/O pit/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O even/RB/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O agrees/VBZ/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Kemp/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O write/VB/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O housing/NN/O law/NN/O --/:/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O Members/NNS/O cynically/RB/O view/VBP/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O discrediting/NN/O of/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O mainly/RB/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O shove/VB/O through/RP/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O slate/NN/O of/IN/O projects/NNS/O ././O
Exhibit/NN/O A/NN/O is/VBZ/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O House/NNP/B-ORG vote/NN/O to/TO/O fund/VB/O 40/CD/O pet/JJ/O projects/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O discretionary/JJ/O fund/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ././O
None/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O grants/NNS/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O requested/VBN/O by/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O judged/VBN/O competitively/RB/O or/CC/O were/VBD/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O hearing/NN/O ././O
More/JJR/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O observers/NNS/O now/RB/O realize/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O key/NN/O to/TO/O ending/VBG/O future/JJ/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG scandals/NNS/O lies/VBZ/O in/IN/O forcing/VBG/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O clean/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O act/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Sun/NNP/B-ORG concluded/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Pierce/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O only/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O a/DT/O part/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O gone/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O reformed/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O it/PRP/O concluded/VBD/O ,/,/O Members/NNPS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O ``/``/O have/VB/O to/TO/O start/VB/O looking/VBG/O into/IN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O doing/VBG/O something/NN/O about/IN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O practices/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O the/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG program/NN/O is/VBZ/O hemorrhaging/VBG/O bad/JJ/O loans/NNS/O ././O
