No/DT/O way/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O appears/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O thing/NN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O learning/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG story/NN/O is/VBZ/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O enlarge/VB/O its/PRP$/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O honey/NN/O pot/NN/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O special/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O idle/JJ/O fear/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O the/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG lost/VBD/O $/$/O 4.2/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O loan/NN/O defaults/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O begin/VB/O hearings/NNS/O next/IN/O week/NN/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O proposal/NN/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O existing/VBG/O federal/JJ/O housing/NN/O programs/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O formula/NN/O for/IN/O ensuring/VBG/O even/RB/O more/JJR/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG red/JJ/O ink/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O sounds/VBZ/O like/IN/O a/DT/O formula/NN/O for/IN/O ensuring/VBG/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O dragged/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG tar/NN/O pit/NN/O ././O
Exhibit/NN/O A/NN/O is/VBZ/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O House/NNP/B-ORG vote/NN/O to/TO/O fund/VB/O 40/CD/O pet/JJ/O projects/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O discretionary/JJ/O fund/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ././O
None/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O grants/NNS/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O requested/VBN/O by/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O judged/VBN/O competitively/RB/O or/CC/O were/VBD/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O hearing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Sun/NNP/B-ORG concluded/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Pierce/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O only/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O a/DT/O part/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O gone/VBN|JJ/O ././O
