The/DT/O missing/JJ/O watch/NN/O is/VBZ/O emblematic/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON encountered/VBD/O in/IN/O building/VBG/O his/PRP$/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O California/NNP/B-ORG Plant/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG into/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O detective/NN/O and/CC/O security/NN/O agency/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE through/IN/O acquisitions/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O joined/VBD/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O in/IN/O 1963/CD/O and/CC/O bought/VBD/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O owners/NNS/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O decided/VBD/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O easily/RB/O merge/VB/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG operations/NNS/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O while/NN/O slashing/VBG/O overhead/JJ/O costs/NNS/O because/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O already/RB/O operated/VBD/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O cities/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O could/MD/O acquire/VB/O a/DT/O staff/NN/O of/IN/O loyal/JJ/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG employees/NNS/O ,/,/O many/DT/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O had/VBD/O spent/VBN/O their/PRP$/O entire/JJ/O careers/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O eliminate/VB/O a/DT/O competitor/NN/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O get/VB/O the/DT/O name/NN/O recognition/NN/O he/PRP/O 'd/VBD/O wanted/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O relished/VBD/O the/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O demonstrate/VB/O an/DT/O entrepreneur/NN/O like/IN/O himself/PRP/O ,/,/O who/WP/O 'd/VBD/O spent/VBN/O his/PRP$/O whole/JJ/O career/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O security/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O run/VB/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG better/RBR/O than/IN/O an/DT/O unfocused/JJ/O conglomerate/NN/O or/CC/O investment/NN/O banker/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O love/VBP/O this/DT/O business/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Five/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O rapid/JJ/O expansion/NN/O under/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O an/DT/O emphasis/NN/O on/IN/O marketing/VBG/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O services/NNS/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O improving/VBG/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O hurt/VBN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG profits/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON claims/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O team/NN/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O tell/VB/O whether/IN/O accounts/NNS/O receivable/JJ/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O paid/VBN/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O accusations/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O turnaround/NN/O strategy/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O simple/JJ/O :/:/O just/RB/O hack/VB/O away/RP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O fat/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O shut/VBD/O down/RP/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O tony/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE headquarters/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O says/VBZ/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG had/VBD/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O under/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O boasts/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O made/VBN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG profitable/JJ/O again/RB/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O earnings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O combined/JJ/O companies/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O cover/VB/O debt/NN/O service/NN/O and/CC/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O borrow/VB/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O subordinated/JJ/O debt/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O service/VB/O debt/NN/O and/CC/O still/RB/O turn/VB/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O profit/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG misrepresented/VBD/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O of/IN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG before/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ,/,/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O pending/VBG/O lawsuits/NNS/O and/CC/O material/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG was/VBD/O in/IN/O default/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O registered/VBN/O the/DT/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG name/NN/O and/CC/O trademark/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE Kingdom/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O tell/VB/O California/NNP/B-ORG Plant/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG about/IN/O some/DT/O labor/NN/O controversies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O an/DT/O inventory/NN/O of/IN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG memorabilia/NNS/O disclosed/VBD/O that/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O watches/NNS/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O forked/VBN/O over/RP/O by/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O key/NN/O to/TO/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG future/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O sticking/VBG/O to/TO/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O best/RBS/O --/:/O being/VBG/O a/DT/O security/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O renewing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O emphasis/NN/O on/IN/O investigations/NNS/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O undercover/JJ/O investigations/NNS/O for/IN/O corporations/NNS/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ``/``/O just/RB/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
