Avery/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O a/DT/O group/NN/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O management/NN/O of/IN/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O 's/POS/O main/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O valued/VBD/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Avery/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O a/DT/O coal/NN/O company/NN/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O at/IN/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O proxy/JJ/O materials/NNS/O it/PRP/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O control/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O companies/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O fees/NNS/O and/CC/O repayment/NN/O of/IN/O debt/NN/O ,/,/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O left/VBN/O with/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 24/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O cash/NN/O and/CC/O securities/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG sale/NN/O ././O
Avery/NNP/B-ORG paid/VBD/O $/$/O 750/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O various/JJ/O legal/JJ/O and/CC/O financing/NN/O fees/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Middlebury/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O --/:/O a/DT/O move/NN/O that/WDT/O burdened/VBD/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O debt/NN/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBN/O Sept./NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 734.2/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O a/DT/O net/JJ/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 47.1/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
An/DT/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O was/VBD/O magnified/VBN/O by/IN/O accounting/NN/O adjustments/NNS/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O loss/NN/O was/VBD/O smaller/JJR/O on/IN/O a/DT/O cash/NN/O basis/NN/O ././O
Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O 2,600/CD/O employees/NNS/O and/CC/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Brazil/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O related/JJ/O development/NN/O ,/,/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O completed/VBD/O a/DT/O recapitalization/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O its/PRP$/O controlling/VBG/O shareholders/NNS/O and/CC/O top/JJ/O officers/NNS/O ,/,/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Peltz/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON May/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O surrendered/VBD/O warrants/NNS/O and/CC/O preferred/JJ/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O larger/JJR/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O a/DT/O fully/RB/O diluted/JJ/O basis/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O raised/VBD/O their/PRP$/O stake/NN/O to/TO/O 68/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O 51/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O December/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O Messrs./NNPS/O Peltz/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O May/NNP/B-PERSON sold/VBD/O their/PRP$/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O Triangle/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O packaging/NN/O company/NN/O they/PRP/O controlled/VBD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O Pechiney/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O executives/NNS/O had/VBD/O profited/VBN/O handsomely/RB/O by/IN/O building/VBG/O American/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Can/MD/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Triangle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O asset/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O January/NNP/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O acquired/VBD/O the/DT/O non-packaging/JJ/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O Triangle/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O controlling/JJ/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O ,/,/O by/IN/O extension/NN/O ,/,/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O August/NNP/O proxy/NN/O material/NN/O ,/,/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O unless/IN/O it/PRP/O sold/VBD/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O its/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O service/NN/O debt/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O hurt/VBN/O and/CC/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O shareholder/NN/O value/NN/O would/MD/O ``/``/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O erode/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Until/IN/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG makes/VBZ/O an/DT/O acquisition/NN/O ,/,/O Messrs./NNPS/O Peltz/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O May/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O waive/VB/O their/PRP$/O direct/JJ/O salaries/NNS/O and/CC/O bonuses/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
For/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O a/DT/O month/NN/O for/IN/O management/NN/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O company/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Messrs./NN/O Peltz/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O May/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O proxy/JJ/O material/NN/O ././O
