There/EX/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O wanted/JJ/O poster/NN/O offering/VBG/O ``/``/O Rewards/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Arrest/NN/O of/IN/O Express/NN/O and/CC/O Train/NN/O Robbers/NNS/O Frank/NNP/O James/NNP/O and/CC/O Jesse/NNP/O W./NNP/O James/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O the/DT/O original/JJ/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG logo/NN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O eye/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O inscription/NN/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O Never/RB/O Sleep/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O inspired/VBD/O the/DT/O phrase/NN/O ``/``/O private/JJ/O eye/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Then/RB/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O two/CD/O gold/NN/O watches/NNS/O once/RB/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O Allan/NNP/B-PERSON Pinkerton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O founded/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O 1850/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O three/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O claims/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O missing/JJ/O watch/NN/O is/VBZ/O emblematic/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON encountered/VBD/O in/IN/O building/VBG/O his/PRP$/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O California/NNP/B-ORG Plant/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG into/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O detective/NN/O and/CC/O security/NN/O agency/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE through/IN/O acquisitions/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O joined/VBD/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O in/IN/O 1963/CD/O and/CC/O bought/VBD/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O owners/NNS/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O California/NNP/B-ORG Plant/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG opened/VBD/O 125/CD/O offices/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Yet/CC/O although/IN/O California/NNP/B-ORG Plant/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O netting/VBG/O bigger/JJR/O and/CC/O bigger/JJR/O clients/NNS/O --/:/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O provided/VBD/O security/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O 1984/CD/O Summer/NNP/O Olympics/NNP/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE --/:/O it/PRP/O still/RB/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O name/NN/O recognition/NN/O of/IN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ././O
So/RB/O when/WRB/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG decided/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O divestiture/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O food/NN/O and/CC/O security/NN/O industries/NNS/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON saw/VBD/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O accomplish/VB/O several/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O decided/VBD/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O easily/RB/O merge/VB/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG operations/NNS/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O while/NN/O slashing/VBG/O overhead/JJ/O costs/NNS/O because/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O already/RB/O operated/VBD/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O cities/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O could/MD/O acquire/VB/O a/DT/O staff/NN/O of/IN/O loyal/JJ/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG employees/NNS/O ,/,/O many/DT/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O had/VBD/O spent/VBN/O their/PRP$/O entire/JJ/O careers/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O eliminate/VB/O a/DT/O competitor/NN/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O get/VB/O the/DT/O name/NN/O recognition/NN/O he/PRP/O 'd/VBD/O wanted/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O relished/VBD/O the/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O demonstrate/VB/O an/DT/O entrepreneur/NN/O like/IN/O himself/PRP/O ,/,/O who/WP/O 'd/VBD/O spent/VBN/O his/PRP$/O whole/JJ/O career/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O security/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O run/VB/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG better/RBR/O than/IN/O an/DT/O unfocused/JJ/O conglomerate/NN/O or/CC/O investment/NN/O banker/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O security/NN/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O my/PRP$/O favorite/JJ/O subject/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O love/VBP/O this/DT/O business/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O LBO/NNP/O guys/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O run/VB/O a/DT/O business/NN/O anyway/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O hitches/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O that/DT/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O proceeded/VBD/O almost/RB/O blindly/RB/O in/IN/O doing/VBG/O the/DT/O $/$/O 95/CD/O million/CD/O acquisition/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O completed/VBN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O any/DT/O due/JJ/O diligence/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O competitive/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O might/MD/O have/VB/O scared/VBN/O us/PRP/O off/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Five/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O rapid/JJ/O expansion/NN/O under/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O an/DT/O emphasis/NN/O on/IN/O marketing/VBG/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O services/NNS/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O improving/VBG/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O hurt/VBN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG profits/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON claims/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O team/NN/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O tell/VB/O whether/IN/O accounts/NNS/O receivable/JJ/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O paid/VBN/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ././O
And/CC/O regional/JJ/O offices/NNS/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O egregiously/RB/O overstaffed/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O claims/VBZ/O ././O
One/CD/O office/NN/O had/VBD/O 19/CD/O people/NNS/O doing/VBG/O the/DT/O work/NN/O of/IN/O three/CD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O and/CC/O half/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O employees/NNS/O had/VBD/O company/NN/O automobiles/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O accusations/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O turnaround/NN/O strategy/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O simple/JJ/O :/:/O just/RB/O hack/VB/O away/RP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O fat/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O shut/VBD/O down/RP/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O tony/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE headquarters/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O says/VBZ/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG had/VBD/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O under/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O boasts/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O made/VBN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG profitable/JJ/O again/RB/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O earnings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O combined/JJ/O companies/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O cover/VB/O debt/NN/O service/NN/O and/CC/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O borrow/VB/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O subordinated/JJ/O debt/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O had/VBN/O to/TO/O refinance/VB/O if/IN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O there/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O service/VB/O debt/NN/O and/CC/O still/RB/O turn/VB/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O profit/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG could/MD/O become/VB/O entangled/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O protracted/JJ/O legal/JJ/O fracas/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O former/JJ/O parent/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG misrepresented/VBD/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O of/IN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG before/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ,/,/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O pending/VBG/O lawsuits/NNS/O and/CC/O material/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG was/VBD/O in/IN/O default/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O registered/VBN/O the/DT/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG name/NN/O and/CC/O trademark/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE Kingdom/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O tell/VB/O California/NNP/B-ORG Plant/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG about/IN/O some/DT/O labor/NN/O controversies/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O previously/RB/O had/VBN/O discussions/NNS/O with/IN/O representatives/NNS/O of/IN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Inc./NN/I-ORG concerning/VBG/O the/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O concluded/VBD/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O liability/NN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O As/IN/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O a/DT/O litigation/NN/O matter/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O further/JJ/O comment/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O then/RB/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O case/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O missing/JJ/O gold/NN/O watch/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O an/DT/O inventory/NN/O of/IN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG memorabilia/NNS/O disclosed/VBD/O that/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O watches/NNS/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O forked/VBN/O over/RP/O by/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brand/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG failure/NN/O to/TO/O surrender/VB/O the/DT/O gold/NN/O watch/NN/O has/VBZ/O damaged/VBN/O new/JJ/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O in/IN/O an/DT/O amount/NN/O as/RB/O yet/RB/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O to/TO/O be/VB/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O determined/VBN/O and/CC/O deprived/VBN/O it/PRP/O of/IN/O a/DT/O valuable/JJ/O artifact/NN/O for/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O bargained/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O charges/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O key/NN/O to/TO/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG future/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O sticking/VBG/O to/TO/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O best/RBS/O --/:/O being/VBG/O a/DT/O security/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O renewing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O emphasis/NN/O on/IN/O investigations/NNS/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O undercover/JJ/O investigations/NNS/O for/IN/O corporations/NNS/O ././O
Although/IN/O investigations/NNS/O now/RB/O account/VBP/O for/IN/O only/RB/O about/RB/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG total/JJ/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O that/DT/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O business/NN/O has/VBZ/O traditionally/RB/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O ``/``/O glamorous/JJ/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O carries/VBZ/O historical/JJ/O and/CC/O sentimental/JJ/O value/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Author/NN/O Dashiell/NNP/B-PERSON Hammett/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O wrote/VBD/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Maltese/JJ/O Falcon/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Pinkerton/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG detective/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG ``/``/O just/RB/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Wathen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Their/PRP$/O approach/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O work/NN/O ;/:/O mine/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ././O
