Most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 10/CD/O analysts/NNS/O polled/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O by/IN/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE expect/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE dollar/NN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O only/RB/O mildly/RB/O in/IN/O November/NNP/O ././O
Half/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O polled/VBN/O see/VBP/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O trending/VBG/O lower/JJR/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O three/CD/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O others/NNS/O forecast/VBP/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O rebound/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/O Year/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O late/JJ/O afternoon/NN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE trading/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O stood/VBD/O at/IN/O 1.8415/CD/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O marks/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 1.8340/CD/O marks/NNS/O late/RB/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O 142.85/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 141.90/CD/O yen/NNS/O late/RB/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
A/DT/O month/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O survey/NN/O predicted/VBD/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O 1.8690/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 139.75/CD/O yen/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O October/NNP/O ././O
Sterling/NN/O was/VBD/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.5805/CD/O ,/,/O down/RB/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.5820/CD/O late/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE Wednesday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE currency/NN/O was/VBD/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O about/RB/O 142.95/CD/O yen/NNS/O at/IN/O midmorning/NN/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 142.80/CD/O yen/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O opening/NN/O and/CC/O up/RB/O from/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE close/NN/O of/IN/O 142.15/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O average/NN/O of/IN/O estimates/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 10/CD/O economists/NNS/O polled/VBN/O puts/VBZ/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O around/IN/O 1.8200/CD/O marks/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O November/NNP/O and/CC/O at/IN/O 141.33/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O late/JJ/O January/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O consensus/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O trading/VBG/O around/IN/O 1.8200/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O near/IN/O 142/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
Those/DT/O with/IN/O a/DT/O bullish/JJ/O view/NN/O see/VBP/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O trading/VBG/O up/RB/O near/IN/O 1.9000/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 145/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O bears/NNS/O see/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE currency/NN/O trading/VBG/O around/IN/O 1.7600/CD/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O 138/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O polled/VBN/O predict/VBP/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O will/MD/O slip/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG eases/VBZ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O rate/NN/O banks/NNS/O charge/VBP/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O on/IN/O overnight/JJ/O loans/NNS/O ;/:/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG influences/VBZ/O the/DT/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O adding/VBG/O or/CC/O draining/VBG/O reserves/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O banking/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O discount/NN/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O currently/RB/O 7/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O rate/NN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG charges/VBZ/O member/NN/O banks/NNS/O for/IN/O loans/NNS/O ,/,/O using/VBG/O government/NN/O securities/NNS/O as/IN/O collateral/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O cut/NN/O ``/``/O because/IN/O of/IN/O problems/NNS/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O sectors/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O and/CC/O automobiles/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Bolstering/VBG/O his/PRP$/O argument/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O that/IN/O new/JJ/O home/NN/O sales/NNS/O for/IN/O September/NNP/O were/VBD/O down/RB/O 14/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O August/NNP/O 's/POS/O revised/JJ/O 3.1/CD/O %/NN/O fall/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O drop/NN/O marked/VBD/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O monthly/JJ/O tumble/NN/O since/IN/O a/DT/O 19/CD/O %/NN/O slide/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O 1982/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O 's/POS/O survey/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O currency/NN/O analysts/NNS/O predicted/VBD/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O pressured/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O narrowing/NN/O of/IN/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O differentials/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O early/JJ/O October/NNP/O the/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O raised/VBD/O its/PRP$/O discount/NN/O and/CC/O Lombard/NNP/O rates/NNS/O by/IN/O a/DT/O full/JJ/O percentage/NN/O point/NN/O ././O
Several/JJ/O other/JJ/O European/JJ/O central/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O notably/RB/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O followed/VBD/O the/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O Bundesbank/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O lead/NN/O by/IN/O raising/VBG/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O key/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O a/DT/O week/NN/O later/RB/O ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE raised/VBD/O its/PRP$/O official/JJ/O discount/NN/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O half/JJ/O point/NN/O to/TO/O 3.75/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O discount/NN/O rate/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O base/JJ/O rate/NN/O on/IN/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O commercial/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Tomoshige/NNP/B-PERSON Kakita/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O deputy/NN/O manager/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O treasury/NN/O department/NN/O of/IN/O Mitsui/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O suggested/VBD/O that/IN/O uncertainty/NN/O about/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE stocks/NNS/O and/CC/O bonds/NNS/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O Japanese/JJ/O investors/NNS/O leery/JJ/O of/IN/O holding/VBG/O those/DT/O securities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O near/JJ/O term/NN/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O damping/VBG/O dollar/NN/O demand/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O 135/CD/O is/VBZ/O broken/VBN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O panic/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O seen/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O predicted/VBD/O ,/,/O explaining/VBG/O that/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O are/VBP/O comfortable/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O anywhere/RB/O between/IN/O current/JJ/O levels/NNS/O and/CC/O 135/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O contended/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O ease/VB/O rates/NNS/O further/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O predicted/VBD/O Bundesbank/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O will/MD/O relax/VB/O key/JJ/O rates/NNS/O in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON Zapfel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O trader/NN/O at/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O took/VBD/O an/DT/O opposite/JJ/O stance/NN/O ././O
West/JJ/O German/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O unchanged/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O these/DT/O great/JJ/O dollar/NN/O bears/NNS/O you/PRP/O see/VBP/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Zapfel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O really/RB/O see/VB/O it/PRP/O dropping/VBG/O far/RB/O below/IN/O 1.80/CD/O marks/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O predicted/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O will/MD/O skid/VB/O below/IN/O 1.80/CD/O marks/NNS/O to/TO/O around/IN/O 1.78/CD/O marks/NNS/O this/DT/O month/NN/O and/CC/O 1.75/CD/O marks/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O beginning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O finally/RB/O seeing/VBG/O the/DT/O culmination/NN/O of/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O recessionary/JJ/O buildup/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O noting/VBG/O a/DT/O continuing/VBG/O downward/JJ/O trend/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O shaky/JJ/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O and/CC/O ``/``/O gloomier/JJR/O economic/JJ/O times/NNS/O ahead/RB/O ''/''/O all/DT/O signal/VBP/O a/DT/O significantly/RB/O lower/JJR/O dollar/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Owen/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Kleinwort/NNP/B-ORG Benson/NNP/I-ORG suggested/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O chancellor/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Major/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O will/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O line/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O autumn/NN/O statement/NN/O later/RB/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O helping/VBG/O to/TO/O underpin/VB/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O warned/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O at/IN/O risk/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Commodity/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O gold/NN/O for/IN/O current/JJ/O delivery/NN/O dropped/VBD/O $/$/O 3.10/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 374.70/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O in/IN/O moderate/JJ/O trading/NN/O ././O
Estimated/JJ/O volume/NN/O was/VBD/O 3.5/CD/O million/CD/O ounces/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O early/RB/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Wednesday/NNP/O ,/,/O gold/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 373.80/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ././O
Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Hill/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Hastings/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Erik/NNP/B-PERSON Kirschbaum/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Caitlin/NNP/B-PERSON Randall/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Appell/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
