Shop/NNP/B-ORG Television/NNP/I-ORG Network/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O Penney/NNP/B-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O its/PRP$/O exclusive/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O with/IN/O Shop/NNP/B-ORG Television/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O does/VBZ/O the/DT/O production/NN/O ,/,/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O cable/NN/O distribution/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG J.C./NNP/I-ORG Penney/NNP/I-ORG Television/NNP/I-ORG Shopping/NNP/I-ORG Channel/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O channel/NN/O reaches/VBZ/O 6.5/CD/O million/CD/O homes/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Penney/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Rosen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Shop/NNP/B-ORG Television/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O Penney/NN/B-ORG decided/VBD/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O its/PRP$/O involvement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O service/NN/O for/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O charge/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/NN/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ended/VBN/O April/NNP/O 29/CD/O ,/,/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O discontinuing/VBG/O the/DT/O service/NN/O ././O
