Lyphomed/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Rosemont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ill./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Medco/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Food/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG granted/VBD/O full/JJ/O marketing/NN/O approval/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O drug/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O condition/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O beats/VBZ/O between/IN/O 150/CD/O and/CC/O 200/CD/O beats/NNS/O a/DT/O minute/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O condition/NN/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O paroxysmal/JJ/O supraventricular/JJ/O tachycardia/NN/O ,/,/O leads/VBZ/O to/TO/O dizziness/NN/O and/CC/O fainting/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O typical/JJ/O healthy/JJ/O heart/NN/O beats/VBZ/O 70/CD/O times/NNS/O a/DT/O minute/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O drug/NN/O ,/,/O called/VBN/O adenocard/NN/O ,/,/O returns/VBZ/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O normal/JJ/O rhythm/NN/O within/IN/O seconds/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Lyphomed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Medco/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG developed/VBD/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O and/CC/O licensed/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O Lyphomed/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O sale/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ././O
