A/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE official/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O sent/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Investigation/NNP/I-ORG a/DT/O packet/NN/O of/IN/O documents/NNS/O relating/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O previously/RB/O reported/VBN/O $/$/O 400,000/CD/O contribution/NN/O from/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O solicited/VBN/O by/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Cranston/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Federal/JJ/O examiner/NN/O Alex/NNP/B-PERSON Barabolak/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O operations/NNS/O amounted/VBD/O to/TO/O ``/``/O pyramiding/VBG/O debt/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O a/DT/O luxurious/JJ/O life/NN/O style/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O owners/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O collapse/NN/O may/MD/O cost/VB/O taxpayers/NNS/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O estimates/NNS/O ,/,/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O expensive/JJ/O thrift/NN/O failure/NN/O in/IN/O history/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O there/EX/O 's/POS/O overwhelming/JJ/O evidence/NN/O to/TO/O indicate/VB/O probable/JJ/O criminal/JJ/O activity/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Meek/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O participated/VBD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O examination/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Irvine/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O thrift/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O evidence/NN/O pointed/VBD/O to/TO/O wrongdoing/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O allege/VB/O any/DT/O specific/JJ/O violation/NN/O ././O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Newsom/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O official/NN/O who/WP/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O examined/VBD/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O also/RB/O saw/VBD/O evidence/NN/O that/IN/O crimes/NNS/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O committed/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O sure/RB/O smells/VBZ/O like/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O loans/NNS/O he/PRP/O sampled/VBN/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O dead/JJ/O meat/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O made/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O Later/RB/O on/RB/O ,/,/O my/PRP$/O concerns/NNS/O about/IN/O a/DT/O whitewash/NN/O became/VBD/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O serious/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O sour/JJ/O loans/NNS/O ``/``/O appalling/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O opened/VBD/O the/DT/O file/NN/O up/RP/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O just/RB/O jumped/VBD/O at/IN/O you/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Leonard/NNP/B-PERSON Bickwit/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O for/IN/O Lincoln/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O corporation/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O deny/VBP/O any/DT/O criminal/JJ/O behavior/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O association/NN/O or/CC/O its/PRP$/O officers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O Those/DT/O who/WP/O testified/VBD/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O yesterday/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O have/VB/O consistently/RB/O maintained/VBN/O that/IN/O anyone/NN/O who/WP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O agree/VB/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O coverup/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O whitewash/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O excessive/JJ/O influence/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Bickwit/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O simply/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O agree/VB/O with/IN/O that/DT/O or/CC/O the/DT/O findings/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O investigation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O deputies/NNS/O complained/VBD/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O given/VBN/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O respond/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O criticism/NN/O brought/VBD/O out/RP/O during/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG hearings/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O Committee/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Gonzalez/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O has/VBZ/O used/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O forum/NN/O to/TO/O flay/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O affair/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O demand/VB/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O step/VB/O aside/RB/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O job/NN/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O things/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Newsom/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O were/VBD/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O misleading/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Kevin/NNP/B-PERSON O'Connell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE regulators/VBZ/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O eventually/RB/O declared/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O loans/NNS/O the/DT/O state/NN/O regulator/NN/O cited/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O loss/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O forced/VBD/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O make/VB/O an/DT/O $/$/O 18/CD/O million/CD/O downward/JJ/O adjustment/NN/O on/IN/O another/DT/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O response/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O whitewash/NN/O would/MD/O simply/RB/O be/VB/O ,/,/O look/VB/O what/WP/O happened/VBD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O another/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE official/NN/O ,/,/O Alvin/NNP/B-PERSON Smuzynski/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O later/RB/O brought/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O billion/CD/O fraud/NN/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O complained/VBN/O that/IN/O regulators/NNS/O waited/VBD/O far/RB/O too/RB/O long/RB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O ignoring/VBG/O a/DT/O recommendation/NN/O from/IN/O regional/JJ/O officials/NNS/O to/TO/O place/VB/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG into/IN/O receivership/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O failed/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O took/VBD/O the/DT/O reckless/JJ/O course/NN/O of/IN/O ignoring/VBG/O the/DT/O evidence/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
State/NN/O thrift/NN/O examiner/NN/O Eugene/NNP/B-PERSON Stelzer/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O found/VBD/O the/DT/O chief/JJ/O federal/JJ/O examiner/NN/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON Scott/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O be/VB/O totally/RB/O uninterested/JJ/O in/IN/O one/CD/O allegedly/RB/O fraudulent/JJ/O series/NN/O of/IN/O transactions/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Riley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O examiner/NN/O who/WP/O worked/VBD/O under/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Scott/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O found/VBD/O his/PRP$/O chief/NN/O oddly/RB/O upbeat/JJ/O about/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Asked/VBN/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Scott/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O Mr./NNP/O Scott/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O spoken/VBN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O advised/VBN/O him/PRP/O not/RB/O to/TO/O talk/VB/O to/TO/O anybody/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Meek/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O day/NN/O or/CC/O two/CD/O before/IN/O Lincoln/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O entered/VBD/O bankruptcy/NN/O proceedings/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O examiners/NNS/O saw/VBD/O ``/``/O a/DT/O truck/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O sign/NN/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O that/WDT/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG `/``/I-ORG Document/NNP/I-ORG Destruction/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG ././O '/''/O
We/PRP/O observed/VBD/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O two/CD/O large/JJ/O plastic/NN/O bags/NNS/O of/IN/O shredded/JJ/O paper/NN/O loaded/VBN/O into/IN/O this/DT/O truck/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Bickwit/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O paper/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O donated/VBN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O a/DT/O charitable/JJ/O organization/NN/O that/WDT/O sells/VBZ/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O recycling/VBG/O ././O
They/PRP/O shredded/VBD/O it/PRP/O simply/RB/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O contained/VBD/O financial/JJ/O information/NN/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O creditors/NNS/O and/CC/O depositors/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
