The/DT/O two/CD/O units/NNS/O are/VBP/O Prentice/NNP/B-ORG Hall/NNP/I-ORG Information/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O publishes/VBZ/O tax/NN/O ,/,/O financial/JJ/O planning/NN/O and/CC/O business/NN/O law/NN/O information/NN/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Prentice/NNP/B-ORG Hall/NNP/I-ORG Information/NNP/I-ORG Network/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O electronically/RB/O delivers/VBZ/O tax/NN/O information/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O units/NNS/O were/VBD/O sold/VBN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Rosenfeld/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O previously/RB/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Prentice/NNP/B-ORG Hall/NNP/I-ORG Tax/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Professional/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG division/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O newly/RB/O formed/VBN/O Macmillan/NNP/B-ORG Professional/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Reference/NNP/I-ORG division/NN/O ././O
