Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG Cos./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O launching/VBG/O a/DT/O massive/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O advertising/NN/O campaign/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O put/VB/O the/DT/O tobacco/NN/O giant/NN/O 's/POS/O name/NN/O in/IN/O TV/NN/O commercials/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1950s/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O stopped/VBD/O advertising/VBG/O its/PRP$/O namesake/NN/O cigarette/NN/O brand/NN/O on/IN/O television/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O patriotic/JJ/O celebration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 200th/JJ/O anniversary/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O cigarettes/NNS/O or/CC/O smoking/NN/O ;/:/O cigarette/NN/O ads/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O prohibited/VBN/O on/IN/O television/NN/O since/IN/O 1971/CD/O ././O
Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O became/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O food/NN/O company/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O $/$/O 12.9/CD/O billion/CD/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Kraft/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O seems/VBZ/O determined/JJ/O to/TO/O evolve/VB/O beyond/IN/O its/PRP$/O roots/NNS/O in/IN/O Marlboro/NNP/B-ORG country/NN/O ././O
Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG hopes/VBZ/O that/IN/O by/IN/O taking/VBG/O its/PRP$/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O theme/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O airwaves/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O publications/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O reach/VB/O the/DT/O broadest/JJS/O possible/JJ/O audience/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O commercial/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O trumpets/VBZ/O the/DT/O themes/NNS/O of/IN/O liberty/NN/O and/CC/O freedom/NN/O of/IN/O expression/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O special/JJ/O appeal/NN/O for/IN/O smokers/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Pertschuk/NNP/B-PERSON adds/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O commercial/JJ/O dovetails/VBZ/O perfectly/RB/O with/IN/O major/JJ/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG political/JJ/O strategy/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O include/VB/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O its/PRP$/O print/NN/O advertising/NN/O by/IN/O invoking/VBG/O the/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O wooing/VBG/O blacks/NNS/O by/IN/O portraying/VBG/O itself/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O protector/NN/O of/IN/O civil/JJ/O rights/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O marketers/NNS/O say/VBP/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG approach/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O effective/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O agree/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ads/NNS/O '/POS/O implied/VBN/O smoking/NN/O message/NN/O is/VBZ/O unmistakable/JJ/O ././O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Winger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O partner/NN/O at/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-ORG Consulting/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O adds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O popular/JJ/O to/TO/O drape/VB/O yourself/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O flag/NN/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ././O
RJR/NNP/B-ORG Nabisco/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG say/VBP/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG lead/NN/O ././O
