Unocal/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O Petroleos/NNP/B-ORG de/FW/I-ORG Venezuela/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O create/VB/O a/DT/O petroleum/NN/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O refining/NN/O general/JJ/O partnership/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Midwest/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Unocal/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O would/MD/O enable/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O recover/VB/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O refining/NN/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O investment/NN/O and/CC/O prepare/VB/O for/IN/O expected/JJ/O growth/NN/O in/IN/O exploration/NN/O ,/,/O production/NN/O ,/,/O chemicals/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O areas/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O financing/NN/O would/MD/O consist/VB/O of/IN/O $/$/O 250/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O placement/NN/O obtained/VBN/O through/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O a/DT/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O revolving/JJ/O credit/NN/O line/NN/O underwritten/VBN/O by/IN/O Chase/NNP/B-ORG Manhattan/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O ,/,/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O facilities/NNS/O Dec./NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O would/MD/O also/RB/O serve/VB/O another/DT/O 3,300/CD/O independent/JJ/O Unocal/NNP/B-ORG gasoline/NN/O stations/NNS/O ././O
Petroleos/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O supply/VB/O 135,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O a/DT/O day/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O refinery/NN/O ,/,/O Unocal/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
