``/``/O We/PRP/O 'll/MD/O raise/VB/O it/PRP/O through/IN/O bank/NN/O loans/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O 'll/MD/O raise/VB/O it/PRP/O through/IN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O new/JJ/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O equity/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O loan/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O arranged/VBN/O by/IN/O February/NNP/O ,/,/O will/MD/O supply/VB/O about/RB/O half/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O financing/NN/O ././O
British/NNP/B-ORG Satellite/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O already/RB/O has/VBZ/O raised/VBN/O #/#/O 423.5/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O 10/CD/O backers/NNS/O ,/,/O initially/RB/O expected/VBD/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O #/#/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Besides/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O British/NNP/B-ORG Satellite/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG other/JJ/O backers/NNS/O include/VBP/O Pearson/NNP/B-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Reed/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Granada/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O consortium/NN/O faced/VBD/O a/DT/O setback/NN/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O when/WRB/O technical/JJ/O problems/NNS/O forced/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O postpone/VB/O the/DT/O September/NNP/O launch/NN/O until/IN/O next/JJ/O spring/NN/O ././O
Continued/JJ/O uncertainty/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O timing/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O consortium/NN/O 's/POS/O debut/NN/O could/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O a/DT/O #/#/O 450/CD/O million/CD/O cash/NN/O injection/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bankers/NNS/O also/RB/O insist/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O loans/NNS/O depend/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O consortium/NN/O raising/VBG/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O from/IN/O new/JJ/O and/CC/O existing/VBG/O backers/NNS/O ././O
British/NNP/B-ORG Satellite/NNP/I-ORG today/NN/O is/VBZ/O unveiling/VBG/O a/DT/O #/#/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O advertising/NN/O and/CC/O promotional/JJ/O drive/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O consortium/NN/O 's/VBZ/O planned/JJ/O five/CD/O channels/NNS/O of/IN/O movies/NNS/O ,/,/O sports/NNS/O ,/,/O entertainment/NN/O and/CC/O news/NN/O shows/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O rivals/NNS/O currently/RB/O are/VBP/O locked/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O costly/JJ/O bidding/NN/O contest/NN/O for/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE film/NN/O rights/NNS/O ././O
