Paramount/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Associates/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG consumer/NN/O and/CC/O commercial/JJ/O finance/NN/O subsidiary/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 3.35/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Paramount/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O gain/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O recorded/VBN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O fourth/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O ended/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Paramount/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ``/``/O completes/VBZ/O the/DT/O strategic/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O ''/''/O it/PRP/O began/VBD/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O would/MD/O enable/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O entertainment/NN/O and/CC/O publishing/NN/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O it/PRP/O planned/VBD/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O Associates/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O entity/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ././O
