-LRB-/-LRB-/O During/IN/O its/PRP$/O centennial/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O report/VB/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O century/NN/O that/DT/O stand/NN/O as/IN/O milestones/NNS/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O business/NN/O history/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Bioengineers/NNS/O set/VBD/O out/RP/O to/TO/O duplicate/VB/O that/DT/O feat/NN/O --/:/O scientifically/RB/O and/CC/O commercially/RB/O --/:/O with/IN/O new/JJ/O life/NN/O forms/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O 1953/CD/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Watson/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O unlocked/VBD/O the/DT/O double/JJ/O helix/NN/O of/IN/O DNA/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O deoxyribonucleic/JJ/O acid/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O genetic/JJ/O key/NN/O to/TO/O heredity/NN/O ././O
Twenty/CD/O years/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O two/CD/O California/NNP/B-GPE academics/NNS/O ,/,/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON Cohen/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Herbert/NNP/B-PERSON Boyer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O made/VBD/O ``/``/O recombinant/JJ/O ''/''/O DNA/NN/O ,/,/O transplanting/VBG/O a/DT/O toad/NN/O 's/POS/O gene/NN/O into/IN/O bacteria/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O then/RB/O reproduced/VBD/O toad/NN/O genes/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O apiece/RB/O and/CC/O an/DT/O injection/NN/O of/IN/O outside/JJ/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O formed/VBD/O Genentech/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Genentech/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O first/JJ/O product/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O brain/NN/O protein/NN/O called/VBD/O somatostatin/NN/O ,/,/O proved/VBD/O its/PRP$/O technology/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O cloned/VBN/O ,/,/O human/JJ/O insulin/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O market/NN/O potential/NN/O and/CC/O Genentech/NNP/B-ORG licensed/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O Eli/NNP/B-ORG Lilly/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O produced/VBD/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O insulin/NN/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O 1.5/CD/O million/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE diabetics/NNS/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O laboratory/NN/O credentials/NNS/O established/VBN/O ,/,/O Boyer/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Swanson/NNP/B-PERSON headed/VBD/O for/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O in/IN/O 1980/CD/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Genentech/NN/B-ORG had/VBD/O only/RB/O one/CD/O profitable/JJ/O year/NN/O behind/IN/O it/PRP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O $/$/O 116,000/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.6/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1979/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O no/DT/O product/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Nonetheless/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O $/$/O 36/CD/O million/CD/O issue/NN/O they/PRP/O floated/VBD/O in/IN/O 1980/CD/O opened/VBD/O at/IN/O $/$/O 35/CD/O and/CC/O leaped/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 89/CD/O within/IN/O 20/CD/O minutes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O trip/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O test/NN/O tube/NN/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O without/IN/O snags/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O judgment/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O reversed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Boyer/NNP/B-PERSON holding/VBG/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O patents/NNS/O for/IN/O making/VBG/O recombinant/JJ/O DNA/NNP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O now/RB/O assigned/VBN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O schools/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Genentech/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O 1988/CD/O sales/NNS/O were/VBD/O $/$/O 335/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O both/CC/O from/IN/O licensing/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
