Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG Cos./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O launching/VBG/O a/DT/O massive/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O advertising/NN/O campaign/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O put/VB/O the/DT/O tobacco/NN/O giant/NN/O 's/POS/O name/NN/O in/IN/O TV/NN/O commercials/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1950s/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O stopped/VBD/O advertising/VBG/O its/PRP$/O namesake/NN/O cigarette/NN/O brand/NN/O on/IN/O television/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O patriotic/JJ/O celebration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 200th/JJ/O anniversary/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O cigarettes/NNS/O or/CC/O smoking/NN/O ;/:/O cigarette/NN/O ads/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O prohibited/VBN/O on/IN/O television/NN/O since/IN/O 1971/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O even/RB/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O begins/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O is/VBZ/O drawing/VBG/O fire/NN/O from/IN/O anti-smoking/JJ/O advocates/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O criticize/VB/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG attempt/NN/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O its/PRP$/O beleaguered/JJ/O image/NN/O by/IN/O wrapping/VBG/O itself/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O document/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O cornerstone/NN/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O democracy/NN/O ././O
Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O became/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O food/NN/O company/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O $/$/O 12.9/CD/O billion/CD/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Kraft/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O seems/VBZ/O determined/JJ/O to/TO/O evolve/VB/O beyond/IN/O its/PRP$/O roots/NNS/O in/IN/O Marlboro/NNP/B-ORG country/NN/O ././O
Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG hopes/VBZ/O that/IN/O by/IN/O taking/VBG/O its/PRP$/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O theme/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O airwaves/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O publications/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O reach/VB/O the/DT/O broadest/JJS/O possible/JJ/O audience/NN/O ././O
Until/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O corporate/JJ/O ads/NNS/O ,/,/O mainly/RB/O promoting/VBG/O its/PRP$/O sponsorship/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O arts/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VB/O appeared/VBN/O almost/RB/O exclusively/RB/O in/IN/O newspapers/NNS/O and/CC/O magazines/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Most/JJS/O people/NNS/O --/:/O whether/IN/O in/IN/O Toledo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tucson/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Topeka/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O got/VBN/O a/DT/O clue/NN/O who/WP/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Guy/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O corporate/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O they/PRP/O think/VBP/O well/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O through/IN/O our/PRP$/O support/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O follows/VBZ/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O think/VB/O well/RB/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O products/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O commercial/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O trumpets/VBZ/O the/DT/O themes/NNS/O of/IN/O liberty/NN/O and/CC/O freedom/NN/O of/IN/O expression/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O special/JJ/O appeal/NN/O for/IN/O smokers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O some/DT/O anti-smoking/JJ/O activists/NNS/O disagree/VBP/O ,/,/O expressing/VBG/O anger/NN/O at/IN/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O see/VBP/O as/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O innocence/NN/O by/IN/O association/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O treated/VBN/O like/IN/O the/DT/O Medellin/NNP/B-GPE -LCB-/-LRB-/O drug/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O mafia/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O the/DT/O Founding/VBG/O Fathers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Pertschuk/NNP/B-PERSON adds/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O commercial/JJ/O dovetails/VBZ/O perfectly/RB/O with/IN/O major/JJ/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG political/JJ/O strategy/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O include/VB/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O its/PRP$/O print/NN/O advertising/NN/O by/IN/O invoking/VBG/O the/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O wooing/VBG/O blacks/NNS/O by/IN/O portraying/VBG/O itself/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O protector/NN/O of/IN/O civil/JJ/O rights/NNS/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O The/DT/O commercial/NN/O features/NNS/O ,/,/O among/IN/O others/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O voice/NN/O of/IN/O Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Luther/NNP/I-PERSON King/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O slain/VBN/O civil/JJ/O rights/NNS/O leader/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Many/JJ/O marketers/NNS/O say/VBP/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG approach/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O effective/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O agree/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ads/NNS/O '/POS/O implied/VBN/O smoking/NN/O message/NN/O is/VBZ/O unmistakable/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O wagons/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O circle/NN/O and/CC/O defend/VB/O the/DT/O smoking/NN/O franchise/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Winger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O partner/NN/O at/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-ORG Consulting/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O adds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O popular/JJ/O to/TO/O drape/VB/O yourself/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O flag/NN/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O do/VB/O that/DT/O and/CC/O at/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O send/VB/O a/DT/O message/NN/O that/WDT/O supports/VBZ/O your/PRP$/O business/NN/O ,/,/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O brilliant/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
RJR/NNP/B-ORG Nabisco/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG say/VBP/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG lead/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG corporate/JJ/O campaign/NN/O runs/VBZ/O little/JJ/O risk/NN/O of/IN/O getting/VBG/O yanked/VBN/O off/IN/O the/DT/O tube/NN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O showing/VBG/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Madison/NNP/I-PERSON taking/VBG/O a/DT/O puff/NN/O or/CC/O lighting/VBG/O up/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Laurence/NNP/B-PERSON Tribe/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O professor/NN/O of/IN/O constitutional/JJ/O law/NN/O at/IN/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O All/DT/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O do/VB/O is/VBZ/O borrow/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O legitimacy/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bill/NNP/O of/IN/O Rights/NNPS/O itself/PRP/O ././O
