BUSH/NNP/B-PERSON AND/CC/O GORBACHEV/NNP/B-PERSON WILL/MD/O HOLD/VB/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O informal/JJ/O talks/NNS/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O simultaneous/JJ/O announcement/NN/O was/VBD/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ././O
East/JJ/O German/JJ/O leader/NN/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON arrived/VBD/O in/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O talks/NNS/O today/NN/O with/IN/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O restructuring/NN/O proposals/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG approved/VBD/O a/DT/O permanent/JJ/O smoking/NN/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O nearly/RB/O all/DT/O domestic/JJ/O airline/NN/O routes/NNS/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 27.1/CD/O billion/CD/O transportation/NN/O bill/NN/O that/WDT/O must/MD/O still/RB/O overcome/VB/O budget/NN/O obstacles/NNS/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O chamber/NN/O also/RB/O sent/VBD/O to/TO/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 67/CD/O billion/CD/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O measure/NN/O that/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O construction/NN/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O space/NN/O station/NN/O ././O
Chinese/JJ/O leader/NN/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O former/JJ/O President/NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O deeply/RB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O turmoil/NN/O and/CC/O counterrevolutionary/JJ/O rebellion/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O gripped/VBD/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O spring/NN/O ././O
Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O troops/NNS/O broke/VBD/O through/IN/O a/DT/O guerrilla/NN/O blockade/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O strategic/JJ/O Salang/NNP/B-FAC Highway/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O allowing/VBG/O trucks/NNS/O carrying/VBG/O food/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O necessities/NNS/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE after/IN/O a/DT/O missile/NN/O attack/NN/O on/IN/O rebel/NN/O strongholds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O convoy/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O 100/CD/O vehicles/NNS/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O deliveries/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O capital/NN/O in/IN/O about/RB/O 10/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
Turkey/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O legislature/NN/O elected/VBD/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Ozal/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O civilian/JJ/O president/NN/O since/IN/O 1960/CD/O ,/,/O opening/VBG/O the/DT/O way/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O change/NN/O of/IN/O government/NN/O under/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O premier/NN/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O select/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O vote/NN/O in/IN/O Ankara/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O boycotted/VBN/O by/IN/O opposition/NN/O politicians/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O vowed/VBD/O to/TO/O oust/VB/O Ozal/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O also/RB/O urged/VBD/O whites/NNS/O to/TO/O refrain/VB/O from/IN/O panic/NN/O over/IN/O growing/JJ/O black/JJ/O protests/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O massive/JJ/O anti-apartheid/JJ/O rally/NN/O Sunday/NNP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O outskirts/NNS/O of/IN/O Soweto/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Researchers/NNP/O in/IN/O Belgium/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O developed/VBN/O a/DT/O genetic/JJ/O engineering/NN/O technique/NN/O for/IN/O creating/VBG/O hybrid/JJ/O plants/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O crops/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O cotton/NN/O ,/,/O soybeans/NNS/O and/CC/O rice/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O bomb/NN/O exploded/VBD/O at/IN/O a/DT/O leftist/JJ/O union/NN/O hall/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Salvador/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O killing/VBG/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O eight/CD/O people/NNS/O and/CC/O injuring/VBG/O about/RB/O 30/CD/O others/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O two/CD/O Americans/NNPS/O ,/,/O authorities/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Hungary/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG voted/VBD/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O a/DT/O national/JJ/O referendum/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O election/NN/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O post/NN/O of/IN/O president/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O balloting/NN/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O when/WRB/O and/CC/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O the/DT/O position/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O replaces/VBZ/O a/DT/O collective/JJ/O presidency/NN/O under/IN/O a/DT/O pact/NN/O signed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O ruling/VBG/O Socialists/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/O opposition/NN/O groups/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O held/VBN/O Nov/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG denied/VBD/O asylum/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Vietnamese/JJ/O man/NN/O who/WP/O escaped/VBD/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O homeland/NN/O by/IN/O lashing/VBG/O himself/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O rudder/NN/O housing/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O tanker/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O in/IN/O monsoon/NN/O seas/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O Sen./NNP/O Pell/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Rhode/NNP/B-GPE Island/NNP/I-GPE said/VBD/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Immigration/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Naturalization/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O review/VB/O the/DT/O stowaway/NN/O 's/POS/O request/NN/O ././O
