Avery/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O a/DT/O group/NN/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O management/NN/O of/IN/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O 's/POS/O main/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O valued/VBD/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Avery/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O a/DT/O coal/NN/O company/NN/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O at/IN/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O proxy/JJ/O materials/NNS/O it/PRP/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O control/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Avery/NNP/B-ORG paid/VBD/O $/$/O 750/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O various/JJ/O legal/JJ/O and/CC/O financing/NN/O fees/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Middlebury/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O --/:/O a/DT/O move/NN/O that/WDT/O burdened/VBD/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O debt/NN/O ././O
An/DT/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O was/VBD/O magnified/VBN/O by/IN/O accounting/NN/O adjustments/NNS/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O loss/NN/O was/VBD/O smaller/JJR/O on/IN/O a/DT/O cash/NN/O basis/NN/O ././O
Uniroyal/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O 2,600/CD/O employees/NNS/O and/CC/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Brazil/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O executives/NNS/O had/VBD/O profited/VBN/O handsomely/RB/O by/IN/O building/VBG/O American/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Can/MD/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Triangle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O asset/NN/O ././O
