Clarcor/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O J.L./NNP/B-ORG Clark/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O group/NN/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Anderson/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 70.3/CD/O million/CD/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O terminated/VBN/O ././O
Clarcor/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O packaging/NN/O and/CC/O filtration/NN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O agree/VB/O on/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O sale/NN/O price/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O packaging/NN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O consist/VB/O of/IN/O cash/NN/O ,/,/O notes/NNS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O amount/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O determined/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O 's/POS/O future/JJ/O performance/NN/O ././O
Clarcor/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O inviting/VBG/O proposals/NNS/O from/IN/O other/JJ/O prospective/JJ/O purchasers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O Clarcor/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Anderson/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Rockford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ill/NNP/B-GPE ././O
