As/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 50/CD/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O employees/NNS/O at/IN/O Specialized/NNP/B-ORG Bicycle/NNP/I-ORG Components/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ride/VBP/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
When/WRB/O they/PRP/O return/VBP/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O desks/NNS/O at/IN/O 1/CD/O p.m./NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O pedaled/VBN/O 20/CD/O miles/NNS/O ././O
Such/JJ/O fervor/NN/O for/IN/O cycling/NN/O helped/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Sinyard/NNP/B-PERSON build/VB/O a/DT/O creative/JJ/O company/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O forefront/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O industry/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O have/VBP/O grown/VBN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 80/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 26/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
With/IN/O 65/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O sales/NNS/O coming/VBG/O from/IN/O mountain/NN/O bikes/NNS/O ,/,/O Specialized/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O widely/RB/O considered/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O market/NN/O leader/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O today/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O needs/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O entrepreneurial/JJ/O spirit/NN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O ever/RB/O ././O
Thus/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sinyard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O must/MD/O innovate/VB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O ever/RB/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O by/IN/O developing/VBG/O new/JJ/O products/NNS/O specifically/RB/O for/IN/O mountain/NN/O biking/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O must/MD/O become/VB/O more/RBR/O structured/JJ/O to/TO/O better/RBR/O manage/VB/O its/PRP$/O growth/NN/O ././O
Accomplishing/VBG/O both/DT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O balancing/NN/O act/NN/O as/RB/O challenging/JJ/O as/IN/O riding/VBG/O a/DT/O unicycle/NN/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O I/PRP/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O to/TO/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O another/DT/O word/NN/O :/:/O process/NN/O ././O
That/IN/O 's/POS/O my/PRP$/O challenge/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O Mike/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O challenge/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O We/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Sinyard/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O were/VBD/O soaring/VBG/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O still/RB/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O system/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O probably/RB/O appropriate/JJ/O for/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O sales/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Adds/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Eidsmo/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O What/WP/O felt/VBD/O good/JJ/O that/IN/O day/NN/O was/VBD/O done/VBN/O that/DT/O day/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O But/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O risky/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O of/IN/O Specialized/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O adopt/VB/O a/DT/O corporate/JJ/O structure/NN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O lose/VB/O the/DT/O magic/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O creative/JJ/O drive/NN/O ././O
Hoping/VBG/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pack/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O emphasizing/VBG/O innovation/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O replacing/VBG/O the/DT/O frame/NN/O 's/POS/O steel/NN/O lugs/NNS/O with/IN/O titanium/NN/O ones/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sinyard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O its/PRP$/O next/JJ/O generation/NN/O of/IN/O frames/NNS/O even/RB/O lighter/JJR/O ././O
It/PRP/O currently/RB/O costs/VBZ/O $/$/O 750/CD/O ,/,/O though/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sinyard/NNP/B-PERSON thinks/VBZ/O the/DT/O price/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O reduced/VBN/O within/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O between/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 250/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O slash/VB/O the/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O least/RBS/O expensive/JJ/O mountain/NN/O bike/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 279/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 750/CD/O in/IN/O
But/CC/O demands/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O creativity/NN/O are/VBP/O certain/JJ/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-ORG Cycling/NNP/I-ORG Federation/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O Philip/NNP/B-PERSON Milburn/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O mountain/NN/O biking/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O growing/VBG/O at/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O monstrous/JJ/O rate/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O getting/VBG/O into/IN/O this/DT/O ././O ''/''/O
Accessories/NNS/O not/RB/O only/RB/O sell/VBP/O faster/RBR/O than/IN/O whole/JJ/O bikes/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O also/RB/O offer/VBP/O profit/NN/O margins/NNS/O nearly/RB/O double/RB/O the/DT/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O or/CC/O so/RB/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O complete/JJ/O cycles/NNS/O ././O
Competition/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O complete/JJ/O bikes/NNS/O is/VBZ/O heating/VBG/O up/RP/O too/RB/O ././O
Trek/NNP/B-ORG previously/RB/O made/VBD/O only/JJ/O traditional/JJ/O road/NN/O bikes/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O take/VB/O a/DT/O rocket/NN/O scientist/NN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O a/DT/O road/NN/O bike/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O mountain/NN/O bike/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Trek/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O president/NN/O ,/,/O Dick/NNP/B-PERSON Burke/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Schwinn/NNP/B-ORG Bicycle/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O established/VBD/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O with/IN/O bike/NN/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O mainland/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O sell/VB/O bikes/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Derby/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Luxembourg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O acquired/VBN/O such/JJ/O major/JJ/O brands/NNS/O as/IN/O Peugeot/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Raleigh/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Nishiki/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O internationalization/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O business/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sinyard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O replacing/VBG/O independent/JJ/O distributors/NNS/O overseas/RB/O with/IN/O wholly/RB/O owned/VBN/O subsidiaries/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O will/MD/O cut/VB/O out/RP/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O middleman/NN/O and/CC/O give/VB/O Specialized/NNP/B-ORG more/JJR/O control/NN/O over/IN/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O sales/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O as/IN/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Austin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Giant/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O president/NN/O ,/,/O puts/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ``/``/O With/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bigger/JJR/O players/NNS/O consolidating/VBG/O their/PRP$/O strength/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O game/NN/O has/VBZ/O changed/VBN/O ././O
