Democrats/NNPS/O want/VBP/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O provision/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O usual/JJ/O procedural/JJ/O obstacles/NNS/O ././O
Republicans/NNPS/O ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O by/IN/O combining/VBG/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O two/CD/O politically/RB/O popular/JJ/O issues/NNS/O that/IN/O Democrats/NNPS/O could/MD/O find/VB/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O block/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O talks/NNS/O between/IN/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Majority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Mitchell/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Maine/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O his/PRP$/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG counterpart/NN/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Dole/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O confident/JJ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O sufficient/JJ/O votes/NNS/O to/TO/O block/VB/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O measure/NN/O with/IN/O procedural/JJ/O actions/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O that/DT/O could/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O vulnerable/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O veto/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Democrats/NNP/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O a/DT/O presidential/JJ/O rejection/NN/O would/MD/O give/VB/O their/PRP$/O party/NN/O a/DT/O valuable/JJ/O issue/NN/O in/IN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O congressional/JJ/O elections/NNS/O ././O
Senate/NNP/B-ORG Democrats/NNPS/O are/VBP/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O today/NN/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O the/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG proposal/NN/O ././O
Pushing/VBG/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O on/IN/O legislation/NN/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O default/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O very/RB/O good/JJ/O strategy/NN/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
At/IN/O 12:01/CD/O a.m./NN/O EST/RB/O today/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O temporary/JJ/O $/$/O 2.87/CD/O trillion/CD/O debt/NN/O limit/NN/O expired/VBD/O ././O
To/TO/O avoid/VB/O default/NN/O ,/,/O lawmakers/NNS/O must/MD/O pass/VB/O legislation/NN/O raising/VBG/O the/DT/O limit/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.12/CD/O trillion/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 2.80/CD/O trillion/CD/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O Wednesday/NNP/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG ././O
