Sanwa/NNP/B-ORG Shutter/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O affiliated/JJ/O company/NN/O in/IN/O Malaysia/NN/B-GPE ,/,/O established/VBN/O this/DT/O April/NNP/O ,/,/O will/MD/O begin/VB/O manufacturing/VBG/O steel/NN/O doors/NNS/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O partner/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O is/VBZ/O Sin/NNP/B-ORG Kean/NNP/I-ORG Boon/NNP/I-ORG Metal/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Penang/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O concern/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O partner/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O was/VBD/O created/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O growing/VBG/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O steel/NN/O doors/NNS/O ,/,/O concurrent/JJ/O with/IN/O increasing/VBG/O local/JJ/O concern/NN/O about/IN/O fire/NN/O prevention/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
