Bureaucrats/NNS/O may/MD/O deserve/VB/O their/PRP$/O bad/JJ/O reputation/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
He/PRP/O sent/VBD/O out/RP/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O news/NN/O releases/NNS/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O Kensington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Md./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O office/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lesko/NNP/B-PERSON figured/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O flooded/VBN/O with/IN/O entries/NNS/O by/IN/O now/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lesko/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O goes/VBZ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O determined/VBN/O that/IN/O bureaucrats/NNS/O are/VBP/O eligible/JJ/O for/IN/O nomination/NN/O by/IN/O other/JJ/O bureaucrats/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O admits/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O had/VBN/O much/JJ/O luck/NN/O generating/VBG/O free/JJ/O publicity/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O contest/NN/O ././O
Newspapers/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O this/DT/O one/CD/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O generally/RB/O ignored/VBN/O his/PRP$/O news/NN/O releases/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lesko/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O prepared/JJ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O that/DT/O explanation/NN/O ././O
