MCI/NNP/B-ORG COMMUNICATIONS/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O filed/VBD/O a/DT/O shelf/NN/O registration/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O issuance/NN/O of/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 750/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O debt/NN/O securities/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O funds/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O for/IN/O refinancing/VBG/O existing/VBG/O debt/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O concern/NN/O at/IN/O lower/JJR/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O and/CC/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O general/JJ/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O effective/JJ/O date/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O registration/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O determined/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
