Putnam/NNP/B-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Grade/NNP/I-ORG Municipal/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O listed/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O symbol/NN/O PGM/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Hibernia/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Orleans/NNP/I-GPE bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O join/VB/O the/DT/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG Thursday/NNP/O under/IN/O HIB/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Three/CD/O companies/NNS/O began/VBD/O trading/VBG/O over/IN/O the/DT/O counter/NN/O ././O
Rally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Inc./NN/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ky./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O restaurant/NN/O franchisor/NN/O ,/,/O started/VBD/O trading/VBG/O under/IN/O RLLY/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Sierra/NNP/B-ORG Tucson/NNP/I-ORG Cos./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Tucson/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O started/VBD/O trading/VBG/O under/IN/O STSN/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Aldus/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Seattle/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O makes/VBZ/O computer/NN/O software/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
Options/NNS/O give/VBP/O a/DT/O holder/NN/O the/DT/O right/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O the/DT/O obligation/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O or/CC/O sell/VB/O a/DT/O security/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O set/VBN/O price/NN/O within/IN/O a/DT/O set/VBN/O period/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O ././O
