The/DT/O air/NN/O force/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O take/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 250/CD/O more/JJR/O ././O
Officially/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O statement/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O an/DT/O attack/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Rafale/NNP/O ././O
Adm./NNP/O Goupil/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O comments/NNS/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O inflame/VB/O the/DT/O broader/JJR/O dispute/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O establishment/NN/O here/RB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O role/NN/O of/IN/O Dassault/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Rafale/NNP/O project/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O inability/NN/O jointly/RB/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O a/DT/O plane/NN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O French/JJ/O officials/NNS/O question/VBP/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O can/MD/O continue/VB/O paying/VBG/O for/IN/O expensive/JJ/O independent/JJ/O programs/NNS/O ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dassault/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O resisted/VBN/O pressure/NN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O ././O
What/WP/O brought/VBD/O the/DT/O naval/JJ/O issue/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O head/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Crusaders/NNPS/O are/VBP/O literally/RB/O falling/VBG/O apart/RB/O ,/,/O without/IN/O any/DT/O immediate/JJ/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
Adm./NNP/O Goupil/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Crusader/NNP/O squadron/NN/O leader/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O other/JJ/O country/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O Crusaders/NNPS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE ,/,/O retired/VBD/O its/PRP$/O last/JJ/O ones/NNS/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O French/JJ/O Crusader/NNP/O crash/NN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O heightened/VBD/O pressure/NN/O for/IN/O new/JJ/O planes/NNS/O here/RB/O ././O
Adm./NNP/O Goupil/NNP/B-PERSON rejected/VBD/O Dassault/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O to/TO/O renovate/VB/O the/DT/O Crusaders/NNPS/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O was/VBD/O impossible/JJ/O to/TO/O estimate/VB/O ././O
Even/RB/O modernized/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Crusaders/NNPS/O represent/VBP/O an/DT/O obsolete/JJ/O and/CC/O dangerous/JJ/O protection/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O aircraft/NN/O carriers/NNS/O France/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O sent/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O such/JJ/O crises/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O wars/NNS/O in/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-LOC Persian/NNP/I-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC ././O
