A/DT/O bill/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O permit/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O monitor/VB/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O of/IN/O securities/NNS/O firms/NNS/O '/POS/O holding/VBG/O companies/NNS/O is/VBZ/O facing/VBG/O tough/JJ/O opposition/NN/O from/IN/O some/DT/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O firms/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O is/VBZ/O unnecessary/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O legislation/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O issues/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O focus/NN/O of/IN/O hearings/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Telecommunications/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Subcommittee/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Subcommittee/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Breeden/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O formal/JJ/O position/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O also/RB/O require/VB/O investors/NNS/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O large/JJ/O trades/NNS/O and/CC/O give/VB/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG additional/JJ/O authority/NN/O during/IN/O market/NN/O emergencies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bridge/JJ/O loans/NNS/O are/VBP/O intended/JJ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O temporary/JJ/O financing/NN/O for/IN/O acquisitions/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O some/DT/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O executives/NNS/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O such/JJ/O fears/NNS/O are/VBP/O unwarranted/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O July/NNP/O 6/CD/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Subcommittee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O no/DT/O retail/JJ/O brokerage/NN/O firm/NN/O failed/VBN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O market/NN/O crash/NN/O demonstrates/VBZ/O that/IN/O current/JJ/O rules/NNS/O are/VBP/O adequate/JJ/O ././O
First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O CS/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O larger/JJR/O issuers/NNS/O of/IN/O bridge/JJ/O loans/NNS/O on/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O concerned/JJ/O that/IN/O once/IN/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O the/DT/O power/NN/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O holding/VBG/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O try/VB/O to/TO/O regulate/VB/O their/PRP$/O activities/NNS/O ././O
Sources/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O and/CC/O on/IN/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG Hill/NNP/I-ORG say/VBP/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O placate/VB/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O while/IN/O addressing/VBG/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O concerns/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O possible/JJ/O ././O
An/DT/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Subcommittee/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O some/DT/O legislators/NNS/O support/VBP/O the/DT/O concept/NN/O of/IN/O risk/NN/O disclosure/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O adds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O nobody/NN/O is/VBZ/O wedded/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O language/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O O'Brien/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O elaborate/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O SIA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O position/NN/O in/IN/O testimony/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Telecommunications/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Subcommittee/NNP/I-ORG this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
