First/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O somewhat/RB/O affected/JJ/O idealism/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1960s/NNS/O ././O
What/WP/O now/RB/O ?/./O
To/TO/O judge/VB/O from/IN/O novels/NNS/O that/WDT/O mirror/VBP/O the/DT/O contemporary/JJ/O scene/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O back/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O anxiety/NN/O ././O
Lisa/NNP/B-PERSON Zeidner/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON third/JJ/O novel/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Limited/JJ/O Partnerships/NNS/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O North/NNP/B-ORG Point/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O 256/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 18.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O stylish/JJ/O ,/,/O funny/JJ/O and/CC/O thoughtful/JJ/O look/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O love/NN/O relationships/NNS/O are/VBP/O affected/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O pressures/NNS/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O ,/,/O more/RBR/O specifically/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Nora/NNP/B-PERSON Worth/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON DeWitt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 33/CD/O and/CC/O 39/CD/O respectively/RB/O ,/,/O live/VBP/O together/RB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O townhouse/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O transitional/JJ/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE neighborhood/NN/O ././O
Nora/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O artistic/JJ/O aspirations/NNS/O ,/,/O knows/VBZ/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O lucky/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O working/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O food/NN/O stylist/NN/O ,/,/O prepping/VBG/O pies/NNS/O ,/,/O burgers/NNS/O ,/,/O frosty/JJ/O cold/JJ/O drinks/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O comestibles/NNS/O to/TO/O look/VB/O as/RB/O appetizing/JJ/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O in/IN/O front/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O camera/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O reasons/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O housewives/NNS/O with/IN/O Nikons/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/O degrees/NNS/O from/IN/O cooking/NN/O schools/NNS/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE who/WP/O would/MD/O kill/VB/O for/IN/O her/PRP$/O job/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Nora/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON feel/VBP/O trapped/JJ/O ././O
Uncertainty/NN/O dogs/VBZ/O every/DT/O aspect/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O lives/NNS/O ././O
Malcolm/NN/B-PERSON faces/VBZ/O bankruptcy/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG audit/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Nora/NNP/B-PERSON finds/VBZ/O an/DT/O extra/JJ/O $/$/O 30,000/CD/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O bank/NN/O account/NN/O ,/,/O suddenly/RB/O increasing/VBG/O her/PRP$/O available/JJ/O funds/NNS/O some/DT/O fifteenfold/RB/O ././O
While/IN/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O wondering/VBG/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O live/VB/O it/PRP/O up/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O do/VB/O something/NN/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O dramatic/JJ/O ,/,/O say/VB/O get/VB/O married/VBN/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O life/NN/O is/VBZ/O further/RBR/O complicated/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O reappearance/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O flame/NN/O ,/,/O David/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O film/NN/O critic/NN/O and/CC/O actor/NN/O who/WP/O always/RB/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O just/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O brink/NN/O of/IN/O stardom/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O characters/NNS/O confront/VBP/O a/DT/O world/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O increasingly/RB/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O middle/JJ/O way/NN/O ''/''/O between/IN/O the/DT/O extremes/NNS/O of/IN/O success/NN/O and/CC/O failure/NN/O ,/,/O wealth/NN/O and/CC/O poverty/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O making/VBG/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Nora/NNP/B-PERSON such/JJ/O wonderfully/RB/O representative/JJ/O specimens/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O class/NN/O and/CC/O generation/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Zeidner/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O somewhat/RB/O neglected/VBN/O the/DT/O task/NN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O them/PRP/O distinctively/RB/O individual/JJ/O characters/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O readers/NNS/O may/MD/O well/RB/O feel/VB/O the/DT/O pangs/NNS/O of/IN/O recognition/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O foundering/JJ/O middle/JJ/O classes/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O ones/NNS/O in/IN/O trouble/NN/O --/:/O or/CC/O whose/WP$/O troubles/NNS/O provide/VBP/O material/NN/O for/IN/O fiction/NN/O ././O
Patrician/NN/O ,/,/O dynamic/JJ/O Scott/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O founder/NN/O and/CC/O head/NN/O of/IN/O PegaSys/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O initially/RB/O finds/VBZ/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O threat/NN/O risible/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O skilled/JJ/O team/NN/O soon/RB/O discover/VBP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O up/IN/O against/IN/O two/CD/O factors/NNS/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O counted/VBN/O on/IN/O :/:/O first/LS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O business/NN/O climate/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O a/DT/O failing/VBG/O company/NN/O with/IN/O few/JJ/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O debts/NNS/O can/MD/O borrow/VB/O against/IN/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O successful/JJ/O company/NN/O it/PRP/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O ;/:/O second/LS/O ,/,/O that/IN/O standing/VBG/O behind/IN/O AIW/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O sinister/JJ/O consortium/NN/O of/IN/O much/RB/O bigger/JJR/O ,/,/O shadier/JJR/O and/CC/O shrewder/JJR/O foreign/JJ/O interests/NNS/O secretly/RB/O providing/VBG/O the/DT/O money/NN/O and/CC/O muscle/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O like/IN/O a/DT/O spy/NN/O or/CC/O mystery/NN/O story/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O novel/NN/O has/VBZ/O strong/JJ/O elements/NNS/O of/IN/O allegory/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O good/JJ/O and/CC/O evil/JJ/O forces/NNS/O battle/VBP/O it/PRP/O out/RP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Garber/NNP/B-PERSON depicts/VBZ/O these/DT/O moral/JJ/O qualities/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O broad/JJ/O brush/NN/O strokes/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O satire/NN/O that/WDT/O occasionally/RB/O descends/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O realm/NN/O of/IN/O cliched/JJ/O caricatures/NNS/O ././O
