The/DT/O holding/NN/O of/IN/O 13.6/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O is/VBZ/O up/RB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O 6.7/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O that/DT/O Burmah/NNP/B-ORG announced/VBD/O SHV/NNP/B-ORG held/VBD/O as/IN/O of/IN/O last/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
SHV/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O merged/VBD/O its/PRP$/O North/NNP/B-LOC Sea/NNP/I-LOC oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O operations/NNS/O with/IN/O those/DT/O of/IN/O Calor/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Calor/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O identified/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O suitor/NN/O for/IN/O Burmah/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Burmah/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O held/VBN/O any/DT/O discussions/NNS/O with/IN/O SHV/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O that/IN/O ``/``/O no/DT/O deal/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O nature/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O contemplation/NN/O ././O
