The/DT/O first/JJ/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O trouble/NN/O came/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE carrier/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Swire/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O posted/VBD/O a/DT/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O and/CC/O warned/VBD/O that/IN/O margins/NNS/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O under/IN/O pressure/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Securities/NNS/O analysts/NNS/O ,/,/O many/DT/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O scrapped/VBD/O their/PRP$/O buy/JJ/O recommendations/NNS/O after/IN/O seeing/VBG/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O interim/JJ/O figures/NNS/O ,/,/O believe/VBP/O more/JJR/O jolts/NNS/O lie/VBP/O ahead/RB/O ././O
Fuel/NN/O and/CC/O personnel/NN/O costs/NNS/O are/VBP/O rising/VBG/O ,/,/O and/CC/O tourism/NN/O in/IN/O and/CC/O through/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE remains/VBZ/O clouded/JJ/O by/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O turmoil/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O killings/NNS/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ././O
These/DT/O factors/NNS/O are/VBP/O further/RBR/O complicated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O 's/POS/O push/NN/O to/TO/O transform/VB/O itself/PRP/O from/IN/O a/DT/O regional/JJ/O carrier/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O one/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Hall/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Hall/NNP/B-PERSON expects/VBZ/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O profit/NN/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O around/IN/O 13/CD/O %/NN/O annually/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O next/JJ/O ././O
Cathay/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O several/JJ/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O business/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O step/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O beef/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O fleet/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O expansion/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O could/MD/O cost/VB/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O US$/$/O 5.7/CD/O billion/CD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O eight/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O expand/VB/O the/DT/O fleet/NN/O to/TO/O about/IN/O 43/CD/O planes/NNS/O by/IN/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 30/CD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Sun/NNP/B-ORG Hung/NNP/I-ORG Kai/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Some/DT/O jobs/NNS/O already/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O moved/VBN/O to/TO/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O place/VB/O others/NNS/O in/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Bell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O partly/RB/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O retaining/VBG/O existing/VBG/O staff/NN/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O leaving/VBG/O to/TO/O secure/VB/O foreign/JJ/O passports/NNS/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O 1997/CD/O ././O
Cathay/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE as/IN/O a/DT/O destination/NN/O worth/JJ/O visiting/VBG/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O merits/NNS/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O just/RB/O a/DT/O stopover/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Eddington/NNP/B-PERSON regards/VBZ/O promoting/VBG/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE as/IN/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O attracting/VBG/O visitors/NNS/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O travel/VB/O abroad/RB/O has/VBZ/O surged/VBN/O ././O
Cathay/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O decline/VBP/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O speculation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Eddington/NNP/B-PERSON sees/VBZ/O alliances/NNS/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O carriers/NNS/O --/:/O particularly/RB/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O link/NN/O with/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG --/:/O as/IN/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strategy/NN/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O believe/VBP/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O approached/VBN/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O swaps/NNS/O by/IN/O other/JJ/O carriers/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O regular/JJ/O basis/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O popularity/NN/O of/IN/O share/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O has/VBZ/O grown/VBN/O among/IN/O European/JJ/O carriers/NNS/O ././O
Asian/JJ/O traffic/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O currently/RB/O accounts/VBZ/O for/IN/O 65/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O business/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O 's/POS/O mainstay/NN/O ././O
Further/JJ/O expansion/NN/O into/IN/O southern/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC is/VBZ/O also/RB/O possible/JJ/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Bell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O special/JJ/O section/NN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O aviation/NN/O rights/NNS/O states/VBZ/O that/IN/O landing/VBG/O rights/NNS/O for/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE airlines/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O include/VBP/O the/DT/O smaller/JJR/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Dragon/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O negotiated/VBN/O by/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE government/NN/O ././O
