Chairman/NNP/O Jamie/NNP/B-PERSON Whitten/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Miss/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Appropriations/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG proposed/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 2.85/CD/O billion/CD/O emergency/NN/O funding/NN/O package/NN/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O recovery/NN/O from/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O earthquake/NN/O and/CC/O extend/VB/O further/JJR/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O East/JJ/B-LOC Coast/JJ/I-LOC victims/NNS/O of/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O up/RP/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Appropriations/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG today/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O panel/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O add/VB/O provisions/NNS/O waiving/VBG/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O highway/NN/O funds/NNS/O and/CC/O may/MD/O also/RB/O shift/VB/O money/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O package/NN/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O the/DT/O share/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Small/NNP/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O will/MD/O support/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O will/MD/O thank/VB/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O will/MD/O augment/VB/O it/PRP/O where/WRB/O appropriate/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Vic/NNP/B-PERSON Fazio/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Dubbed/VBN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O Dire/JJ/O Emergency/NN/O Supplemental/NN/O to/TO/O Meet/VB/O the/DT/O Needs/NNS/O of/IN/O Natural/JJ/O Disasters/NNS/O of/IN/O National/JJ/O Significance/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O is/VBZ/O vintage/JJ/O Whitten/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O asserting/VBG/O federal/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O and/CC/O in/IN/O disdaining/VBG/O budget/NN/O impediments/NNS/O ././O
