Comair/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O Cincinnati/NNP/B-GPE that/IN/O it/PRP/O bought/VBD/O Airline/NNP/B-ORG Aviation/NNP/I-ORG Academy/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O pilot/NN/O training/NN/O school/NN/O based/VBN/O at/IN/O Sanford/NNP/B-FAC Regional/NNP/I-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC near/IN/O Orlando/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Fla/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Comair/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O paid/VBD/O cash/NN/O but/CC/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O price/NN/O ././O
Comair/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O Comair/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O regional/JJ/O air/NN/O carrier/NN/O ././O
Airline/NNP/B-ORG Aviation/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 5/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 6/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O great/JJ/O growth/NN/O potential/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE pilots/NNS/O nearing/VBG/O retirement/NN/O age/NN/O ,/,/O Comair/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O unit/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O renamed/VBN/O Comair/NNP/B-ORG Aviation/NNP/I-ORG Academy/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Scott/NNP/B-PERSON Williams/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O son/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O founder/NN/O ,/,/O Comair/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
