Although/IN/O major/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE manufacturers/NNS/O have/VBP/O all/DT/O but/CC/O ceded/VBN/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O segment/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O future/JJ/O business/NN/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O not/RB/O everyone/NN/O here/RB/O is/VBZ/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O give/VB/O up/RP/O ././O
Planar/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Beaverton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ore./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O of/IN/O these/DT/O firms/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O similar/JJ/O plans/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O except/IN/O for/IN/O Zenith/NNP/B-ORG Electronics/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O collaborating/VBG/O with/IN/O Toshiba/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O computer/NN/O displays/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O poorly/RB/O positioned/VBN/O to/TO/O exploit/VB/O advances/NNS/O in/IN/O large/JJ/O panels/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O found/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O not/RB/O developing/VBG/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O thought/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O GE/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O small/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE firms/NNS/O are/VBP/O persisting/VBG/O because/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O strong/JJ/O positions/NNS/O in/IN/O patents/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O because/IN/O the/DT/O prize/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O there/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O seized/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O No/DT/O one/NN/O yet/RB/O has/VBZ/O shown/VBN/O the/DT/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O manufacture/VB/O these/DT/O panels/NNS/O ''/''/O at/IN/O commercial/JJ/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Zvi/NNP/B-PERSON Yaniv/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Ovonic/NNP/B-ORG Imaging/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O thinks/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O from/IN/O doing/VBG/O that/DT/O ././O
The/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O hearing/VBG/O conflicting/JJ/O advice/NN/O about/IN/O what/WP/O its/PRP$/O role/NN/O in/IN/O HDTV/NN/O should/MD/O be/VB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O doing/VBG/O much/JJ/O for/IN/O now/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O material/NN/O support/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O extending/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O struggling/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O awards/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG Advanced/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Projects/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O DARPA/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O are/VBP/O a/DT/O pittance/NN/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O what/WP/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O other/JJ/O prospective/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O are/VBP/O spending/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG estimates/VBZ/O that/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O government/NN/O and/CC/O industry/NN/O spending/NN/O on/IN/O HDTV/NN/O research/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O over/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
``/``/O Unless/IN/O it/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O more/JJR/O help/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE industry/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Friedman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Photonics/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Brody/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Magnascreen/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O president/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O poised/VBN/O to/TO/O snatch/VB/O the/DT/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O put/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O commercial/JJ/O use/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O with/IN/O earlier/JJR/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE innovations/NNS/O in/IN/O color/NN/O television/NN/O and/CC/O video/NN/O recording/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O panels/NNS/O are/VBP/O like/IN/O oversized/JJ/O semiconductors/NNS/O surfaced/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O million/CD/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O picture/NN/O elements/NNS/O ,/,/O each/DT/O contributing/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O color/NN/O and/CC/O tone/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O TV/NN/O image/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG abandoned/VBD/O the/DT/O project/NN/O along/IN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O advanced/JJ/O television/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Brody/NNP/B-PERSON left/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O find/VB/O other/JJ/O backers/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O claim/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O commercialize/VB/O the/DT/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG patents/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O contends/VBZ/O that/IN/O those/DT/O patents/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O infringed/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O producers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Most/JJS/O American/JJ/O investors/NNS/O have/VBP/O just/RB/O given/VBN/O up/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Brody/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O prepared/JJ/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O in/IN/O an/DT/O area/NN/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O see/VB/O a/DT/O domestic/JJ/O source/NN/O for/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O HDTV/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O requirements/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O source/NN/O of/IN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Kelly/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O DARPA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O defense/NN/O manufacturing/NN/O office/NN/O ././O
So/RB/O DARPA/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O developing/VBG/O large/JJ/O display/NN/O panels/NNS/O by/IN/O doling/VBG/O out/RP/O research/NN/O funds/NNS/O ././O
HDTV/NN/O already/RB/O has/VBZ/O some/DT/O military/JJ/O applications/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O creating/VBG/O realistic/JJ/O flight/NN/O simulations/NNS/O and/CC/O transmitting/VBG/O information/NN/O to/TO/O combat/NN/O commanders/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O ordering/VBG/O displays/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O Aegis/NNP/O cruisers/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG wants/VBZ/O smaller/JJR/O versions/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O Abrams/NNP/O battle/NN/O tanks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O encourage/VB/O HDTV/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O benefits/NNS/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O spin/VB/O off/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O semiconductor/NN/O and/CC/O computer/NN/O industries/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O yuppie/NN/O television/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O argues/VBZ/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Clifford/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O department/NN/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O of/IN/O microelectronics/NNS/O and/CC/O instrumentation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O industry/NN/O will/MD/O create/VB/O industrial/JJ/O products/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O displays/NNS/O for/IN/O work/NN/O stations/NNS/O and/CC/O medical/JJ/O diagnostic/JJ/O equipment/NN/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O acquires/VBZ/O a/DT/O mass/NN/O consumer/NN/O market/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Although/IN/O some/DT/O HDTV/NN/O advocates/NNS/O are/VBP/O calling/VBG/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O forms/NNS/O of/IN/O aid/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O antitrust/JJ/O relief/NN/O for/IN/O research/NN/O consortia/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O small/JJ/O firms/NNS/O simply/RB/O would/MD/O prefer/VB/O more/JJR/O DARPA/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O ././O
Each/DT/O claims/VBZ/O to/TO/O possess/VB/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O wants/VBZ/O just/RB/O a/DT/O bit/RB/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O commercial/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O also/RB/O want/VBP/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O policy/NN/O to/TO/O reflect/VB/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG department/NN/O 's/POS/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O their/PRP$/O future/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O help/VB/O them/PRP/O sell/VB/O overseas/RB/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O technology/NN/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O an/DT/O attitude/NN/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O just/RB/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O learned/VBN/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O takes/VBZ/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O ././O
