For/IN/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Airways/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O smooth/JJ/O ride/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O ending/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O trouble/NN/O came/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE carrier/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Swire/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O posted/VBD/O a/DT/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O and/CC/O warned/VBD/O that/IN/O margins/NNS/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O under/IN/O pressure/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Securities/NNS/O analysts/NNS/O ,/,/O many/DT/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O scrapped/VBD/O their/PRP$/O buy/JJ/O recommendations/NNS/O after/IN/O seeing/VBG/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O interim/JJ/O figures/NNS/O ,/,/O believe/VBP/O more/JJR/O jolts/NNS/O lie/VBP/O ahead/RB/O ././O
Fuel/NN/O and/CC/O personnel/NN/O costs/NNS/O are/VBP/O rising/VBG/O ,/,/O and/CC/O tourism/NN/O in/IN/O and/CC/O through/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE remains/VBZ/O clouded/JJ/O by/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O turmoil/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O killings/NNS/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O sense/NN/O is/VBZ/O we/PRP/O would/MD/O never/RB/O be/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O again/RB/O where/WRB/O everything/NN/O works/VBZ/O for/IN/O us/PRP/O the/DT/O way/NN/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O before/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Rod/NNP/B-PERSON Eddington/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O commercial/JJ/O director/NN/O ././O
Sarah/NNP/B-PERSON Hall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O James/NNP/B-ORG Capel/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG Far/NNP/I-ORG East/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O much/JJ/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O do/VB/O about/IN/O rising/VBG/O costs/NNS/O for/IN/O jet/NN/O fuel/NN/O ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE tight/JJ/O labor/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O the/DT/O strengthening/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O pegged/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE dollar/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O factors/NNS/O are/VBP/O further/RBR/O complicated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O 's/POS/O push/NN/O to/TO/O transform/VB/O itself/PRP/O from/IN/O a/DT/O regional/JJ/O carrier/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O one/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Hall/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Hall/NNP/B-PERSON expects/VBZ/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O profit/NN/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O around/IN/O 13/CD/O %/NN/O annually/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O next/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O earned/VBD/O $/$/O 2.82/CD/O billion/CD/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 361.5/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O HK$/$/O 11.79/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Cathay/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O several/JJ/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O business/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O step/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O beef/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O fleet/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O expansion/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O could/MD/O cost/VB/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O US$/$/O 5.7/CD/O billion/CD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O eight/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O expand/VB/O the/DT/O fleet/NN/O to/TO/O about/IN/O 43/CD/O planes/NNS/O by/IN/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 30/CD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Sun/NNP/B-ORG Hung/NNP/I-ORG Kai/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Some/DT/O jobs/NNS/O already/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O moved/VBN/O to/TO/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O place/VB/O others/NNS/O in/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Bell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O partly/RB/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O retaining/VBG/O existing/VBG/O staff/NN/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O leaving/VBG/O to/TO/O secure/VB/O foreign/JJ/O passports/NNS/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O 1997/CD/O ././O
Cathay/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE as/IN/O a/DT/O destination/NN/O worth/JJ/O visiting/VBG/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O merits/NNS/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O just/RB/O a/DT/O stopover/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O the/DT/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O killings/NNS/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O hurt/VBN/O its/PRP$/O China/NNP/B-GPE flights/NNS/O ,/,/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O other/JJ/O routes/NNS/O have/VBP/O retained/VBN/O high/JJ/O load/NN/O factors/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Eddington/NNP/B-PERSON regards/VBZ/O promoting/VBG/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE as/IN/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O attracting/VBG/O visitors/NNS/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O travel/VB/O abroad/RB/O has/VBZ/O surged/VBN/O ././O
Cathay/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O decline/VBP/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O speculation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Eddington/NNP/B-PERSON sees/VBZ/O alliances/NNS/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O carriers/NNS/O --/:/O particularly/RB/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O link/NN/O with/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG --/:/O as/IN/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strategy/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O emphasizes/VBZ/O that/IN/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O swapping/VBG/O equity/NN/O stakes/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE carrier/NN/O or/CC/O with/IN/O Lufthansa/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O airline/NN/O with/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O cooperated/VBN/O for/IN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O believe/VBP/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O approached/VBN/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O swaps/NNS/O by/IN/O other/JJ/O carriers/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O regular/JJ/O basis/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O popularity/NN/O of/IN/O share/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O has/VBZ/O grown/VBN/O among/IN/O European/JJ/O carriers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O think/VBP/O alliances/NNS/O are/VBP/O very/RB/O important/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Eddington/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O 'd/MD/O rather/RB/O put/VB/O funds/NNS/O into/IN/O our/PRP$/O own/JJ/O business/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O someone/NN/O else/NN/O 's/POS/O ././O
I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O sure/JJ/O cross-ownership/NN/O would/MD/O necessarily/RB/O make/VB/O things/NNS/O smoother/JJR/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O a/DT/O pattern/NN/O it/PRP/O aims/VBZ/O to/TO/O copy/VB/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O key/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE destinations/NNS/O ,/,/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG recently/RB/O announced/VBD/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE by/IN/O flying/VBG/O into/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE hub/NN/O and/CC/O routing/VBG/O continuing/VBG/O passengers/NNS/O onto/IN/O a/DT/O flight/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE carrier/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 'll/MD/O never/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O operation/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O never/RB/O have/VB/O one/NN/O as/RB/O big/JJ/O as/IN/O us/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Eddington/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O this/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O coordinate/VB/O good/JJ/O extensions/NNS/O to/TO/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
We/PRP/O 'll/MD/O coordinate/VB/O on/IN/O this/DT/O end/NN/O to/TO/O places/NNS/O like/IN/O Bangkok/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Manila/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
Asian/JJ/O traffic/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O currently/RB/O accounts/VBZ/O for/IN/O 65/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O business/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O 's/POS/O mainstay/NN/O ././O
Further/JJ/O expansion/NN/O into/IN/O southern/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC is/VBZ/O also/RB/O possible/JJ/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Bell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O reincorporated/VBN/O offshore/RB/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O 1997/CD/O ,/,/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O an/DT/O option/NN/O for/IN/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG because/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O jeopardize/VB/O its/PRP$/O landing/NN/O rights/NNS/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ././O
And/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Eddington/NNP/B-PERSON emphatically/RB/O rules/VBZ/O out/RP/O a/DT/O move/NN/O to/TO/O London/NNP/B-GPE :/:/O ``/``/O Our/PRP$/O lifeblood/NN/O is/VBZ/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE traffic/NN/O rights/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O special/JJ/O section/NN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O aviation/NN/O rights/NNS/O states/VBZ/O that/IN/O landing/VBG/O rights/NNS/O for/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE airlines/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O include/VBP/O the/DT/O smaller/JJR/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Dragon/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O negotiated/VBN/O by/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE government/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O critics/NNS/O fret/VBP/O that/IN/O post-1997/JJ/O officials/NNS/O ultimately/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O responsible/JJ/O to/TO/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O My/PRP$/O feeling/NN/O is/VBZ/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O have/VB/O a/DT/O hope/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O run/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O identified/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O Cathay/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O love/VB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O going/VBG/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O general/JJ/O sense/NN/O is/VBZ/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O have/VB/O to/TO/O do/VB/O something/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O confident/JJ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O protects/VBZ/O our/PRP$/O route/NN/O structure/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O and/CC/O our/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O and/CC/O prosper/VB/O ././O
