In/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O sheer/JJ/O brutality/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Somali/JJ/O regime/NN/O of/IN/O Siad/NNP/B-ORG Barre/NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O rank/VB/O as/IN/O No./NNP/O 1/CD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O reason/NN/O that/DT/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE remains/VBZ/O in/IN/O obscurity/NN/O is/VBZ/O numbers/NNS/O :/:/O a/DT/O sparsely/RB/O populated/JJ/O wasteland/NN/O of/IN/O 8.5/CD/O million/CD/O people/NNS/O spread/VBN/O out/RB/O over/IN/O an/DT/O expanse/NN/O nearly/RB/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON dictatorship/NN/O simply/RB/O is/VBZ/O limited/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O torture/VB/O and/CC/O kill/VB/O ././O
Beheading/VBG/O small/JJ/O children/NNS/O ,/,/O stabbing/VBG/O elderly/JJ/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O death/NN/O ,/,/O raping/VBG/O and/CC/O shooting/VBG/O women/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O burying/VBG/O people/NNS/O alive/RB/O are/VBP/O just/RB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O grisly/JJ/O activities/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Somali/JJ/O armed/JJ/O forces/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Up/IN/O to/TO/O 500,000/CD/O Somalis/NNPS/O have/VBP/O escaped/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O relative/JJ/O safety/NN/O of/IN/O Marxist/JJ/O Ethiopia/NNP/B-GPE because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O behavior/NN/O of/IN/O President/NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O troops/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O port/NN/O of/IN/O Berbera/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O men/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O rival/JJ/O Issak/NNP/O clan/NN/O were/VBD/O rounded/VBN/O up/RP/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O imprisoned/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O then/RB/O taken/VBN/O out/RB/O at/IN/O night/NN/O in/IN/O groups/NNS/O of/IN/O five/CD/O to/TO/O 50/CD/O men/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O executed/VBN/O without/IN/O any/DT/O judicial/JJ/O process/NN/O whatsoever/RB/O ././O
Guns/NNS/O were/VBD/O never/RB/O used/VBN/O :/:/O Each/DT/O man/NN/O was/VBD/O stabbed/VBN/O to/TO/O death/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O knife/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O horrific/JJ/O details/NNS/O are/VBP/O only/RB/O now/RB/O emerging/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O painstakingly/RB/O documented/VBN/O report/NN/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O interviews/NNS/O with/IN/O randomly/RB/O selected/VBN/O refugees/NNS/O ././O
What/WP/O gives/VBZ/O these/DT/O events/NNS/O particular/JJ/O significance/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O wider/JJR/O drama/NN/O affecting/VBG/O the/DT/O strategic/JJ/O positions/NNS/O of/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE on/IN/O the/DT/O horn/NN/O of/IN/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Not/RB/O since/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1970s/NNS/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O horn/NN/O been/VBN/O so/RB/O up/IN/O for/IN/O grabs/NNS/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O suddenly/RB/O become/VBN/O in/IN/O just/RB/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O rule/NN/O is/VBZ/O crumbling/VBG/O fast/RB/O ././O
Mutinies/NNS/O wrack/VBP/O his/PRP$/O armed/JJ/O forces/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O really/RB/O just/RB/O an/DT/O armed/JJ/O gang/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O control/VBP/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Inflation/NN/O is/VBZ/O at/IN/O record/NN/O levels/NNS/O ././O
Desperate/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O called/VBN/O in/RP/O the/DT/O Libyans/NNPS/O to/TO/O help/VB/O fight/VB/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Somali/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Movement/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O north/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O groups/NNS/O picking/VBG/O away/RP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O regime/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O capital/NN/O of/IN/O Mogadishu/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE consists/VBZ/O of/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O runway/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O port/NN/O of/IN/O Berbera/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O aircraft/NN/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O for/IN/O surveillance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC of/IN/I-LOC Aden/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O the/DT/B-LOC Indian/NNP/I-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O desert/NN/O behind/IN/O them/PRP/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O a/DT/O land/NN/O of/IN/O mass/NN/O executions/NNS/O and/CC/O utter/JJ/O anarchy/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O ,/,/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O brutality/NN/O and/CC/O ineptitude/NN/O ,/,/O nobody/NN/O is/VBZ/O any/RB/O longer/RB/O in/IN/O control/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O due/RB/O to/TO/O dramatic/JJ/O events/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O battlefield/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O and/CC/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O those/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O bases/NNS/O may/MD/O soon/RB/O be/VB/O as/RB/O endangered/VBN/O and/CC/O as/RB/O lonely/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O runway/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O Sept./NNP/O 7/CD/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O wrote/VBD/O on/IN/O these/DT/O pages/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O killing/VBG/O and/CC/O capturing/VBG/O of/IN/O 10,000/CD/O Ethiopian/JJ/O soldiers/NNS/O by/IN/O Eritrean/JJ/O and/CC/O Tigrean/JJ/O guerrillas/NNS/O ././O
Recently/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Wollo/NNP/B-GPE province/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O of/IN/O Ethiopia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tigrean/JJ/O forces/NNS/O have/VBP/O killed/VBN/O ,/,/O wounded/VBN/O and/CC/O captured/VBN/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O 20,000/CD/O government/NN/O troops/NNS/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Think/VB/O what/WP/O these/DT/O numbers/NNS/O mean/VBP/O --/:/O considering/VBG/O the/DT/O headline/NN/O space/NN/O devoted/VBN/O to/TO/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O deaths/NNS/O in/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O country/NN/O of/IN/O little/JJ/O strategic/JJ/O importance/NN/O !/./O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Tigrean/JJ/O armies/NNS/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O 200/CD/O miles/NNS/O north/RB/O of/IN/O Addis/NNP/B-GPE Ababa/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O threatening/VBG/O the/DT/O town/NN/O of/IN/O Dese/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O cut/VB/O off/RP/O Mr./NNP/O Mengistu/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O capital/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O port/NN/O of/IN/O Assab/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O through/IN/O which/WDT/O all/DT/O fuel/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O supplies/NNS/O reach/VBP/O Addis/NNP/B-GPE Ababa/NNP/I-GPE ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mengistu/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O transfer/VB/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O troops/NNS/O from/IN/O Eritrea/NNP/B-GPE just/RB/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O the/DT/O town/NN/O ,/,/O thereby/RB/O risking/VBG/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O even/RB/O more/JJR/O territory/NN/O in/IN/O Eritrea/NNP/B-GPE only/RB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O Tigreans/NNPS/O at/IN/O bay/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mengistu/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O in/IN/O an/DT/O increasingly/RB/O weak/JJ/O position/NN/O :/:/O Half/PDT/O his/PRP$/O army/NN/O is/VBZ/O tied/VBN/O down/RP/O defending/VBG/O the/DT/O northern/JJ/O city/NN/O of/IN/O Asmara/NNP/B-GPE from/IN/O the/DT/O Eritreans/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O weaker/JJR/O he/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O he/PRP/O turns/VBZ/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O help/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O this/DT/O all/DT/O means/NNS/O in/IN/O shorthand/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O dominance/NN/O in/IN/O Ethiopia/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O collapsing/VBG/O as/RB/O fast/RB/O as/IN/O President/NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O regime/NN/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O ././O
Back/RB/O to/TO/O Somalia/NN/B-GPE :/:/O
The/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O credit/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O begun/VBN/O distancing/VBG/O itself/PRP/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O evinced/VBN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O publish/VB/O the/DT/O Gersony/NNP/B-PERSON report/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O press/NN/O has/VBZ/O ignored/VBN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O suspended/VBN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O economic/JJ/O aid/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O enough/JJ/O ././O
Because/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O still/RB/O perceived/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O tied/VBN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O goes/VBZ/O the/DT/O runway/NN/O could/MD/O go/VB/O too/RB/O ././O
Considering/VBG/O how/WRB/O tenuous/JJ/O the/DT/O security/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O runway/NN/O is/VBZ/O anyway/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O better/JJR/O option/NN/O --/:/O both/DT/O morally/RB/O and/CC/O strategically/RB/O --/:/O would/MD/O be/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O to/TO/O blast/VB/O the/DT/O regime/NN/O publicly/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O terms/NNS/O clear/JJ/O enough/RB/O for/IN/O all/DT/O influential/JJ/O Somalis/NNPS/O to/TO/O understand/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O certainty/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O days/NNS/O are/VBP/O numbered/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE should/MD/O take/VB/O care/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O position/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O go/VB/O down/RB/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
Nobody/NN/O is/VBZ/O sure/JJ/O what/WP/O will/MD/O come/VB/O next/JJ/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O whom/WP/O the/DT/O successor/NN/O might/MD/O be/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O as/IN/O one/CD/O expert/NN/O tells/VBZ/O me/PRP/O :/:/O ``/``/O Whoever/WP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O work/VB/O pretty/RB/O damn/RB/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O worse/JJR/O than/IN/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
Ethiopian/JJ/O politics/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O sophisticated/JJ/O ,/,/O secretive/JJ/O and/CC/O Byzantine/JJ/O in/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O black/JJ/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Remember/VB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O took/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Mengistu/NNP/B-PERSON many/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O what/WP/O became/VBD/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O creeping/VBG/O coup/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O to/TO/O topple/VB/O Emperor/NNP/O Haile/NNP/B-PERSON Selassie/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O 1974/CD/O and/CC/O 1975/CD/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O simply/RB/O no/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O engineer/VB/O a/DT/O succession/NN/O covertly/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O is/VBZ/O sometimes/RB/O possible/JJ/O elsewhere/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O continent/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O one/CD/O great/JJ/O advantage/NN/O :/:/O The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O are/VBP/O universally/RB/O loathed/VBN/O throughout/IN/O Ethiopia/NN/B-GPE for/IN/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O country/NN/O this/DT/O past/JJ/O decade/NN/O --/:/O famine/NN/O and/CC/O all/DT/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O just/RB/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC where/WRB/O the/DT/O march/NN/O of/IN/O events/NNS/O is/VBZ/O finally/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE side/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O on/IN/O the/DT/O horn/NN/O of/IN/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE liability/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O is/VBZ/O what/WP/O remains/VBZ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O link/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O should/MD/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O fast/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kaplan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O author/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Surrender/VB/O or/CC/O Starve/VB/O :/:/O The/DT/O Wars/NNS/O Behind/IN/O the/DT/O Famine/NN/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Westview/NNP/B-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O 1988/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O lives/VBZ/O in/IN/O Lisbon/NNP/B-GPE ././O
