The/DT/O Vatican/NNP/B-FAC ,/,/O which/WDT/O denies/VBZ/O any/DT/O wrongdoing/NN/O ,/,/O paid/VBD/O $/$/O 250/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Milan/NNP/B-GPE bank/NN/O 's/POS/O creditors/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O goodwill/NN/O gesture/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ././O
Italian/JJ/O news/NN/O reports/NNS/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Carboni/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O colleague/NN/O obtained/VBD/O 1.2/CD/O billion/CD/O lire/NNS/O in/IN/O checks/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Vatican/NNP/B-FAC official/NN/O ,/,/O Pavel/NNP/B-PERSON Hnilica/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Italian/JJ/O papers/NNS/O speculated/VBD/O the/DT/O briefcase/NN/O contained/VBD/O papers/NNS/O either/CC/O exonerating/VBG/O the/DT/O Vatican/NNP/B-FAC bank/NN/O from/IN/O blame/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O scandal/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O showing/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Istituto/NNP/I-ORG per/FW/I-ORG le/FW/I-ORG Opere/NNP/I-ORG di/FW/I-ORG Religione/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O channeled/VBD/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O East/JJ/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC groups/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Solidarity/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
