David/NNP/B-PERSON Nash/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O formerly/RB/O group/NN/O finance/NN/O director/NN/O at/IN/O Cadbury/NNP/B-ORG Schweppes/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O become/VB/O Grand/NNP/B-ORG Met/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG first/JJ/O group/NN/O finance/NN/O director/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O reassigned/VBD/O several/JJ/O executive/NN/O responsibilities/NNS/O ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Tagg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O formerly/RB/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O gambling/NN/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O appointed/VBN/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O for/IN/O retailing/NN/O and/CC/O property/NN/O ././O
Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Cawdron/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O group/NN/O strategy/NN/O development/NN/O director/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Shardlow/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O group/NN/O personnel/NNS/O director/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O become/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O 's/POS/O management/NN/O committee/NN/O ././O
