The/DT/O official/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON DeVillars/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O asked/VBD/O Clean/NNP/B-ORG Harbors/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/O more/JJR/O information/NN/O before/IN/O ruling/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O permit/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O site/NN/O ././O
Critics/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O town/NN/O of/IN/O Braintree/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O incinerator/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O health/NN/O hazard/NN/O ././O
Clean/NNP/B-ORG Harbors/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Quincy/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O will/MD/O proceed/VB/O expeditiously/RB/O ''/''/O to/TO/O submit/VB/O the/DT/O data/NNS|NN/O requested/VBN/O ././O
Alan/NNP/B-PERSON McKim/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Clean/NNP/B-ORG Harbors/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O very/RB/O much/RB/O encouraged/JJ/O ''/''/O by/IN/O the/DT/O official/NN/O 's/POS/O praise/NN/O of/IN/O Clean/NNP/B-ORG Harbors/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O data/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O report/NN/O ././O
