OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O more/JJR/O petroleum/NN/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O sell/VB/O is/VBZ/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O cast/VB/O a/DT/O shadow/NN/O over/IN/O world/NN/O oil/NN/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Output/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Exporting/NNP/I-ORG Countries/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O already/RB/O at/IN/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O most/JJS/O member/NN/O nations/NNS/O are/VBP/O running/VBG/O flat/RB/O out/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O organization/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O in/IN/O Vienna/NNP/B-GPE beginning/VBG/O Nov./NNP/O 25/CD/O ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O rising/VBG/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG oil/NN/O and/CC/O production/NN/O restraint/NN/O by/IN/O some/DT/O members/NNS/O have/VBP/O kept/VBN/O prices/NNS/O firm/JJ/O despite/IN/O rampant/JJ/O cheating/NN/O by/IN/O others/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O could/MD/O change/VB/O if/IN/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O oil/NN/O softens/VBZ/O seasonally/RB/O early/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O as/IN/O some/DT/O think/VBP/O may/MD/O happen/VB/O ././O
At/IN/O that/DT/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 13/CD/O members/NNS/O have/VBP/O reached/VBN/O their/PRP$/O output/NN/O limits/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O estimated/VBN/O that/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O three/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O possibly/RB/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O seven/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O --/:/O of/IN/O spare/JJ/O capacity/NN/O still/RB/O exists/VBZ/O within/IN/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O puts/VBZ/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O current/JJ/O capacity/NN/O at/IN/O 28/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O 29/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O higher/JJR/O than/IN/O some/DT/O other/JJ/O estimates/NNS/O ././O
Either/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O overhang/NN/O is/VBZ/O big/JJ/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O delicately/RB/O balanced/JJ/O oil/NN/O markets/NNS/O on/IN/O edge/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O modest/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O additional/JJ/O output/NN/O by/IN/O those/DT/O with/IN/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O extra/JJ/O capacity/NN/O and/CC/O reserves/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Saudi/NNP/B-GPE Arabia/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Iraq/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O could/MD/O upset/VB/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Iraqi/JJ/O oil/NN/O minister/NN/O and/CC/O Saudi/JJ/O oil/NN/O minister/NN/O Hisham/NNP/B-PERSON Nazer/NNP/I-PERSON insisted/VBD/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O comments/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O countries/NNS/O would/MD/O act/VB/O responsibly/RB/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O a/DT/O stable/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O interviews/NNS/O later/RBR/O ,/,/O both/DT/O ministers/NNS/O stressed/VBD/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O expect/VBP/O future/JJ/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG quotas/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O based/VBN/O mainly/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O production/NN/O capacity/NN/O and/CC/O reserves/NNS/O of/IN/O each/DT/O member/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O that/DT/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O countries/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O unused/JJ/O oil/NN/O capacity/NN/O would/MD/O get/VB/O bigger/JJR/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O any/DT/O future/JJ/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O production/NN/O ceiling/NN/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O under/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O system/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O an/DT/O inconclusive/JJ/O Geneva/NNP/B-GPE meeting/NN/O late/JJ/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O oil/NN/O ministers/NNS/O halfheartedly/RB/O approved/VBD/O another/DT/O increase/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O production/NN/O ceiling/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O doled/VBD/O it/PRP/O out/RP/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O existing/VBG/O formula/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O meant/VBD/O that/IN/O even/RB/O those/DT/O countries/NNS/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O produce/VB/O more/JJR/O received/VBD/O higher/JJR/O official/JJ/O allotments/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O main/JJ/O effect/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ceiling/NN/O boost/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O ``/``/O legitimize/VB/O ''/''/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O overproduction/NN/O already/RB/O coming/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O quota/NN/O cheaters/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O breakthrough/NN/O at/IN/O Geneva/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Previously/RB/O ,/,/O no/DT/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG member/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O a/DT/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O percentage/NN/O share/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O total/JJ/O output/NN/O target/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O ceiling/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O concept/NN/O of/IN/O disproportionate/JJ/O quotas/NNS/O for/IN/O those/DT/O with/IN/O unused/JJ/O capacity/NN/O ,/,/O advanced/VBN/O there/RB/O in/IN/O an/DT/O Iranian/JJ/O proposal/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O generally/RB/O endorsed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O ministers/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O politics/NNS/O got/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O ././O
Libya/NNP/B-GPE accepted/VBD/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O only/RB/O so/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O promised/VBN/O production/NN/O parity/NN/O with/IN/O Kuwait/NNP/B-GPE ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE Arab/NNP/I-GPE Emirates/NNPS/I-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O chronic/JJ/O quota/NN/O cheater/NN/O ,/,/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O give/VB/O any/DT/O guarantee/NN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O change/VB/O its/PRP$/O ways/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O ministers/NNS/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O study/VB/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O be/VB/O the/DT/O basis/NN/O for/IN/O discussion/NN/O at/IN/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O 's/POS/O meeting/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O understood/VBN/O several/JJ/O compromises/NNS/O already/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O worked/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ceiling/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O lifted/VBN/O to/TO/O 21.5/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O Kuwait/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE Arab/NNP/I-GPE Emirates/NNP/I-GPE much/RB/O higher/JJR/O official/JJ/O quotas/NNS/O while/IN/O reducing/VBG/O percentage/NN/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O some/DT/O others/NNS/O ././O
Libya/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O previous/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O are/VBP/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O considered/VBN/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE Arab/NNP/I-GPE Emirates/NNPS/I-GPE is/VBZ/O still/RB/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Saudi/NNP/B-GPE Arabia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O kingpin/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O surfaced/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O obstacle/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Insisting/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O 24.5/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O ceiling/NN/O ,/,/O Saudi/JJ/O officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O long/RB/O pressed/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O pro/JJ/O rata/JJ/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O increases/NNS/O to/TO/O all/DT/O members/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Geneva/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O supported/VBD/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O left/VBN/O the/DT/O Saudi/JJ/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG total/NN/O intact/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O increased/VBD/O actual/JJ/O Saudi/JJ/O volume/NN/O to/TO/O nearly/RB/O 5.3/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O daily/RB/O from/IN/O five/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Though/IN/O tiny/JJ/O ,/,/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O share/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nazer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Saudi/JJ/O oil/NN/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O reiterated/VBD/O here/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O kingdom/NN/O would/MD/O insist/VB/O on/IN/O maintaining/VBG/O its/PRP$/O percentage/NN/O share/NN/O of/IN/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG production/NN/O under/IN/O any/DT/O quota/NN/O revisions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Under/IN/O any/DT/O circumstances/NNS/O ,/,/O Saudi/NNP/B-GPE Arabia/NNP/I-GPE should/MD/O get/VB/O more/JJR/O ''/''/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O less/JJR/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Nazer/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
