The/DT/O investigation/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O coordinated/VBN/O with/IN/O one/NN/O already/RB/O under/IN/O way/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O follows/VBZ/O the/DT/O discovery/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O Ferranti/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O called/VBN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O serious/JJ/O ''/''/O fraud/NN/O involving/VBG/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE subsidiary/NN/O ././O
Ferranti/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O off/RP/O #/#/O 185/CD/O million/CD/O against/IN/O the/DT/O phantom/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O ,/,/O reducing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O net/JJ/O asset/NN/O value/NN/O by/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O half/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Serious/NNP/I-ORG Fraud/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O division/NN/O of/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Metropolitan/NNP/B-ORG Police/NNP/I-ORG responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O investigating/VBG/O financial/JJ/O crimes/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O would/MD/O take/VB/O in/RP/O ``/``/O allegations/NNS/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O prior/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O surrounding/JJ/O and/CC/O subsequent/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O merger/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Ferranti/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O welcomes/VBZ/O the/DT/O investigation/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O ``/``/O cooperate/VB/O fully/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O British/JJ/O defense/NN/O electronics/NNS/O group/NN/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O sell/VB/O #/#/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O may/MD/O seek/VB/O a/DT/O merger/NN/O to/TO/O strengthen/VB/O itself/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O troubles/NNS/O ././O
