Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Investors/NNPS/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O lowered/VBD/O the/DT/O ratings/NNS/O of/IN/O some/DT/O $/$/O 145/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O Pinnacle/NNP/B-ORG debt/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O accelerating/VBG/O deficiency/NN/O in/IN/O liquidity/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O said/VBD/O was/VBD/O evidenced/VBN/O by/IN/O Pinnacle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O elimination/NN/O of/IN/O dividend/NN/O payments/NNS/O ././O
Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Sargent/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Pinnacle/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O action/NN/O ``/``/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O really/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O effect/NN/O on/IN/O us/PRP/O ././O
Securities/NNS/O of/IN/O MeraBank/NNP/B-ORG were/VBD/O placed/VBN/O under/IN/O review/NN/O last/JJ/O May/MD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O under/IN/O review/NN/O for/IN/O downgrade/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
