The/DT/O only/JJ/O reason/NN/O that/DT/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE remains/VBZ/O in/IN/O obscurity/NN/O is/VBZ/O numbers/NNS/O :/:/O a/DT/O sparsely/RB/O populated/JJ/O wasteland/NN/O of/IN/O 8.5/CD/O million/CD/O people/NNS/O spread/VBN/O out/RB/O over/IN/O an/DT/O expanse/NN/O nearly/RB/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON dictatorship/NN/O simply/RB/O is/VBZ/O limited/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O torture/VB/O and/CC/O kill/VB/O ././O
Guns/NNS/O were/VBD/O never/RB/O used/VBN/O :/:/O Each/DT/O man/NN/O was/VBD/O stabbed/VBN/O to/TO/O death/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O knife/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O horrific/JJ/O details/NNS/O are/VBP/O only/RB/O now/RB/O emerging/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O painstakingly/RB/O documented/VBN/O report/NN/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O interviews/NNS/O with/IN/O randomly/RB/O selected/VBN/O refugees/NNS/O ././O
What/WP/O gives/VBZ/O these/DT/O events/NNS/O particular/JJ/O significance/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O wider/JJR/O drama/NN/O affecting/VBG/O the/DT/O strategic/JJ/O positions/NNS/O of/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE on/IN/O the/DT/O horn/NN/O of/IN/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O rule/NN/O is/VBZ/O crumbling/VBG/O fast/RB/O ././O
Inflation/NN/O is/VBZ/O at/IN/O record/NN/O levels/NNS/O ././O
Desperate/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O called/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Libyans/NNPS/O to/TO/O help/VB/O fight/VB/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Somali/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Movement/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O north/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O groups/NNS/O picking/VBG/O away/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O regime/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O capital/NN/O of/IN/O Mogadishu/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE consists/VBZ/O of/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O runway/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O port/NN/O of/IN/O Berbera/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O aircraft/NN/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O for/IN/O surveillance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC of/IN/I-LOC Aden/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O the/DT/B-LOC Indian/NNP/I-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mengistu/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O in/IN/O an/DT/O increasingly/RB/O weak/JJ/O position/NN/O :/:/O Half/PDT/O his/PRP$/O army/NN/O is/VBZ/O tied/VBN/O down/RB/O defending/VBG/O the/DT/O northern/JJ/O city/NN/O of/IN/O Asmara/NNP/B-GPE from/IN/O the/DT/O Eritreans/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O weaker/JJR/O he/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O he/PRP/O turns/VBZ/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O help/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O this/DT/O all/DT/O means/NNS/O in/IN/O shorthand/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O dominance/NN/O in/IN/O Ethiopia/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O collapsing/VBG/O as/RB/O fast/RB/O as/IN/O President/NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O regime/NN/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O suspended/VBN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O economic/JJ/O aid/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O certainty/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O days/NNS/O are/VBP/O numbered/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE should/MD/O take/VB/O care/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O position/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O go/VB/O down/RB/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
Nobody/NN/O is/VBZ/O sure/JJ/O what/WP/O will/MD/O come/VB/O next/JJ/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O whom/WP/O the/DT/O successor/NN/O might/MD/O be/VB/O ././O
Ethiopian/JJ/O politics/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O sophisticated/JJ/O ,/,/O secretive/JJ/O and/CC/O Byzantine/JJ/O in/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O black/JJ/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O simply/RB/O no/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O engineer/VB/O a/DT/O succession/NN/O covertly/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O is/VBZ/O sometimes/RB/O possible/JJ/O elsewhere/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O continent/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O just/RB/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC where/WRB/O the/DT/O march/NN/O of/IN/O events/NNS/O is/VBZ/O finally/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE side/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O on/IN/O the/DT/O horn/NN/O of/IN/O Africa/NNP/B-LOC as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE liability/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O is/VBZ/O what/WP/O remains/VBZ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O link/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Barre/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O should/MD/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O fast/RB/O ././O
