OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O more/JJR/O petroleum/NN/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O sell/VB/O is/VBZ/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O cast/VB/O a/DT/O shadow/NN/O over/IN/O world/NN/O oil/NN/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Output/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Exporting/NNP/I-ORG Countries/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O already/RB/O at/IN/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O most/JJS/O member/NN/O nations/NNS/O are/VBP/O running/VBG/O flat/RB/O out/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O organization/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O in/IN/O Vienna/NNP/B-GPE beginning/VBG/O Nov./NNP/O 25/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O puts/VBZ/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O current/JJ/O capacity/NN/O at/IN/O 28/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O 29/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O higher/JJR/O than/IN/O some/DT/O other/JJ/O estimates/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Iraqi/JJ/O oil/NN/O minister/NN/O and/CC/O Saudi/JJ/O oil/NN/O minister/NN/O Hisham/NNP/B-PERSON Nazer/NNP/I-PERSON insisted/VBD/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O comments/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O countries/NNS/O would/MD/O act/VB/O responsibly/RB/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O a/DT/O stable/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O doled/VBD/O it/PRP/O out/RP/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O existing/VBG/O formula/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O meant/VBD/O that/IN/O even/RB/O those/DT/O countries/NNS/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O produce/VB/O more/JJR/O received/VBD/O higher/JJR/O official/JJ/O allotments/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O main/JJ/O effect/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ceiling/NN/O boost/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O ``/``/O legitimize/VB/O ''/''/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O overproduction/NN/O already/RB/O coming/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O quota/NN/O cheaters/NNS/O ././O
Libya/NNP/B-GPE accepted/VBD/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O only/RB/O so/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O promised/VBN/O production/NN/O parity/NN/O with/IN/O Kuwait/NNP/B-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O understood/VBN/O several/JJ/O compromises/NNS/O already/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O worked/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ceiling/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O lifted/VBN/O to/TO/O 21.5/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O Kuwait/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE Arab/NNP/I-GPE Emirates/NNP/I-GPE much/RB/O higher/JJR/O official/JJ/O quotas/NNS/O while/IN/O reducing/VBG/O percentage/NN/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O some/DT/O others/NNS/O ././O
Libya/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O previous/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O are/VBP/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O considered/VBN/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE Arab/NNP/I-GPE Emirates/NNPS/I-GPE is/VBZ/O still/RB/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Saudi/NNP/B-GPE Arabia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O kingpin/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O surfaced/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O obstacle/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nazer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Saudi/JJ/O oil/NN/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O reiterated/VBD/O here/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O kingdom/NN/O would/MD/O insist/VB/O on/IN/O maintaining/VBG/O its/PRP$/O percentage/NN/O share/NN/O of/IN/O OPEC/NNP/B-ORG production/NN/O under/IN/O any/DT/O quota/NN/O revisions/NNS/O ././O
