Sitting/VBG/O at/IN/O the/DT/O bar/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Four/NNP/B-ORG Seasons/NNPS/I-ORG restaurant/NN/O ,/,/O architect/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON McDonough/NNP/I-PERSON seems/VBZ/O oblivious/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O glamorous/JJ/O clientele/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O elegant/JJ/O setting/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ogling/VBG/O the/DT/O curtains/NNS/O rippling/VBG/O above/IN/O the/DT/O ventilation/NN/O ducts/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Look/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O air/NN/O is/VBZ/O moving/VBG/O around/RB/O !/./O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O ventilation/NN/O here/RB/O is/VBZ/O great/JJ/O !/./O ''/''/O
After/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O relative/JJ/O obscurity/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O starting/VBG/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O notice/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O ecological/JJ/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O aesthetic/JJ/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O architecture/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O designed/VBN/O furniture/NN/O and/CC/O homes/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O commercial/JJ/O and/CC/O office/NN/O space/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O designing/VBG/O a/DT/O Broadway/NNP/B-FAC stage/NN/O set/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O show/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O band/NN/O Kid/NNP/B-ORG Creole/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Coconuts/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
What/WP/O really/RB/O stirs/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O muse/NN/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O aerobic/JJ/O architecture/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O the/DT/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O :/:/O Is/VBZ/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ready/JJ/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O ?/./O
The/DT/O project/NN/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O acquired/VBN/O a/DT/O certain/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE cachet/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O sales/NNS/O proceeds/NNS/O will/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Design/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Foundation/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O AIDS/NNP/O ././O
A/DT/O cake/NN/O topped/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O replica/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O auctioned/VBN/O at/IN/O an/DT/O AIDS/NNP/O benefit/NN/O at/IN/O Sotheby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG in/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
If/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O plans/NNS/O get/VBP/O executed/VBN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Polish/JJ/O center/NN/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O will/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O from/IN/O aluminum/NN/O ,/,/O steel/NN/O and/CC/O glass/NN/O recycled/VBN/O from/IN/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O abundant/JJ/O rubble/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O windows/NNS/O will/MD/O open/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O carpets/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O glued/VBN/O down/RP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O walls/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O coated/VBN/O with/IN/O nontoxic/JJ/O finishes/NNS/O ././O
To/TO/O the/DT/O extent/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O budget/NN/O will/MD/O allow/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O rely/VB/O on/IN/O solid/JJ/O wood/NN/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O plywood/NN/O or/CC/O particle/NN/O board/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O limit/VB/O the/DT/O emission/NN/O of/IN/O formaldehyde/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O way/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Poles/NNPS/O will/MD/O compensate/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O center/NN/O 's/POS/O emissions/NNS/O of/IN/O carbon/NN/O dioxide/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O prime/JJ/O suspect/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O global/JJ/O atmospheric/JJ/O warming/NN/O many/JJ/O scientists/NNS/O fear/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O news/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O exactly/RB/O moved/VBN/O others/NNS/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O profession/NN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O architectural/JJ/O Johnny/NNP/B-PERSON Appleseeds/NNPS/I-PERSON ././O
All/DT/O architects/NNS/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ecological/JJ/O consequences/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O work/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Burgee/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE firm/NN/O is/VBZ/O designing/VBG/O the/DT/O redevelopment/NN/O of/IN/O Times/NNP/B-FAC Square/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O all/DT/O carry/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O that/DT/O extreme/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Karen/NNP/B-PERSON Nichols/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O associate/NN/O at/IN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Graves/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON architecture/NN/O firm/NN/O in/IN/O Princeton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O really/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O mercy/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O construction/NN/O industry/NN/O can/MD/O and/CC/O will/MD/O do/VB/O readily/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON responds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O asking/VBG/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O broaden/VB/O their/PRP$/O agendas/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O son/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O executive/NN/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O stationed/VBN/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O countries/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O born/VBN/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O attended/VBD/O 19/CD/O schools/NNS/O in/IN/O places/NNS/O ranging/VBG/O from/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O Shaker/NNP/B-GPE Heights/NNPS/I-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O before/IN/O entering/VBG/O Dartmouth/NNP/B-ORG College/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O earned/VBD/O a/DT/O master/NN/O 's/POS/O degree/NN/O in/IN/O architecture/NN/O from/IN/O Yale/NNP/B-ORG ././O
His/PRP$/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O natural/JJ/O environment/NN/O dates/VBZ/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O youth/NN/O ././O
Living/VBG/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O made/VBD/O him/PRP/O sensitive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O limits/NNS/O on/IN/O food/NN/O ,/,/O power/NN/O and/CC/O water/NN/O supplies/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O his/PRP$/O first/JJ/O school/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE he/PRP/O was/VBD/O thought/VBN/O a/DT/O little/RB/O strange/JJ/O for/IN/O shutting/VBG/O off/RP/O open/JJ/O water/NN/O taps/NNS/O and/CC/O admonishing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O schoolmates/NNS/O to/TO/O take/VB/O only/JJ/O brief/JJ/O showers/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O and/CC/O a/DT/O Dartmouth/NNP/B-ORG roommate/NN/O established/VBD/O a/DT/O company/NN/O that/WDT/O restored/VBD/O three/CD/O hydroelectric/JJ/O power/NN/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O Vermont/NNP/B-GPE ././O
At/IN/O Yale/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O designed/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O solarheated/JJ/O houses/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O Ireland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O first/JJ/O professional/JJ/O project/NN/O fully/RB/O to/TO/O reflect/VB/O his/PRP$/O environmental/JJ/O ardor/NN/O was/VBD/O his/PRP$/O 1986/CD/O design/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O headquarters/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Environmental/NNP/I-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Since/IN/O the/DT/O 1970s/NNS/O energy/NN/O crisis/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O conserve/VB/O energy/NN/O by/IN/O sealing/VBG/O buildings/NNS/O have/VBP/O had/VBN/O an/DT/O unintended/JJ/O side/NN/O effect/NN/O :/:/O high/JJ/O indoor/JJ/O pollution/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O reduce/VB/O it/PRP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O fund/NN/O 's/POS/O building/NN/O ,/,/O workers/NNS/O rubbed/VBD/O beeswax/NN/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O polyurethane/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O floors/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O budget/NN/O was/VBD/O only/RB/O $/$/O 400,000/CD/O ././O
``/``/O Athens/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O Spartan/JJ/O means/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O fund/NN/O 's/POS/O lawyers/NNS/O work/VBP/O in/IN/O an/DT/O Athenian/JJ/O grove/NN/O of/IN/O potted/JJ/O trees/NNS/O ././O
Economists/NNS/O and/CC/O administrators/NNS/O sit/VBP/O along/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O boulevard/NN/O ''/''/O with/IN/O street/NN/O lamps/NNS/O and/CC/O ficus/NN/O trees/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O offices/NNS/O ,/,/O triphosphorous/JJ/O bulbs/NNS/O simulate/VBP/O daylight/NN/O ././O
Offices/NNS/O with/IN/O outside/JJ/O windows/NNS/O have/VBP/O inside/JJ/O windows/NNS/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O let/VB/O in/RP/O more/RBR/O real/JJ/O daylight/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O proved/VBD/O a/DT/O healthy/JJ/O office/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O cost/VB/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Frederic/NNP/B-PERSON Krupp/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/NN/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O fund/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O guess/VBP/O I/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O really/RB/O notice/VB/O the/DT/O trees/NNS/O ././O
Maybe/RB/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O hidden/VBN/O by/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Neither/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Quilted/NNP/I-ORG Giraffe/NNP/I-ORG nor/CC/O the/DT/O Paul/NNP/B-ORG Stuart/NNP/I-ORG renovation/NN/O reflects/VBZ/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O environmental/JJ/O concern/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O restaurant/NN/O was/VBD/O conceived/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O sparkling/JJ/O ,/,/O crystalline/JJ/O ``/``/O geode/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
To/TO/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O replace/VB/O the/DT/O wood/NN/O from/IN/O two/CD/O English/JJ/O oaks/NNS/O used/VBN/O for/IN/O paneling/NN/O at/IN/O Paul/NNP/B-ORG Stuart/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O friends/NNS/O planted/VBD/O 1,000/CD/O acorns/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ambitious/JJ/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE project/NN/O still/RB/O awaits/VBZ/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O city/NN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O developer/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O Polish/NNP/O American/NNP/O ,/,/O Sasha/NNP/B-PERSON Muniak/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O had/VBD/O worked/VBN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O an/DT/O earlier/JJR/O project/NN/O and/CC/O recruited/VBD/O him/PRP/O as/IN/O architect/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O center/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O center/NN/O will/MD/O provide/VB/O space/NN/O for/IN/O computer/NN/O hardware/NN/O and/CC/O facsimile/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O telecommunications/NN/O equipment/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O readily/RB/O accessible/JJ/O in/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE now/RB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O a/DT/O growing/VBG/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Westerners/NNPS/O doing/VBG/O business/NN/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Mr./NNP/O McDonough/NNP/B-PERSON thinks/VBZ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC ``/``/I-FAC Eiffel/NNP/I-FAC Tower/NNP/I-FAC of/IN/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O a/DT/O symbol/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O resurgence/NN/O of/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O any/DT/O nation/NN/O can/MD/O use/VB/O environmentally/RB/O benign/JJ/O architecture/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Jessica/NNP/B-PERSON Mathews/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O World/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O perhaps/RB/O a/DT/O quarter/NN/O of/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O soil/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O contaminated/VBN/O for/IN/O safe/JJ/O farming/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O air/NN/O pollution/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O pollution/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O killing/VBG/O forests/NNS/O and/CC/O destroying/VBG/O buildings/NNS/O that/WDT/O date/VBP/O back/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Middle/NNP/O Ages/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O future/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O forest/NN/O remains/VBZ/O uncertain/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Muniak/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Balag/NNP/B-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O set/VB/O aside/RB/O the/DT/O money/NN/O to/TO/O plant/VB/O and/CC/O maintain/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O discussions/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O going/VBG/O on/RB/O over/IN/O where/WRB/O to/TO/O place/VB/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O maintained/VBN/O ././O
After/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Muniak/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O in/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE there/EX/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O worried/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O more/RBR/O worried/JJ/O about/IN/O bread/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O table/NN/O ././O
