-LRB-/-LRB-/O Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Seita/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O net/JJ/O profit/NN/O soared/VBD/O 150/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 461.6/CD/O million/CD/O French/JJ/O francs/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 73.5/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O FFr/SYM/O 27.68/CD/O billion/CD/O -/:/O a/DT/O 1.7/CD/O %/NN/O profit/NN/O margin/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O ways/NNS/O to/TO/O exploit/VB/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O network/NN/O of/IN/O 39,000/CD/O tobacco/NN/O agents/NNS/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O cafes/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O Seita/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O own/VB/O the/DT/O French/JJ/O tabacs/NNS/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O close/JJ/O alliance/NN/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O offers/VBZ/O distribution/NN/O possibilities/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O proposal/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O introduce/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O payment/NN/O system/NN/O for/IN/O parking/NN/O in/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Instead/RB/O of/IN/O paying/VBG/O for/IN/O parking/NN/O by/IN/O putting/VBG/O money/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O existing/VBG/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O deliver/VBP/O little/JJ/O paper/NN/O receipts/NNS/O ,/,/O drivers/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O electronic/JJ/O cards/NNS/O in/IN/O local/JJ/O tobacco/NN/O shops/NNS/O ././O
Once/RB/O activated/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O card/NN/O would/MD/O sit/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O car/NN/O 's/POS/O window/NN/O ,/,/O showing/VBG/O traffic/NN/O wardens/NNS/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O time/NN/O the/DT/O motorist/NN/O could/MD/O remain/VB/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O motorist/NN/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O car/NN/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O turn/VB/O the/DT/O card/NN/O off/RP/O and/CC/O ,/,/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O showed/VBD/O time/NN/O remaining/VBG/O ,/,/O save/VB/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O later/RB/O ././O
Seita/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O partner/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O developed/VBN/O by/IN/O Matra/NNP/B-ORG SA/NNP/I-ORG using/VBG/O Japanese/JJ/O technology/NN/O ././O
Seita/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Matra/NNP/B-ORG currently/RB/O are/VBP/O negotiating/VBG/O with/IN/O city/NN/O officials/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O service/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O Seita/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O further/JJ/O diversification/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG Nabisco/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG French/JJ/O cracker/NN/O subsidiary/NN/O ,/,/O Belin/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O hopes/NNS/O of/IN/O selling/VBG/O its/PRP$/O products/NNS/O in/IN/O tobacco/NN/O stores/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O lost/VBD/O the/DT/O bidding/NN/O to/TO/O food/NN/O group/NN/O BSN/NNP/B-ORG SA/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O currently/RB/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O bidding/VBG/O for/IN/O Swedish/NNP/B-ORG Match/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
And/CC/O it/PRP/O retains/VBZ/O an/DT/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O acquiring/VBG/O candies/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O articles/NNS/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O in/IN/O tobacco/NN/O shops/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O shore/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O tobacco/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O Seita/NNP/B-ORG retains/VBZ/O a/DT/O manufacturing/NN/O monopoly/NN/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O hurt/VBN/O by/IN/O rising/VBG/O imports/NNS/O and/CC/O from/IN/O waning/VBG/O cigarette/NN/O demand/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O aim/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O de/FW/B-PERSON Galle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O win/VB/O market/NN/O share/NN/O from/IN/O imported/VBN/O cigarettes/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O smokers/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O switching/VBG/O to/TO/O blonde/JJ/O cigarettes/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O buying/VBG/O French/JJ/O ././O
