He/PRP/O was/VBD/O all/RB/O too/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O ,/,/O inadequately/RB/O supervised/JJ/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O had/VBD/O spun/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O control/NN/O and/CC/O nearly/RB/O wrecked/VBD/O President/NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O second/JJ/O term/NN/O ././O
Gen./NNP/O Scowcroft/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O plan/VB/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O right/RB/O now/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O is/VBZ/O weighing/VBG/O that/DT/O possibility/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O official/NN/O adds/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG itself/PRP/O was/VBD/O established/VBN/O in/IN/O 1947/CD/O because/IN/O policy/NN/O makers/NNS/O sensed/VBD/O a/DT/O need/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O increasingly/RB/O complex/JJ/O world/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O a/DT/O formal/JJ/O system/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O that/IN/O communications/NNS/O flowed/VBD/O smoothly/RB/O between/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O intelligence/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O task/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O perennial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O insist/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE crisis/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O had/VBD/O just/RB/O resigned/VBN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O feud/NN/O with/IN/O Assistant/NNP/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Bernard/NNP/B-PERSON Aronson/NNP/I-PERSON over/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O policy/NN/O on/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O support/NN/O for/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Contra/JJ/O rebels/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O absence/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Briggs/NNP/B-PERSON underscored/VBD/O the/DT/O possible/JJ/O inadequacy/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O confidants/NNS/O of/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
