With/IN/O the/DT/O dust/NN/O settling/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O failed/VBN/O coup/NN/O attempt/NN/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O many/JJ/O lingering/VBG/O questions/NNS/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O will/MD/O ponder/VB/O is/VBZ/O this/DT/O :/:/O Is/VBZ/O the/DT/O National/NNP/B-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG staff/NN/O big/JJ/O enough/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O does/VBZ/O it/PRP/O have/VB/O enough/JJ/O clout/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O do/VB/O its/PRP$/O job/NN/O of/IN/O coordinating/VBG/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O ?/./O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O adviser/NN/O ,/,/O Lt./NNP/O Gen./NNP/O Brent/NNP/B-PERSON Scowcroft/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O came/VBD/O into/IN/O office/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O intent/JJ/O on/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O leaner/JJR/O and/CC/O more/RBR/O disciplined/JJ/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O all/RB/O too/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O ,/,/O inadequately/RB/O supervised/JJ/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O had/VBD/O spun/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O control/NN/O and/CC/O nearly/RB/O wrecked/VBD/O President/NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O second/JJ/O term/NN/O ././O
So/RB/O ,/,/O following/VBG/O both/DT/O the/DT/O style/NN/O he/PRP/O pursued/VBD/O as/IN/O President/NNP/O Ford/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O adviser/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O recommendations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Tower/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Gen./NNP/O Scowcroft/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O pruned/VBN/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O and/CC/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O sticks/VBZ/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O assigned/JJ/O tasks/NNS/O --/:/O namely/RB/O ,/,/O gathering/VBG/O the/DT/O views/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O intelligence/NN/O community/NN/O ;/:/O serving/VBG/O as/IN/O an/DT/O honest/JJ/O broker/NN/O in/IN/O distilling/VBG/O that/DT/O information/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O making/VBG/O sure/JJ/O presidential/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O are/VBP/O carried/VBN/O out/RB/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE episode/NN/O has/VBZ/O raised/VBN/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O is/VBZ/O sufficiently/RB/O big/JJ/O ,/,/O diverse/JJ/O and/CC/O powerful/JJ/O to/TO/O coordinate/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE policy/NN/O on/IN/O tough/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O coup/NN/O attempt/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O aftermath/NN/O ,/,/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staffers/NNS/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O stretched/VBN/O very/RB/O thin/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O senior/JJ/O administration/NN/O official/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O very/RB/O small/JJ/O shop/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Gen./NNP/O Scowcroft/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O plan/VB/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O right/RB/O now/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O is/VBZ/O weighing/VBG/O that/DT/O possibility/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O official/NN/O adds/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O problem/NN/O with/IN/O this/DT/O administration/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O by/IN/O design/NN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O greatly/RB/O diminished/VBN/O ,/,/O both/DT/O in/IN/O a/DT/O physical/JJ/O sense/NN/O and/CC/O in/IN/O a/DT/O procedural/JJ/O sense/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O role/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG itself/PRP/O was/VBD/O established/VBN/O in/IN/O 1947/CD/O because/IN/O policy/NN/O makers/NNS/O sensed/VBD/O a/DT/O need/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O increasingly/RB/O complex/JJ/O world/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O a/DT/O formal/JJ/O system/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O that/IN/O communications/NNS/O flowed/VBD/O smoothly/RB/O between/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O intelligence/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O law/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O council/NN/O includes/VBZ/O the/DT/O president/NN/O ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O secretaries/NNS/O of/IN/O state/NN/O and/CC/O defense/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O practice/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O central/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O and/CC/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Joint/NNP/I-ORG Chiefs/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Staff/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O serve/VBP/O as/IN/O unofficial/JJ/O members/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O size/NN/O ,/,/O shape/NN/O and/CC/O role/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O left/VBN/O for/IN/O each/DT/O president/NN/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O adviser/NN/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O ././O
That/DT/O task/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O perennial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O staff/NN/O of/IN/O professional/JJ/O officers/NNS/O is/VBZ/O down/RP/O to/TO/O about/IN/O 50/CD/O from/IN/O about/IN/O 70/CD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O insist/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE crisis/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O one/CD/O clear/JJ/O problem/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O coup/NN/O attempt/NN/O was/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staffer/NN/O most/RBS/O experienced/JJ/O in/IN/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O Everett/NNP/B-PERSON Briggs/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O gone/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O had/VBD/O just/RB/O resigned/VBN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O feud/NN/O with/IN/O Assistant/NNP/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Bernard/NNP/B-PERSON Aronson/NNP/I-PERSON over/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O policy/NN/O on/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O support/NN/O for/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Contra/JJ/O rebels/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O absence/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Briggs/NNP/B-PERSON underscored/VBD/O the/DT/O possible/JJ/O inadequacy/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O confidants/NNS/O of/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O neither/DT/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O extensive/JJ/O background/NN/O in/IN/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O the/DT/B-LOC Middle/NNP/I-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC or/CC/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC ././O
In/IN/O those/DT/O areas/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O role/NN/O of/IN/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staffers/NNS/O under/IN/O them/PRP/O therefore/RB/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O more/RBR/O important/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O just/RB/O as/IN/O every/DT/O previous/JJ/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG adviser/NN/O has/VBZ/O ,/,/O Gen./NNP/B-PERSON Scowcroft/NNP/I-PERSON now/RB/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O mull/VB/O at/IN/O what/WDT/O point/NN/O the/DT/O NSC/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O becomes/VBZ/O too/RB/O lean/JJ/O and/CC/O too/RB/O restrained/JJ/O ././O
