A/DT/O former/JJ/O Sperry/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG marketing/VBG/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O admitting/VBG/O his/PRP$/O role/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG procurement/JJ/O scandal/NN/O ,/,/O pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O bribery/NN/O and/CC/O conspiracy/NN/O charges/NNS/O for/IN/O helping/VBG/O funnel/VB/O $/$/O 400,000/CD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O midlevel/JJ/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG acquisition/NN/O official/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/NNS/O ././O
Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lavelle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O marketing/VBG/O director/NN/O for/IN/O Sperry/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Clearwater/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Fla./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O admitted/VBD/O participating/VBG/O in/IN/O a/DT/O scheme/NN/O to/TO/O bribe/VB/O Garland/NNP/B-PERSON Tomlin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bribery/NN/O scheme/NN/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O between/IN/O 1982/CD/O and/CC/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O documents/NNS/O filed/VBN/O by/IN/O prosecutors/NNS/O in/IN/O connection/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lavelle/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O guilty/JJ/O plea/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O district/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Alexandria/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Sperry/NNP/B-ORG merged/VBD/O with/IN/O Burroughs/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O become/VB/O Unisys/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O late/JJ/O 1986/CD/O ././O
Court/NN/O documents/NNS/O filed/VBN/O by/IN/O prosecutors/NNS/O indicate/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Tomlin/NNP/B-PERSON tried/VBD/O to/TO/O steer/VB/O to/TO/O Sperry/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O multimillion/JJ/O dollar/NN/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O computerize/VB/O maintenance/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG electronics/NNS/O equiment/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tomlin/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O illegally/RB/O provided/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Lavelle/NNP/B-PERSON with/IN/O inside/JJ/O information/NN/O and/CC/O documents/NNS/O intended/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O Sperry/NNP/B-ORG an/DT/O unfair/JJ/O advantage/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O competition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O documents/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Sperry/NNP/B-ORG ultimately/RB/O was/VBD/O eliminated/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O competition/NN/O without/IN/O receiving/VBG/O the/DT/O work/NN/O ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Gardner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Unisys/NNP/B-ORG vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Neal/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O company/NN/O consultant/NN/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O admitted/VBN/O participating/VBG/O in/IN/O this/DT/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O bribery/NN/O schemes/NNS/O ././O
Unisys/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O that/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O officials/NNS/O who/WP/O participated/VBD/O in/IN/O improper/JJ/O activities/NNS/O have/VBP/O left/VBN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lavelle/NNP/B-PERSON faces/VBZ/O a/DT/O maximum/NN/O of/IN/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O jail/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O fine/NN/O ././O
