Guardian/NNP/B-ORG Royal/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Assurance/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O British/JJ/O composite/JJ/O insurer/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O a/DT/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Nationwide/NNP/B-ORG Anglia/NNP/I-ORG Building/NNP/I-ORG Society/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG estate/NN/O agency/NN/O business/NN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O create/VB/O a/DT/O range/NN/O of/IN/O commercial/JJ/O linkages/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Officials/NNS/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O or/CC/O the/DT/O exact/JJ/O stake/NN/O that/IN/O GRE/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O hold/VB/O in/IN/O Nationwide/NNP/B-ORG Anglia/NNP/I-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG Agents/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Nationwide/NNP/B-ORG Anglia/NNP/I-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG Agents/NNPS/I-ORG will/MD/O market/VB/O GRE/NNP/B-ORG life/NN/O insurance/NN/O ,/,/O pension/NN/O and/CC/O investment/NN/O products/NNS/O through/IN/O its/PRP$/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 1,000/CD/O retail/JJ/O outlets/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.K/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Besides/IN/O the/DT/O marketing/NN/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O GRE/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Nationwide/NNP/B-ORG Anglia/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O life/NN/O insurance/NN/O products/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O composite/JJ/O insurer/NN/O ././O
