David/NNP/B-PERSON Baltimore/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O just/RB/O been/VBN/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O already/RB/O knows/VBZ/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O like/JJ/O to/TO/O go/VB/O through/IN/O life/NN/O with/IN/O ``/``/O Nobel/NNP/O laureate/NN/O ''/''/O appended/VBN/O to/TO/O one/PRP/O 's/POS/O name/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O currently/RB/O experiencing/VBG/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O like/JJ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O phrase/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O under/IN/O investigation/NN/O for/IN/O scientific/JJ/O fraud/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O also/RB/O attached/VBN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O name/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Nobel/NNP/O committee/NN/O made/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O addition/NN/O ;/:/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Dingell/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON congressional/JJ/O committee/NN/O created/VBD/O the/DT/O second/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O of/IN/O Dr./NNP/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O public/JJ/O faces/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O view/NN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O while/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O under/IN/O consideration/NN/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O Joshua/NNP/B-PERSON Lederberg/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O prestigious/JJ/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG research/NN/O institution/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O light/VB/O that/IN/O a/DT/O substantial/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O faculty/NN/O were/VBD/O upset/JJ/O over/IN/O or/CC/O even/RB/O opposed/VBN/O to/TO/O Dr./NNP/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O impending/VBG/O appointment/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O were/VBD/O disturbed/VBN/O at/IN/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O regarded/VBD/O as/IN/O Dr./NNP/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O confrontational/JJ/O attitude/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O Dingell/NNP/B-PERSON committee/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O held/VBD/O hearings/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O dispute/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O lab/NN/O notebooks/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O researcher/NN/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O co-authored/VBN/O a/DT/O scientific/JJ/O paper/NN/O with/IN/O Dr./NNP/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Rep./NNP/O Dingell/NNP/B-PERSON even/RB/O managed/VBD/O to/TO/O enlist/VB/O the/DT/O services/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Secret/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O his/PRP$/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON paper/NN/O ././O
Insofar/RB/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dingell/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O institutions/NNS/O that/WDT/O receive/VBP/O its/PRP$/O funding/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG scientists/NNS/O were/VBD/O no/DT/O doubt/RB/O discomfited/JJ/O by/IN/O Dr./NNP/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O unflattering/JJ/O public/JJ/O opinion/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O congressional/JJ/O patron/NN/O ,/,/O whose/WP$/O behavior/NN/O reminded/VBD/O Dr./NNP/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/O McCarthy/NNP/B-PERSON era/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O well/RB/O may/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O venerable/JJ/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O brushed/VBN/O up/RB/O publicly/RB/O against/IN/O the/DT/O intimidations/NNS/O now/RB/O common/JJ/O in/IN/O American/JJ/O science/NN/O ././O
Scientists/NNS/O are/VBP/O mistaken/VBN/O who/WP/O still/RB/O think/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O anti-science/JJ/O movement/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O their/PRP$/O concern/NN/O or/CC/O that/IN/O a/DT/B-PERSON David/NNP/I-PERSON Baltimore/NNP/I-PERSON could/MD/O have/VB/O somehow/RB/O placated/VBN/O a/DT/B-PERSON John/NNP/I-PERSON Dingell/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Dingell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O by/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O decreed/VBN/O another/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG investigation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Baltimore/NNP/B-PERSON paper/NN/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O to/TO/O several/JJ/O previous/JJ/O investigations/NNS/O ././O
Something/NN/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O what/WP/O most/JJS/O scientists/NNS/O would/MD/O recognize/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O truth/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O sought/VBN/O here/RB/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Fortunately/RB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O signs/NNS/O that/IN/O increasing/VBG/O numbers/NNS/O of/IN/O scientists/NNS/O understand/VBP/O the/DT/O necessity/NN/O of/IN/O speaking/VBG/O out/RB/O ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Hubel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Nobel/NNP/O laureate/NN/O at/IN/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O the/DT/O lead/NN/O in/IN/O defending/VBG/O research/NN/O with/IN/O animals/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O has/VBZ/O Dr./NNP/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON DeBakey/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
NASA/NNP/B-ORG defended/VBD/O itself/PRP/O vigorously/RB/O and/CC/O successfully/RB/O against/IN/O a/DT/O Rifkin/NNP/B-PERSON suit/NN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O the/DT/O Galileo/NNP/O launch/NN/O ././O
Scientists/NNS/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O understand/VB/O that/IN/O while/IN/O they/PRP/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O believe/VB/O their/PRP$/O work/NN/O is/VBZ/O primarly/RB/O about/IN/O establishing/VBG/O new/JJ/O knowledge/NN/O or/CC/O doing/VBG/O good/JJ/O ,/,/O today/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O about/IN/O power/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O a/DT/B-PERSON David/NNP/I-PERSON Baltimore/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O or/CC/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O target/NN/O --/:/O decides/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O better/JJR/O to/TO/O stand/VB/O up/RP/O to/TO/O these/DT/O forces/NNS/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O fellow/JJ/O scientists/NNS/O would/MD/O do/VB/O well/RB/O to/TO/O recognize/VB/O what/WP/O is/VBZ/O fundamentally/RB/O at/IN/O stake/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O offer/VB/O their/PRP$/O public/JJ/O support/NN/O ././O
