If/IN/O the/DT/O request/NN/O is/VBZ/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Cheney/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O need/VB/O only/JJ/O permission/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O move/VB/O the/DT/O money/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG budget/NN/O analysts/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O give/VB/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG flexibility/NN/O that/IN/O no/DT/O other/JJ/O federal/JJ/O agency/NN/O has/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O simply/RB/O a/DT/O way/NN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O cuts/NNS/O less/RBR/O onerous/JJ/O for/IN/O defense/NN/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O for/IN/O domestic/JJ/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Chairman/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Sasser/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Tenn/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O oppose/VB/O the/DT/O request/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O president/NN/O 's/POS/O request/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O indicate/VB/O how/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Cheney/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O shift/VB/O the/DT/O money/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O request/NN/O was/VBD/O made/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O the/DT/O department/NN/O ``/``/O maximum/JJ/O flexibility/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O deal/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O cuts/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Budget/NNP/B-ORG Director/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Darman/NNP/I-PERSON structured/VBD/O the/DT/O $/$/O 16.1/CD/O billion/CD/O spending/NN/O reduction/NN/O ,/,/O half/NN/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O must/MD/O come/VB/O from/IN/O defense/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O ``/``/O impose/VB/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O bit/NN/O more/JJR/O discipline/NN/O ''/''/O by/IN/O applying/VBG/O cuts/NNS/O to/TO/O each/DT/O individual/JJ/O program/NN/O ,/,/O project/NN/O or/CC/O activity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O give/VB/O agencies/NNS/O ``/``/O less/JJR/O ability/NN/O .../:/O to/TO/O fudge/VB/O over/RP/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O ././O
