Your/PRP$/O Oct./NNP/O 2/CD/O article/NN/O on/IN/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Yankelovich/NNP/I-PERSON cited/VBD/O the/DT/O quote/NN/O ``/``/O A/DT/O good/JJ/O name/NN/O is/VBZ/O better/JJR/O than/IN/O great/JJ/O riches/NNS/O ''/''/O as/IN/O being/VBG/O from/IN/O Cervantes/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O ``/``/O Don/NNP/O Quixote/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
Actually/RB/O ,/,/O Cervantes/NNP/B-PERSON borrowed/VBD/O that/IN/O quote/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O writer/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O 25/CD/O centuries/NNS/O earlier/RB/O :/:/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O King/NNP/O Solomon/NNP/B-PERSON wrote/VBD/O those/DT/O words/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Book/NN/O of/IN/O Proverbs/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O 22:1/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Hill/NNP/I-PERSON
