CRI/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O reduced/VBD/O the/DT/O estimated/VBN/O cash/NN/O distribution/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Housing/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Partners/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG trust/NN/O to/TO/O between/IN/O 71/CD/O cents/NNS/O and/CC/O 74/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O ,/,/O from/IN/O between/IN/O 75/CD/O cents/NNS/O and/CC/O 80/CD/O cents/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ending/VBG/O June/NNP/O 9/CD/O ,/,/O 1990/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O change/NN/O in/IN/O expected/JJ/O cash/NN/O distributions/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Champs/NNP/B-ORG real/JJ/O estate/NN/O investment/NN/O trust/NN/O stems/VBZ/O from/IN/O a/DT/O revised/VBN/O estimate/NN/O of/IN/O administrative/JJ/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Jay/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Cohen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Champs/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
