The/DT/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Reproductive/NNP/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O illustrates/VBZ/O how/WRB/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG rulings/NNS/O often/RB/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O ripple/JJ/O effect/NN/O ,/,/O spreading/VBG/O into/IN/O areas/NNS/O of/IN/O law/NN/O and/CC/O policy/NN/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O actual/JJ/O cases/NNS/O decided/VBN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O never/RB/O were/VBD/O contemplated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O justices/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O preamble/NN/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O human/JJ/O life/NN/O begins/VBZ/O at/IN/O conception/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O unborn/JJ/O children/NNS/O have/VBP/O rights/NNS/O protected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Constitution/NNP/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O in/IN/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE said/VBD/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O was/VBD/O unconstitutional/JJ/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O an/DT/O earlier/JJR/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ruling/NN/O that/IN/O states/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O justify/VB/O stricter/JJR/O abortion/NN/O curbs/NNS/O by/IN/O changing/VBG/O the/DT/O definition/NN/O of/IN/O when/WRB/O life/NN/O begins/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O majority/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O up/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O state/NN/O courts/NNS/O for/IN/O now/RB/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O definition/NN/O has/VBZ/O any/DT/O bearing/NN/O on/IN/O other/JJ/O state/NN/O laws/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O protesters/NNS/O said/VBD/O their/PRP$/O actions/NNS/O were/VBD/O justified/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O save/VB/O the/DT/O lives/NNS/O of/IN/O unborn/JJ/O children/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O her/PRP$/O appeal/NN/O was/VBD/O argued/VBN/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Missouri/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Appeals/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O her/PRP$/O lawyer/NN/O also/RB/O relied/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O ././O
Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 1973/CD/O decision/NN/O that/WDT/O recognized/VBD/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O right/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Mario/NNP/B-PERSON Mandina/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Kansas/NNP/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG Lawyers/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O abortion/NN/O foes/NNS/O succeed/VBP/O in/IN/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O to/TO/O escape/VB/O prosecution/NN/O for/IN/O trespass/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O This/DT/O will/MD/O shut/VB/O down/RP/O abortion/NN/O in/IN/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O ironic/JJ/O result/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O case/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG expressly/RB/O stopped/VBD/O short/RB/O of/IN/O overruling/VBG/O Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
A/DT/O Boone/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE judge/NN/O rejected/VBD/O the/DT/O motion/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Dodson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Jefferson/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O appealed/VBN/O ././O
