Aim/NNP/B-ORG Prime/NNP/I-ORG Rate/NNP/I-ORG Plus/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Allied/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG II/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 6,500,000/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Cyanamid/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 1,250,000/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Chemex/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceuticals/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 1,200,000/CD/O units/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/O ././O
Immune/NNP/B-ORG Response/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O Three/CD/O million/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Marsam/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceuticals/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 1,300,000/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Smith/NNP/B-ORG Barney/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/I-ORG Harris/NNP/I-ORG Upham/NNP/I-ORG ././O
RMI/NNP/B-ORG Titanium/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Tidewater/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O 4,631,400/CD/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O Approximately/RB/O $/$/O 230/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O general/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O consolidated/JJ/O loan/NN/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O Series/NN/O D/NNP/O ,/,/O via/IN/O competitive/JJ/O bid/NN/O ././O
Montgomery/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O general/JJ/O consolidated/JJ/O public/JJ/O improvement/NN/O bonds/NNS/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O Series/NN/O B/NNP/O ,/,/O via/IN/O competitive/JJ/O bid/NN/O ././O
Trinity/NNP/B-ORG River/NNP/I-ORG Authority/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 134,750,000/CD/O of/IN/O regional/JJ/O wastewater/NN/O system/NN/O improvement/NN/O revenue/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O Series/NN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O via/IN/O competitive/JJ/O bid/NN/O ././O
Broward/NNP/B-ORG County/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG District/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 185/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O school/NN/O district/NN/O general/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O ././O
Michigan/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 80/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O Michigan/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG general/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O $/$/O 70/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O environmental/JJ/O protection/NN/O project/NN/O bonds/NNS/O and/CC/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O recreation/NN/O project/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O ././O
West/NNP/B-ORG Virginia/NNP/I-ORG Parkways/NNPS/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Tourism/NNP/I-ORG Authority/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O $/$/O 143/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O parkway/NN/O revenue/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O Series/NN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG group/NN/O ././O
San/NNP/B-GPE Antonio/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O $/$/O 640/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O gas/NN/O and/CC/O electric/JJ/O revenue/NN/O refunding/VBG/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O via/IN/O a/DT/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O ././O
