Chicago/NNP/B-GPE businessmen/NNS/O Bertram/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Lee/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Bynoe/NNP/I-PERSON signed/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O the/DT/O Denver/NNP/B-ORG Nuggets/NNPS/I-ORG basketball/NN/O team/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O as/IN/O principal/JJ/O owners/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O Saturday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O partners/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O team/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O purchased/VBN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 54/CD/O million/CD/O by/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O group/NN/O including/VBG/O Comsat/NNP/B-ORG Video/NNP/I-ORG Enterprises/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Communications/NNPS/B-ORG Satellite/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG based/VBN/O here/RB/O ././O
Comsat/NNP/B-ORG Video/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O pay/VB/O $/$/O 17/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O 62.5/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O Messrs./NNPS/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Bynoe/NNP/B-PERSON putting/VBG/O up/RP/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O 37.5/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O team/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ,/,/O Nuggets/NNPS/B-ORG owner/NN/O Sidney/NNP/B-PERSON Shlenker/NNP/I-PERSON could/MD/O receive/VB/O up/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O additional/JJ/O payments/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O franchise/NN/O 's/POS/O future/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
Messrs./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Bynoe/NNP/B-PERSON last/JJ/O July/NNP/O announced/VBD/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O them/PRP/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O black/JJ/O principal/JJ/O owners/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O professional/JJ/O sports/NNS/O franchise/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O fell/VBD/O apart/RB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O for/IN/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O financing/NN/O ././O
Comsat/NNP/B-ORG Video/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Wussler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O his/PRP$/O No./NN/O 2/CD/O executive/NN/O post/NN/O with/IN/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG just/RB/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O Comsat/NNP/B-ORG position/NN/O ././O
