Both/DT/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Backer/NNP/B-ORG Spielvogel/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cigarette/NN/O account/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O severe/JJ/O blow/NN/O to/TO/O Wells/NNP/B-ORG Rich/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O account/NN/O billed/VBD/O almost/RB/O $/$/O 60/CD/O million/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Leading/VBG/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Advertisers/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O said/VBD/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O asked/VBN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O to/TO/O create/VB/O campaigns/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O the/DT/O brand/NN/O 's/POS/O slipping/VBG/O market/NN/O share/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O brand/NN/O is/VBZ/O No./NN/O 7/CD/O overall/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O cigarette/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Maxwell/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
That/DT/O ad/NN/O generated/VBD/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O publicity/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O trade/NN/O magazine/NN/O launched/VBD/O a/DT/O contest/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O readers/NNS/O to/TO/O guess/VB/O who/WP/O the/DT/O guy/NN/O was/VBD/O and/CC/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O doing/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O brand/NN/O early/RB/O on/RB/O achieved/VBD/O an/DT/O upscale/JJ/O appeal/NN/O --/:/O a/DT/O trait/NN/O that/IN/O some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O believe/VBP/O is/VBZ/O partly/RB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O staid/JJ/O performance/NN/O ././O
Wells/NNP/B-ORG Rich/NNP/I-ORG Greene/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O directed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Wells/NNP/I-PERSON Lawrence/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O emerged/VBD/O the/DT/O victor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O review/NN/O and/CC/O retained/VBD/O the/DT/O business/NN/O ././O
