Move/VB/O over/RB/O ,/,/O pornographic/JJ/O phone/NN/O services/NNS/O :/:/O A/DT/O legal/JJ/O service/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O 900/CD/O ''/''/O number/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O launched/VBN/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Though/IN/O the/DT/O service/NN/O is/VBZ/O available/JJ/O only/RB/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Telelawyer/NNP/O founder/NN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Cane/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O franchise/VB/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O other/JJ/O states/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O aim/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O bedridden/JJ/O ,/,/O have/VB/O no/DT/O access/NN/O to/TO/O transportation/NN/O ,/,/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O find/VB/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O their/PRP$/O case/NN/O or/CC/O simply/RB/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O afford/VB/O lawyers/NNS/O '/POS/O consultation/NN/O fees/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Cane/NNP/B-PERSON stresses/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O to/TO/O lure/VB/O clients/NNS/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O doorstep/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O will/MD/O only/RB/O deal/VB/O with/IN/O clients/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O phone/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Telelawyer/NNP/O is/VBZ/O apparently/RB/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O telephone/NN/O service/NN/O that/WDT/O offers/VBZ/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O equivalent/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O office/NN/O visit/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O whether/IN/O a/DT/O caller/NN/O has/VBZ/O reason/NN/O to/TO/O sue/VB/O ,/,/O Cane/NNP/B-ORG lawyers/NNS/O review/VBP/O documents/NNS/O and/CC/O perform/VBP/O research/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O necessary/JJ/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O help/NN/O of/IN/O three/CD/O law/NN/O clerks/NNS/O and/CC/O several/JJ/O support/NN/O staffers/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O charge/NN/O for/IN/O research/NN/O --/:/O only/RB/O for/IN/O time/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O phone/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O requires/VBZ/O further/JJ/O legal/JJ/O work/NN/O or/CC/O litigation/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Cane/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O lawyers/NNS/O may/MD/O refer/VB/O the/DT/O client/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O law/NN/O firm/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O firm/NN/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O about/IN/O 50/CD/O calls/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O average/JJ/O call/NN/O lasts/VBZ/O about/IN/O 15/CD/O minutes/NNS/O ././O
Out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 2/CD/O charge/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O law/NN/O firm/NN/O pockets/VBZ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 1.55/CD/O ././O
JURY/NN/O CONVICTS/VBZ/O congressman/NN/O in/IN/O connection/NN/O with/IN/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG scandal/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O jury/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE found/VBD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Rep./NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Garcia/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.Y/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Jane/NNP/B-PERSON Lee/NNP/I-PERSON Garcia/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O extorting/VBG/O $/$/O 76,000/CD/O from/IN/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O return/NN/O for/IN/O official/JJ/O acts/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O congressman/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O jury/NN/O found/VBD/O them/PRP/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O conspiracy/NN/O in/IN/O obtaining/VBG/O the/DT/O payments/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O were/VBD/O disguised/VBN/O as/IN/O fees/NNS/O for/IN/O consulting/NN/O services/NNS/O from/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Garcia/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Edward/NNP/B-PERSON J.M./NNP/I-PERSON Little/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O assistant/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorneys/NNS/O who/WP/O prosecuted/VBD/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Garcia/NNP/B-PERSON trial/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG prosecutions/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Little/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O people/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O convicted/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG cases/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O former/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Rep./NNP/O Mario/NNP/B-PERSON Biaggi/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.Y/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Lawyers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Garcias/NNPS/B-PERSON said/VBD/O they/PRP/O plan/VBP/O to/TO/O appeal/VB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Garcia/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE 18th/JJ/O congressional/JJ/O district/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O the/DT/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O decided/VBN/O whether/IN/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O resign/VB/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O consulting/VBG/O with/IN/O my/PRP$/O political/JJ/O advisers/NNS/O and/CC/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O way/NN/O of/IN/O preserving/VBG/O the/DT/O interests/NNS/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O constituents/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Garcia/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 56/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Garcia/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 49/CD/O ,/,/O formerly/RB/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Garcia/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O congressional/JJ/O staff/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Garcias/NNPS/B-PERSON were/VBD/O cleared/VBN/O of/IN/O four/CD/O other/JJ/O felony/NN/O counts/NNS/O ,/,/O involving/VBG/O the/DT/O receipt/NN/O of/IN/O bribes/NNS/O and/CC/O gratuities/NNS/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE Judge/NNP/O Leonard/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Sand/NNP/I-PERSON set/VBD/O the/DT/O Garcias/NNPS/B-PERSON '/POS/O sentencing/NN/O for/IN/O Jan./NNP/O 5/CD/O ././O
DISCIPLINARY/NN/O PROCEEDINGS/NNS/O against/IN/O lawyers/NNS/O open/JJ/O to/TO/O public/NN/O in/IN/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE ././O
While/IN/O investigations/NNS/O into/IN/O lawyer/NN/O misconduct/NN/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O secret/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O public/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O notified/VBN/O once/RB/O a/DT/O formal/JJ/O complaint/NN/O is/VBZ/O filed/VBN/O against/IN/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O actual/JJ/O disciplinary/JJ/O hearings/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O public/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE attorneys/NNS/O will/MD/O lose/VB/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O sue/VB/O clients/NNS/O who/WP/O file/VBP/O malicious/JJ/O complaints/NNS/O against/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
Non-lawyers/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O added/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O inquiry/NN/O panels/NNS/O that/WDT/O look/VBP/O into/IN/O allegations/NNS/O of/IN/O misconduct/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O publishing/VBG/O the/DT/O names/NNS/O of/IN/O lawyers/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O facing/VBG/O charges/NNS/O unnecessarily/RB/O subjects/VBZ/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O public/JJ/O derogation/NN/O ././O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lupel/NNP/B-PERSON anticipates/VBZ/O no/DT/O legal/JJ/O action/NN/O to/TO/O reverse/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Illinois/NNP/I-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG decision/NN/O to/TO/O institute/VB/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O right/NN/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O rule/NN/O change/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O practice/VB/O ././O
You/PRP/O only/RB/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O privilege/NN/O to/TO/O practice/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O Delaware/NNP/B-GPE office/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE firm/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O negotiating/VBG/O settlements/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O freely/RB/O nationwide/RB/O despite/IN/O its/PRP$/O record/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O admitted/VBN/O felon/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O firm/NN/O has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O $/$/O 11.5/CD/O million/CD/O overall/NN/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O with/IN/O states/NNS/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O to/TO/O six/CD/O felony/NN/O counts/NNS/O of/IN/O securities/NNS/O and/CC/O mail/NN/O fraud/NN/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 650/CD/O million/CD/O civil/JJ/O settlement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
