Nora/NNP/B-PERSON Worth/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON DeWitt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 33/CD/O and/CC/O 39/CD/O respectively/RB/O ,/,/O live/VBP/O together/RB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O townhouse/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O transitional/JJ/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE neighborhood/NN/O ././O
Nora/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O artistic/JJ/O aspirations/NNS/O ,/,/O knows/VBZ/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O lucky/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O working/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O food/NN/O stylist/NN/O ,/,/O prepping/VBG/O pies/NNS/O ,/,/O burgers/NNS/O ,/,/O frosty/JJ/O cold/JJ/O drinks/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O comestibles/NNS/O to/TO/O look/VB/O as/RB/O appetizing/JJ/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O in/IN/O front/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O camera/NN/O ././O
Uncertainty/NN/O dogs/VBZ/O every/DT/O aspect/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O lives/NNS/O ././O
Malcolm/NN/B-PERSON faces/VBZ/O bankruptcy/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG audit/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Nora/NNP/B-PERSON finds/VBZ/O an/DT/O extra/JJ/O $/$/O 30,000/CD/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O bank/NN/O account/NN/O ,/,/O suddenly/RB/O increasing/VBG/O her/PRP$/O available/JJ/O funds/NNS/O some/DT/O fifteenfold/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O characters/NNS/O confront/VBP/O a/DT/O world/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O increasingly/RB/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O middle/JJ/O way/NN/O ''/''/O between/IN/O the/DT/O extremes/NNS/O of/IN/O success/NN/O and/CC/O failure/NN/O ,/,/O wealth/NN/O and/CC/O poverty/NN/O ././O
Patrician/NN/O ,/,/O dynamic/JJ/O Scott/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O founder/NN/O and/CC/O head/NN/O of/IN/O PegaSys/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O initially/RB/O finds/VBZ/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O threat/NN/O risible/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Garber/NNP/B-PERSON depicts/VBZ/O these/DT/O moral/JJ/O qualities/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O broad/JJ/O brush/NN/O strokes/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O satire/NN/O that/WDT/O occasionally/RB/O descends/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O realm/NN/O of/IN/O cliched/JJ/O caricatures/NNS/O ././O
