Wisconsin/NNP/B-ORG Toy/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O definitively/RB/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O closely/RB/O held/JJ/O Everything/NNP/B-ORG 's/VBZ/I-ORG a/DT/I-ORG Dollar/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O stock/NN/O currently/RB/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 4.7/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Milwaukee/NNP/B-GPE toy/NN/O retailer/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O Everything/NNP/B-ORG 's/VBZ/I-ORG a/DT/I-ORG Dollar/NNP/I-ORG holders/NNS/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O holdings/NNS/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O 354,600/CD/O newly/RB/O issued/VBN/O Wisconsin/NNP/B-ORG Toy/NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O ././O
Wisconsin/NNP/B-ORG Toy/NNP/I-ORG currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O about/IN/O 4.7/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O company/NN/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON Borie/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O until/IN/O January/NNP/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Pic/NNP/B-ORG 'N/CC/I-ORG Save/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O buy/VB/O a/DT/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O Wisconsin/NNP/B-ORG Toy/NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O will/MD/O act/VB/O as/IN/O head/NN/O of/IN/O Everything/NNP/B-ORG 's/VBZ/I-ORG a/DT/I-ORG Dollar/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Wisconsin/NNP/B-ORG Toy/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O 71/CD/O retail/JJ/O stores/NNS/O ,/,/O primarily/RB/O in/IN/O discount/NN/O settings/NNS/O ././O
