When/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG upheld/VBD/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O abortion/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O last/JJ/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O justices/NNS/O almost/RB/O certainly/RB/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O drunk/JJ/O driving/NN/O ,/,/O trespassing/NN/O and/CC/O false/JJ/O imprisonment/NN/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O minds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Reproductive/NNP/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O illustrates/VBZ/O how/WRB/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG rulings/NNS/O often/RB/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O ripple/JJ/O effect/NN/O ,/,/O spreading/VBG/O into/IN/O areas/NNS/O of/IN/O law/NN/O and/CC/O policy/NN/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O actual/JJ/O cases/NNS/O decided/VBN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O never/RB/O were/VBD/O contemplated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O justices/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE case/NN/O ,/,/O unforeseen/JJ/O consequences/NNS/O may/MD/O have/VB/O arisen/VBN/O because/IN/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O reinstated/VBD/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O 1986/CD/O abortion/NN/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O preamble/NN/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O human/JJ/O life/NN/O begins/VBZ/O at/IN/O conception/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O unborn/JJ/O children/NNS/O have/VBP/O rights/NNS/O protected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Constitution/NNP/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O in/IN/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE said/VBD/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O was/VBD/O unconstitutional/JJ/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O an/DT/O earlier/JJR/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ruling/NN/O that/IN/O states/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O justify/VB/O stricter/JJR/O abortion/NN/O curbs/NNS/O by/IN/O changing/VBG/O the/DT/O definition/NN/O of/IN/O when/WRB/O life/NN/O begins/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG concluded/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O premature/JJ/O to/TO/O rule/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O constitutionality/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O because/IN/O the/DT/O definition/NN/O of/IN/O human/JJ/O life/NN/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O been/VBN/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O restrict/VB/O abortion/NN/O services/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O majority/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O up/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O state/NN/O courts/NNS/O for/IN/O now/RB/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O definition/NN/O has/VBZ/O any/DT/O bearing/NN/O on/IN/O other/JJ/O state/NN/O laws/NNS/O ././O
Already/RB/O ,/,/O local/JJ/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE judges/NNS/O have/VBP/O relied/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O restored/VBN/O preamble/NN/O in/IN/O two/CD/O separate/JJ/O cases/NNS/O to/TO/O throw/VB/O out/RP/O criminal/JJ/O trespass/NN/O charges/NNS/O against/IN/O anti-abortion/JJ/O demonstrators/NNS/O who/WP/O blocked/VBD/O access/NN/O to/TO/O Reproductive/NNP/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O abortion/NN/O clinic/NN/O in/IN/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O protesters/NNS/O said/VBD/O their/PRP$/O actions/NNS/O were/VBD/O justified/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O save/VB/O the/DT/O lives/NNS/O of/IN/O unborn/JJ/O children/NNS/O ././O
Under/IN/O a/DT/O 1981/CD/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE law/NN/O ,/,/O persons/NNS/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O crimes/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O trespassing/NN/O ,/,/O may/MD/O offer/VB/O a/DT/O defense/NN/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O actions/NNS/O were/VBD/O justified/JJ/O ``/``/O as/IN/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O measure/NN/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O an/DT/O imminent/JJ/O public/NN/O or/CC/O private/JJ/O injury/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Relying/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O 's/POS/O statement/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O fetus/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O unborn/JJ/O child/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O St./NNP/B-ORG Louis/NNP/I-ORG County/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG judges/NNS/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O accepted/VBD/O the/DT/O justification/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O clinic/NN/O protesters/NNS/O were/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O save/VB/O lives/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O another/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O protester/NN/O ,/,/O Ann/NNP/B-PERSON O'Brien/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O trespass/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Webster/NNP/B-PERSON ruling/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O her/PRP$/O appeal/NN/O was/VBD/O argued/VBN/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Missouri/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Appeals/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O her/PRP$/O lawyer/NN/O also/RB/O relied/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O effect/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG Webster/NNP/B-PERSON opinion/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O left/VBD/O room/NN/O for/IN/O grass/NN/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O cracks/NNS/O of/IN/O Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cracks/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON Belz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE lawyer/NN/O who/WP/O represented/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O O'Brien/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE protesters/NNS/O ././O
Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 1973/CD/O decision/NN/O that/WDT/O recognized/VBD/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O right/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Mario/NNP/B-PERSON Mandina/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Kansas/NNP/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG Lawyers/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O abortion/NN/O foes/NNS/O succeed/VBP/O in/IN/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O preamble/NN/O to/TO/O escape/VB/O prosecution/NN/O for/IN/O trespass/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O This/DT/O will/MD/O shut/VB/O down/RP/O abortion/NN/O in/IN/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O risk/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O protesters/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O keep/VB/O an/DT/O abortion/NN/O clinic/NN/O open/JJ/O if/IN/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O 3,000/CD/O people/NNS/O standing/VBG/O outside/IN/O every/DT/O day/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O ironic/JJ/O result/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O case/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG expressly/RB/O stopped/VBD/O short/RB/O of/IN/O overruling/VBG/O Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O possible/JJ/O consequences/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ruling/NN/O appear/VBP/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O unintended/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O Boone/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE judge/NN/O rejected/VBD/O the/DT/O motion/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Dodson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Jefferson/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O appealed/VBN/O ././O
And/CC/O in/IN/O a/DT/O case/NN/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O is/VBZ/O arguing/VBG/O that/IN/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE authorities/NNS/O are/VBP/O wrongfully/RB/O imprisoning/VBG/O the/DT/O fetus/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O pregnant/JJ/O woman/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O jail/NN/O for/IN/O theft/NN/O and/CC/O forgery/NN/O ././O
