This/DT/O business/NN/O trust/NN/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O board/NN/O elected/VBD/O Kieran/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Burke/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O to/TO/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O post/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O as/IN/O president/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Burke/NNP/B-PERSON succeeds/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Manley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O men/NNS/O were/VBD/O unavailable/JJ/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O named/VBN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Gellert/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O director/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O shareholder/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O the/DT/O vacant/JJ/O seat/NN/O of/IN/O chairman/NN/O ././O
