The/DT/B-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Thrift/NNP/I-ORG Supervision/NNP/I-ORG banned/VBD/O B.J./NNP/B-PERSON Garman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O failed/VBN/O Vision/NNP/B-ORG Banc/NNP/I-ORG Savings/NNPS/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Kingsville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O from/IN/O working/VBG/O in/IN/O any/DT/O financial/JJ/O institution/NN/O insured/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
Generally/RB/O ,/,/O regulators/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O announced/VBN/O enforcement/NN/O actions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O OTS/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O took/VBD/O effect/NN/O Aug./NNP/O 9/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O banned/VBD/O another/DT/O ``/``/O key/JJ/O Vision/NNP/B-ORG Banc/NNP/I-ORG insider/NN/O ''/''/O from/IN/O insured/JJ/O financial/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O individual/JJ/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O identified/VBN/O ././O
Vision/NNP/B-ORG Banc/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O placed/VBN/O in/IN/O government/NN/O conservatorship/NN/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O operates/VBZ/O under/IN/O the/DT/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Resolution/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O created/VBN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O or/CC/O liquidate/VB/O insolvent/JJ/O thrifts/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O OTS/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O specifically/RB/O why/WRB/O the/DT/O action/NN/O was/VBD/O taken/VBN/O against/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Garman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O said/VBD/O examiners/NNS/O found/VBD/O a/DT/O variety/NN/O of/IN/O insider/NN/O dealings/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O ``/``/O extraordinary/JJ/O loan/NN/O commissions/NNS/O ''/''/O paid/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O firm/NN/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O Vision/NNP/B-ORG Banc/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O loans/NNS/O diverted/VBN/O through/IN/O borrowers/NNS/O back/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Garman/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
