That/DT/O total/NN/O was/VBD/O below/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 140/CD/O million/CD/O the/DT/O auction/NN/O house/NN/O estimated/VBD/O the/DT/O collection/NN/O might/MD/O sell/VB/O for/IN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O was/VBD/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O that/IN/O an/DT/O unprecedented/JJ/O financial/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O Sotheby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG had/VBD/O made/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Dorrance/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O proved/VBD/O profitable/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O auction/NN/O house/NN/O ././O
Sotheby/NNP/B-ORG 's/VBZ/O provided/VBD/O the/DT/O Dorrance/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O a/DT/O guarantee/NN/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 120/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O obtain/VB/O the/DT/O collection/NN/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O taking/VBG/O a/DT/O greater/JJR/O than/IN/O usual/JJ/O financial/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O property/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O Dorrance/NNP/B-PERSON estate/NN/O ,/,/O auctioned/VBN/O off/RP/O in/IN/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O held/VBN/O over/IN/O four/CD/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O included/VBD/O porcelains/NNS/O ,/,/O furniture/NN/O and/CC/O paintings/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/B-PERSON Henri/NNP/I-PERSON Matisse/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O auctioned/VBN/O last/JJ/O Wednesday/NNP/O ,/,/O fetched/VBD/O $/$/O 12.4/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O world/NN/O record/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O artist/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O paintings/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Dorrance/NNP/B-PERSON collection/NN/O remain/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O at/IN/O Sotheby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG annual/JJ/O old/JJ/O masters/NNS/O paintings/NNS/O auction/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
