Groupe/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG chairman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Belgian/JJ/O insurer/NN/O is/VBZ/O prepared/JJ/O to/TO/O give/VB/O up/RP/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O independence/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O white/JJ/O knight/NN/O if/IN/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O repel/VB/O a/DT/O raider/NN/O ././O
Amid/IN/O heavy/JJ/O buying/NN/O of/IN/O shares/NNS/O in/IN/O Belgium/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O insurer/NN/O ,/,/O Maurice/NNP/B-PERSON Lippens/NNP/I-PERSON also/RB/O warned/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O white/JJ/O knight/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O buying/VBG/O out/RP/O a/DT/O raider/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O leave/VB/O speculators/NNS/O with/IN/O big/JJ/O losses/NNS/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O AG/NNP/B-ORG stock/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O the/DT/O beginning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O has/VBZ/O nearly/RB/O doubled/VBN/O ,/,/O giving/VBG/O AG/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O market/NN/O value/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 105/CD/O billion/CD/O Belgian/JJ/O francs/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 2.7/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O likely/JJ/O white/JJ/O knight/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG Generale/NNP/I-ORG de/FW/I-ORG Belgique/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O already/RB/O owns/VBZ/O 18/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O AG/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O which/WDT/O itself/PRP/O is/VBZ/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Cie/NNP/B-ORG ././I-ORG Financiere/NNP/I-ORG de/FW/I-ORG Suez/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O acquisitive/JJ/O French/JJ/O financial/JJ/O conglomerate/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Lippens/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O a/DT/O rescue/NN/O also/RB/O could/MD/O involve/VB/O Asahi/NNP/B-ORG Mutual/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O AG/NNP/B-ORG ././O
AG/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O hardly/RB/O alone/RB/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O anxiety/NN/O ././O
Worried/JJ/O by/IN/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG directives/NNS/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O remove/VB/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O barriers/NNS/O to/TO/O cross-border/JJ/O insurance/NN/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O starting/VBG/O in/IN/O mid-1990/NN/O ,/,/O insurers/NNS/O are/VBP/O rushing/VBG/O to/TO/O find/VB/O partners/NNS/O and/CC/O preparing/VBG/O for/IN/O price/NN/O wars/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNPS/B-GPE ,/,/O insurers/NNS/O are/VBP/O flirting/VBG/O with/IN/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lippens/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O shares/NNS/O changing/VBG/O hands/NNS/O has/VBZ/O grown/VBN/O significantly/RB/O since/IN/O mid-September/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O estimated/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O raider/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O amass/VB/O no/DT/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 4/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shares/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O have/VBP/O all/DT/O ``/``/O very/RB/O clearly/RB/O stated/VBN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O not/RB/O acquired/VBN/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O acquiring/VBG/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O AG/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Any/DT/O raider/NN/O would/MD/O find/VB/O it/PRP/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O crack/VB/O AG/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O battlements/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O ``/``/O syndicate/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O shareholders/NNS/O holds/VBZ/O just/RB/O under/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O AG/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lippens/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O members/NNS/O have/VBP/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O one/NN/O another/DT/O the/DT/O right/NN/O of/IN/O first/JJ/O refusal/NN/O should/MD/O they/PRP/O sell/VBP/O any/DT/O AG/NNP/B-ORG shares/NNS/O ././O
Aside/RB/O from/IN/O Generale/NNP/B-ORG de/FW/I-ORG Belgique/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Asahi/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O syndicate/NN/O includes/VBZ/O Antwerpsche/NNP/B-ORG Hypotheekkas/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Belgian/JJ/O savings/NN/O bank/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O various/JJ/O family/NN/O interests/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O Generale/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O confirmed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O giant/JJ/O Belgian/JJ/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O AG/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O a/DT/O raider/NN/O seek/VB/O control/NN/O ././O
Asahi/NNS/B-ORG officials/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O without/IN/O bid/NN/O talk/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O surge/NN/O in/IN/O prices/NNS/O for/IN/O Brussels/NNP/B-GPE real/JJ/O estate/NN/O has/VBZ/O excited/VBN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O AG/NNP/B-ORG ././O
