Businessland/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O purchased/VBD/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O regional/JJ/O computer/NN/O retailer/NN/O ,/,/O Data/NNPS/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Centre/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Springfield/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Data/NNPS/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG has/VBZ/O five/CD/O retail/JJ/O stores/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O northeast/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O specializes/VBZ/O in/IN/O selling/VBG/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O big/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE metropolitan/JJ/O area/NN/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzsimmons/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Data/NNPS/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O was/VBD/O profitable/JJ/O and/CC/O expected/VBD/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Businessland/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O operates/VBZ/O stores/NNS/O in/IN/O 50/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE metropolitan/JJ/O areas/NNS/O ,/,/O planned/VBD/O to/TO/O absorb/VB/O his/PRP$/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O operations/NNS/O ././O
