A/DT/O major/JJ/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE newspaper/NN/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O department/NN/O store/NN/O concern/NN/O is/VBZ/O planning/VBG/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O about/IN/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ././O
Campeau/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O 's/POS/O owner/NN/O ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O report/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O service/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O identify/VB/O its/PRP$/O Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG sources/NNS/O ././O
Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O available/JJ/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O early/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O morning/NN/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Campeau/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Campeau/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O annual/JJ/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O valued/VBD/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG at/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE confirmed/VBD/O that/IN/O Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG Store/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O approached/VBN/O by/IN/O representatives/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O management/NN/O committee/NN/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Mr./NNP/O Traub/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG does/VBZ/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 1.2/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O accuses/VBZ/O the/DT/O retailer/NN/O and/CC/O several/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O officers/NNS/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O false/JJ/O and/CC/O misleading/JJ/O statements/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O business/NN/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O material/JJ/O adverse/JJ/O information/NN/O about/IN/O its/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O Campeau/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O seen/VBN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
