Law/NN/O firms/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O feasted/VBN/O and/CC/O grown/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O mergers/NNS/O and/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O work/NN/O are/VBP/O feeling/VBG/O the/DT/O squeeze/NN/O as/IN/O that/DT/O work/NN/O declines/VBZ/O ././O
While/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O too/RB/O early/JJ/O to/TO/O tell/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O dearth/NN/O of/IN/O takeover/NN/O activity/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O temporary/JJ/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O say/VBP/O their/PRP$/O firms/NNS/O are/VBP/O bracing/VBG/O for/IN/O lower/JJR/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O merger/NN/O work/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O so/RB/O lucrative/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ././O
Much/RB/O of/IN/O this/DT/O work/NN/O was/VBD/O done/VBN/O for/IN/O higher/JJR/O fees/NNS/O than/IN/O other/JJ/O legal/JJ/O work/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O generally/RB/O billed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O hour/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O deals/NNS/O take/VBP/O longer/RBR/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O and/CC/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O fewer/JJR/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O bill/VB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O premium/NN/O as/IN/O when/WRB/O deals/NNS/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O from/IN/O start/NN/O to/TO/O finish/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O lawyer/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE firm/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O settling/VBG/O down/RP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O less/RBR/O active/JJ/O period/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O Everyone/NN/O is/VBZ/O waiting/VBG/O to/TO/O see/VB/O if/IN/O deals/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O done/VBN/O at/IN/O sensible/NN/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O if/IN/O money/NN/O is/VBZ/O available/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Nusbaum/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O co-chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Willkie/NNP/B-ORG Farr/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O right/RB/O now/RB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O change/NN/O is/VBZ/O fundamental/JJ/O or/CC/O cyclical/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O slump/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O more/RBR/O obvious/JJ/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O began/VBD/O earlier/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O transactions/NNS/O are/VBP/O taking/VBG/O a/DT/O much/RB/O longer/JJR/O time/NN/O to/TO/O conclude/VB/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O fall/VBP/O apart/RP/O for/IN/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O financing/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O more/RBR/O stringent/JJ/O scrutiny/NN/O by/IN/O state/NN/O courts/NNS/O ././O
Lawyers/NNS/O also/RB/O say/VBP/O an/DT/O erratic/JJ/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O and/CC/O uncertain/JJ/O financing/NN/O conditions/NNS/O have/VBP/O sharply/RB/O reduced/VBN/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O lucrative/JJ/O big/JJ/O deals/NNS/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O proposed/VBN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O mergers/NNS/O slowdown/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O affected/VBN/O foreign/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O domestic/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O European/JJ/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O American/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON King/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O managing/NN/O partner/NN/O at/IN/O that/DT/O firm/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O the/DT/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O things/NNS/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O will/MD/O actually/RB/O surface/VB/O in/IN/O live/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O in/IN/O light/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O market/NN/O conditions/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O the/DT/O trial/NN/O of/IN/O former/JJ/O Haas/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Eugene/NNP/B-PERSON Laff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O defense/NN/O accused/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O witnesses/NNS/O of/IN/O threatening/VBG/O to/TO/O kill/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Lang/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O filed/VBD/O a/DT/O memorandum/NN/O asking/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O trial/NN/O record/NN/O include/VB/O a/DT/O secretly/RB/O taped/VBN/O conversation/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O witness/NN/O ,/,/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Lorin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O told/VBD/O a/DT/O Haas/NNP/B-ORG stockbroker/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O be/VB/O killed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O conversation/NN/O was/VBD/O taped/VBN/O by/IN/O federal/JJ/O investigators/NNS/O in/IN/O what/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O implicate/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O his/PRP$/O opening/VBG/O arguments/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O the/DT/O jury/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O real/JJ/O master/NN/O criminal/NN/O ''/''/O behind/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O manipulation/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON knew/VBD/O nothing/NN/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
In/IN/O March/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O indicted/VBN/O on/IN/O 15/CD/O counts/NNS/O of/IN/O conspiracy/NN/O ,/,/O mail/NN/O and/CC/O securities/NNS/O fraud/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O obstructing/VBG/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O charged/VBN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON were/VBD/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O conspiracy/NN/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O the/DT/O prices/NNS/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O at/IN/O artificially/RB/O high/JJ/O prices/NNS/O ././O
During/IN/O his/PRP$/O cross/NN/O examination/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON read/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O transcripts/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O conversation/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O taped/VBN/O Oct./NNP/O 20/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON Aslanian/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Haas/NNP/B-ORG broker/NN/O who/WP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O carry/VB/O a/DT/O hidden/JJ/O microphone/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O conversation/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O pleaded/VBN/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O conspiracy/NN/O to/TO/O commit/VB/O securities/NNS/O violations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O manipulation/NN/O and/CC/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O cooperate/VB/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O transcript/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O be/VB/O killed/VBN/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Aslanian/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O him/PRP/O that/IN/O information/NN/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON by/IN/O another/DT/O conspirator/NN/O could/MD/O jeopardize/VB/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O scheme/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON then/RB/O repeated/VBD/O the/DT/O threat/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Aslanian/NNP/B-PERSON urged/VBD/O him/PRP/O not/RB/O to/TO/O say/VB/O such/JJ/O things/NNS/O ././O
From/IN/O the/DT/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transcript/NN/O read/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O unclear/JJ/O what/WP/O exactly/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON feared/VBD/O might/MD/O happen/VB/O ././O
When/WRB/O asked/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O copy/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transcript/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Judge/NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON P./NNP/I-PERSON Griesa/NNP/I-PERSON had/VBD/O instructed/VBN/O him/PRP/O not/RB/O to/TO/O release/VB/O it/PRP/O or/CC/O the/DT/O memorandum/NN/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O trial/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON asked/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON whether/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O so/RB/O upset/JJ/O ``/``/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O considered/VBD/O killing/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON ?/./O .../:/O
Is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O it/PRP/O true/JJ/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O were/VBD/O so/RB/O worked/VBN/O up/RP/O that/IN/O framing/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON for/IN/O this/DT/O crime/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O planned/VBD/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON responded/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O No/UH/O ././O ''/''/O
When/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON asked/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Lorin/NNP/B-PERSON whether/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O taken/VBN/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O have/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Laff/NNP/B-PERSON killed/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O witness/NN/O again/RB/O said/VBD/O no/UH/O ././O
Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Lieb/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O assistant/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O prosecuting/VBG/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O trial/NN/O ././O
TRUSTEE/NN/O WHO/WP/O MONITORED/VBD/O settlement/NN/O payments/NNS/O to/TO/O Dalkon/NNP/O Shield/NNP/O claimants/NNS/O quits/VBZ/O ././O
Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Saltzburg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O five/CD/O trustees/NNS/O appointed/VBN/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O payments/NNS/O to/TO/O women/NNS/O injured/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Dalkon/NNP/O Shield/NNP/O intrauterine/JJ/O contraceptive/NN/O ,/,/O resigned/VBD/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O personal/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Saltzburg/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O teaches/VBZ/O evidence/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Virginia/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Law/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O deputy/NN/O assistant/NN/O attorney/NN/O general/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG until/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O submitted/VBD/O his/PRP$/O resignation/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O to/TO/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Merhige/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O Richmond/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O Monday/NNP/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Saltzburg/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O ``/``/O reluctantly/RB/O ''/''/O accept/VB/O the/DT/O resignation/NN/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG proposes/VBZ/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O remaining/VBG/O four/CD/O trustees/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Claimants/NNPS/O Trust/NNP/O have/VBP/O 60/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O nominate/VB/O a/DT/O successor/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Saltzburg/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Judge/NNP/O Merhige/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O make/VB/O the/DT/O appointment/NN/O ././O
CHICAGO/NNP/O LAW/NN/O FIRM/NN/O recruits/VBZ/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG vice/NN/O president/NN/O :/:/O
For/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Menell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 43/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O served/VBD/O as/IN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O government/NN/O affairs/NNS/O at/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O previously/RB/O was/VBD/O staff/NN/O director/NN/O and/CC/O counsel/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG committee/NN/O on/IN/O banking/NN/O ,/,/O housing/NN/O and/CC/O urban/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O lawyer/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O office/NN/O is/VBZ/O partner/NN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Macari/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O legislative/JJ/O director/NN/O ././O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Sherman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 42/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O advise/VB/O midsized/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sherman/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O former/JJ/O deputy/NN/O general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O for/IN/O SmithKline/NNP/B-ORG Beckman/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O now/RB/O SmithKline/NNP/B-ORG Beecham/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
