Delmed/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/O 's/POS/O top/JJ/O two/CD/O officers/NNS/O resigned/VBD/O and/CC/O were/VBD/O succeeded/VBN/O by/IN/O executives/NNS/O of/IN/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG holder/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O negotiating/VBG/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O a/DT/O controlling/JJ/O stake/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O and/CC/O sells/VBZ/O a/DT/O dialysis/NN/O solution/NN/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O treating/VBG/O kidney/NN/O diseases/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O negotiations/NNS/O about/IN/O pricing/NN/O had/VBD/O collapsed/VBN/O between/IN/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O distributor/NN/O ,/,/O National/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Care/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Delmed/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Ehrlich/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ehrlich/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O continue/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O ././O
Leslie/NNP/B-PERSON I./NN/I-PERSON Shapiro/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O resigned/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ehrlich/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O succeeded/VBN/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O by/IN/O Gerd/NNP/B-PERSON Krick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O pharmaceutical/JJ/O concern/NN/O ././O
Ben/NNP/B-PERSON Lipps/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O ././O
None/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O officials/NNS/O was/VBD/O available/JJ/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O trading/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG closed/VBD/O at/IN/O 50/CD/O cents/NNS/O ,/,/O down/RB/O 6.25/CD/O cents/NNS/O ././O
Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O about/IN/O 42/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O fully/RB/O diluted/JJ/O common/JJ/O stock/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O discussing/VBG/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O under/IN/O which/WDT/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O buy/VB/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG stock/NN/O for/IN/O cash/NN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O its/PRP$/O beneficial/JJ/O ownership/NN/O to/TO/O between/IN/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O fully/RB/O diluted/JJ/O common/JJ/O stock/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O also/RB/O would/MD/O combine/VB/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O issue/VB/O about/IN/O 123.5/CD/O million/CD/O additional/JJ/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O to/TO/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG at/IN/O an/DT/O average/JJ/O price/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 65/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O under/IN/O no/DT/O circumstances/NNS/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 75/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O explore/VB/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O combination/NN/O with/IN/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O apparent/JJ/O that/IN/O any/DT/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O combination/NN/O ``/``/O would/MD/O be/VB/O substantially/RB/O less/RBR/O favorable/JJ/O than/IN/O those/DT/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
While/IN/O the/DT/O discussions/NNS/O between/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O National/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Care/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O been/VBN/O discontinued/VBN/O ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O supply/VB/O dialysis/NN/O products/NNS/O through/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG after/IN/O their/PRP$/O exclusive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ends/NNS/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O exploring/VBG/O distribution/NN/O arrangements/NNS/O with/IN/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
