This/DT/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O Atsushi/NNP/B-PERSON Kageyama/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Manager/NNP/O 's/POS/O Journal/NNP/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Looking/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Real/JJ/O Thing/NN/O in/IN/O Sony/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O editorial/NN/O page/NN/O ,/,/O Oct./NNP/O 2/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Though/IN/O I/PRP/O agree/VBP/O with/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Kageyama/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O comments/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O he/PRP/O points/VBZ/O the/DT/O gun/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O direction/NN/O :/:/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O Americans/NNPS/O who/WP/O must/MD/O be/VB/O criticized/VBN/O for/IN/O not/RB/O understanding/VBG/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O culture/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O who/WP/O insist/VBP/O on/IN/O forcing/VBG/O their/PRP$/O culture/NN/O on/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O want/VBP/O us/PRP/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O their/PRP$/O culture/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O refuse/VBP/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O culture/NN/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O managers/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O Americans/NNPS/O to/TO/O behave/VB/O as/IN/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O Japanese/NNPS/O ;/:/O instead/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O must/MD/O manage/VB/O Americans/NNPS/O as/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O ././O
Americans/NNPS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O conform/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O culture/NN/O when/WRB/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
What/WP/O is/VBZ/O wrong/JJ/O with/IN/O expecting/VBG/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O to/TO/O conform/VB/O to/TO/O American/JJ/O norms/NNS/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O locate/VBP/O here/RB/O ?/./O
Americans/NNPS/O place/VBP/O native/JJ/O or/CC/O native/JJ/O speakers/NNS/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O subsidiaries/NNS/O overseas/RB/O ././O
European/JJ/O multinationals/NNS/O do/VBP/O likewise/RB/O ;/:/O even/RB/O in/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O their/PRP$/O affiliates/NNS/O are/VBP/O usually/RB/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O American/JJ/O managers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O insist/VBP/O upon/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O managers/NNS/O everywhere/RB/O they/PRP/O set/VBP/O up/RP/O shop/NN/O ././O
Do/VBP/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O feel/VB/O so/RB/O superior/JJ/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O find/VB/O capable/JJ/O American/JJ/O managers/NNS/O ?/./O
Paul/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Herbig/NNP/I-PERSON Indiana/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG Bloomington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ind/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kageyama/NNP/B-PERSON suggests/VBZ/O that/IN/O Kotobuki/NNP/B-ORG Electronics/NNPS/I-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG workers/NNS/O were/VBD/O having/VBG/O difficulty/NN/O understanding/VBG/O their/PRP$/O foreign/JJ/O bosses/NNS/O '/POS/O perspective/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Kageyama/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O an/DT/O excellent/JJ/O job/NN/O of/IN/O explaining/VBG/O the/DT/O differences/NNS/O ,/,/O both/DT/O cultural/JJ/O and/CC/O philosophic/JJ/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O question/VBP/O his/PRP$/O perspective/NN/O ././O
Would/MD/O he/PRP/O suggest/VB/O that/IN/O employees/NNS/O of/IN/O an/DT/O American/JJ/O company/NN/O doing/VBG/O business/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE conform/VB/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O new/JJ/O bosses/NNS/O '/POS/O culture/NN/O and/CC/O philosophy/NN/O ?/./O
Obviously/RB/O not/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O workers/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O motivated/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O reach/VB/O its/PRP$/O full/JJ/O potential/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O when/WRB/O management/NN/O embraces/VBZ/O the/DT/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O perspective/NN/O ././O
A./JJ/B-PERSON Lawton/NNP/I-PERSON Langford/NNP/I-PERSON President/NNP/O Municipal/NNP/B-ORG Code/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG Tallahassee/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Fla/NNP/B-GPE ././O
I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Kageyama/NNP/B-PERSON left/VBD/O out/RP/O one/CD/O major/JJ/O aspect/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O culture/NN/O that/WDT/O permeated/VBD/O his/PRP$/O piece/NN/O :/:/O the/DT/O belief/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O superiority/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O culture/NN/O and/CC/O behavior/NN/O vs./FW/O others/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O manager/NN/O should/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O rebut/VB/O the/DT/O opinions/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O employees/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O style/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O management/NN/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O should/MD/O listen/VB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O how/WRB/O that/DT/O criticism/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O constructively/RB/O to/TO/O advance/VB/O his/PRP$/O objective/NN/O of/IN/O carrying/VBG/O out/RP/O a/DT/O set/NN/O of/IN/O tasks/NNS/O through/IN/O the/DT/O efforts/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O subordinates/NNS/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O culture/NN/O vs./FW/O American/JJ/O culture/NN/O is/VBZ/O irrelevant/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O key/NN/O is/VBZ/O how/WRB/O a/DT/O manager/NN/O from/IN/O one/CD/O culture/NN/O can/MD/O motivate/VB/O employees/NNS/O from/IN/O another/DT/O ././O
For/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Kageyama/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O argue/VB/O that/IN/O American/JJ/O employees/NNS/O must/MD/O passively/RB/O accept/VB/O a/DT/O direct/JJ/O imposition/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O way/NN/O of/IN/O doing/VBG/O things/NNS/O is/VBZ/O outright/RB/O cultural/JJ/O chauvinism/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O order/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O are/VBP/O neglecting/VBG/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O synthesize/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O culture/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O fusion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O both/DT/O national/JJ/O cultures/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kageyama/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O accurate/JJ/O to/TO/O deny/VB/O a/DT/O specific/JJ/O anti-American/JJ/O bias/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O deny/VB/O a/DT/O general/JJ/O bigotry/NN/O in/IN/O seeing/VBG/O things/NNS/O only/RB/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O way/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O response/NN/O to/TO/O criticism/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O a/DT/O better/JJR/O explanation/NN/O of/IN/O policies/NNS/O without/IN/O altering/VBG/O the/DT/O reasons/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O convinced/JJ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Kageyama/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O still/RB/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O attack/VB/O the/DT/O root/NN/O cause/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O simply/RB/O treating/VBG/O symptoms/NNS/O ././O
Norman/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Owens/NNP/I-PERSON Tempe/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz/NNP/B-GPE ././O
