Rupert/NNP/B-PERSON Murdoch/NNP/I-PERSON acquired/VBD/O a/DT/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Grupo/NNP/B-ORG Zeta/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O Spanish/JJ/O magazine/NN/O and/CC/O newspaper/NN/O publisher/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O cash/NN/O injection/NN/O boosted/VBD/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O capital/NN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O four-fold/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 8.47/CD/O billion/CD/O pesetas/NNS/O from/IN/O 1.82/CD/O billion/CD/O pesetas/NNS/O ,/,/O greatly/RB/O enhancing/VBG/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O investments/NNS/O ,/,/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Chairman/NNP/O Antonio/NNP/B-PERSON Asensio/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O retain/VB/O a/DT/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O in/IN/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG ././O
