Maggie/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON must/MD/O be/VB/O doing/VBG/O something/NN/O right/RB/O ;/:/O her/PRP$/O political/JJ/O enemies/NNS/O are/VBP/O screaming/VBG/O louder/RBR/O than/IN/O ever/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O return/NN/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O excoriated/VBN/O from/IN/O Fleet/NNP/B-FAC Street/NNP/I-FAC to/TO/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O an/DT/O obstructionist/NN/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O disastrous/JJ/O farce/NN/O in/IN/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O screamed/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Manchester/NNP/I-ORG Guardian/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O She/PRP/O can/MD/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O be/VB/O trusted/VBN/O to/TO/O behave/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O civilised/JJ/O --/:/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O unflaky/JJ/O --/:/O fashion/NN/O when/WRB/O abroad/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Egad/UH/O ././O
Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Brian/NNP/B-PERSON Mulroney/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Hawke/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O paper/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O enraged/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG London/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O she/PRP/O had/VBD/O ``/``/O contravened/VBN/O protocol/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O usual/JJ/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O sin/NN/O was/VBD/O saying/VBG/O what/WP/O she/PRP/O thought/VBD/O ././O
She/PRP/O issued/VBD/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O statement/NN/O ,/,/O separating/VBG/O herself/PRP/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Commonwealth/NNP/B-ORG document/NN/O reasserting/VBG/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O value/NN/O of/IN/O imposing/VBG/O sanctions/NNS/O against/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE ././O
While/IN/O supporting/VBG/O the/DT/O Commonwealth/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O in/IN/O utterly/RB/O condemning/VBG/O apartheid/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O her/PRP$/O statement/NN/O urged/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O ``/``/O encourage/VB/O change/VB/O ''/''/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O inflict/VB/O further/JJ/O punishment/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O black/JJ/O population/NN/O ././O
Actually/RB/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O consensus/NN/O somewhere/RB/O on/IN/O sanctions/NNS/O :/:/O In/IN/O May/NNP/O a/DT/O Gallup/NNP/O Poll/NNP/O found/VBD/O that/DT/O most/JJS/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O blacks/NNS/O ,/,/O 85/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O oppose/VBP/O economic/JJ/O sanctions/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O once/RB/O again/RB/O gone/VBN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O grain/NN/O ././O
Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Mahathir/NNP/B-PERSON Mohamad/NNP/I-PERSON sniffed/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O If/IN/O everybody/NN/O else/RB/O puts/VBZ/O out/RP/O their/PRP$/O left/JJ/O foot/NN/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O put/VBP/O out/RP/O your/PRP$/O right/JJ/O foot/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O are/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O step/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O If/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O one/CD/O against/IN/O 48/CD/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O very/RB/O sorry/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O 48/CD/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O indeed/RB/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O one/CD/O opponent/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O throw/VB/O her/PRP/O off/RB/O political/JJ/O course/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O mysteriously/RB/O intractable/JJ/O inflation/NN/O problem/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O join/VB/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O chorus/NN/O that/IN/O as/IN/O one/CD/O proclaims/VBZ/O how/WRB/O offputting/JJ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON refuses/VBZ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O along/RP/O by/IN/O going/VBG/O along/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O refreshing/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O one/CD/O world/NN/O figure/NN/O who/WP/O knows/VBZ/O what/WP/O she/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O in/RB/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O inclined/VBN/O to/TO/O reflexively/RB/O compromise/VB/O those/DT/O beliefs/NNS/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON understands/VBZ/O better/RBR/O than/IN/O those/DT/O distressed/JJ/O at/IN/O her/PRP$/O style/NN/O that/IN/O ultimately/RB/O history/NN/O and/CC/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O voters/NNS/O will/MD/O decide/VB/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O right/JJ/O about/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O sanctioning/VBG/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE or/CC/O running/VBG/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O economy/NN/O ././O
