Rupert/NNP/B-PERSON Murdoch/NNP/I-PERSON acquired/VBD/O a/DT/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Grupo/NNP/B-ORG Zeta/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O Spanish/JJ/O magazine/NN/O and/CC/O newspaper/NN/O publisher/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Also/RB/O participating/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O was/VBD/O Servifilm/NNP/B-ORG Spain/NNP/I-ORG Cinematografica/NNP/I-ORG S.A/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O cash/NN/O injection/NN/O boosted/VBD/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O capital/NN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O four-fold/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 8.47/CD/O billion/CD/O pesetas/NNS/O from/IN/O 1.82/CD/O billion/CD/O pesetas/NNS/O ,/,/O greatly/RB/O enhancing/VBG/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O investments/NNS/O ,/,/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Following/VBG/O its/PRP$/O failure/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O a/DT/O license/NN/O for/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O first/JJ/O three/CD/O private/JJ/O television/NN/O stations/NNS/O ,/,/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O investment/NN/O opportunities/NNS/O in/IN/O communications/NNS/O and/CC/O publishing/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 30/CD/O billion/CD/O pesetas/NNS/O ,/,/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG publishes/VBZ/O over/IN/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O magazines/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O popular/JJ/O Tiempo/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Interviu/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Panorama/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O three/CD/O regional/JJ/O dailies/NNS/O ././O
Chairman/NNP/O Antonio/NNP/B-PERSON Asensio/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O retain/VB/O a/DT/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O in/IN/O Zeta/NNP/B-ORG ././O
