THE/DT/B-ORG BIG/NNP/I-ORG BOARD/NNP/I-ORG PLANS/VBZ/O to/TO/O launch/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O vehicle/NN/O for/IN/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O today/NN/O amid/IN/O growing/VBG/O controversy/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O practice/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O exchange/NN/O argues/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O product/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG temporarily/RB/O approved/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O help/VB/O ease/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O worsen/VB/O any/DT/O volatility/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
SEC/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O consider/VB/O imposing/VBG/O ``/``/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O halt/VB/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O during/IN/O sharp/JJ/O swings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Kemper/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG has/VBZ/O stopped/VBN/O executing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O stock/NN/O trades/NNS/O through/IN/O four/CD/O big/JJ/O securities/NNS/O firms/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O involvement/NN/O in/IN/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O Kemper/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O say/VBP/O is/VBZ/O ruining/VBG/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O trend/NN/O is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O proponents/NNS/O less/RBR/O optimistic/JJ/O a/DT/O tax/NN/O cut/NN/O will/MD/O pass/VB/O ././O
Bethlehem/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG profit/NN/O plunged/VBD/O 54/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O hurt/VBN/O by/IN/O higher/JJR/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O lower/JJR/O shipments/NNS/O to/TO/O key/JJ/O clients/NNS/O ././O
PS/NNP/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Hampshire/NNP/I-ORG received/VBD/O a/DT/O sweetened/VBN/O bid/NN/O from/IN/O another/DT/O suitor/NN/O ,/,/O United/NNP/B-PERSON Illuminating/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O which/WDT/O valued/VBD/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O proposal/NN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 2.29/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O apparently/RB/O topping/VBG/O all/DT/O others/NNS/O so/RB/O far/RB/O ././O
Financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O quieted/VBD/O ,/,/O with/IN/O stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O edging/VBG/O lower/RBR/O ,/,/O bonds/NNS/O inching/VBG/O up/RB/O and/CC/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O almost/RB/O unchanged/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG industrials/NNS/O closed/VBD/O off/RB/O 5.94/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O 2653.28/CD/O ././O
GM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Hughes/NNP/B-ORG Electronics/NNPS/I-ORG unit/NN/O said/VBD/O profit/NN/O slid/VBD/O 22/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O finance/NN/O unit/NN/O ,/,/O GMAC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O net/NN/O fell/VBD/O 3.1/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O EDS/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O profit/NN/O rose/VBD/O 16/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Campeau/NNP/B-ORG reportedly/RB/O may/MD/O receive/VB/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O offer/NN/O for/IN/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG from/IN/O Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG Store/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Campeau/NNP/B-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
UAL/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O pilots/NNS/O and/CC/O machinists/NNS/O unions/NNS/O appear/VBP/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O the/DT/O key/NN/O to/TO/O any/DT/O future/JJ/O takeover/NN/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O ././O
Provigo/NNP/B-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O all/DT/O non-food/JJ/O operations/NNS/O to/TO/O refocus/VB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O retail/NN/O and/CC/O wholesale/JJ/O grocery/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG expects/VBZ/O operating/VBG/O margins/NNS/O of/IN/O over/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O sharply/RB/O higher/JJR/O earnings/NNS/O per/IN/O share/NN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O ././O
Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG industrials/NNS/O 2653.28/CD/O ,/,/O off/RB/O 5.94/CD/O ;/:/O transportation/NN/O 1199.32/CD/O ,/,/O off/RB/O 11.38/CD/O ;/:/O utilities/NNS/O 216.49/CD/O ,/,/O up/RB/O 1.45/CD/O ././O
Dollar/NN/O :/:/O 141.52/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O 0.07/CD/O ;/:/O 1.8353/CD/O marks/NNS/O ,/,/O off/RB/O 0.0002/CD/O ././O
