Bosses/NNS/O have/VBP/O big/JJ/O ears/NNS/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O would/MD/O make/VB/O even/RB/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Bond/NNP/I-PERSON green/JJ/O with/IN/O envy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O practice/NN/O is/VBZ/O common/JJ/O at/IN/O catalog/NN/O ,/,/O insurance/NN/O and/CC/O phone/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O banks/NNS/O and/CC/O telemarketers/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O trade/NN/O groups/NNS/O and/CC/O worker/NN/O organizations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Workers/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O opposes/VBZ/O such/JJ/O monitoring/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O supervisors/NNS/O listen/VBP/O in/RB/O on/IN/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O calls/NNS/O each/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O firms/NNS/O monitor/VBP/O for/IN/O recordkeeping/NN/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
Businesses/NNS/O ``/``/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O verify/VB/O information/NN/O and/CC/O ensure/VB/O accuracy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Hiltunen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O media/NNS/O relations/NNS/O ././O
Shearson/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O taped/VBN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O institutional/JJ/O trading/NN/O desks/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O commodities/NNS/O and/CC/O futures/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O about/IN/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Both/DT/O companies/NNS/O stress/VBP/O that/IN/O employees/NNS/O know/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O recorded/VBN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O customer/NN/O conversations/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O taped/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Counter/NNP/I-ORG Spy/NNP/I-ORG Shop/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O offers/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O Secret/JJ/O Connection/NN/O ''/''/O attache/NN/O case/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O can/MD/O surreptitiously/RB/O record/VB/O conversations/NNS/O for/IN/O nine/CD/O hours/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O stretch/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O common/JJ/O use/NN/O of/IN/O spying/VBG/O devices/NNS/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O divorce/NN/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O private/JJ/O investigators/NNS/O ././O
Nine/CD/O states/NNS/O have/VBP/O introduced/VBN/O bills/NNS/O requiring/VBG/O that/IN/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O customers/NNS/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O monitoring/NN/O ././O
Two/CD/O bills/NNS/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG hope/VBP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O such/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O national/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O outlook/NN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O federal/JJ/O bills/NNS/O is/VBZ/O uncertain/JJ/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O remembering/VBG/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O defeat/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ACLU/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O worker/NN/O organizations/NNS/O back/VBP/O tighter/JJR/O laws/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O employers/NNS/O and/CC/O device/NN/O manufacturers/NNS/O object/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O powerful/JJ/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O represents/VBZ/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O telemarketers/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O instrumental/JJ/O in/IN/O derailing/VBG/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O bill/NN/O ././O
Spiegel/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O opposes/VBZ/O the/DT/O beeper/JJR/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O noise/NN/O it/PRP/O requires/VBZ/O would/MD/O interfere/VB/O with/IN/O customer/NN/O orders/NNS/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O irritation/NN/O and/CC/O even/JJ/O errors/NNS/O ././O
Laura/NNP/B-PERSON Dale/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O center/NN/O manager/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O catalog/NN/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O customer/NN/O order/NN/O center/NN/O in/IN/O Reno/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Nev./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O defends/VBZ/O monitoring/NN/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Bonomo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Nynex/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O company/NN/O needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O operators/NNS/O to/TO/O evaluate/VB/O performance/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O ././O
Federal/JJ/O wiretap/NN/O statutes/NNS/O recognize/VBP/O the/DT/O right/NN/O of/IN/O employers/NNS/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O for/IN/O evaluation/NN/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O CWA/NNP/B-ORG claims/VBZ/O that/IN/O monitoring/VBG/O not/RB/O only/RB/O infringes/VBZ/O on/IN/O employee/NN/O privacy/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O increases/VBZ/O stress/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O electronics/NNS/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O closely/RB/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O Dellums/NNP/B-PERSON bill/NN/O ././O
Radio/NNP/B-ORG Shack/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O policy/NN/O against/IN/O selling/VBG/O products/NNS/O if/IN/O a/DT/O salesperson/NN/O suspects/VBZ/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O illegally/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O voluntarily/RB/O stopped/VBD/O selling/VBG/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Big/JJ/O Ear/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O powerful/JJ/O microphone/NN/O ././O
