Quickview/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O filed/VBD/O a/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O against/IN/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O claiming/VBG/O patent/NN/O infringement/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O element/NN/O of/IN/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O popular/JJ/O HyperCard/NNP/O software/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O Minneapolis/NNP/B-GPE federal/JJ/O court/NN/O ,/,/O claims/VBZ/O that/IN/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG violated/VBD/O a/DT/O Quickview/NNP/B-ORG patent/NN/O that/WDT/O allows/VBZ/O computer/NN/O users/NNS/O to/TO/O display/VB/O ``/``/O only/JJ/O portions/NNS/O of/IN/O multiple/JJ/O fields/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O computer/NN/O screen/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O contents/NNS/O of/IN/O any/DT/O given/VBN/O field/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O HyperCard/NNP/O program/NN/O allows/VBZ/O users/NNS/O to/TO/O design/VB/O applications/NNS/O for/IN/O Macintosh/NNP/B-ORG computers/NNS/O without/IN/O having/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O hardcore/NN/O programmers/NNS/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O distributed/VBN/O with/IN/O every/DT/O Macintosh/NNP/B-ORG sold/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O popular/JJ/O computer/NN/O programs/NNS/O of/IN/O all/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O analysts/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Quickview/NNP/B-ORG suit/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O appear/VB/O to/TO/O bode/VB/O major/JJ/O difficulties/NNS/O for/IN/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Nonetheless/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O seeks/VBZ/O unspecified/JJ/O damages/NNS/O that/IN/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O for/IN/O Quickview/NNP/B-ORG claimed/VBD/O could/MD/O run/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O millions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Cupertino/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O the/DT/O case/NN/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O merit/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O HyperCard/NNP/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O infringe/VB/O ``/``/O any/DT/O valid/JJ/O claims/NNS/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Quickview/NNP/B-ORG patents/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O filed/VBD/O an/DT/O action/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O declaration/NN/O that/IN/O Quickview/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O claims/NNS/O are/VBP/O invalid/JJ/O ././O
