Toshiba/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O French/JJ/O marketing/NN/O concern/NN/O has/VBZ/O started/VBN/O operating/VBG/O under/IN/O the/DT/O aegis/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O subsidiary/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O formerly/RB/O handled/VBD/O all/DT/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O Toshiba/NNP/B-ORG electronic/JJ/O products/NNS/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
A/DT/O recent/JJ/O change/NN/O in/IN/O French/JJ/O law/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Toshiba/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O permitted/VBD/O formation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O semiconductor/NN/O marketing/NN/O arm/NN/O in/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ././O
