Amoco/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O install/VB/O two/CD/O platforms/NNS/O and/CC/O drill/VB/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 22/CD/O wells/NNS/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O oil/NN/O reserves/NNS/O it/PRP/O discovered/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Atlantic/NNP/I-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC about/IN/O 25/CD/O miles/NNS/O off/IN/O the/DT/O coast/NN/O of/IN/O Congo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Amoco/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O energy/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O operator/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O 43.75/CD/O %/NN/O working/VBG/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O partners/NNS/O include/VBP/O Hydro/NNP/B-ORG Congo/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Congolese/JJ/O state/NN/O oil/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Kuwait/NNP/B-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Exploration/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O a/DT/O 6.25/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O ././O
Production/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O about/IN/O 40,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O a/DT/O day/NN/O after/IN/O completion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O drilling/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
