PAPERS/NNS/O :/:/O
In/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Hartford/NNP/I-ORG Courant/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O facsimile/JJ/O edition/NN/O and/CC/O some/DT/O other/JJ/O newspapers/NNS/O are/VBP/O considering/VBG/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O ././O
WHO/WP/O 'S/VBZ/O NEWS/NNP/O :/:/O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON T./NNP/I-PERSON Carr/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O advertising/VBG/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Playboy/NNP/B-ORG magazine/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O publisher/NN/O of/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Lampoon/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Heavy/NNP/B-ORG Metal/NNP/I-ORG magazines/NNS/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Agoglia/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O editor/NN/O for/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Lampoon/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O Heavy/NNP/B-ORG Metal/NNP/I-ORG ././O
