As/IN/O a/DT/O presidential/JJ/O candidate/NN/O in/IN/O 1980/CD/O ,/,/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON forthrightly/RB/O expressed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O with/IN/O Rolling/NNP/B-ORG Stone/NNP/I-ORG magazine/NN/I-ORG published/VBN/O that/IN/O March/NNP/O ././O
What/WP/O did/VBD/O he/PRP/O think/VB/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG decision/NN/O legalizing/VBG/O abortion/NN/O ?/./O
``/``/O I/PRP/O happen/VBP/O to/TO/O think/VB/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O right/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O flatly/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON became/VBD/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON running/JJ/O mate/NN/O ././O
Suddenly/RB/O ,/,/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON the/DT/O pro-choice/JJ/O advocate/NN/O became/VBD/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON the/DT/O anti-abortionist/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O vacillation/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O end/VB/O there/RB/O ././O
Just/RB/O a/DT/O month/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON sternly/RB/O threatened/VBD/O to/TO/O veto/VB/O a/DT/O pending/VBG/O welfare/NN/O bill/NN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O provided/VBD/O any/DT/O abortion/NN/O funds/NNS/O ,/,/O except/IN/O to/TO/O save/VB/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O life/NN/O ././O
Then/RB/O ,/,/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O --/:/O declaring/VBG/O that/IN/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O any/DT/O conflict/NN/O over/IN/O this/DT/O ''/''/O --/:/O the/DT/O president/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O consider/VB/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O to/TO/O fund/VB/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O poor/JJ/O women/NNS/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O only/RB/O four/CD/O days/NNS/O after/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON resurrected/VBD/O the/DT/O veto/NN/O threat/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O support/VB/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O for/IN/O abortions/NNS/O except/IN/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O mother/NN/O 's/POS/O life/NN/O is/VBZ/O threatened/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O proclaimed/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O finally/RB/O vetoed/VBD/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O last/JJ/O weekend/NN/O ././O
So/RB/O what/WP/O does/VBZ/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON really/RB/O believe/VB/O ?/./O
The/DT/O answer/NN/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O murky/JJ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O get/VB/O this/DT/O popular/JJ/O president/NN/O in/IN/O trouble/NN/O with/IN/O each/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O increasingly/RB/O vocal/JJ/O ,/,/O increasingly/RB/O powerful/JJ/O sides/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O is/VBZ/O mistrust/NN/O and/CC/O criticism/NN/O from/IN/O all/RB/O around/RB/O ././O
Anti-abortion/JJ/O forces/NNS/O regard/VBP/O him/PRP/O as/IN/O at/IN/O best/RB/O an/DT/O uncertain/JJ/O ally/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O totally/RB/O geared/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O punitive/JJ/O position/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O plainly/RB/O uncomfortable/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O abortion/NN/O question/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O nine/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O striven/VBN/O to/TO/O convince/VB/O anti-abortion/JJ/O activists/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O stalwart/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O position/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ever/RB/O since/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Webster/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Reproductive/NNP/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG decision/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O changed/VBD/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O landscape/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O seemingly/RB/O has/VBZ/O tried/VBN/O just/RB/O as/RB/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O saying/VBG/O anything/NN/O more/JJR/O unless/IN/O pressed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O wall/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O Americans/NNPS/O still/RB/O agonize/VB/O over/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O personal/JJ/O feelings/NNS/O about/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O agonizing/JJ/O over/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O vacillate/VB/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O political/JJ/O risk/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O far/RB/O less/JJR/O if/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O drew/VBD/O a/DT/O firm/JJ/O line/NN/O and/CC/O hewed/VBD/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O experts/NNS/O insist/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O position/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O better/JJR/O off/RP/O to/TO/O stick/VB/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O than/IN/O to/TO/O move/VB/O around/RB/O very/RB/O much/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Republican/NNP/O strategist/NN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Sears/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O need/NN/O for/IN/O consistency/NN/O is/VBZ/O especially/RB/O acute/JJ/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sears/NNP/B-PERSON maintains/VBZ/O ,/,/O lacks/VBZ/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O ideological/JJ/O base/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O quickest/JJS/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O public/JJ/O attitudes/NNS/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O ever/RB/O seen/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O former/JJ/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON pollster/NN/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Wirthlin/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Ten/CD/O days/NNS/O ago/RB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O asked/VBN/O to/TO/O amplify/VB/O the/DT/O reasons/NNS/O behind/IN/O his/PRP$/O anti-abortion/JJ/O stance/NN/O ././O
Running/VBG/O for/IN/O president/NN/O in/IN/O early/JJ/O 1980/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O also/RB/O quoted/VBN/O as/IN/O supporting/VBG/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O for/IN/O abortions/NNS/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O ,/,/O incest/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O save/VB/O the/DT/O life/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mother/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O supporting/VBG/O the/DT/O landmark/NN/O Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./FW/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG decision/NN/O legalizing/VBG/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O opposed/VBD/O the/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O promising/JJ/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O ././O
As/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O running/NN/O mate/NN/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON plunged/VBD/O headlong/RB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O anti-abortion/JJ/O position/NN/O ,/,/O endorsing/VBG/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O outlawing/VBG/O abortion/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O acknowledged/VBD/O only/RB/O one/CD/O difference/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON --/:/O that/IN/O the/DT/O amendment/NN/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O have/VB/O exceptions/NNS/O for/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O to/TO/O save/VB/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O life/NN/O ././O
Throughout/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O sometimes/RB/O supporting/VBG/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O for/IN/O abortion/NN/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O and/CC/O sometimes/RB/O opposing/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG convention/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O again/RB/O came/VBD/O out/RP/O for/IN/O an/DT/O amendment/NN/O with/IN/O exceptions/NNS/O for/IN/O rape/NN/O ,/,/O incest/NN/O and/CC/O life/NN/O endangerment/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O rhetoric/NN/O gathered/VBD/O momentum/NN/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O rolled/VBD/O into/IN/O office/NN/O ,/,/O affirming/VBG/O his/PRP$/O ``/``/O firm/JJ/O support/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O cause/NN/O ''/''/O during/IN/O an/DT/O anti-abortion/JJ/O rally/NN/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O inauguration/NN/O last/JJ/O January/NNP/O ././O
He/PRP/O again/RB/O urged/VBD/O passage/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O outlawing/VBG/O abortion/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O ruled/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O began/VBD/O to/TO/O lower/VB/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O was/VBD/O handed/VBN/O down/RP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O vacationing/VBG/O president/NN/O dispatched/VBD/O Chief/NNP/O of/IN/O Staff/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Sununu/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O issue/VB/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O and/CC/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O answer/VB/O questions/NNS/O himself/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O did/VBD/O later/RB/O threaten/VB/O vetoes/NNS/O over/IN/O legislation/NN/O restoring/VBG/O the/DT/B-GPE District/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/I-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE right/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O tax/NN/O money/NN/O to/TO/O fund/NN/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O poor/JJ/O women/NNS/O and/CC/O over/IN/O restoring/VBG/O funding/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Nations/NNPS/I-ORG Population/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG ././O
What/WP/O few/JJ/O comments/NNS/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O initiated/VBN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O oblique/JJ/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O urging/VBG/O ``/``/O greater/JJR/O efforts/NNS/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O protection/NN/O of/IN/O human/JJ/O life/NN/O ''/''/O at/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O of/IN/O Catholic/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O in/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O likewise/RB/O avoided/VBN/O any/DT/O involvement/NN/O in/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O special/JJ/O legislative/JJ/O session/NN/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O anti-abortion/NN/O forces/NNS/O had/VBD/O regarded/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O key/JJ/O test/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O state/NN/O lawmakers/NNS/O to/TO/O toughen/VB/O abortion/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O session/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O enact/VB/O any/DT/O new/JJ/O curbs/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O see/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON trapped/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O neither/CC/O comfortable/JJ/O with/IN/O nor/CC/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O escape/VB/O ././O
Ken/NNP/B-PERSON Ruberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Republican/NNP/I-ORG Mainstream/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O party/NN/O moderates/NNS/O ,/,/O observes/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O administration/NN/O finds/VBZ/O itself/PRP/O in/IN/O an/DT/O ideological/JJ/O cul/NN/O de/IN/O sac/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O find/VB/O it/PRP/O difficult/JJ/O --/:/O if/IN/O not/RB/O impossible/JJ/O --/:/O to/TO/O get/VB/O itself/PRP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O ././O
