Keith/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Tucker/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O insurance/NN/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O concern/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tucker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 44/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Trivest/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Trivest/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O closely/RB/O held/JJ/O investment/NN/O companies/NNS/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE ././O
His/PRP$/O selection/NN/O increases/VBZ/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O to/TO/O 12/CD/O members/NNS/O ././O
Torchmark/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Samuel/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Upchurch/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 37/CD/O ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O selected/VBN/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O the/DT/O remainder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O term/NN/O vacated/VBN/O by/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON S.P./NNP/I-PERSON Samford/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O director/NN/O ././O
