U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O begin/VB/O visits/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O several/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O to/TO/O sites/NNS/O in/IN/O Austin/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE Springs/NNPS/I-GPE ,/,/O Colo./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Middletown/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O and/CC/O Phoenix/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Sanford/NNP/B-PERSON Kane/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O finalists/NNS/O were/VBD/O chosen/VBN/O from/IN/O among/IN/O 57/CD/O locations/NNS/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O financial/JJ/O ,/,/O business/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O life/NN/O considerations/NNS/O ././O
Conspicuous/JJ/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O absence/NN/O is/VBZ/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O several/JJ/O other/JJ/O California/NNP/B-GPE cities/NNS/O mounted/VBD/O major/JJ/O campaigns/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O to/TO/O woo/VB/O the/DT/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O founded/VBN/O last/JJ/O June/NNP/O by/IN/O seven/CD/O electronics/NNS/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O venture/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O announce/VB/O a/DT/O final/JJ/O site/NN/O by/IN/O late/JJ/O November/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kane/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O several/JJ/O other/JJ/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O join/VB/O some/DT/O time/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O completes/VBZ/O a/DT/O business/NN/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O probably/RB/O later/RBR/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
