International/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Davy/NNP/B-ORG McKee/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O London/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Davy/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O awarded/VBN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 55/CD/O million/CD/O contract/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG Corps/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Engineers/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/O the/DT/O closure/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Helen/NNP/B-LOC Kramer/NNP/I-LOC Landfill/NNP/I-LOC Superfund/NNP/I-LOC site/NN/O in/IN/O Mantua/NNP/B-GPE Township/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.J/NNP/B-GPE ././O
International/NNP/B-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O environmental/JJ/O management/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O includes/VBZ/O construction/NN/O of/IN/O slurry/NN/O walls/NNS/O ,/,/O gas/NN/O collection/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O multilayer/JJ/O cap/NN/O and/CC/O water/NN/O treatment/NN/O plant/NN/O ././O
