Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O consolidating/VBG/O control/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Asian/JJ/O operations/NNS/O under/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O organization/NN/O here/RB/O that/DT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O W./NNP/B-PERSON Wayne/NNP/I-PERSON Booker/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
These/DT/O functions/NNS/O are/VBP/O currently/RB/O performed/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Melbourne/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O headquarters/NN/O in/IN/O Dearborn/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich/NNP/B-GPE ././O
