Comments/NNS/O by/IN/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Greenspan/NNP/I-PERSON lent/VBD/O some/DT/O support/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O ended/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O lower/RBR/O against/IN/O most/JJS/O major/JJ/O currencies/NNS/O ././O
Traders/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O statements/NNS/O are/VBP/O ordinarily/RB/O cautious/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O especially/RB/O careful/JJ/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O any/DT/O jarring/JJ/O proclamations/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O fears/NNS/O about/IN/O equities/NNS/O still/RB/O unnerving/VBG/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O essential/JJ/O focus/NN/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O domestic/JJ/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O goals/NNS/O of/IN/O price/NN/O stability/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O stable/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O perhaps/RB/O his/PRP$/O most/RBS/O telling/JJ/O remark/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON termed/VBD/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE inflation/NN/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O around/IN/O 4.5/CD/O %/NN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O much/RB/O too/RB/O high/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ignored/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O that/DT/O inflation/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O brought/VBN/O down/RB/O ``/``/O close/RB/O to/TO/O zero/NN/O ''/''/O without/IN/O throwing/VBG/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O viewed/VBD/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O 's/POS/O comments/NNS/O as/IN/O an/DT/O indication/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O is/VBZ/O disinclined/VBN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O further/RBR/O in/IN/O the/DT/O near/JJ/O future/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O late/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE trading/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O 1.8353/CD/O marks/NNS/O ,/,/O down/RB/O from/IN/O 1.8355/CD/O marks/NNS/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O 141.52/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 141.45/CD/O yen/NNS/O late/JJ/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
Sterling/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.6145/CD/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.6055/CD/O late/JJ/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE currency/NN/O opened/VBN/O for/IN/O trading/NN/O at/IN/O 141.60/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O Wednesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE close/NN/O of/IN/O 141.55/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O traders/NNS/O forecast/VBP/O a/DT/O continuation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O bearish/JJ/O trend/NN/O and/CC/O predict/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE currency/NN/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O stuck/JJ/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O relatively/RB/O narrow/JJ/O ranges/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O near/JJ/O term/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O shift/VB/O lower/RBR/O ././O
But/CC/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Doug/NNP/B-PERSON Madison/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O corporate/JJ/O trader/NN/O with/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O short/JJ/O positions/NNS/O must/MD/O first/RB/O be/VB/O corrected/VBN/O ,/,/O spurring/VBG/O a/DT/O temporary/JJ/O upswing/NN/O ,/,/O before/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O can/MD/O turn/VB/O lower/RBR/O ././O
Market/NN/O participants/NNS/O hope/VBP/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O GNP/NNP/O report/NN/O will/MD/O offer/VB/O more/RBR/O substantial/JJ/O evidence/NN/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O analysts/NNS/O are/VBP/O quick/JJ/O to/TO/O point/VB/O out/RP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O figures/NNS/O may/MD/O overstate/VB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O 's/POS/O vigor/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O `/``/O r/NN/O '/''/O word/NN/O is/VBZ/O looming/VBG/O again/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O dealer/NN/O ,/,/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O persistent/JJ/O concern/NN/O among/IN/O some/DT/O market/NN/O analysts/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE economy/NN/O is/VBZ/O heading/VBG/O toward/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O slowdown/NN/O if/IN/O not/RB/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O reckon/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O quarter/NN/O 's/POS/O figures/NNS/O will/MD/O present/VB/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O accurate/JJ/O picture/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE economy/NN/O ,/,/O showing/VBG/O a/DT/O marked/JJ/O slowdown/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O sectors/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O housing/NN/O starts/NNS/O and/CC/O equities/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Commodity/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O gold/NN/O for/IN/O current/JJ/O delivery/NN/O settled/VBD/O at/IN/O $/$/O 369.10/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ,/,/O down/RB/O $/$/O 1.10/CD/O ././O
Estimated/VBN/O volume/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O light/JJ/O 1.7/CD/O million/CD/O ounces/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O early/JJ/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O gold/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 368.24/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ././O
