The/DT/O Montvale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O unit/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O operating/NN/O structure/NN/O ``/``/O creates/VBZ/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O focused/JJ/O and/CC/O responsive/JJ/O organization/NN/O geared/VBN/O to/TO/O effectively/RB/O managing/VBG/O the/DT/O size/NN/O and/CC/O scope/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O 's/POS/O current/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O consumer/NN/O brands/NNS/O unit/NN/O was/VBD/O absorbed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O photographic/JJ/O ,/,/O pharmaceutical/JJ/O and/CC/O chemical/NN/O concern/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O acquired/VBD/O Sterling/NNP/B-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O related/JJ/O matter/NN/O ,/,/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Black/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O consumer/NN/O brand/NN/O Minwax/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O group/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O household/NN/O products/NNS/O operating/VBG/O group/NN/O ././O
