Place/VB/O a/DT/O phone/NN/O order/NN/O through/IN/O most/JJS/O any/DT/O catalog/NN/O and/CC/O chances/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O clerk/NN/O who/WP/O answers/VBZ/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O the/DT/O only/RB/O one/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O ././O
Bosses/NNS/O have/VBP/O big/JJ/O ears/NNS/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ././O
Or/CC/O open/VB/O up/RP/O an/DT/O electronics/NNS/O magazine/NN/O and/CC/O peruse/VB/O the/DT/O ads/NNS/O for/IN/O sneaky/JJ/O tape/NN/O recorders/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O snooping/VBG/O gadgets/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O would/MD/O make/VB/O even/RB/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Bond/NNP/I-PERSON green/JJ/O with/IN/O envy/NN/O ././O
Eavesdropping/NN/O --/:/O both/DT/O corporate/JJ/O and/CC/O private/JJ/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O rise/NN/O ,/,/O thanks/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O proliferation/NN/O of/IN/O surveillance/NN/O technologies/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O New/JJ/O technologies/NNS/O are/VBP/O changing/VBG/O the/DT/O way/NN/O we/PRP/O deal/VBP/O with/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O and/CC/O the/DT/O way/NN/O we/PRP/O work/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Janlori/NNP/B-PERSON Goldman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O staff/NN/O attorney/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Civil/NNP/I-ORG Liberties/NNPS/I-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O expectation/NN/O of/IN/O confidentiality/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O eroded/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
On/IN/O the/DT/O corporate/JJ/O side/NN/O ,/,/O companies/NNS/O claim/VBP/O that/IN/O monitoring/VBG/O employee/NN/O phone/NN/O conversations/NNS/O is/VBZ/O both/DT/O legal/JJ/O and/CC/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O gauge/VB/O productivity/NN/O and/CC/O ensure/VB/O good/JJ/O service/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O practice/NN/O is/VBZ/O common/JJ/O at/IN/O catalog/NN/O ,/,/O insurance/NN/O and/CC/O phone/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O banks/NNS/O and/CC/O telemarketers/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O trade/NN/O groups/NNS/O and/CC/O worker/NN/O organizations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Workers/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O opposes/VBZ/O such/JJ/O monitoring/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O supervisors/NNS/O listen/VBP/O in/RP/O on/IN/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O calls/NNS/O each/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Among/IN/O companies/NNS/O saying/VBG/O they/PRP/O monitor/VBP/O employees/NNS/O are/VBP/O United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O United/NNP/B-ORG Parcel/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Nynex/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Spiegel/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O circulation/NN/O department/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O newspaper/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O firms/NNS/O monitor/VBP/O for/IN/O recordkeeping/NN/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
Businesses/NNS/O ``/``/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O verify/VB/O information/NN/O and/CC/O ensure/VB/O accuracy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Hiltunen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O media/NNS/O relations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE recently/RB/O bought/VBD/O the/DT/O Veritrac/NNP/O system/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O the/DT/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG cleanup/NN/O effort/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Shearson/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O taped/VBN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O institutional/JJ/O trading/NN/O desks/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O commodities/NNS/O and/CC/O futures/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O about/IN/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Both/DT/O companies/NNS/O stress/VBP/O that/IN/O employees/NNS/O know/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O recorded/VBN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O customer/NN/O conversations/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O taped/VBN/O ././O
Eavesdropping/NN/O by/IN/O individuals/NNS/O is/VBZ/O harder/JJR/O to/TO/O measure/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O devices/NNS/O are/VBP/O there/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O asking/NN/O ,/,/O whether/IN/O in/IN/O stores/NNS/O or/CC/O through/IN/O the/DT/O mail/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Counter/NNP/I-ORG Spy/NNP/I-ORG Shop/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O offers/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O Secret/JJ/O Connection/NN/O ''/''/O attache/NN/O case/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O can/MD/O surreptitiously/RB/O record/VB/O conversations/NNS/O for/IN/O nine/CD/O hours/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O stretch/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O common/JJ/O use/NN/O of/IN/O spying/VBG/O devices/NNS/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O divorce/NN/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O private/JJ/O investigators/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O tape/NN/O recordings/NNS/O to/TO/O uncover/VB/O ,/,/O say/VB/O ,/,/O infidelity/NN/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O admissible/JJ/O in/IN/O court/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O mean/VB/O leverage/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O ././O
Concerned/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O increased/JJ/O availability/NN/O of/IN/O surveillance/NN/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O heavier/JJR/O use/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O lawmakers/NNS/O have/VBP/O proposed/VBN/O laws/NNS/O addressing/VBG/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Nine/CD/O states/NNS/O have/VBP/O introduced/VBN/O bills/NNS/O requiring/VBG/O that/IN/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O customers/NNS/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O monitoring/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O four/CD/O states/NNS/O --/:/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Michigan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O have/VBP/O adopted/VBN/O rules/NNS/O that/IN/O all/DT/O parties/NNS/O involved/VBN/O must/MD/O consent/VB/O when/WRB/O phone/NN/O calls/NNS/O are/VBP/O recorded/VBN/O ././O
Two/CD/O bills/NNS/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG hope/VBP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O such/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O national/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O May/NNP/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Don/NNP/B-PERSON Edwards/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O introduced/VBD/O congressional/JJ/O legislation/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O require/VB/O an/DT/O audible/JJ/O beeping/NN/O during/IN/O any/DT/O employee/NN/O monitoring/NN/O ,/,/O warning/VBG/O people/NNS/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O heard/VBN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O The/DT/O legislation/NN/O is/VBZ/O similar/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O 1987/CD/O ``/``/O beeper/NN/O bill/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O defeated/VBN/O after/IN/O heavy/JJ/O lobbying/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O telemarketing/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
The/DT/O outlook/NN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O federal/JJ/O bills/NNS/O is/VBZ/O uncertain/JJ/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O remembering/VBG/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O defeat/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ACLU/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O worker/NN/O organizations/NNS/O back/VBP/O tighter/JJR/O laws/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O employers/NNS/O and/CC/O device/NN/O manufacturers/NNS/O object/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O sympathetic/JJ/O with/IN/O workers/NNS/O who/WP/O feel/VBP/O under/IN/O the/DT/O gun/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Barton/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Direct/NNP/I-ORG Marketing/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O lobbying/VBG/O strenuously/RB/O against/IN/O the/DT/O Edwards/NNP/B-PERSON beeper/NN/O bill/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O way/NN/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O find/VB/O out/RP/O how/WRB/O your/PRP$/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O doing/VBG/O is/VBZ/O by/IN/O listening/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O powerful/JJ/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O represents/VBZ/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O telemarketers/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O instrumental/JJ/O in/IN/O derailing/VBG/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O bill/NN/O ././O
Spiegel/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O opposes/VBZ/O the/DT/O beeper/JJR/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O noise/NN/O it/PRP/O requires/VBZ/O would/MD/O interfere/VB/O with/IN/O customer/NN/O orders/NNS/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O irritation/NN/O and/CC/O even/JJ/O errors/NNS/O ././O
Laura/NNP/B-PERSON Dale/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O center/NN/O manager/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O catalog/NN/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O customer/NN/O order/NN/O center/NN/O in/IN/O Reno/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Nev./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O defends/VBZ/O monitoring/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O like/VBP/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O up/RB/O and/CC/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O operators/NNS/O are/VBP/O achieving/VBG/O our/PRP$/O standards/NNS/O of/IN/O company/NN/O service/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Ms./NNP/O Dale/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O supervises/VBZ/O 350/CD/O operators/NNS/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Bonomo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Nynex/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O company/NN/O needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O operators/NNS/O to/TO/O evaluate/VB/O performance/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Sometimes/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O pull/VB/O someone/NN/O off/IN/O the/DT/O phones/NNS/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O training/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Federal/JJ/O wiretap/NN/O statutes/NNS/O recognize/VBP/O the/DT/O right/NN/O of/IN/O employers/NNS/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O employees/NNS/O '/POS/O for/IN/O evaluation/NN/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O viewed/VBN/O monitoring/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O best/RBS/O handled/VBN/O in/IN/O union/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O opponents/NNS/O ,/,/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O CWA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O say/VBP/O new/JJ/O laws/NNS/O are/VBP/O needed/VBN/O because/IN/O monitoring/NN/O is/VBZ/O heavily/RB/O concentrated/JJ/O in/IN/O service/NN/O industries/NNS/O and/CC/O 81/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O monitored/JJ/O workers/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O represented/VBN/O by/IN/O unions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O CWA/NNP/B-ORG claims/VBZ/O that/IN/O monitoring/VBG/O not/RB/O only/RB/O infringes/VBZ/O on/IN/O employee/NN/O privacy/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O increases/VBZ/O stress/NN/O ././O
Currently/RB/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O person/NN/O taping/VBG/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O party/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O conversation/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O all/RB/O right/JJ/O to/TO/O record/VB/O without/IN/O the/DT/O knowledge/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O person/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Intercepting/VBG/O other/JJ/O people/NNS/O 's/POS/O private/JJ/O conversations/NNS/O is/VBZ/O illegal/JJ/O and/CC/O punishable/JJ/O by/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O fines/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 10,000/CD/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
The/DT/O electronics/NNS/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O closely/RB/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O Dellums/NNP/B-PERSON bill/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O vendors/NNS/O contend/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O control/VB/O how/WRB/O their/PRP$/O products/NNS/O are/VBP/O used/VBN/O ././O
Radio/NNP/B-ORG Shack/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O policy/NN/O against/IN/O selling/VBG/O products/NNS/O if/IN/O a/DT/O salesperson/NN/O suspects/VBZ/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O illegally/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Everything/NN/O sold/VBD/O at/IN/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Shack/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O legal/JJ/O purpose/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Bernard/NNP/B-PERSON Appel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Tandy/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O studied/VBN/O the/DT/O Dellums/NNP/B-PERSON bill/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O requiring/VBG/O a/DT/O beeping/VBG/O tone/NN/O on/IN/O recorders/NNS/O ``/``/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ludicrous/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Shack/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O aware/JJ/O that/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O products/NNS/O are/VBP/O controversial/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O voluntarily/RB/O stopped/VBD/O selling/VBG/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Big/JJ/O Ear/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O powerful/JJ/O microphone/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O its/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O pick/VB/O up/RP/O rustlings/NNS/O and/CC/O flapping/VBG/O wings/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O meant/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O toy/NN/O for/IN/O children/NNS/O for/IN/O bird/NN/O watching/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Appel/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O getting/VBG/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O complaints/NNS/O that/IN/O people/NNS/O were/VBD/O using/VBG/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O eavesdrop/VB/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O neighbors/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
