Yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O vote/NN/O dealt/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O of/IN/O these/DT/O bills/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 156.7/CD/O billion/CD/O measure/NN/O funding/VBG/O the/DT/O departments/NNS/O of/IN/O Labor/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Education/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Health/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Human/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O stark/JJ/O numbers/NNS/O yesterday/NN/O --/:/O when/WRB/O 282/CD/O votes/NNS/O were/VBD/O needed/VBN/O --/:/O indicate/VBP/O the/DT/O president/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O commanding/JJ/O position/NN/O for/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Unless/IN/O he/PRP/O changes/VBZ/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O lose/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O leadership/NN/O aide/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O came/VBD/O as/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG sent/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O president/NN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O a/DT/O stopgap/NN/O spending/NN/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O operating/VBG/O through/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 15/CD/O and/CC/O provide/VB/O $/$/O 2.85/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O emergency/NN/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O recovery/NN/O from/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE earthquake/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O package/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O above/IN/O the/DT/O recommendations/NNS/O of/IN/O Budget/NNP/B-ORG Director/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Darman/NNP/I-PERSON this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O importance/NN/O of/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O was/VBD/O content/JJ/O to/TO/O use/VB/O its/PRP$/O influence/NN/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O any/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG amendments/NNS/O adding/VBG/O further/JJ/O new/JJ/O appropriations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O includes/VBZ/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O finance/VB/O this/DT/O credit/NN/O and/CC/O further/RBR/O raises/VBZ/O the/DT/O obligation/NN/O ceiling/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Small/NNP/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG sixfold/RB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.8/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O the/DT/O expected/JJ/O loan/NN/O activity/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O direct/JJ/O cash/NN/O assistance/NN/O ,/,/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O is/VBZ/O provided/VBN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O highway/NN/O construction/NN/O funds/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O $/$/O 1.35/CD/O billion/CD/O is/VBZ/O divided/VBN/O between/IN/O general/JJ/O emergency/NN/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O reserve/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O president/NN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O unanticipated/JJ/O costs/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O disasters/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Majority/NNP/O Whip/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Cranston/NNP/I-PERSON used/VBD/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O not/RB/O only/RB/O the/DT/O expanded/VBN/O credit/NN/O but/CC/O also/RB/O more/RBR/O generous/JJ/O treatment/NN/O than/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O permitted/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O highway/NN/O funds/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O underlying/VBG/O stopgap/NN/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O second/NN/O required/VBN/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG this/DT/O fall/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O since/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O began/VBD/O Oct./NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O only/RB/O the/DT/O Energy/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Interior/NNP/B-ORG departments/NNS/O are/VBP/O operating/VBG/O on/IN/O permanent/JJ/O appropriations/NNS/O enacted/VBN/O into/IN/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O vote/NN/O yesterday/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O partisan/JJ/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O though/IN/O the/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O leadership/NN/O is/VBZ/O ambivalent/JJ/O about/IN/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O address/VB/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O is/VBZ/O increasingly/RB/O measured/VBN/O in/IN/O party/NN/O terms/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O comparison/NN/O ,/,/O Republicans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O held/VBN/O closer/RBR/O to/TO/O the/DT/O anti-abortion/JJ/O movement/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG meeting/NN/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Silvio/NNP/B-PERSON Conte/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O ranking/JJ/O minority/NN/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Appropriations/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O argued/VBD/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O friend/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON against/IN/O a/DT/O veto/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O though/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Conte/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Minority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Michel/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE stood/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O plainly/RB/O uncomfortable/JJ/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O moral/JJ/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Hyde/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Ill./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O eloquent/JJ/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O anti-abortion/JJ/O movement/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O after/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O benefit/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG finds/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O candidates/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O defensive/NN/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE gubernatorial/JJ/O candidate/NN/O Rep./NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Florio/NNP/I-PERSON pointedly/RB/O returned/VBD/O from/IN/O campaigning/NN/O to/TO/O vote/VB/O against/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O yesterday/NN/O in/IN/O contrast/NN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O opponent/NN/O ,/,/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG Rep./NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Courter/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O ardently/RB/O supported/VBN/O abortion/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O but/CC/O was/VBD/O absent/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O support/VBP/O him/PRP/O over/IN/O rape/NN/O victims/NNS/O ,/,/O this/DT/O may/MD/O be/VB/O your/PRP$/O last/JJ/O term/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
