A/DT/O major/JJ/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE newspaper/NN/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O department/NN/O store/NN/O concern/NN/O is/VBZ/O planning/VBG/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O about/IN/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ././O
Campeau/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O 's/POS/O owner/NN/O ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O report/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O service/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O identify/VB/O its/PRP$/O Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG sources/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O rumors/NNS/O we/PRP/O expect/VBP/O to/TO/O hear/VB/O during/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O 's/POS/O process/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O available/JJ/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O early/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O morning/NN/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Campeau/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Campeau/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O annual/JJ/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O valued/VBD/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG at/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Among/IN/O previously/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O possible/JJ/O bidders/NNS/O is/VBZ/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Marvin/NNP/B-PERSON Traub/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O aligned/VBN/O himself/PRP/O with/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Blackstone/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE confirmed/VBD/O that/IN/O Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG Store/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O approached/VBN/O by/IN/O representatives/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O management/NN/O committee/NN/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Mr./NNP/O Traub/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O detailed/JJ/O financial/JJ/O figures/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O passed/VBN/O yet/RB/O to/TO/O any/DT/O prospective/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Nobody/NN/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O make/VB/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O bid/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O middle/NN/O of/IN/O November/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O one/CD/O investment/NN/O banker/NN/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O discussions/NNS/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O who/WP/O might/MD/O raise/VB/O its/PRP$/O hand/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O in/IN/O very/RB/O early/JJ/O stages/NNS/O still/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG does/VBZ/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 1.2/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O executive/NN/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O situation/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O No/DT/O book/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O issued/VBN/O regarding/VBG/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O projections/NNS/O ,/,/O so/RB/O I/PRP/O doubt/VBP/O very/RB/O much/RB/O whether/IN/O any/DT/O bid/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O made/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Campeau/NNP/B-ORG shareholder/NN/O filed/VBD/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O charging/VBG/O Campeau/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Chairman/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Campeau/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O officers/NNS/O with/IN/O violating/VBG/O securities/NNS/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O accuses/VBZ/O the/DT/O retailer/NN/O and/CC/O several/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O officers/NNS/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O false/JJ/O and/CC/O misleading/JJ/O statements/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O business/NN/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O material/JJ/O adverse/JJ/O information/NN/O about/IN/O its/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O Campeau/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O seen/VBN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
