Alltel/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O 55/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Pond/NNP/B-ORG Branch/NNP/I-ORG Telephone/NNP/I-ORG Company/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG cellular/JJ/O franchise/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O own/VB/O already/RB/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Alltel/NNP/B-ORG holds/VBZ/O 45/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O franchise/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O Aiken/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O S.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Augusta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ga/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Alltel/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O provides/VBZ/O local/JJ/O telephone/NN/O service/NN/O in/IN/O 25/CD/O states/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O exercised/VBD/O its/PRP$/O right/NN/O of/IN/O first/JJ/O refusal/NN/O following/VBG/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O from/IN/O an/DT/O undisclosed/JJ/O third/JJ/O party/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O majority/NN/O position/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O franchise/NN/O ././O
