The/DT/B-ORG Internal/NNP/I-ORG Revenue/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O let/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Tax/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG decide/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O oil/NN/O man/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Herbert/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O owe/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O are/VBP/O liquidated/VBN/O ././O
Although/IN/O the/DT/O action/NN/O removes/VBZ/O one/CD/O obstacle/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O overall/JJ/O settlement/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O means/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O be/VB/O stripped/VBN/O of/IN/O virtually/RB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O if/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Tax/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG rules/VBZ/O against/IN/O him/PRP/O in/IN/O a/DT/O 1982/CD/O case/NN/O heard/VBN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O seeking/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O back/JJ/O taxes/NNS/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O hearing/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O bankruptcy/NN/O case/NN/O yesterday/NN/O turned/VBD/O down/RP/O a/DT/O proposed/VBN/O $/$/O 65.7/CD/O million/CD/O settlement/NN/O between/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O major/JJ/O creditor/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Peruvian/JJ/O minerals/NNS/O concern/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O claim/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 251/CD/O million/CD/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O turning/VBG/O down/RP/O the/DT/O compromise/NN/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Abramson/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O a/DT/O claim/NN/O of/IN/O only/RB/O $/$/O 19.7/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG attorneys/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O appeal/VB/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O district/NN/O court/NN/O ././O
Regarding/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O taxes/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O apparently/RB/O agreed/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O basic/JJ/O formula/NN/O for/IN/O liquidating/VBG/O his/PRP$/O estate/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O get/VB/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proceeds/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O liquidating/JJ/O trust/NN/O and/CC/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O would/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O at/IN/O odds/NNS/O over/IN/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O owe/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O demanded/VBN/O $/$/O 90/CD/O million/CD/O but/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O no/DT/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 60/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Grover/NNP/B-PERSON Hartt/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O government/NN/O lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O warned/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON stood/VBD/O to/TO/O lose/VB/O certain/JJ/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O properties/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O in/IN/O English/JJ/O pottery/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE condominium/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O assets/NNS/O he/PRP/O might/MD/O have/VB/O kept/VBN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O settled/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O they/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O roll/VB/O the/DT/O dice/NNS/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O let/VB/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Hartt/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON McCartin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O client/NN/O welcomed/VBD/O the/DT/O gamble/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Tax/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O rule/VB/O before/IN/O early/RB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
