Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON Kuan/NNP/I-PERSON Yew/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leader/NN/O and/CC/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O leading/VBG/O statesmen/NNS/O for/IN/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O recently/RB/O announced/VBD/O his/PRP$/O intention/NN/O to/TO/O retire/VB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O --/:/O though/IN/O not/RB/O necessarily/RB/O to/TO/O end/VB/O his/PRP$/O influence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O whose/WP$/O hair/NN/O is/VBZ/O thinning/VBG/O and/CC/O gray/JJ/O and/CC/O whose/WP$/O face/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O perpetual/JJ/O pallor/NN/O ,/,/O nonetheless/RB/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O display/VB/O an/DT/O energy/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O precision/NN/O of/IN/O thought/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O willingness/NN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O publicly/RB/O what/WP/O most/JJS/O other/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O dare/VBP/O say/VB/O only/RB/O privately/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O interview/NN/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O touch/VB/O on/IN/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O domestic/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
Skipping/VBG/O personal/JJ/O pleasantries/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON picked/VBD/O up/RP/O exactly/RB/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O left/VBD/O off/RP/O several/JJ/O months/NNS/O earlier/RB/O --/:/O before/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O crackdown/NN/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O warned/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O orthodox/JJ/O leadership/NN/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE feared/VBD/O a/DT/O plurality/NN/O of/IN/O views/NNS/O ././O
Excerpts/NNS/O follow/VBP/O :/:/O
On/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O turmoil/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O very/RB/O unhappy/JJ/O scene/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O took/VBD/O Zhao/NNP/B-PERSON Ziyang/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O former/JJ/O premier/NN/O and/CC/O party/NN/O chief/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O team/NN/O of/IN/O economists/NNS/O who/WP/O understood/VBD/O how/WRB/O the/DT/O Western/JJ/O economies/NNS/O work/VBP/O and/CC/O now/RB/O that/DT/O team/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O in/IN/O exile/NN/O ,/,/O part/NN/O being/VBG/O rusticated/VBN/O and/CC/O part/NN/O missing/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
Rebuilding/VBG/O that/DT/O team/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON predicted/VBD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O take/VB/O another/DT/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O sad/JJ/O for/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O for/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC because/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE could/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O engine/NN/O for/IN/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O just/RB/O for/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE but/CC/O for/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Korea/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC ././O ''/''/O
On/IN/O similarities/NNS/O between/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE :/:/O ``/``/O In/IN/O important/JJ/O particulars/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O are/VBP/O different/JJ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNPS/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O already/RB/O industrialized/JJ/O .../:/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O inefficiency/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O industrial/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O much/RB/O greater/JJR/O --/:/O it/PRP/O 's/POS/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O industrialize/VB/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O with/RP/O ././O ''/''/O
Asked/VBN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Chinese/JJ/O officials/NNS/O ,/,/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O one/CD/O day/NN/O face/VB/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O conflict/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O liberalize/VB/O economically/RB/O and/CC/O yet/RB/O retain/VB/O political/JJ/O control/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O think/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O face/VBP/O a/DT/O deeper/JJR/O dilemma/NN/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O more/RBR/O in/IN/O blinkers/NNS/O than/IN/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNPS/O --/:/O I/PRP/O mean/VBP/O keeping/VBG/O their/PRP$/O people/NNS/O cut/VBN/O off/RP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O outside/JJ/O world/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O awareness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O peoples/NNS/O are/VBP/O more/RBR/O introverted/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNPS/O ././O ''/''/O
Regardless/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O still/RB/O believes/VBZ/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O while/IN/O falling/VBG/O far/RB/O short/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O efficiency/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Western/JJ/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O may/MD/O well/RB/O manage/VB/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O considerably/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O such/JJ/O an/DT/O arrangement/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O all/DT/O benefit/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O And/CC/O if/IN/O the/DT/O Europeans/NNPS/O come/VBN/O in/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O benefit/VBP/O too/RB/O ././O
An/DT/O Asian/JJ/O bloc/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O intended/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O possible/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
I/PRP/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O earlier/JJR/O strident/JJ/O notes/NNS/O struck/VBN/O by/IN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Commerce/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON Mosbacher/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Trade/NNP/O Representative/NNP/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O Carla/NNP/B-PERSON Hills/NNP/I-PERSON have/VBP/O been/VBN/O more/RBR/O rounded/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O becoming/VBG/O more/RBR/O patient/JJ/O and/CC/O circumspect/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O total/NN/O relationship/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O important/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O total/NN/O relationship/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON sees/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O the/DT/O flow/NN/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O fund/VB/O the/DT/O deficits/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O investments/NNS/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O are/VBP/O making/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O satisfy/VB/O American/JJ/O demand/NN/O that/IN/O American/JJ/O products/NNS/O consumed/VBN/O in/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE should/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O in/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O with/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O capital/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O political/JJ/O turbulence/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O may/MD/O mean/VB/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O slow/VB/O market/NN/O adjustments/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O timorous/JJ/O in/IN/O tackling/VBG/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O voters/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O opening/VBG/O up/RP/O more/RBR/O to/TO/O agricultural/JJ/O imports/NNS/O from/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O hurting/VBG/O their/PRP$/O farmers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
On/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC :/:/O Asked/VBN/O if/IN/O his/PRP$/O offer/NN/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O military/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O help/VB/O preserve/VB/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O at/IN/O bases/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O What/WP/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O done/VBN/O is/VBZ/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O easier/JJR/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE to/TO/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O host/VB/O American/JJ/O bases/NNS/O without/IN/O it/PRP/O being/VBG/O said/VBN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O lackeys/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O imperialists/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O ones/NNS/O in/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC or/CC/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC ././O
We/PRP/O are/VBP/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O share/VB/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O burden/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O host/NN/O to/TO/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O imperial/JJ/O power/NN/B-GPE ././O
We/PRP/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O burden/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O carries/VBZ/O no/DT/O stigma/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O prepared/JJ/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
I/PRP/O really/RB/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O understand/VB/O how/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Filipinos/NNPS/O feel/VBP/O so/RB/O passionately/RB/O involved/JJ/O in/IN/O this/DT/O father/NN/O figure/NN/O that/WDT/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O dispose/VB/O of/IN/O and/CC/O yet/RB/O they/PRP/O need/VBP/O ././O
I/PRP/O just/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O understand/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
My/PRP$/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O British/NNPS/O are/VBP/O totally/RB/O different/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O lorded/VBD/O it/PRP/O over/IN/O me/PRP/O ././O
They/PRP/O did/VBD/O me/PRP/O some/DT/O good/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O did/VBD/O themselves/PRP/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O good/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O let/VB/O me/PRP/O down/RP/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O came/VBD/O down/RB/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O during/IN/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O .../:/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O feel/VB/O down/RB/O or/CC/O done/VBN/O in/RB/O because/IN/O I/PRP/O show/VBP/O British/JJ/O serials/NNS/O on/IN/O my/PRP$/O television/NN/O network/NN/O or/CC/O read/VBP/O their/PRP$/O books/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O mean/VBP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O normal/JJ/O adult/NN/O relationship/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O the/DT/O Filipinos/NNPS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Americans/NNPS/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O I/PRP/O talk/VBP/O to/TO/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O passion/NN/O about/IN/O Filipino/JJ/O manhood/NN/O being/VBG/O diminished/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O squatted/VBN/O upon/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Americans/NNPS/O and/CC/O so/RB/O on/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O occasional/JJ/O Englishman/NNP/O tries/VBZ/O to/TO/O put/VB/O on/RP/O airs/NNS/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O let/VBP/O it/PRP/O pass/VB/O .../:/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O just/RB/O comic/JJ/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O try/VBP/O to/TO/O pretend/VB/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O still/RB/O the/DT/O master/NN/O race/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON added/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Filipinos/NNPS/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O very/RB/O difficult/JJ/O ''/''/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O presence/NN/O to/TO/O last/VB/O beyond/IN/O five/CD/O or/CC/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O military/JJ/O alternatives/NNS/O if/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE pulls/VBZ/O back/RB/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O already/RB/O are/VBP/O present/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O suppose/VBP/O sooner/RBR/O or/CC/O later/RBR/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O gap/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O naval/JJ/O side/NN/O ././O
Maybe/RB/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNPS/O ,/,/O maybe/RB/O even/RB/O the/DT/O Indians/NNPS/O ././O ''/''/O
On/IN/O economic/JJ/O consequences/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O diminished/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE presence/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O America/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/RB/O major/JJ/O power/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O history/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O used/VBN/O its/PRP$/O military/JJ/O might/NN/O to/TO/O sustain/VB/O a/DT/O system/NN/O that/WDT/O enables/VBZ/O all/DT/O participants/NNS/O to/TO/O equally/RB/O benefit/VB/O without/IN/O her/PRP/O as/IN/O the/DT/O provider/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O security/NN/O taking/VBG/O royalties/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Asked/VBN/O why/WRB/O so/RB/O few/JJ/O nations/NNS/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O share/VB/O his/PRP$/O views/NNS/O of/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Many/JJ/O people/NNS/O see/VBP/O it/PRP/O that/DT/O way/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O just/RB/O taken/VBN/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O granted/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Is/VBZ/O the/DT/O trouble/NN/O over/RP/O ?/./O
Can/MD/O Sihanouk/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Hun/NNP/B-PERSON Sen/NNP/I-PERSON knock/VB/O off/RP/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG still/RB/O supported/VBN/O by/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ?/./O
He/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O way/NN/O forward/RB/O ?/./O
To/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O process/NN/O for/IN/O elections/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O lose/VBP/O ,/,/O then/RB/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O expect/VB/O China/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O stop/VB/O aid/NN/O ././O
Let/VB/O 's/PRP/O put/VB/O it/PRP/O bluntly/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O Chinese/NNPS/O can/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O seen/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O use/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O then/RB/O discard/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Ms./NNP/O House/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wain/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O The/DT/B-ORG Asian/NNP/I-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG ././O
