The/DT/O bill/NN/O would/MD/O require/VB/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O an/DT/O airline/NN/O 's/POS/O stock/NN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O threatened/VBD/O safety/NN/O ,/,/O reduced/VBD/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O ,/,/O or/CC/O put/VBD/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O under/IN/O foreign/JJ/O control/NN/O ././O
Debate/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O faces/VBZ/O a/DT/O veto/NN/O threat/NN/O from/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O amendment/NN/O would/MD/O require/VB/O the/DT/O department/NN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O airline/NN/O by/IN/O anyone/NN/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O run/VBN/O two/CD/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O carriers/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O filed/VBN/O for/IN/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O under/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O 1983/CD/O ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Continental/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG filed/VBD/O for/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Eastern/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG filed/VBD/O for/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O subtitled/VBN/O the/DT/O `/``/O Do/VBP/O n't/RB/O let/VB/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lorenzo/NNP/I-PERSON take/VB/O over/RP/O another/DT/O airline/NN/O '/''/O amendment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Oberstar/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Minn./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG aviation/NN/O subcommittee/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O provision/NN/O was/VBD/O unnecessary/JJ/O because/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O already/RB/O would/MD/O give/VB/O the/DT/O department/NN/O ample/JJ/O power/NN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O undesirable/JJ/O deals/NNS/O ././O
