Concerns/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O pace/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Vienna/NNP/B-GPE talks/NNS/O --/:/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O destruction/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O 100,000/CD/O weapons/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O major/JJ/O reductions/NNS/O and/CC/O realignments/NNS/O of/IN/O troops/NNS/O in/IN/O central/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC --/:/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O registered/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O called/VBN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O September/NNP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O ././O
Tanks/NNS/O currently/RB/O are/VBP/O defined/VBN/O as/IN/O armored/JJ/O vehicles/NNS/O weighing/VBG/O 25/CD/O tons/NNS/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O that/IN/O carry/VB/O large/JJ/O guns/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O complicated/VBD/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O by/IN/O offering/VBG/O to/TO/O include/VB/O light/JJ/O tanks/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O as/RB/O light/JJ/O as/IN/O 10/CD/O tons/NNS/O ././O
France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE all/DT/O have/VBP/O light/JJ/O tanks/NNS/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O dispute/NN/O over/IN/O that/DT/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O one/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE official/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O potential/JJ/O treaty/NN/O stopper/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O only/RB/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Soviet/JJ/O leader/NN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON may/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O resolve/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Accounting/NN/O problems/NNS/O raise/VBP/O more/JJR/O knotty/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
Other/JJ/O nations/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O sure/JJ/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O arsenals/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O bigger/JJR/O danger/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O would/MD/O delay/VB/O action/NN/O so/RB/O long/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O might/MD/O back/VB/O away/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O conciliatory/JJ/O attitude/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O worry/VBP/O more/RBR/O about/IN/O things/NNS/O becoming/VBG/O so/RB/O unraveled/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O side/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O might/MD/O become/VB/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O negotiate/VB/O ././O
