Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O be/VB/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O public/JJ/O enemies/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O two/CD/O entertainment/NN/O giants/NNS/O could/MD/O end/VB/O up/RP/O becoming/VBG/O partners/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O ventures/NNS/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O acrimonious/JJ/O legal/JJ/O dispute/NN/O over/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE producers/NNS/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Guber/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Jon/NNP/B-PERSON Peters/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Bros./NNPS/I-ORG studio/NN/O and/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG signaled/VBD/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O close/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O asking/VBG/O a/DT/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE Superior/NNP/O Court/NNP/O to/TO/O postpone/VB/O a/DT/O hearing/NN/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O tomorrow/NN/O on/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O request/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O preliminary/JJ/O injunction/NN/O blocking/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON from/IN/O taking/VBG/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O posts/NNS/O at/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNPS/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O separate/JJ/O statements/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O ``/``/O further/JJ/O discussions/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O legal/JJ/O battle/NN/O have/VBP/O hurled/VBN/O accusations/NNS/O of/IN/O duplicity/NN/O at/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O for/IN/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O both/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O accused/VBN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O of/IN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O sabotage/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O 's/POS/O prospects/NNS/O for/IN/O success/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O entertainment/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O discussions/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O any/DT/O cash/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O let/VB/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG participate/VB/O in/IN/O certain/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O businesses/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O record/NN/O club/NN/O of/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNPS/I-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O discussing/VBG/O certain/JJ/O business/NN/O ventures/NNS/O involving/VBG/O cable/NN/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O movies/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O swap/VB/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sprawling/JJ/O Burbank/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O studio/NN/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG share/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O MGM/NNP/B-ORG studio/NN/O lot/NN/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG acquired/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O Lorimar/NNP/B-ORG Telepictures/NNPS/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O tough/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O smooth/JJ/O partnership/NN/O in/IN/O anything/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O sworn/VBN/O affidavits/NNS/O filed/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O came/VBD/O from/IN/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNPS/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Yetnikoff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O head/VB/O a/DT/O committee/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O oversee/VB/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O entertainment/NN/O division/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O both/DT/O records/NNS/O and/CC/O movies/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O his/PRP$/O affidavit/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Yetnikoff/NNP/B-PERSON accused/VBD/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Steven/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Ross/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O having/VBG/O an/DT/O ``/``/O antiSony/JJ/O ,/,/O anti-Japanese/JJ/O bias/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O tried/VBN/O to/TO/O talk/VB/O him/PRP/O out/RB/O of/IN/O letting/VBG/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG buy/VB/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNPS/I-ORG two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O for/IN/O that/DT/O reason/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O co-chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG after/IN/O the/DT/O merger/NN/O is/VBZ/O complete/JJ/O ,/,/O denied/VBD/O that/IN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O affidavit/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O called/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Yetnikoff/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remarks/NNS/O ``/``/O vicious/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O claims/NNS/O ``/``/O reckless/JJ/O ,/,/O irresponsible/JJ/O and/CC/O baseless/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O saying/VBG/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG under/IN/O his/PRP$/O leadership/NN/O has/VBZ/O started/VBN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O businesses/NNS/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O enjoys/VBZ/O ``/``/O warm/JJ/O professional/NN/O and/CC/O personal/JJ/O relationships/NNS/O ''/''/O with/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O executives/NNS/O including/VBG/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Akio/NNP/B-PERSON Morita/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O visited/VBN/O my/PRP$/O home/NN/O here/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O acrimony/NN/O between/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Yetnikoff/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O officials/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Time/NNP/B-ORG side/NN/O of/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O reportedly/RB/O been/VBN/O increasingly/RB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O yield/VB/O attractive/JJ/O business/NN/O opportunities/NNS/O ././O
Talks/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O could/MD/O unravel/VB/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O once/RB/O since/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG announced/VBD/O its/PRP$/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O hire/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O appear/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O willing/JJ/O now/RB/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O 's/POS/O terms/NNS/O to/TO/O resolve/VB/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O although/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O it/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O to/TO/O fulfill/VB/O the/DT/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O sworn/VBN/O court/NN/O declarations/NNS/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O the/DT/O relationship/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O repaired/VBN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O acrimony/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O legal/JJ/O battle/NN/O ././O
Any/DT/O settlement/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O exclude/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON from/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O projects/NNS/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O at/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O
But/CC/O that/IN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON might/MD/O not/RB/O eventually/RB/O get/VB/O their/PRP$/O hands/NNS/O on/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O projects/NNS/O ;/:/O studios/NNS/O develop/VBP/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O movies/NNS/O but/CC/O produce/VBP/O only/RB/O 10/CD/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O each/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Once/RB/O a/DT/O studio/NN/O chooses/VBZ/O not/RB/O to/TO/O actually/RB/O make/VB/O a/DT/O movie/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O development/NN/O ,/,/O producers/NNS/O are/VBP/O typically/RB/O free/JJ/O to/TO/O take/VB/O it/PRP/O elsewhere/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O almost/RB/O certainly/RB/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O participate/VB/O in/IN/O future/JJ/O sequels/NNS/O to/TO/O ``/``/O Batman/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O blockbuster/NN/O hit/NN/O they/PRP/O produced/VBD/O for/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O
