Instead/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O GAO/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Congressional/NNP/I-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O consider/VB/O using/VBG/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG debt/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O less/RBR/O expensive/JJ/O and/CC/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O oversight/NN/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O projected/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O require/VB/O between/IN/O $/$/O 50/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 100/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O temporary/JJ/O working/JJ/O capital/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O borrowing/NN/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O these/DT/O funds/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O paid/VBN/O off/RB/O as/IN/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O sick/JJ/O thrifts/NNS/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O To/TO/O allow/VB/O this/DT/O massive/JJ/O level/NN/O of/IN/O unfettered/JJ/O federal/JJ/O borrowing/NN/O without/IN/O prior/JJ/O congressional/JJ/O approval/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O irresponsible/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Fortney/NNP/B-PERSON Stark/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O introduced/VBN/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O limit/VB/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O authority/NN/O to/TO/O issue/VB/O debt/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O or/CC/O merge/VB/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O insolvent/JJ/O thrifts/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O meantime/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O must/MD/O raise/VB/O cash/NN/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O ,/,/O until/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Mullins/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O assistant/NN/O secretary/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O working/JJ/O capital/NN/O is/VBZ/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O costs/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bailout/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O allowing/VBG/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O savings/NNS/O and/CC/O loans/NNS/O without/IN/O their/PRP$/O bad/JJ/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O hold/VB/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O until/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O under/IN/O favorable/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O possibility/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O raising/VBG/O no/DT/O working/JJ/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
