Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON Kuan/NNP/I-PERSON Yew/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leader/NN/O and/CC/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O leading/VBG/O statesmen/NNS/O for/IN/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O recently/RB/O announced/VBD/O his/PRP$/O intention/NN/O to/TO/O retire/VB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O --/:/O though/IN/O not/RB/O necessarily/RB/O to/TO/O end/VB/O his/PRP$/O influence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O whose/WP$/O hair/NN/O is/VBZ/O thinning/VBG/O and/CC/O gray/JJ/O and/CC/O whose/WP$/O face/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O perpetual/JJ/O pallor/NN/O ,/,/O nonetheless/RB/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O display/VB/O an/DT/O energy/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O precision/NN/O of/IN/O thought/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O willingness/NN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O publicly/RB/O what/WP/O most/JJS/O other/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O dare/VBP/O say/VB/O only/RB/O privately/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O interview/NN/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O touch/VB/O on/IN/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O domestic/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O already/RB/O industrialized/JJ/O .../:/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O inefficiency/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O industrial/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O awareness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
An/DT/O Asian/JJ/O bloc/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O intended/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O becoming/VBG/O more/RBR/O patient/JJ/O and/CC/O circumspect/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O political/JJ/O turbulence/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O may/MD/O mean/VB/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O slow/VB/O market/NN/O adjustments/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O are/VBP/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O share/VB/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O burden/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O host/NN/O to/TO/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O imperial/JJ/O power/NN/B-GPE ././O
I/PRP/O really/RB/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O understand/VB/O how/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O Filipinos/NNPS/O feel/VBP/O so/RB/O passionately/RB/O involved/JJ/O in/IN/O this/DT/O father/NN/O figure/NN/O that/WDT/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O dispose/VB/O of/IN/O and/CC/O yet/RB/O they/PRP/O need/VBP/O ././O
I/PRP/O just/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O understand/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
My/PRP$/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O British/NNPS/O are/VBP/O totally/RB/O different/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O lorded/VBD/O it/PRP/O over/IN/O me/PRP/O ././O
They/PRP/O did/VBD/O me/PRP/O some/DT/O good/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O did/VBD/O themselves/PRP/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O good/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O feel/VB/O down/RB/O or/CC/O done/VBN/O in/RB/O because/IN/O I/PRP/O show/VBP/O British/JJ/O serials/NNS/O on/IN/O my/PRP$/O television/NN/O network/NN/O or/CC/O read/VBP/O their/PRP$/O books/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O mean/VBP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O normal/JJ/O adult/NN/O relationship/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O occasional/JJ/O Englishman/NNP/O tries/VBZ/O to/TO/O put/VB/O on/RP/O airs/NNS/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O let/VBP/O it/PRP/O pass/VB/O .../:/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON added/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Filipinos/NNPS/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O very/RB/O difficult/JJ/O ''/''/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O presence/NN/O to/TO/O last/VB/O beyond/IN/O five/CD/O or/CC/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O suppose/VBP/O sooner/RBR/O or/CC/O later/RBR/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O gap/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O naval/JJ/O side/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O House/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wain/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O The/DT/B-ORG Asian/NNP/I-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG ././O
