Canonie/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O anticipates/VBZ/O naming/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Donovan/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O succeed/VB/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON F./NNP/I-PERSON Brissette/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 55/CD/O ,/,/O as/IN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O March/NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Brissette/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O remain/VB/O a/DT/O Canonie/NNP/B-ORG board/NN/O member/NN/O and/CC/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
