AMERICAN/NNP/B-ORG BRANDS/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Old/NNP/B-GPE Greenwich/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O increased/VBD/O its/PRP$/O quarterly/JJ/O 11/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 68/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O from/IN/O 61/CD/O cents/NNS/O ,/,/O payable/JJ/O Dec./NNP/O 1/CD/O to/TO/O stock/NN/O of/IN/O record/NN/O Nov./NNP/O 10/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O increase/NN/O follows/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O report/NN/O of/IN/O strong/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O reflects/VBZ/O what/WP/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNPS/I-ORG called/VBD/O its/PRP$/O ``/``/O tradition/NN/O of/IN/O sharing/VBG/O earnings/NNS/O growth/NN/O ''/''/O with/IN/O shareholders/NNS/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O consumer/NN/O products/NNS/O company/NN/O with/IN/O core/NN/O businesses/NNS/O in/IN/O tobacco/NN/O ,/,/O distilled/JJ/O spirits/NNS/O and/CC/O life/NN/O insurance/NN/O ././O
