Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNPS/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O dropped/VBN/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O today/NN/O ,/,/O from/IN/O the/DT/O recreational/JJ/O products/NNS/O and/CC/O services/NNS/O industry/NN/O group/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG Equity/NNP/O Market/NNP/O Index/NNP/O ././O
Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O acquired/VBN/O by/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
