The/DT/O materials/NNS/O ,/,/O discovered/VBN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O conduct/VBP/O electricity/NN/O without/IN/O resistance/NN/O and/CC/O promise/VBP/O smaller/JJR/O ,/,/O faster/JJR/O computers/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O new/JJ/O technologies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O latest/JJS/O research/NN/O pact/NN/O bolsters/VBZ/O Du/NNP/B-ORG Pont/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG growing/VBG/O portfolio/NN/O of/IN/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O superconductors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Wilmington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Del./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O chemicals/NNS/O concern/NN/O previously/RB/O signed/VBD/O research/NN/O superconductor/NN/O agreements/NNS/O with/IN/O Oak/NNP/B-ORG Ridge/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Laboratory/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O with/IN/O Argonne/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Laboratory/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Du/NNP/B-ORG Pont/NNP/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O $/$/O 4.5/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O superconductor/NN/O work/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Houston/NNP/I-ORG ././O
