The/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O abominable/JJ/O construction/NN/O practices/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE --/:/O as/IN/O evidenced/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O collapse/NN/O of/IN/O sand/NN/O apartment/NN/O blocks/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Armenian/JJ/O earthquake/NN/O --/:/O as/IN/O a/DT/O metaphor/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE economic/JJ/O system/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O sublime/JJ/O example/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Cockburn/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O satirical/JJ/O muse/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O await/VBP/O his/PRP$/O sequel/NN/O :/:/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O social/JJ/O resiliency/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE Bay/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O outstanding/JJ/O work/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O governments/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O private/JJ/O charitable/JJ/O organizations/NNS/O there/RB/O as/IN/O metaphors/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O supremacy/NN/O of/IN/O whatever/WDT/O failed/JJ/O system/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Cockburn/NNP/B-PERSON now/RB/O believes/VBZ/O in/IN/O ././O
It/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O scream/NN/O ././O
William/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON
