Chez/NNP/B-ORG Panisse/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O listed/VBN/O among/IN/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O 30/CD/O restaurants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O by/IN/O Connoisseur/NNP/B-ORG magazine/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O tattered/JJ/O black/JJ/O binder/NN/O ,/,/O bulging/VBG/O with/IN/O 18/CD/O years/NNS/O '/POS/O worth/NN/O of/IN/O recipes/NNS/O held/VBN/O together/RB/O by/IN/O rubber/NN/O bands/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O chef/NN/O Lindsey/NNP/B-PERSON Shere/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O purse/NN/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O stolen/VBN/O from/IN/O her/PRP$/O house/NN/O recently/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O Berkeley/NNP/B-GPE police/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O leads/NNS/O but/CC/O doubt/VB/O the/DT/O crime/NN/O was/VBD/O driven/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O passion/NN/O for/IN/O sweets/NNS/O ././O
Chez/NNP/B-ORG Panisse/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O founder/NN/O ,/,/O Alice/NNP/B-PERSON Waters/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O the/DT/O inventor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cooking/JJ/O style/NN/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE cuisine/NN/O and/CC/O whose/WP$/O patrons/NNS/O make/VBP/O reservations/NNS/O a/DT/O month/NN/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O exactly/RB/O subjected/VBN/O diners/NNS/O to/TO/O vanilla/NN/O ice/NN/O cream/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O theft/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC Area/NNP/I-LOC 's/POS/I-LOC pastry/NN/O community/NN/O express/VBP/O disbelief/NN/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Shere/NNP/B-PERSON kept/VBD/O only/RB/O one/CD/O copy/NN/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O valuable/JJ/O notes/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O received/VBN/O moral/JJ/O support/NN/O from/IN/O Baker/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Dozen/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE pastry/NN/O chefs/NNS/O that/WDT/O meets/VBZ/O regularly/RB/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O issues/NNS/O like/VB/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O meringues/NNS/O from/IN/O weeping/VBG/O and/CC/O how/WRB/O bovine/JJ/O eating/JJ/O habits/NNS/O affect/VBP/O butter/NN/O texture/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Shere/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O offered/VBN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 500/CD/O reward/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O 's/POS/O return/NN/O but/CC/O figures/VBZ/O she/PRP/O 'll/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O reinvent/VB/O many/JJ/O recipes/NNS/O from/IN/O scratch/NN/O ././O
