Japan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O found/VBN/O another/DT/O safe/JJ/O outlet/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O money/NN/O :/:/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE home/NN/O mortgages/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O may/MD/O not/RB/O come/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O surprise/NN/O to/TO/O Americans/NNPS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O watched/VBN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O snap/VBP/O up/RP/O properties/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE from/IN/O golf/NN/O courses/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-FAC Center/NNP/I-FAC ././O
The/DT/O steady/JJ/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mortgage/NN/O securities/NNS/O market/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O even/RB/O triggered/VBN/O talk/NN/O of/IN/O building/NN/O up/RP/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O market/NN/O here/RB/O ././O
Evidence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O growing/VBG/O Japanese/JJ/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O mortgage/NN/O securities/NNS/O abounds/VBZ/O ././O
Industrial/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O claims/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O Japanese/JJ/O buyer/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE mortgage/NN/O securities/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O double/VB/O its/PRP$/O purchases/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O an/DT/O amount/NN/O one/CD/O official/NN/O puts/VBZ/O at/IN/O several/JJ/O billion/CD/O dollars/NNS/O ././O
These/DT/O securities/NNS/O are/VBP/O attractive/JJ/O to/TO/O Japanese/JJ/O investors/NNS/O for/IN/O three/CD/O reasons/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O secondary/JJ/O market/NN/O in/IN/O federally/RB/O backed/JJ/O mortgage/NN/O securities/NNS/O now/RB/O exceeds/VBZ/O $/$/O 900/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O nearly/RB/O half/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 2.2/CD/O trillion/CD/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE residential/JJ/O mortgages/NNS/O issued/VBN/O ././O
