Mr./NNP/O Mulford/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O responding/VBG/O to/TO/O critics/NNS/O of/IN/O intervention/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O intervention/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O highly/RB/O visible/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O seriously/RB/O by/IN/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O and/CC/O works/VBZ/O better/RBR/O than/IN/O ``/``/O was/VBD/O recognized/VBN/O some/DT/O time/NN/O ago/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Differences/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/O usefulness/NN/O of/IN/O intervention/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O restrain/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O resurfaced/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O hearing/NN/O ././O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG Vice/NNP/O Chairman/NNP/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O dissented/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O told/VBD/O lawmakers/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O became/VBD/O convinced/JJ/O about/IN/O what/WP/O looked/VBD/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O like/IN/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O push/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O down/RP/O against/IN/O the/DT/O fundamentals/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Intervention/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O useful/JJ/O only/RB/O to/TO/O smooth/VB/O disorderly/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O to/TO/O fundamentally/RB/O influence/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O 's/POS/O value/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON LaFalce/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.Y/NNP/B-GPE ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON refused/VBD/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O jointly/RB/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mulford/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O instead/RB/O asked/VBD/O to/TO/O appear/VB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O had/VBD/O completed/VBN/O his/PRP$/O testimony/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O denied/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O LaFalce/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O statement/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mulford/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O reports/NNS/O of/IN/O tension/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O been/VBN/O exaggerated/JJ/O ,/,/O insisting/VBG/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O involved/VBD/O ``/``/O nuances/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O ``/``/O in/IN/O the/DT/O scheme/NN/O of/IN/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O these/DT/O things/NNS/O are/VBP/O minor/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
On/IN/O other/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mulford/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O contributing/VBG/O to/TO/O imbalances/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O economy/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O success/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O exporter/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O solution/NN/O is/VBZ/O stronger/JJR/O domestic/JJ/O growth/NN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O in/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE -RCB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O because/IN/O the/DT/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O German/JJ/O economy/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O stronger/JJR/O than/IN/O expected/VBN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mulford/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O difficult/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O argue/VB/O that/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE ought/MD/O to/TO/O adopt/VB/O more/RBR/O stimulative/JJ/O monetary/JJ/O and/CC/O fiscal/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Germany/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O is/VBZ/O largely/RB/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O European/JJ/O countries/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mulford/NNP/B-PERSON acknowledged/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O nonetheless/RB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O successful/JJ/O in/IN/O European/JJ/O markets/NNS/O if/IN/O not/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O German/JJ/O export/NN/O push/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
