His/PRP$/O new/JJ/O stake/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O form/NN/O of/IN/O preferred/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O receive/VBP/O higher/JJR/O dividends/NNS/O but/CC/O have/VBP/O voting/VBG/O rights/NNS/O only/RB/O in/IN/O extraordinary/JJ/O shareholders/NNS/O assemblies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-PERSON Aga/NNP/I-PERSON Khan/NNP/I-PERSON owns/VBZ/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Ifint/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O IFI/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O 23/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O capital/NN/O will/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O to/TO/O 232.4/CD/O billion/CD/O lire/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 172.5/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O from/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O 204.3/CD/O billion/CD/O lire/NNS/O ././O
IFI/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O has/VBZ/O nonvoting/JJ/O preferred/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O quoted/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Milan/NNP/I-ORG stock/NN/I-ORG exchange/NN/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O transactions/NNS/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O an/DT/O IFI/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O no/DT/O cash/NN/O would/MD/O change/VB/O hands/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O strengthens/VBZ/O the/DT/O existing/VBG/O links/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Agnellis/NNPS/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/B-PERSON Aga/NNP/I-PERSON Khan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O Ismaili/NNP/O Moslems/NNPS/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O longtime/JJ/O family/NN/O friend/NN/O and/CC/O frequently/RB/O goes/VBZ/O sailing/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Agnelli/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Agnelli/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/B-PERSON Aga/NNP/I-PERSON Khan/NNP/I-PERSON also/RB/O have/VBP/O some/DT/O business/NN/O ties/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Agnelli/NNP/I-ORG company/NN/I-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O rule/VB/O out/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O agreement/NN/O could/MD/O lead/VB/O to/TO/O further/JJ/O collaboration/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O Ifint/NNP/B-ORG earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O bought/VBD/O an/DT/O 18/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Alisarda/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-PERSON Aga/NNP/I-PERSON Khan/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON airline/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O flies/VBZ/O between/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Sardinia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mediobanca/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O during/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O the/DT/O shares/NNS/O back/RP/O to/TO/O Giovanni/NNP/B-PERSON Agnelli/NNP/I-PERSON for/IN/O 333/CD/O billion/CD/O lire/NNS/O ././O
