``/``/O This/DT/O week/NN/O was/VBD/O uneventful/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O CD/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Norberto/NNP/B-PERSON Mehl/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Banxquote/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Banks/NNS/O that/WDT/O adjusted/VBD/O payouts/NNS/O on/IN/O CDs/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O recent/JJ/O week/NN/O made/VBD/O only/RB/O fractional/JJ/O moves/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O market/NN/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O move/VBP/O up/RB/O rapidly/RB/O ,/,/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O bank/NN/O CD/NN/O yields/NNS/O sometimes/RB/O lag/VBP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mehl/NNP/B-PERSON attributed/VBD/O the/DT/O rise/NN/O specifically/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bill/NN/O increase/NN/O ././O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O banks/NNS/O surveyed/VBN/O by/IN/O Banxquote/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O six/CD/O regions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O 8.33/CD/O %/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O yield/NN/O available/JJ/O ././O
Just/RB/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O BankAmerica/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O yields/NNS/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O those/DT/O maturities/NNS/O was/VBD/O 8.61/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O on/IN/O average/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O California/NNP/B-GPE banks/NNS/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O yields/NNS/O on/IN/O CDs/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Banxquote/NNP/B-ORG ././O
