The/DT/O venture/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O in/IN/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O rapid/JJ/O expansion/NN/O of/IN/O overseas/JJ/O investment/NN/O ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O put/VBN/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 700/CD/O million/CD/O into/IN/O bottling/VBG/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Aside/RB/O from/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O the/DT/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC division/NN/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O focusing/VBG/O much/RB/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O attention/NN/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O because/IN/O when/WRB/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG looks/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O an/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O demographic/JJ/O gold/NN/O mine/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O countries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O economies/NNS/O are/VBP/O growing/VBG/O ,/,/O resulting/VBG/O in/IN/O a/DT/O rise/NN/O in/IN/O disposable/JJ/O income/NN/O that/IN/O consumers/NNS/O can/MD/O use/VB/O for/IN/O soft/JJ/O drinks/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O typically/RB/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O minority/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O acquiring/VBG/O stakes/NNS/O in/IN/O bottling/VBG/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O bottlers/NNS/O '/POS/O efficiency/NN/O and/CC/O production/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O some/DT/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O marketing/NN/O ././O
Coke/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O tended/VBN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O its/PRP$/O control/NN/O when/WRB/O results/NNS/O were/VBD/O sluggish/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O given/VBN/O country/NN/O ././O
Coke/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O be/VB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O more/RBR/O quickly/RB/O developing/VBG/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O untapped/JJ/O potential/NN/O in/IN/O those/DT/O markets/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O whether/IN/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O direction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ././O
