Liberty/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Bancorp/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Florence/NNP/B-ORG Deposit/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Florence/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ky./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O first/RB/O announced/VBN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O completed/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 13.1/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Liberty/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG exchanged/VBD/O about/IN/O 78.64/CD/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O common/JJ/O stock/NN/O for/IN/O each/DT/O of/IN/O Florence/NNP/B-ORG Deposit/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 5,600/CD/O shares/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ././O
Liberty/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O assets/NNS/O exceeding/VBG/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
