The/DT/O closely/RB/O held/JJ/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O company/NN/O also/RB/O will/MD/O announce/VB/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O supply/VB/O computers/NNS/O to/TO/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O sell/VB/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG machines/NNS/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O label/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG machine/NN/O ,/,/O called/VBN/O the/DT/O RC6280/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O $/$/O 150,000/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O basic/JJ/O system/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O computer/NN/O processes/VBZ/O 55/CD/O million/CD/O instructions/NNS/O per/IN/O second/NN/O and/CC/O uses/VBZ/O only/RB/O one/CD/O central/JJ/O processing/VBG/O chip/NN/O ,/,/O unlike/IN/O many/JJ/O rival/JJ/O machines/NNS/O using/VBG/O several/JJ/O processors/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O that/DT/O price/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O machine/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O offers/VBZ/O up/IN/O to/TO/O 10/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O performance/NN/O of/IN/O similar/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ././O
Mips/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O wedge/VB/O into/IN/O markets/NNS/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O traditional/JJ/O RISC/NNP/O applications/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O engineering/NN/O ;/:/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O machine/NN/O will/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O businesses/NNS/O and/CC/O for/IN/O communications/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O clearly/RB/O demonstrates/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O systems/NNS/O company/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O just/RB/O a/DT/O chip/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Hime/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
RISC/NNP/O technology/NN/O speeds/VBZ/O up/RP/O a/DT/O computer/NN/O by/IN/O simplifying/VBG/O the/DT/O internal/JJ/O software/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O thing/NN/O it/PRP/O says/VBZ/O about/IN/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O on/IN/O a/DT/O roll/NN/O right/RB/O now/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Gant/NNP/B-PERSON at/IN/O InfoCorp/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O getting/VBG/O some/DT/O major/JJ/O wins/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O added/VBD/O ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O supply/VB/O its/PRP$/O computers/NNS/O to/TO/O Nixdorf/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Groupe/NNP/B-ORG Bull/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Tandem/NNP/B-ORG Computers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O MIPS/NNP/B-ORG computers/NNS/O and/CC/O companies/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O NEC/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE Siemens/NNP/B-ORG A.G./NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG chips/NNS/O under/IN/O license/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O machine/NN/O is/VBZ/O essentially/RB/O a/DT/O mainframe/NN/O computer/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Suddenly/RB/O CDC/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O competitive/JJ/O product/NN/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O back/RB/O against/IN/O the/DT/O VAX9000/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O machine/NN/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG announced/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ././O
Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Minneapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Minn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O expects/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG systems/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O RC6280/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O amount/VB/O to/TO/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Nixdorf/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Bull/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O will/MD/O also/RB/O sell/VB/O versions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O machine/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG President/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Miller/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mips/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O start/VB/O shipping/VBG/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O machine/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O of/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O machine/NN/O uses/VBZ/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O processor/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O easier/JJR/O to/TO/O program/VB/O than/IN/O competing/VBG/O machines/NNS/O using/VBG/O several/JJ/O processors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O machine/NN/O can/MD/O run/VB/O software/NN/O written/VBN/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O Mips/NNP/B-ORG computers/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
