Differences/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/O usefulness/NN/O of/IN/O intervention/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O restrain/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O resurfaced/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O hearing/NN/O ././O
Intervention/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O useful/JJ/O only/RB/O to/TO/O smooth/VB/O disorderly/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O to/TO/O fundamentally/RB/O influence/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O 's/POS/O value/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O denied/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O LaFalce/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O statement/NN/O ././O
Germany/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O is/VBZ/O largely/RB/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O European/JJ/O countries/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mulford/NNP/B-PERSON acknowledged/VBD/O ././O
