`/``/O Frequent/JJ/O Drinker/NN/O '/''/O Offer/NN/O Stirs/VBZ/O Up/RP/O Spirited/JJ/O Debate/NN/O
TO/TO/O GRAB/NNP/O a/DT/O bigger/JJR/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O declining/VBG/O scotch/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O launched/VBN/O a/DT/O controversial/JJ/O ``/``/O frequent/JJ/O drinker/NN/O ''/''/O promotion/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O Chivas/NNP/O Regal/NNP/O brand/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O ,/,/O dubbed/VBN/O Chivas/NNP/O Class/NNP/O ,/,/O customers/NNS/O who/WP/O send/VBP/O in/RP/O two/CD/O labels/NNS/O from/IN/O Chivas/NNP/O bottles/NNS/O will/MD/O receive/VB/O an/DT/O upgrade/NN/O in/IN/O seating/VBG/O class/NN/O on/IN/O some/DT/O Trans/NNP/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG flights/NNS/O ././O
Repeat/NN/O customers/NNS/O also/RB/O can/MD/O purchase/VB/O luxury/NN/O items/NNS/O at/IN/O reduced/JJ/O prices/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O mounting/VBG/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O alcohol/NN/O abuse/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O liquor/NN/O marketers/NNS/O consider/VBP/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O frequent/JJ/O buyer/NN/O promotion/NN/O risky/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O very/RB/O leery/JJ/O of/IN/O anything/NN/O that/WDT/O says/VBZ/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O drink/VBP/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O get/VBP/O more/JJR/O ././O ''/''/O
Others/NNS/O question/VBP/O the/DT/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O Chivas/NNP/O 's/POS/O upscale/JJ/O image/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O promotion/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O customers/NNS/O soaking/VBG/O off/RP/O labels/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O really/RB/O bizarre/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Albert/NNP/B-PERSON Lerman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O creative/JJ/O director/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Wells/NNP/B-ORG Rich/NNP/I-ORG Greene/NNP/I-ORG ad/NN/O agency/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Chivas/NNP/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O image/NN/O of/IN/O something/NN/O you/PRP/O would/MD/O savor/VB/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O guzzle/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Chivas/NNP/O Class/NNP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O such/JJ/O promotion/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O Dewar/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O gave/VBD/O discounts/NNS/O on/IN/O Scottish/JJ/O merchandise/NN/O to/TO/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O sent/VBD/O in/RP/O bottle/NN/O labels/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O scope/NN/O of/IN/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Chivas/NNP/O promotion/NN/O sets/VBZ/O it/PRP/O apart/RB/O ././O
Seagram/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O the/DT/O promotion/NN/O is/VBZ/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O brand/NN/O loyalty/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O promote/VB/O heavy/JJ/O drinking/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O saying/VBG/O drink/VB/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O saying/VBG/O trade/NN/O up/RP/O ././O ''/''/O
Goya/NNP/B-ORG Concocts/VBZ/O a/DT/O Milk/NN/O For/IN/O Hispanic/JJ/O Tastes/NNS/O
But/CC/O Goya/NNP/B-ORG Foods/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG believes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O milk/VB/O some/DT/O sales/NNS/O by/IN/O bucking/VBG/O the/DT/O trend/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O give/VB/O Leche/NNP/O Fresca/NNP/O the/DT/O creamier/JJR/O taste/NN/O Goya/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O Hispanics/NNPS/O prefer/VBP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O brand/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O butterfat/NN/O content/NN/O of/IN/O 3.8/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O compares/VBZ/O with/IN/O 3.5/CD/O %/NN/O butterfat/NN/O for/IN/O whole/JJ/O milk/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Borden/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O milk/NN/O producer/NN/O ,/,/O concedes/VBZ/O Goya/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O be/VB/O on/IN/O to/TO/O something/NN/O ././O
Borden/NNP/B-ORG even/RB/O tested/VBD/O a/DT/O milk/NN/O with/IN/O 4/CD/O %/NN/O butterfat/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O but/CC/O decided/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O small/JJ/O ././O
Goya/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O selling/VBG/O Leche/NNP/O Fresca/NNP/O in/IN/O nearly/RB/O 500/CD/O grocery/NN/O stores/NNS/O and/CC/O bodegas/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ././O
And/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O adding/VBG/O 15/CD/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O new/JJ/O outlets/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Greg/NNP/B-PERSON Ricca/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O sales/NNS/O director/NN/O at/IN/O La/NNP/B-ORG Lecheria/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Because/IN/O of/IN/O Leche/NNP/O Fresca/NNP/O 's/POS/O success/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O is/VBZ/O developing/VBG/O other/JJ/O dairy/NN/O products/NNS/O tailored/VBN/O to/TO/O Hispanic/JJ/O tastes/NNS/O ././O
Jewelry/NN/O Makers/NNS/O Copy/VBP/O Cosmetics/NNS/O Sales/NNS/O Ploys/NNS/O
FOR/IN/O YEARS/NNS/O ,/,/O costume/JJ/O jewelry/NN/O makers/NNS/O fought/VBD/O a/DT/O losing/JJ/O battle/NN/O ././O
Jewelry/NN/O displays/NNS/O in/IN/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O were/VBD/O often/RB/O cluttered/JJ/O and/CC/O uninspired/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O merchandise/NN/O was/VBD/O ,/,/O well/UH/O ,/,/O fake/JJ/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O marketers/NNS/O of/IN/O faux/JJ/O gems/NNS/O steadily/RB/O lost/VBD/O space/NN/O in/IN/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O to/TO/O more/RBR/O fashionable/JJ/O rivals/NNS/O --/:/O cosmetics/NNS/O makers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O lately/RB/O ,/,/O retailers/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O fake/JJ/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O more/RBR/O fashionable/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O jewelry/NN/O makers/NNS/O are/VBP/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O use/VB/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O marketing/NN/O tricks/NNS/O honed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O aggressive/JJ/O world/NN/O of/IN/O cosmetics/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O women/NNS/O 's/POS/O fashion/NN/O jewelry/NN/O business/NN/O topped/VBD/O $/$/O 4.9/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Karen/NNP/B-PERSON Alberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O Accessories/NNP/B-ORG magazine/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O growing/VBG/O fast/RB/O ,/,/O with/IN/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O gains/NNS/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O increase/VB/O their/PRP$/O share/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O business/NN/O ,/,/O jewelry/NN/O makers/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Crystal/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Trifari/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Monet/NNP/B-ORG units/NNS/O and/CC/O Swank/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O Anne/NNP/B-ORG Klein/NNP/I-ORG jewelry/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O launching/VBG/O new/JJ/O lines/NNS/O with/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O fanfare/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O fragrance/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O hiring/VBG/O models/NNS/O to/TO/O stroll/VB/O the/DT/O aisles/NNS/O sporting/VBG/O their/PRP$/O jewels/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O even/RB/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O borrow/VB/O a/DT/O perennial/JJ/O favorite/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O beauty/NN/O business/NN/O --/:/O offering/VBG/O a/DT/O gift/NN/O when/WRB/O consumers/NNS/O make/VBP/O a/DT/O purchase/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O started/VBN/O trying/VBG/O just/RB/O about/IN/O anything/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O sales/NNS/O moving/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stores/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Kim/NNP/B-PERSON Renk/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Swank/NNP/B-ORG vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O limits/NNS/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Renk/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O retailers/NNS/O nixed/VBD/O a/DT/O promotion/NN/O for/IN/O pins/NNS/O with/IN/O animal/NN/O motifs/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O idea/NN/O :/:/O bring/VB/O in/RP/O live/JJ/O zoo/NN/O animals/NNS/O ././O
Trifari/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O national/JJ/O ads/NNS/O earlier/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O included/VBD/O paper/NN/O cutouts/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O costume/NN/O finery/NN/O ,/,/O takes/VBZ/O a/DT/O tamer/JJR/O approach/NN/O ././O
Trifari/NNP/B-ORG now/RB/O trains/VBZ/O sales/NNS/O help/NN/O to/TO/O advise/VB/O customers/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O earring/NN/O styles/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O cosmetics/NNS/O firms/NNS/O still/RB/O have/VBP/O one/CD/O big/JJ/O marketing/NN/O edge/NN/O :/:/O They/PRP/O motivate/VBP/O sales/NNS/O people/NNS/O with/IN/O commissions/NNS/O ././O
Jewelry/NN/O makers/NNS/O rarely/RB/O pay/VBP/O commissions/NNS/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O anytime/RB/O soon/RB/O ././O
Odds/NNS/O and/CC/O Ends/NNS/O
DESPITE/IN/O GROWING/VBG/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE consumers/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O shown/VBN/O much/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O refillable/JJ/O packages/NNS/O for/IN/O household/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
Braumeisters/NNPS/B-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG tests/VBZ/O a/DT/O beer/NN/O brewed/VBN/O with/IN/O oat/NN/O bran/NN/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O rice/NN/O or/CC/O corn/NN/O ././O
Called/VBN/O Otto/NNP/O 's/POS/O Original/NNP/O Oat/NNP/O Bran/NNP/O Beer/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O brew/NN/O costs/VBZ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 12.75/CD/O a/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
No/DT/O cholesterol/NN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ././O
