Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Blair/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Enfield/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O win/VB/O election/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O board/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O shareholder/NN/O meeting/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Blair/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O after/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O filed/VBN/O separate/JJ/O lawsuits/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ontario/NNP/I-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O unjust/JJ/O dismissal/NN/O against/IN/O Enfield/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O for/IN/O libel/NN/O against/IN/O its/PRP$/O largest/JJS/O shareholder/NN/O ,/,/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O two/CD/O executives/NNS/O of/IN/O Hees/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Bancorp/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O controls/VBZ/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Blair/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Hees/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O been/VBN/O feuding/VBG/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O election/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O sequel/NN/O to/TO/O Enfield/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O annual/JJ/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Blair/NNP/B-PERSON disallowed/VBD/O proxies/NNS/O in/IN/O favor/NN/O of/IN/O two/CD/O Hees/NNP/B-ORG nominees/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Ontario/NNP/I-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG overturned/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Blair/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O decision/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O Enfield/NNP/B-ORG seeks/VBZ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O severance/NN/O pay/NN/O ,/,/O equivalent/JJ/O to/TO/O C$/$/O 720,000/CD/O ././O
Hees/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG executives/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
Enfield/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O with/IN/O interests/NNS/O in/IN/O manufacturing/VBG/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O 38.5/CD/O %/NN/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ././O
Hees/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O merchant/NN/O bank/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Toronto/NNP/B-GPE financiers/NNS/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Edward/NNP/B-PERSON Bronfman/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
All/PDT/O the/DT/O concerns/NNS/O are/VBP/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Toronto/NNP/B-GPE ././O
