Houston/NNP/B-ORG Lighting/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Houston/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O utility/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O in/IN/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG said/VBD/O Houston/NNP/B-ORG Lighting/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG current/JJ/O situation/NN/O has/VBZ/O some/DT/O positive/JJ/O aspects/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O managing/VBG/O ``/``/O very/RB/O well/RB/O ''/''/O the/DT/O construction/NN/O and/CC/O commercial/JJ/O operation/NN/O risks/NNS/O of/IN/O Units/NNS/O 1/CD/O and/CC/O 2/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC Texas/NNP/I-LOC Project/NNP/O nuclear/JJ/O power/NN/O plant/NN/O ././O
Capital/NN/O requirements/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O declining/VBG/O and/CC/O no/DT/O new/JJ/O generating/VBG/O facilities/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O for/IN/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
