A/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O Imelda/NNP/B-PERSON Marcos/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O n't/RB/O brought/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE against/IN/O her/PRP$/O will/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O marital/JJ/O privileges/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O protect/VBP/O spouses/NNS/O from/IN/O incriminating/VBG/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ,/,/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O apply/VB/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O case/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O claimed/VBN/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O over/RP/O the/DT/O documents/NNS/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O brought/VBN/O here/RB/O involuntarily/RB/O and/CC/O because/RB/O providing/VBG/O the/DT/O materials/NNS/O would/MD/O violate/VB/O her/PRP$/O marital/JJ/O privilege/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O trial/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE law/NN/O requires/VBZ/O criminal/JJ/O defendants/NNS/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O over/RP/O foreign/JJ/O documents/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O those/DT/O sought/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O law/NN/O is/VBZ/O meant/VBN/O to/TO/O overcome/VB/O delays/NNS/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O defendants/NNS/O '/POS/O use/NN/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O procedures/NNS/O to/TO/O block/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE requests/NNS/O for/IN/O records/NNS/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Keenan/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O opinion/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O charged/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Marcoses/NNPS/B-PERSON '/POS/O alleged/VBN/O crimes/NNS/O involved/VBD/O bank/NN/O accounts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O other/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O two/CD/O marital/JJ/O testimonial/JJ/O privileges/NNS/O cited/VBN/O by/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON do/VBP/O n't/RB/O apply/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O one/NN/O permits/VBZ/O a/DT/O witness/NN/O to/TO/O refuse/VB/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O against/IN/O her/PRP$/O spouse/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O second/JJ/O marital/JJ/O privilege/NN/O cited/VBN/O by/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON protects/VBZ/O confidential/JJ/O communications/NNS/O between/IN/O spouses/NNS/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O attorney/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Sandor/NNP/B-PERSON Frankel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O admitted/VBN/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O filed/VBD/O any/DT/O documents/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O those/DT/O sought/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON LaBella/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O assistant/NN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O prosecuting/VBG/O the/DT/O Marcos/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O return/VB/O phone/NN/O calls/NNS/O seeking/VBG/O comment/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O firms/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O registered/VBN/O under/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O law/NN/O as/IN/O foreign/JJ/O legal/JJ/O consultants/NNS/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O practice/NN/O with/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O clients/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O limited/VBN/O to/TO/O advising/VBG/O them/PRP/O on/IN/O matters/NNS/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O office/NN/O may/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O advise/VB/O foreign/JJ/O and/CC/O multinational/JJ/O clients/NNS/O on/IN/O international/JJ/O law/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O office/NN/O will/MD/O tap/VB/O the/DT/O resources/NNS/O of/IN/O Sidley/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 700/CD/O lawyers/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O 400/CD/O Ashurst/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O members/NNS/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Brussels/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Ashurst/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O new/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-LOC Far/NNP/I-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Sidley/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O maintain/VB/O its/PRP$/O association/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Hashidate/NNP/I-ORG Law/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O union/NN/O sued/VBD/O the/DT/O state/NN/O in/IN/O November/NNP/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O alleging/VBG/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O intentionally/RB/O segregated/VBD/O job/NN/O classifications/NNS/O by/IN/O sex/NN/O and/CC/O paid/VBD/O employees/NNS/O in/IN/O predominantly/RB/O female/JJ/O jobs/NNS/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O males/NNS/O in/IN/O comparable/JJ/O jobs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O UAW/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O charged/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O applied/VBD/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O standards/NNS/O for/IN/O determining/VBG/O pay/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O discriminatory/JJ/O manner/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O union/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O bargaining/NN/O representative/NN/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 20,000/CD/O Michigan/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O employees/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O merged/VBN/O firm/NN/O will/MD/O carry/VB/O Norris/NNP/B-ORG McLaughlin/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG name/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O would/MD/O authorize/VB/O courts/NNS/O to/TO/O order/VB/O the/DT/O licenses/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O condition/NN/O of/IN/O probation/NN/O ././O
State/NNP/O Senator/NNP/O J.E./NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Buster/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Brown/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Republican/NNP/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O running/VBG/O for/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O general/NN/O ,/,/O introduced/VBD/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O an/DT/O altered/JJ/O license/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O ``/``/O embarrassment/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O teenagers/NNS/O and/CC/O young/JJ/O adults/NNS/O and/CC/O would/MD/O act/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O deterrant/JJ/O to/TO/O drug/NN/O use/NN/O ././O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Avena/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/NN/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG Civil/NNP/I-ORG Liberties/NNPS/I-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ``/``/O political/JJ/O gimmickry/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O fails/VBZ/O to/TO/O recognize/VB/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O problem/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O health/NN/O issue/NN/O ././O
