Banca/NNP/B-ORG Nazionale/NNP/I-ORG del/FW/I-ORG Lavoro/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O potential/JJ/O losses/NNS/O from/IN/O lending/VBG/O to/TO/O Iraq/NNP/B-GPE could/MD/O reach/VB/O 1.175/CD/O trillion/CD/O lire/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 872/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O marking/VBG/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O quantification/NN/O of/IN/O potential/JJ/O costs/NNS/O of/IN/O unauthorized/JJ/O lending/NN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE branch/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O had/VBD/O ordered/VBN/O BNL/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O come/VB/O up/RP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O suitable/JJ/O program/NN/O by/IN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
BNL/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O elaborate/VB/O on/IN/O what/WDT/O measures/NNS/O were/VBD/O planned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O controls/NNS/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O branches/NNS/O abroad/RB/O ././O
