Solo/JJ/O woodwind/NN/O players/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O creative/JJ/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O work/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O their/PRP$/O repertoire/NN/O and/CC/O audience/NN/O appeal/NN/O are/VBP/O limited/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O oboist/NN/O Heinz/NNP/B-PERSON Holliger/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O line/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O :/:/O He/PRP/O commissions/VBZ/O and/CC/O splendidly/RB/O interprets/VBZ/O fearsome/JJ/O contemporary/JJ/O scores/NNS/O and/CC/O does/VBZ/O some/DT/O conducting/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O play/VB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O Mozart/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Strauss/NNP/B-PERSON concertos/NNS/O over/RB/O and/CC/O over/RB/O again/RB/O ././O
Years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O collaborated/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O music/NN/O gurus/NNS/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Serkin/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Fred/NNP/B-PERSON Sherry/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O the/DT/O very/RB/O countercultural/JJ/O chamber/NN/O group/NN/O Tashi/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O won/VBD/O audiences/NNS/O over/RP/O to/TO/O dreaded/JJ/O contemporary/JJ/O scores/NNS/O like/IN/O Messiaen/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Quartet/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O End/NN/O of/IN/O Time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O dismiss/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Stoltzman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O music/NN/O or/CC/O his/PRP$/O motives/NNS/O as/RB/O merely/RB/O commercial/JJ/O and/CC/O lightweight/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O in/IN/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O plays/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O plays/VBZ/O superbly/RB/O ././O
His/PRP$/O recent/JJ/O appearance/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Metropolitan/NNP/I-ORG Museum/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O dubbed/VBN/O ``/``/O A/DT/O Musical/JJ/O Odyssey/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O case/NN/O in/IN/O point/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O felt/VBD/O more/RBR/O like/IN/O a/DT/O party/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O a/DT/O highly/RB/O polished/JJ/O jam/NN/O session/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O friends/NNS/O ,/,/O than/IN/O a/DT/O classical/JJ/O concert/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O so/RB/O it/PRP/O went/VBD/O through/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O :/:/O an/DT/O ingeniously/RB/O chosen/VBN/O potpourri/NN/O of/IN/O pieces/NNS/O ,/,/O none/NN/O longer/JJR/O than/IN/O five/CD/O minutes/NNS/O ,/,/O none/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O disturb/VB/O or/CC/O challenge/VB/O a/DT/O listener/NN/O ././O
Bach/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Air/NN/O ''/''/O followed/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Deep/JJ/O Peace/NN/O ''/''/O also/RB/O featured/VBD/O a/DT/O slide/NN/O show/NN/O of/IN/O lovely/JJ/O but/CC/O predictable/JJ/O images/NNS/O of/IN/O clouds/NNS/O ,/,/O beaches/NNS/O ,/,/O deserts/NNS/O ,/,/O sunsets/NNS/O ,/,/O etc/FW/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O all/RB/O too/RB/O mellow/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O believed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O probably/RB/O would/MD/O have/VB/O gotten/VBN/O away/RP/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O they/PRP/O not/RB/O felt/VBD/O compelled/VBN/O to/TO/O add/VB/O Ms./NNP/O Collins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O signature/NN/O tune/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Amazing/JJ/O Grace/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ask/VB/O for/IN/O audience/NN/O participation/NN/O ././O
That/WDT/O went/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O permissible/JJ/O line/NN/O for/IN/O warm/JJ/O and/CC/O fuzzy/JJ/O feelings/NNS/O ././O
Was/VBD/O this/DT/O why/WRB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O audience/NN/O departed/VBD/O before/IN/O or/CC/O during/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O half/NN/O ?/./O
Or/CC/O was/VBD/O it/PRP/O because/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Collins/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O gone/VBN/O ?/./O
Either/DT/O way/NN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O pity/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Stolzman/NNP/B-PERSON offered/VBD/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O substantial/JJ/O music/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O evening/NN/O just/RB/O after/IN/O intermission/NN/O :/:/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON Reich/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O New/NNP/O York/NNP/O Counterpoint/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O one/CD/O of/IN/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O Reich/NNP/B-PERSON works/NNS/O that/WDT/O juxtapose/VBP/O a/DT/O live/JJ/O performer/NN/O with/IN/O recorded/JJ/O tracks/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O or/CC/O her/PRP$/O own/JJ/O playing/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Reich/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O new/JJ/O ``/``/O Different/JJ/O Trains/NNS/O ''/''/O for/IN/O string/NN/O quartet/NN/O uses/VBZ/O the/DT/O technique/NN/O magisterially/RB/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O unfortunately/RB/O illustrated/VBD/O this/DT/O intricate/JJ/O ,/,/O jazzy/JJ/O tapestry/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Pearson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O images/NNS/O ,/,/O this/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O geometric/JJ/O or/CC/O repeating/JJ/O objects/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O kitschy/JJ/O mirroring/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O musical/JJ/O structure/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O thoroughly/RB/O distracting/VBG/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reich/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O piece/NN/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Stoltzman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O elegant/JJ/O execution/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O concert/NN/O was/VBD/O more/JJR/O straight/JJ/O jazz/NN/O and/CC/O mellow/JJ/O sounds/NNS/O written/VBN/O by/IN/O Charlie/NNP/B-PERSON Parker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Ornette/NNP/B-PERSON Coleman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Douglas/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Eddie/NNP/B-PERSON Gomez/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O with/IN/O pictures/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON pieces/NNS/O ././O
Is/VBZ/O this/DT/O the/DT/O future/NN/O of/IN/O chamber/NN/O music/NN/O ?/./O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O next/JJ/O ?/./O
Slides/NNS/O to/TO/O illustrate/VB/O Shostakovich/NNP/B-PERSON quartets/NNS/O ?/./O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O an/DT/O unpleasant/JJ/O evening/NN/O ,/,/O certainly/RB/O ,/,/O thanks/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O level/NN/O of/IN/O performance/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O compositional/JJ/O talents/NNS/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O obvious/JJ/O sincerity/NN/O with/IN/O which/WDT/O Mr./NNP/O Stoltzman/NNP/B-PERSON chooses/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O selections/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O neither/RB/O deep/JJ/O nor/CC/O lasting/JJ/O :/:/O light/JJ/O entertainment/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O no/DT/O substitute/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O evening/NN/O of/IN/O Brahms/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
