The/DT/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O pipeline/NN/O concern/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O capacity/NN/O pipeline/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O proposed/VBN/O joint/NN/O venture/NN/O between/IN/O two/CD/O Panhandle/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG units/NNS/B-ORG -/:/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG Transmission/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Trunkline/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Texas/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG Transmission/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O build/VB/O and/CC/O operate/VB/O the/DT/O system/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O connect/VB/O the/DT/B-LOC Arkoma/NNP/I-LOC Basin/NNP/I-LOC with/IN/O several/JJ/O interstate/JJ/O pipelines/NNS/O ././O
