Fibreboard/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O previously/RB/O reported/JJ/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O approximately/RB/O 27,500/CD/O acres/NNS/O of/IN/O timberland/NN/O near/IN/O Truckee/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O closely/RB/O held/JJ/O Sierra/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Arcata/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O $/$/O 32.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
