Warner/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O provide/VB/O financing/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O terms/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O named/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O yet/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O any/DT/O records/NNS/O it/PRP/O produces/VBZ/O will/MD/O be/VB/O distributed/VBN/O by/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O acquired/VBN/O by/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O head/NN/O of/IN/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O discussing/VBG/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O with/IN/O both/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Azoff/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O chose/VBD/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O record/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O ``/``/O their/PRP$/O standing/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O entertainment/NN/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O second/JJ/O to/TO/O none/NN/O ././O
