The/DT/O oboist/NN/O Heinz/NNP/B-PERSON Holliger/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O line/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O :/:/O He/PRP/O commissions/VBZ/O and/CC/O splendidly/RB/O interprets/VBZ/O fearsome/JJ/O contemporary/JJ/O scores/NNS/O and/CC/O does/VBZ/O some/DT/O conducting/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O play/VB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O Mozart/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Strauss/NNP/B-PERSON concertos/NNS/O over/RB/O and/CC/O over/RB/O again/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O in/IN/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O plays/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O plays/VBZ/O superbly/RB/O ././O
His/PRP$/O recent/JJ/O appearance/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Metropolitan/NNP/I-ORG Museum/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O dubbed/VBN/O ``/``/O A/DT/O Musical/JJ/O Odyssey/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O case/NN/O in/IN/O point/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O felt/VBD/O more/RBR/O like/IN/O a/DT/O party/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O a/DT/O highly/RB/O polished/JJ/O jam/NN/O session/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O friends/NNS/O ,/,/O than/IN/O a/DT/O classical/JJ/O concert/NN/O ././O
Bach/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Air/NN/O ''/''/O followed/VBD/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O all/RB/O too/RB/O mellow/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O believed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O probably/RB/O would/MD/O have/VB/O gotten/VBN/O away/RB/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O they/PRP/O not/RB/O felt/VBD/O compelled/VBN/O to/TO/O add/VB/O Ms./NNP/O Collins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O signature/NN/O tune/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Amazing/JJ/O Grace/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ask/VB/O for/IN/O audience/NN/O participation/NN/O ././O
That/WDT/O went/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O permissible/JJ/O line/NN/O for/IN/O warm/JJ/O and/CC/O fuzzy/JJ/O feelings/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O unfortunately/RB/O illustrated/VBD/O this/DT/O intricate/JJ/O ,/,/O jazzy/JJ/O tapestry/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Pearson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O images/NNS/O ,/,/O this/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O geometric/JJ/O or/CC/O repeating/JJ/O objects/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O kitschy/JJ/O mirroring/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O musical/JJ/O structure/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O thoroughly/RB/O distracting/VBG/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reich/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O piece/NN/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Stoltzman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O elegant/JJ/O execution/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O concert/NN/O was/VBD/O more/JJR/O straight/JJ/O jazz/NN/O and/CC/O mellow/JJ/O sounds/NNS/O written/VBN/O by/IN/O Charlie/NNP/B-PERSON Parker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Ornette/NNP/B-PERSON Coleman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Douglas/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Eddie/NNP/B-PERSON Gomez/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O with/IN/O pictures/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON pieces/NNS/O ././O
