A/DT/O bitter/JJ/O conflict/NN/O with/IN/O global/JJ/O implications/NNS/O has/VBZ/O erupted/VBN/O between/IN/O Nomura/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Industrial/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O two/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/VBZ/O most/RBS/O powerful/JJ/O financial/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O are/VBP/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O financial/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O putting/VBG/O their/PRP$/O enormous/JJ/O clout/NN/O to/TO/O work/VB/O ;/:/O increasingly/RB/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O squaring/VBG/O off/RP/O against/IN/O one/CD/O another/DT/O in/IN/O unprecedented/JJ/O public/JJ/O fashion/NN/O ././O
Already/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O consequences/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O felt/VBN/O by/IN/O other/JJ/O players/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O --/:/O even/JJ/O governments/NNS/O ././O
What/WP/O triggered/VBD/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O clash/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O skirmish/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O timing/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE government/NN/O bond/NN/O issue/NN/O ././O
Unwilling/JJ/O to/TO/O put/VB/O up/RP/O new/JJ/O money/NN/O for/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE until/IN/O those/DT/O debts/NNS/O are/VBP/O repaid/VBN/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O banks/NNS/O refused/VBD/O even/RB/O to/TO/O play/VB/O administrative/JJ/O roles/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O financing/NN/O ,/,/O forcing/VBG/O an/DT/O embarrassed/JJ/O Nomura/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O postpone/VB/O it/PRP/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O dispute/NN/O shows/VBZ/O clearly/RB/O the/DT/O global/JJ/O power/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O financial/JJ/O titans/NNS/O ././O
Aside/RB/O from/IN/O Nomura/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O injured/JJ/O pride/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O victim/NN/O so/RB/O far/RB/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE government/NN/O ././O
Barred/VBN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O budget/NN/O law/NN/O from/IN/O making/VBG/O any/DT/O new/JJ/O domestic/JJ/O bond/NN/O issues/NNS/O ,/,/O Wellington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Debt/NNP/B-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O been/VBN/O casting/VBG/O abroad/RB/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O the/DT/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O New/NNP/O Zealand/NNP/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 1.76/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O NZ$/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O it/PRP/O needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O come/VB/O up/RB/O with/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O next/IN/O June/NNP/O 30/CD/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O can/MD/O they/PRP/O block/VB/O Wellington/NNP/B-GPE from/IN/O raising/VBG/O money/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O bankers/NNS/O here/RB/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O as/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O underwriters/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Eurobond/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O might/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O scuttle/VB/O borrowings/NNS/O there/RB/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE finance/NN/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Caygill/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O lashed/VBD/O out/RB/O at/IN/O such/JJ/O suggestions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O may/MD/O very/RB/O well/RB/O be/VB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O banks/NNS/O want/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Zealand/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O irresponsible/JJ/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O not/RB/O about/IN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O blackmailed/VBN/O by/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O banks/NNS/O or/CC/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O international/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
No/DT/O less/RBR/O significant/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O banks/NNS/O '/POS/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O off/RP/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O pressure/VB/O a/DT/O foreign/JJ/O government/NN/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O implications/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O confrontation/NN/O between/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE securities/NNS/O and/CC/O banking/VBG/O industries/NNS/O ././O
Anxiety/NN/O is/VBZ/O rising/VBG/O over/IN/O recent/JJ/O government/NN/O proposals/NNS/O to/TO/O eventually/RB/O lower/VB/O the/DT/O strict/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O that/WDT/O now/RB/O separate/VBP/O --/:/O and/CC/O protect/VBP/O --/:/O the/DT/O two/CD/O industries/NNS/O from/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
Both/DT/O sides/NNS/O are/VBP/O jealously/RB/O guarding/VBG/O their/PRP$/O turf/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O relations/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O flashpoint/NN/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O banks/NNS/O badly/RB/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O break/VB/O into/IN/O all/DT/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O securities/NNS/O business/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O securities/NNS/O companies/NNS/O --/:/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O smaller/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O --/:/O are/VBP/O seeking/VBG/O access/NN/O only/RB/O to/TO/O limited/JJ/O kinds/NNS/O of/IN/O banking/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O open/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O brunt/NN/O of/IN/O competition/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Nomura/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O securities/NNS/O company/NN/O largely/RB/O by/IN/O virtue/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O protected/JJ/O home/NN/O field/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Industrial/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/RBS/O innovative/JJ/O and/CC/O aggressive/JJ/O bank/NN/O in/IN/O capital/NN/O markets/NNS/O abroad/RB/O ,/,/O captain/VBP/O the/DT/O opposing/VBG/O sides/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O their/PRP$/O suspicions/NNS/O of/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O run/VBP/O deep/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O both/DT/O have/VBP/O tried/VBN/O to/TO/O stretch/VB/O the/DT/O limits/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O Industrial/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG started/VBD/O up/RP/O a/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE securities/NNS/O subsidiary/NN/O that/WDT/O sells/VBZ/O Japanese/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O to/TO/O non-Japanese/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O overseas/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O move/NN/O that/WDT/O stirred/VBD/O the/DT/O anger/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O ././O
