Newport/NNP/B-ORG Electronics/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG named/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O slate/NN/O of/IN/O officers/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O move/NN/O that/WDT/O follows/VBZ/O replacement/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O five/CD/O incumbent/JJ/O directors/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
Milton/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Hollander/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 60/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O Barrett/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Weekes/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hollander/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O chairman/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Weekes/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O among/IN/O the/DT/O ousted/VBN/O directors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O declined/VBN/O requests/NNS/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Weekes/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hollander/NNP/B-PERSON wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O have/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O team/NN/O ././O
Scott/NNP/B-PERSON Wakeman/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE operations/NNS/O ,/,/O titles/NNS/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Weekes/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wakeman/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O instrument/NN/O and/CC/O controls/NNS/O division/NN/O of/IN/O closely/RB/O held/JJ/O Omega/NNP/B-ORG Engineering/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O company/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hollander/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
A/DT/O company/NN/O spokesman/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Wakeman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O age/NN/O ././O
James/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Lees/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 51/CD/O ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Newport/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O European/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O European/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O assuming/VBG/O some/DT/O former/JJ/O duties/NNS/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Weekes/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Crozier/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 34/CD/O ,/,/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Virtue/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O another/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ousted/VBN/O directors/NNS/O ././O
