Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Berthold/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Wildbad/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O Belgium/NNP/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O especially/RB/O will/MD/O strengthen/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O efforts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O rapidly/RB/O growing/VBG/O field/NN/O of/IN/O bio-analytical/JJ/O instrumentation/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O applied/JJ/O nuclear/JJ/O physics/NNS/O ././O
Mason/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O toxicology/NN/O lab/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-LOC England/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O with/IN/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O 140/CD/O employees/NNS/O ././O
Mason/NNP/B-ORG serves/VBZ/O commercial/JJ/O and/CC/O government/NN/O customers/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Institutes/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O combined/JJ/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O become/VB/O profitable/JJ/O by/IN/O January/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O James/NNP/B-PERSON P./NNP/I-PERSON Sherblom/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Transgenic/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
