But/CC/O there/EX/O may/MD/O be/VB/O less/JJR/O there/RB/O than/IN/O meets/VBZ/O the/DT/O eye/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O original/JJ/O strategy/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O in/IN/O itself/PRP/O a/DT/O brilliant/JJ/O innovation/NN/O for/IN/O spreading/VBG/O a/DT/O religion/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O create/VB/O new/JJ/O economic/JJ/O enterprises/NNS/O each/DT/O time/NN/O he/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O and/CC/O fund/VB/O his/PRP$/O various/JJ/O religious/JJ/O missions/NNS/O ././O
More/RBR/O stable/JJ/O industries/NNS/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O build/VB/O an/DT/O economically/RB/O viable/JJ/O infrastructure/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Moon/NNP/B-PERSON movement/NN/O in/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Then/RB/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O move/VB/O his/PRP$/O movement/NN/O to/TO/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ././O
Throughout/IN/O the/DT/O 1970s/NNS/O and/CC/O early/RB/O 1980s/NNS/O spokesmen/NNS/O for/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/B-ORG Unification/NNP/I-ORG Church/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O opponents/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O anticult/NN/O movement/NN/O gave/VBD/O wildly/RB/O exaggerated/JJ/O membership/NN/O figures/NNS/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O legacy/NN/O lives/VBZ/O on/RP/O ././O
Some/DT/O estimates/NNS/O have/VBP/O gone/VBN/O as/RB/O high/JJ/O as/IN/O 80,000/CD/O members/NNS/O ././O
Defections/NNS/O ,/,/O burnouts/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O abduction/NN/O ``/``/O deprogrammings/NNS/O ''/''/O kept/VBN/O member/NN/O turnover/NN/O high/RB/O ././O
That/IN/O the/DT/O membership/NN/O number/NN/O has/VBZ/O even/RB/O kept/VBN/O close/RB/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O 1976/CD/O size/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O graying/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O church/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O enthusiastic/JJ/O young/JJ/O ``/``/O Moonies/NNPS/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON era/NN/O who/WP/O remained/VBD/O faithful/NN/O to/TO/O Father/NNP/O Moon/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O now/RB/O parents/NNS/O ,/,/O producing/VBG/O new/JJ/O members/NNS/O by/IN/O procreation/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O conversion/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O reputed/JJ/O wealth/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Unification/NNP/I-ORG Church/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O another/DT/O matter/NN/O of/IN/O contention/NN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O these/DT/O purchases/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O misleading/JJ/O ././O
Most/JJS/O were/VBD/O obtained/VBN/O with/IN/O huge/JJ/O inputs/NNS/O of/IN/O church/NN/O money/NN/O from/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O minimum/NN/O cash/NN/O downpayments/NNS/O and/CC/O sizable/JJ/O mortgages/NNS/O ././O
Only/JJ/O his/PRP$/O factories/NNS/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Korea/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O employing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O followers/NNS/O at/IN/O subsistence/NN/O wages/NNS/O and/CC/O producing/VBG/O everything/NN/O from/IN/O rifles/NNS/O to/TO/O ginseng/NN/O to/TO/O expensive/JJ/O marble/NN/O vases/NNS/O ,/,/O kept/VBD/O the/DT/O money/NN/O flowing/VBG/O westward/RB/O ././O
Virginia/NNP/B-ORG Commonwealth/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG sociologist/NN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Bromley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O researcher/NN/O has/VBZ/O delved/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O complex/JJ/O world/NN/O of/IN/O Unificationist/JJ/B-ORG finances/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O concluded/VBN/O that/IN/O profitable/JJ/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O exceptions/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O the/DT/O rule/NN/O ././O
Likewise/RB/O ,/,/O journalists/NNS/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Burgess/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Isikoff/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG Post/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O estimated/VBN/O that/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O was/VBD/O transferred/VBN/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O deal/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O church/NN/O 's/POS/O annual/JJ/O operating/NN/O losses/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O components/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O church/NN/O had/VBD/O their/PRP$/O budgets/NNS/O cut/VBN/O in/IN/O half/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O and/CC/O again/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O attended/VBD/O several/JJ/O of/IN/O these/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O dual/JJ/O role/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O presenter/NN/O of/IN/O research/NN/O findings/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O an/DT/O investigator/NN/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O hosts/NNS/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Moon/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Paragon/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG eventually/RB/O even/RB/O published/VBD/O three/CD/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O co-edited/JJ/O books/NNS/O on/IN/O religion/NN/O and/CC/O politics/NNS/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O veteran/NN/O watchers/NNS/O of/IN/O Unificationist/JJ/B-ORG affairs/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Dr./NNP/O J./NNP/B-PERSON Gordon/NNP/I-PERSON Melton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Study/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Religion/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O almost/RB/O all/DT/O operations/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O drastically/RB/O reduced/VBN/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Moon/NNP/B-PERSON now/RB/O concentrates/VBZ/O more/RBR/O on/IN/O developing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O empire/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Far/NNP/I-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC had/VBD/O proved/VBN/O even/RB/O less/RBR/O hospitable/JJ/O than/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
European/JJ/O politicians/NNS/O were/VBD/O less/RBR/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O their/PRP$/O governments/NNS/O investigate/VB/O and/CC/O harass/VB/O new/JJ/O religions/NNS/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
So/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Moon/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O in/IN/O retreat/NN/O ,/,/O refocusing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Far/NNP/I-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE continue/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O profitable/JJ/O ././O
Moon/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Tong'Il/NNP/B-ORG industry/NN/O conglomerate/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O investing/VBG/O heavily/RB/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O church/NN/O accountants/NNS/O have/VBP/O high/JJ/O hopes/NNS/O of/IN/O expanding/VBG/O and/CC/O attracting/VBG/O converts/NNS/O even/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bloody/JJ/O massacre/NN/O in/IN/O Tiananmen/NNP/B-FAC Square/NNP/I-FAC ././O
Panda/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O such/JJ/O investment/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Moon/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O put/VB/O up/RP/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O for/IN/O 25/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O profits/NNS/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O return/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O blessing/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O churches/NNS/O and/CC/O spread/VBD/O Unificationism/NNP/O in/IN/O that/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Shupe/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O co-author/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O with/IN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Bromley/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O of/IN/O ``/``/O `/``/O Moonies/NNS/O '/''/O in/IN/O America/NNP/O :/:/O Cult/NN/O ,/,/O Church/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Crusade/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Strange/JJ/O Gods/NNS/O :/:/O The/DT/O Great/JJ/O American/JJ/O Cult/NNP/O Scare/NNP/O ././O
