Concerns/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O pace/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Vienna/NNP/B-GPE talks/NNS/O --/:/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O destruction/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O 100,000/CD/O weapons/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O major/JJ/O reductions/NNS/O and/CC/O realignments/NNS/O of/IN/O troops/NNS/O in/IN/O central/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC --/:/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O registered/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O called/VBN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O September/NNP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O contend/VBP/O that/IN/O a/DT/O reduction/NN/O of/IN/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG forces/NNS/O under/IN/O a/DT/O treaty/NN/O will/MD/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O conventional/JJ/O Soviet/JJ/O attack/NN/O unless/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O retains/VBZ/O a/DT/O residual/JJ/O force/NN/O of/IN/O nuclear/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O no/DT/O ally/NN/O has/VBZ/O complained/VBN/O openly/RB/O ,/,/O preserving/VBG/O the/DT/O impression/NN/O that/IN/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O line/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON position/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O quick/JJ/O agreement/NN/O bringing/VBG/O Soviet/JJ/O conventional/JJ/O forces/NNS/O down/RB/O to/TO/O parity/NN/O with/IN/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O 's/POS/O top/JJ/O bargaining/NN/O priority/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O even/RB/O though/IN/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG negotiators/NNS/O have/VBP/O only/RB/O 10/CD/O months/NNS/O left/VBN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON timetable/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O wrestling/VBG/O over/IN/O such/JJ/O seemingly/RB/O fundamental/JJ/O questions/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O What/WP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O tank/NN/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Five/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O six/CD/O categories/NNS/O of/IN/O weapons/NNS/O under/IN/O negotiation/NN/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O been/VBN/O defined/VBN/O ././O
Tanks/NNS/O currently/RB/O are/VBP/O defined/VBN/O as/IN/O armored/JJ/O vehicles/NNS/O weighing/VBG/O 25/CD/O tons/NNS/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O that/IN/O carry/VB/O large/JJ/O guns/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O complicated/VBD/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O by/IN/O offering/VBG/O to/TO/O include/VB/O light/JJ/O tanks/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O as/RB/O light/JJ/O as/IN/O 10/CD/O tons/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O stickier/JJR/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O ././O
France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE all/DT/O have/VBP/O light/JJ/O tanks/NNS/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ././O
Defining/VBG/O combat/NN/O aircraft/NN/O is/VBZ/O even/RB/O tougher/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O insisted/VBD/O that/DT/O aircraft/NN/O be/VB/O brought/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O argued/VBD/O for/IN/O exempting/VBG/O some/DT/O 4,000/CD/O Russian/JJ/O planes/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O solely/RB/O defensive/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O dispute/NN/O over/IN/O that/DT/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O one/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE official/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O potential/JJ/O treaty/NN/O stopper/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O only/RB/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Soviet/JJ/O leader/NN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON may/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O resolve/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Accounting/NN/O problems/NNS/O raise/VBP/O more/JJR/O knotty/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
Other/JJ/O nations/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O sure/JJ/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O arsenals/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O just/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sloppy/JJ/O ,/,/O both/DT/O on/IN/O our/PRP$/O side/NN/O and/CC/O theirs/PRP/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O Warsaw/NNP/O Pact/NNP/O 's/POS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG analyst/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O bigger/JJR/O danger/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O would/MD/O delay/VB/O action/NN/O so/RB/O long/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNPS/O might/MD/O back/VB/O away/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O conciliatory/JJ/O attitude/NN/O ././O
``/``/O So/RB/O what/WP/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O miss/VBP/O 50/CD/O tanks/NNS/O somewhere/RB/O ?/./O ''/''/O asks/VBZ/O Rep./NNP/O Norman/NNP/B-PERSON Dicks/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Wash./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG group/NN/O that/WDT/O visited/VBD/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O in/IN/O Vienna/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O bottom/JJ/O line/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O get/VB/O that/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Warsaw/NNP/O Pact/NNP/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O superiority/NN/O brought/VBD/O down/RB/O to/TO/O parity/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O pressing/VBG/O ahead/RB/O as/RB/O quickly/RB/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O worry/VBP/O more/RBR/O about/IN/O things/NNS/O becoming/VBG/O so/RB/O unraveled/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O side/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O might/MD/O become/VB/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O negotiate/VB/O ././O
