Northwest/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG settled/VBD/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O lawsuits/NNS/O filed/VBN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O 156/CD/O people/NNS/O killed/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O claims/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O jetliner/NN/O 's/POS/O maker/NN/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O pursued/VBN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O settlements/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O 145/CD/O lawsuits/NNS/O against/IN/O Northwest/NNP/B-ORG were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O 157/CD/O lawsuits/NNS/O were/VBD/O filed/VBN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O crash/NN/O victims/NNS/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/O Judge/NNP/O Julian/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Cook/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON announced/VBD/O the/DT/O settlements/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O jury/NN/O trial/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O reset/VB/O opening/JJ/O arguments/NNS/O for/IN/O today/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O jury/NN/O will/MD/O resolve/VB/O the/DT/O claims/NNS/O against/IN/O McDonnell/NNP/B-ORG Douglas/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Northwest/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O claim/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O defect/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O aircraft/NN/O caused/VBD/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O McDonnell/NNP/B-ORG Douglas/NNP/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG claim/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O plane/NN/O was/VBD/O improperly/RB/O flown/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Safety/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O pilots/NNS/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O set/VB/O the/DT/O plane/NN/O 's/POS/O wing/NN/O flaps/NNS/O and/CC/O slats/NNS/O properly/RB/O for/IN/O takeoff/NN/O and/CC/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O mandatory/JJ/O preflight/JJ/O checks/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O detected/VBN/O the/DT/O error/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O passenger/NN/O who/WP/O survived/VBD/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O was/VBD/O Cecelia/NNP/B-PERSON Cichan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O then/RB/O 4/CD/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Tempe/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O whose/WP$/O parents/NNS/O and/CC/O brother/NN/O died/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O now/RB/O lives/VBZ/O with/IN/O relatives/NNS/O in/IN/O Alabama/NNP/B-GPE ././O
