The/DT/O venture/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O in/IN/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O rapid/JJ/O expansion/NN/O of/IN/O overseas/JJ/O investment/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O because/IN/O when/WRB/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG looks/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O an/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O demographic/JJ/O gold/NN/O mine/NN/O ././O
Coke/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O tended/VBN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O its/PRP$/O control/NN/O when/WRB/O results/NNS/O were/VBD/O sluggish/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O given/VBN/O country/NN/O ././O
Coke/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O be/VB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O more/RBR/O quickly/RB/O developing/VBG/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O untapped/JJ/O potential/NN/O in/IN/O those/DT/O markets/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O Coke/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O whether/IN/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O direction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ././O
