But/CC/O in/IN/O another/DT/O sense/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O $/$/O 846/CD/O million/CD/O purchase/NN/O is/VBZ/O uncharacteristically/RB/O nervy/JJ/O ,/,/O industry/NN/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O of/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG prefer/VBP/O to/TO/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O affinities/NNS/O ,/,/O nearly/RB/O dismissing/VBG/O the/DT/O threat/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O backlash/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE public/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O think/VBP/O there/EX/O will/MD/O be/VB/O positive/JJ/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O negative/JJ/O reactions/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Raymond/NNP/B-PERSON Pettit/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O On/IN/O balance/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O positive/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O some/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O businessmen/NNS/O worry/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O prominent/JJ/O purchase/NN/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O the/DT/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O deal/NN/O that/WDT/O should/MD/O be/VB/O avoided/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O being/VBG/O ././O
In/RB/O particular/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O criticize/VBP/O the/DT/O timing/NN/O ,/,/O coming/VBG/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O heels/NNS/O of/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG controversial/JJ/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNPS/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Officially/RB/O ,/,/O yes/UH/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O encourage/VBP/O the/DT/O free/JJ/O flow/NN/O of/IN/O direct/JJ/O investment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O Foreign/NNP/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O choose/VB/O this/DT/O particular/JJ/O moment/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
During/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O leading/VBG/O business/NN/O organizations/NNS/O have/VBP/O repeatedly/RB/O urged/VBN/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O refrain/VB/O from/IN/O flashy/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O purchases/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O
In/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Arco/NNP/B-FAC Plaza/NNP/I-FAC was/VBD/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O Shuwa/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 620/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Sumitomo/NNP/B-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG paid/VBD/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O IBM/NNP/B-FAC Tower/NNP/I-FAC last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Altogether/RB/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE commercial/JJ/O real/NN/O estate/NN/O grew/VBD/O from/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O to/TO/O about/IN/O $/$/O 7.1/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Many/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O taken/VBN/O the/DT/O warnings/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O to/TO/O heart/NN/O and/CC/O sought/VBD/O development/NN/O partnerships/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O landmark/NN/O properties/NNS/O ././O
Critics/NNS/O say/VBP/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG decision/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O into/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG reflects/VBZ/O the/DT/O degree/NN/O to/TO/O which/WDT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O irritated/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O pressure/NN/O to/TO/O act/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O good/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O to/TO/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O has/VBZ/O just/RB/O the/DT/O elements/NNS/O that/WDT/O should/MD/O win/VB/O support/NN/O from/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O ././O
First/RB/O of/IN/O all/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O friendly/JJ/O acquisition/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG sought/VBD/O out/RP/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O asked/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O share/NN/O ././O
Secondly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O found/VBD/O a/DT/O similarity/NN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O business/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O philosophies/NNS/O and/CC/O intend/VBP/O to/TO/O cooperate/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O range/NN/O of/IN/O activities/NNS/O from/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O to/TO/O telecommunications/NN/O ././O
Finally/RB/O ,/,/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O no/DT/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O interfere/VB/O with/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O management/NN/O beyond/IN/O taking/VBG/O a/DT/O place/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 'll/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O work/VB/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O in/IN/O keeping/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O reputation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O rely/VB/O very/RB/O much/RB/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O leadership/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Jotaro/NNP/B-PERSON Takagi/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O well/RB/O have/VB/O found/VBN/O its/PRP$/O match/NN/O in/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O company/NN/O of/IN/O long/JJ/O history/NN/O ,/,/O strong/JJ/O government/NN/O ties/NNS/O and/CC/O sound/JJ/O resources/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O asset/NN/O terms/NNS/O ,/,/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O firm/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O core/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O holdings/NNS/O is/VBZ/O 190,000/CD/O square/JJ/O meters/NNS/O of/IN/O incredibly/RB/O expensive/JJ/O property/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Marunouchi/NNP/I-LOC district/NN/I-LOC ,/,/O the/DT/O business/NN/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O center/NN/O of/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O often/RB/O jokingly/RB/O called/VBN/O ``/``/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-GPE Village/NNP/I-GPE ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O company/NN/O acquired/VBD/O that/IN/O property/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O some/DT/O 100/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O samurai/NN/O residential/JJ/O land/NN/O running/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O moat/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Imperial/NNP/I-FAC Palace/NNP/I-FAC east/RB/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O hodgepodge/NN/O of/IN/O tiny/JJ/O shops/NNS/O and/CC/O twisted/JJ/O alleys/NNS/O that/WDT/O made/VBD/O up/RP/O the/DT/O merchants/NNS/O '/POS/O district/NN/O ././O
Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG built/VBD/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O dream/NN/O development/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O story/NN/O goes/VBZ/O ,/,/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O official/JJ/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O locate/VB/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O central/JJ/O railway/NN/O station/NN/O there/RB/O ././O
Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG group/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O known/JJ/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O cautiousness/NN/O in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O had/VBN/O little/JJ/O need/NN/O for/IN/O bold/JJ/O overseas/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O :/:/O In/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBN/O March/NNP/O 31/CD/O ,/,/O 57.4/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O total/JJ/O revenue/NN/O came/VBD/O from/IN/O office/NN/O building/NN/O management/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O earnings/NNS/O can/MD/O rise/VB/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 12/CD/O %/NN/O annually/RB/O simply/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O natural/JJ/O turnover/NN/O of/IN/O tenants/NNS/O and/CC/O automatic/JJ/O rent/NN/O increases/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Graeme/NNP/B-PERSON McDonald/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O James/NNP/B-ORG Capel/NNP/I-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O net/JJ/O income/NN/O jumped/VBD/O a/DT/O robust/JJ/O 19/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 35.5/CD/O billion/CD/O yen/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 250.2/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
For/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG purchase/NN/O will/MD/O catapult/VB/O it/PRP/O firmly/RB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O overseas/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O one/CD/O area/NN/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O lagged/VBN/O notably/RB/O behind/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Mitsui/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O purchased/VBN/O the/DT/B-FAC Exxon/NNP/I-FAC Building/NNP/I-FAC ././O
``/``/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O in/IN/O overseas/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O for/IN/O diversification/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Yoshio/NNP/B-PERSON Shima/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O overseas/JJ/O purchase/NN/O for/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O played/VBN/O a/DT/O leading/VBG/O role/NN/O in/IN/O designing/VBG/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE Citicorp/NNP/B-FAC Plaza/NNP/I-FAC ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG investment/NN/O is/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O largest/JJS/O ././O
Nonetheless/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O barely/RB/O make/VB/O a/DT/O dent/NN/O in/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG finances/NNS/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O decided/VBN/O how/WRB/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O raise/VB/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O due/JJ/O in/IN/O cash/NN/O next/IN/O April/NNP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Marunouchi/NNP/B-GPE holdings/NNS/O alone/RB/O are/VBP/O estimated/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O market/NN/O value/NN/O of/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 10/CD/O trillion/CD/O yen/NNS/O to/TO/O 11/CD/O trillion/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O sure/JJ/O to/TO/O win/VB/O a/DT/O favorable/JJ/O loan/NN/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O could/MD/O easily/RB/O issue/VB/O new/JJ/O convertible/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O or/CC/O warrants/NNS/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O home/NN/O ,/,/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O control/VB/O of/IN/O some/DT/O major/JJ/O projects/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O centerpiece/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O complex/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-FAC Landmark/NNP/I-FAC Tower/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O tallest/JJS/O building/NN/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O completed/VBN/O in/IN/O 1993/CD/O ././O
