SFE/NNP/B-ORG Technologies/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O William/NNP/B-PERSON P./NNP/I-PERSON Kuehn/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O elected/VBN/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O troubled/JJ/O electronics/NN/O parts/NNS/O maker/NN/O ././O
Jerome/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Jahn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Rubendall/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O resigning/VBG/O by/IN/O ``/``/O mutual/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O other/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Jahn/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rubendall/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kuehn/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O retain/VB/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O management/NN/O team/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O nine/CD/O months/NNS/O ended/VBN/O July/NNP/O 29/CD/O ,/,/O SFE/NNP/B-ORG Technologies/NNPS/I-ORG reported/VBD/O a/DT/O net/JJ/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 889,000/CD/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 23.4/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
