But/CC/O the/DT/O Peugeot/NNP/B-ORG breakthrough/NN/O came/VBD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O nationwide/JJ/O dispute/NN/O by/IN/O Finance/NNP/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG employees/NNS/O disrupted/VBD/O border/NN/O checkpoints/NNS/O and/CC/O threatened/VBD/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O its/PRP$/O bills/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Peugeot/NNP/B-ORG metalworkers/NNS/O began/VBD/O filing/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shop/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O auto/NN/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Mulhouse/NNP/B-GPE after/IN/O voting/VBG/O 589/CD/O to/TO/O 193/CD/O to/TO/O abandon/VB/O the/DT/O occupation/NN/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O withdrawal/NN/O was/VBD/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O promises/NNS/O by/IN/O Peugeot/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O open/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O in/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE at/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O man/NN/O left/VBD/O the/DT/O premises/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O strike/NN/O by/IN/O customs/NNS/O officers/NNS/O ,/,/O tax/NN/O collectors/NNS/O ,/,/O treasury/NN/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O civil/JJ/O servants/NNS/O attached/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O pose/VB/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O serious/JJ/O challenge/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O government/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O average/JJ/O Frenchman/NNP/O ././O
