Mr./NNP/O Rosenblatt/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O resigned/VBD/O because/IN/O of/IN/O difficulties/NNS/O with/IN/O commuting/VBG/O between/IN/O his/PRP$/O home/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O 's/POS/O editorial/NN/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O Frankly/NNP/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O missed/VBD/O my/PRP$/O family/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Rosenblatt/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Rosenblatt/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O tenure/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O 's/POS/O advertising/NN/O pages/NNS/O and/CC/O circulation/NN/O have/VBP/O grown/VBN/O significantly/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O at/IN/O 2.3/CD/O million/CD/O weekly/RB/O paid/VBN/O circulation/NN/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG still/RB/O ranks/VBZ/O third/JJ/O behind/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Time/NNP/B-ORG magazine/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O 4.4/CD/O million/CD/O circulation/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Washington/NNP/B-ORG Post/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Newsweek/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O 3.3/CD/O million/CD/O circulation/NN/O ././O
Mortimer/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Zuckerman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O editor/NN/O in/IN/O chief/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Rosenblatt/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O be/VB/O succeeded/VBN/O starting/VBG/O today/NN/O by/IN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Ruby/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O 's/POS/O executive/NN/O editor/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Merrill/NNP/B-PERSON McLoughlin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O senior/JJ/O writer/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ruby/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Ms./NNP/O McLoughlin/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O married/VBN/O to/TO/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O offers/NNS/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O work/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O writer/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O an/DT/O editor/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O now/RB/O consider/VB/O those/DT/O offers/NNS/O ././O
