Hammond/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O Fidelity/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG extended/VBD/O its/PRP$/O previous/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O under/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O purchase/VB/O any/DT/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mortgage/NN/O banker/NN/O 's/POS/O common/JJ/O stock/NN/O ,/,/O through/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 31/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O previous/JJ/O agreement/NN/O expired/VBD/O Thursday/NNP/O ././O
Fidelity/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O increased/VBN/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Hammond/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O 23.57/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ././O
Statements/NNS/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O Securities/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG filings/NNS/O led/VBD/O Hammond/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O request/VB/O a/DT/O standstill/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ././O
