Recognition/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O settled/VBD/O a/DT/O civil/JJ/O action/NN/O filed/VBN/O against/IN/O it/PRP/O by/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Postal/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O named/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O former/JJ/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Moore/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Reedy/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O five/CD/O defendants/NNS/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O charged/VBD/O the/DT/O defendants/NNS/O with/IN/O causing/VBG/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Voss/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O ex-member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Postal/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG board/NN/O of/IN/O governors/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O $/$/O 23,000/CD/O in/IN/O bribes/NNS/O ,/,/O kickbacks/NNS/O and/CC/O gratuities/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Voss/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O previously/RB/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O fined/VBN/O $/$/O 11,000/CD/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O role/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O scheme/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O Recognition/NN/B-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O in/IN/O return/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O release/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O claims/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Moore/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Reedy/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O five/CD/O additional/JJ/O defendants/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O parties/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O trial/NN/O on/IN/O criminal/JJ/O allegations/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O two/CD/O former/JJ/O executives/NNS/O began/VBD/O Sept./NNP/O 27/CD/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG District/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Columbia/NNP/I-ORG ././O
They/PRP/O were/VBD/O indicted/VBN/O last/JJ/O October/NNP/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O ,/,/O theft/NN/O and/CC/O conspiracy/NN/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O Postal/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG equipment/NN/O contracts/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O data/NNS/O management/NN/O equipment/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O executives/NNS/O deny/VBP/O the/DT/O charges/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O related/VBN/O development/NN/O ,/,/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Postal/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O barred/VBN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O from/IN/O bidding/VBG/O on/IN/O postal/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O for/IN/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O 120/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Postal/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG originally/RB/O suspended/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O Oct./NNP/O 7/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O renewing/VBG/O the/DT/O ban/NN/O ever/RB/O since/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O a/DT/O lifting/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O suspension/NN/O ././O
