Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG Aeronautical/NNP/I-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O join/VB/O with/IN/O Aermacchi/NNP/B-ORG S.p/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG A./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Varese/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O propose/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O generation/NN/O of/IN/O jet/NN/O trainers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Air/NNP/B-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O 540/CD/O new/JJ/O primary/JJ/O jet/NN/O trainers/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O value/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O between/IN/O 1994/CD/O and/CC/O 2004/CD/O ././O
Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Navy/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O also/RB/O buy/VB/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O 340/CD/O trainer/NN/O aircraft/NN/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O its/PRP$/O T34C/CD/O trainers/NNS/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Beech/NNP/B-ORG Aircraft/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O of/IN/O Raytheon/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
A/DT/O Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O in/IN/O Burbank/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O other/JJ/O companies/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O competing/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Air/NNP/B-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG contract/NN/O ././O
