Mr./NNP/O Wertheimer/NNP/B-PERSON based/VBD/O this/DT/O on/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON that/WDT/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Wall/NNP/B-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG story/NN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O :/:/O ``/``/O One/CD/O question/NN/O .../:/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O with/IN/O whether/IN/O my/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O support/NN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O way/NN/O influenced/VBD/O several/JJ/O political/JJ/O figures/NNS/O to/TO/O take/VB/O up/RP/O my/PRP$/O cause/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O say/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O forceful/JJ/O way/NN/O I/PRP/O can/MD/O :/:/O I/PRP/O certainly/RB/O hope/VB/O so/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O a/DT/O highly/RB/O unusual/JJ/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O Sen./NNP/O DeConcini/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O office/NN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O five/CD/O senators/NNS/O asked/VBD/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O up/RP/O on/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O notes/NNS/O taken/VBN/O by/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O participants/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O regulators/NNS/O said/VBD/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O gambling/VBG/O dangerously/RB/O with/IN/O depositors/NNS/O '/POS/O federally/RB/O insured/VBN/O money/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O a/DT/O ticking/VBG/O time/NN/O bomb/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O complained/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O regulators/NNS/O were/VBD/O being/VBG/O too/RB/O zealous/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O notes/NNS/O show/VBP/O that/IN/O Sen./NNP/O DeConcini/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Loan/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG regulations/NNS/O ``/``/O grossly/RB/O unfair/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Glenn/NNP/B-PERSON insisted/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O thrift/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O viable/JJ/O and/CC/O profitable/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
For/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O regulating/VBG/O thrifts/NNS/O ,/,/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O act/VB/O --/:/O even/RB/O after/IN/O federal/JJ/O auditors/NNS/O warned/VBD/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O 1987/CD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O caused/VBN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O become/VB/O insolvent/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O newly/RB/O formed/VBN/O Resolution/NNP/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O successor/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O filed/VBD/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O several/JJ/O others/NNS/O on/IN/O Sept./NNP/O 15/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O filed/VBN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O alleging/VBG/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O property/NN/O was/VBD/O taken/VBN/O illegally/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O cost/NN/O to/TO/O taxpayers/NNS/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O collapse/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O estimated/VBN/O at/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Details/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O affair/NN/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O public/JJ/O gradually/RB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O reporting/VBG/O by/IN/O several/JJ/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O 1988/CD/O re-election/NN/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Riegle/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O returned/VBD/O $/$/O 76,000/CD/O in/IN/O contributions/NNS/O after/IN/O a/DT/O Detroit/NNP/B-GPE newspaper/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O gathered/VBN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O about/IN/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O with/IN/O regulators/NNS/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O DeConcini/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O after/IN/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O fending/VBG/O off/RP/O intense/JJ/O press/NN/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O returned/VBD/O $/$/O 48,000/CD/O only/JJ/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O shortly/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O formally/RB/O accused/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O defrauding/VBG/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O McCain/NNP/B-PERSON last/JJ/O week/NN/O disclosed/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O belatedly/RB/O had/VBD/O paid/VBN/O $/$/O 13,433/CD/O to/TO/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O reimbursement/NN/O for/IN/O trips/NNS/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O family/NN/O took/VBD/O aboard/IN/O the/DT/O corporate/JJ/O jet/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O vacation/NN/O home/NN/O at/IN/O Cat/NNP/B-GPE Cay/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O Bahamas/NNPS/B-GPE ,/,/O from/IN/O 1984/CD/O through/IN/O 1986/CD/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O McCain/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O meant/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O trips/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O but/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O ``/``/O fell/VBD/O between/IN/O the/DT/O cracks/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O family/NN/O members/NNS/O and/CC/O associates/NNS/O also/RB/O donated/VBD/O $/$/O 112,000/CD/O to/TO/O Sen./NNP/O McCain/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O congressional/JJ/O campaigns/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O press/NN/O accounts/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Sen./NNP/O McCain/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON broke/VBD/O off/RP/O their/PRP$/O friendship/NN/O abruptly/RB/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O because/IN/O the/DT/O senator/NN/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O press/VB/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O executive/NN/O 's/POS/O case/NN/O as/RB/O vigorously/RB/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON wanted/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O became/VBD/O very/RB/O angry/JJ/O at/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O left/VBD/O my/PRP$/O office/NN/O and/CC/O told/VBD/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O that/IN/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O wimp/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Sen./NNP/O McCain/NNP/B-PERSON recalls/VBZ/O ././O
Also/RB/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE newspapers/NNS/O disclosed/VBD/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O in/IN/O corporate/JJ/O donations/NNS/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG Policy/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O committee/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Glenn/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
That/DT/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 34,000/CD/O in/IN/O direct/JJ/O campaign/NN/O donations/NNS/O arranged/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O the/DT/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE senator/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wertheimer/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Ethics/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG should/MD/O hire/VB/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O outside/JJ/O counsel/NN/O to/TO/O conduct/VB/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O was/VBD/O done/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O of/IN/O former/JJ/O House/NNP/B-ORG Speaker/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Wilson/NNP/B-PERSON Abney/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O staff/NN/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ethics/NNS/O panel/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Riegle/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O cooperate/VB/O with/IN/O any/DT/O inquiry/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O conduct/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O ``/``/O entirely/RB/O proper/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Sen./NNP/O McCain/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O ``/``/O deeply/RB/O concerned/VBN/O ''/''/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O might/MD/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O improper/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O decided/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O entirely/RB/O appropriate/JJ/O ''/''/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O fair/JJ/O treatment/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O constituent/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Glenn/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O already/RB/O made/VBN/O a/DT/O complete/JJ/O disclosure/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O role/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O affair/NN/O and/CC/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O completely/RB/O satisfied/VBN/O to/TO/O let/VB/O this/DT/O matter/NN/O rest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Ethics/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ././O ''/''/O
Sen./NNP/O DeConcini/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O When/WRB/O all/DT/O is/VBZ/O said/VBD/O and/CC/O done/VBN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O expect/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O exonerated/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Sen./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O already/RB/O volunteered/VBN/O his/PRP$/O help/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Investigation/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O any/DT/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O portrayed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O role/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O as/IN/O prodding/VBG/O regulators/NNS/O to/TO/O act/VB/O ././O
``/``/O Why/WRB/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG act/VB/O sooner/RBR/O ?/./O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O is/VBZ/O what/WP/O Common/NNP/B-ORG Cause/NNP/I-ORG should/MD/O ask/VB/O be/VB/O investigated/VBN/O ././O
