They/PRP/O hope/VBP/O the/DT/O foreign/JJ/O deals/NNS/O will/MD/O divide/VB/O the/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE opposition/NN/O and/CC/O prod/VB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O push/VB/O for/IN/O ending/VBG/O federal/JJ/O rules/NNS/O that/WDT/O prohibit/VBP/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O from/IN/O grabbing/VBG/O a/DT/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O rerun/NN/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O owning/VBG/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shows/NNS/O they/PRP/O put/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O ././O
Few/JJ/O people/NNS/O privy/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O expect/VBP/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O to/TO/O budge/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O networks/NNS/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O uninhibited/JJ/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O authority/NN/O ''/''/O over/IN/O what/WDT/O shows/NNS/O get/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O ,/,/O charges/VBZ/O Motion/NNP/B-ORG Picture/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Valenti/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O vociferous/JJ/O opponent/NN/O of/IN/O rescinding/VBG/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O ././O
Studio/NN/O executives/NNS/O in/IN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O -/:/O including/JJ/O officials/NNS/O at/IN/O Paramount/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Fries/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O interviewed/VBN/O ././O
Such/JJ/O proclamations/NNS/O leave/VBP/O network/NN/O officials/NNS/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O doubtful/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O will/MD/O bend/VB/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O repeatedly/RB/O it/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O no/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mess/NN/O ,/,/O urging/VBG/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O license/VBP/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O air/NN/O shows/NNS/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O work/VB/O out/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O compromise/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O latest/JJS/O provocation/NN/O :/:/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG plan/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNPS/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 3.4/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O independent/JJ/O producer/NN/O Guber/NNP/B-ORG Peters/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Big/NNP/O Three/CD/O 's/POS/O drumbeat/NN/O for/IN/O deregulation/NN/O began/VBD/O intensifying/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG went/VBD/O ahead/RB/O with/IN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O spoke/VBD/O up/IN/O again/RB/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG bid/NN/O for/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O announced/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O now/RB/O runs/VBZ/O Policy/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O consulting/VBG/O to/TO/O media/NNS/O companies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O networks/NNS/O admit/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O chances/NNS/O of/IN/O getting/VBG/O the/DT/O relief/NN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O are/VBP/O slim/JJ/O --/:/O for/IN/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O ././O
Six/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O tantalizingly/RB/O close/JJ/O ././O
Various/JJ/O evidence/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O Brookings/NNP/B-ORG Institution/NNP/I-ORG study/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O 800/CD/O series/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O had/VBD/O aired/VBN/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O partly/RB/O owned/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1960s/CD/O ,/,/O showed/VBD/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O wield/VB/O undue/JJ/O control/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O as/IN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O alleged/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG effort/NN/O collapsed/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O networks/NNS/O and/CC/O studios/NNS/O have/VBP/O bickered/VBN/O ever/RB/O since/IN/O ././O
Network/NN/O officials/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O talks/NNS/O may/MD/O hope/VB/O the/DT/O foreign/JJ/O influx/NN/O builds/VBZ/O more/JJR/O support/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O that/DT/O seems/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O ././O
