Drug/NNP/B-ORG Emporium/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Wilber/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 39/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O drugstore/NN/O chain/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O succeeds/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O father/NN/O ,/,/O Philip/NNP/B-PERSON T./NNP/I-PERSON Wilber/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O founded/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O remains/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O ././O
Robert/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Lyons/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 39/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O headed/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE region/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O appointed/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Wilber/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
