The/DT/O early/JJ/O episodes/NNS/O make/VBP/O you/PRP/O long/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O rerun/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O of/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O slickly/RB/O produced/VBD/O series/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O criticized/VBN/O by/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O financial/JJ/O cognoscenti/NNS/O as/IN/O inaccurate/JJ/O in/IN/O detail/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O major/JJ/O weakness/NN/O is/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O unrealistic/JJ/O depiction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O characters/NNS/O '/POS/O professional/JJ/O and/CC/O private/JJ/O lives/NNS/O ././O
Trouble/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O lost/VBN/O it/PRP/O just/RB/O as/RB/O quickly/RB/O ././O
Little/JJ/O chance/NN/O that/IN/O Shane/NNP/B-ORG Longman/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O recoup/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
Traders/NNS/O spend/VBP/O the/DT/O morning/NN/O frantically/RB/O selling/VBG/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O belief/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE monthly/JJ/O trade/NN/O figures/NNS/O will/MD/O look/VB/O lousy/JJ/O ././O
Surprisingly/RB/O ,/,/O Shane/NNP/B-ORG Longman/NNP/I-ORG survives/VBZ/O the/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O senior/JJ/O executive/NN/O innocently/RB/O bumble/VB/O his/PRP$/O way/NN/O into/IN/O becoming/VBG/O the/DT/O target/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O criminal/JJ/O insider/NN/O trading/NN/O investigation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O plot/NN/O is/VBZ/O thwarted/VBN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O major/JJ/O stockholder/NN/O ,/,/O kelp/NN/O farming/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O globe/NN/O ,/,/O hurries/VBZ/O home/RB/O to/TO/O support/VB/O the/DT/O executive/NN/O ././O
Two/CD/O share/NN/O a/DT/O house/NN/O almost/RB/O devoid/JJ/O of/IN/O furniture/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O attitude/NN/O is/VBZ/O clearly/RB/O illustrated/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O trading/NN/O room/NN/O 's/POS/O most/RBS/O flamboyant/JJ/O character/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O takes/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O wash/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O laundromat/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O meets/VBZ/O a/DT/O punky/JJ/O French/JJ/O girl/NN/O who/WP/O dupes/VBZ/O him/PRP/O into/IN/O providing/VBG/O a/DT/O home/NN/O for/IN/O her/PRP$/O pet/NN/O piranha/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O promptly/RB/O steals/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O car/NN/O and/CC/O dumps/VBZ/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O Dieppe/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Thames/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE marketing/NN/O agent/NN/O ,/,/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Taffner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O preparing/VBG/O to/TO/O do/VB/O just/RB/O that/DT/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O discreetly/RB/O hopeful/JJ/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O three/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE comedy/NN/O series/NN/O --/:/O ``/``/O Three/NNP/O 's/POS/O Company/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O ``/``/O Too/NNP/O Close/NNP/O for/IN/O Comfort/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Check/NNP/O It/NNP/O Out/NNP/O ''/''/O --/:/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O British/JJ/O antecedents/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O seeds/NNS/O already/RB/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O script/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O pressure/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O much/RB/O for/IN/O Zsa/NNP/B-PERSON Zsa/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O slaps/VBZ/O a/DT/O security/NN/O guard/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O backflips/VBZ/O into/IN/O a/DT/O desktop/NN/O computer/NN/O terminal/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O explodes/VBZ/O ,/,/O covering/VBG/O Huntz/NNP/B-PERSON Hall/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON face/NN/O with/IN/O microchips/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O should/MD/O run/VB/O forever/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rustin/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O senior/JJ/O correspondent/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Journal/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O London/NNP/B-GPE bureau/NN/O ././O
