Sports/NNPS/B-ORG Unlimited/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Tampa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Fla./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O posted/VBD/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 59/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBD/O July/NNP/O 31/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O very/RB/O profitable/JJ/O ''/''/O on/IN/O an/DT/O operating/VBG/O basis/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Richardson/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O specify/VB/O numbers/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O transaction/NN/O ,/,/O management/NN/O bought/VBD/O out/RP/O the/DT/O passive/JJ/O investors/NNS/O '/POS/O holding/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Richardson/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
