Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Sisulu/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG African/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG came/VBD/O home/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O six/CD/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG colleagues/NNS/O ,/,/O five/CD/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O were/VBD/O arrested/VBN/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O in/IN/O 1963/CD/O and/CC/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O life/NN/O imprisonment/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O reunited/VBN/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O families/NNS/O at/IN/O various/JJ/O places/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O as/IN/O the/DT/O graying/VBG/O men/NNS/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O homes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O outlawed/VBN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE since/IN/O 1960/CD/O and/CC/O still/RB/O considered/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O chief/NN/O public/JJ/O enemy/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O white/JJ/O government/NN/O ,/,/O defiantly/RB/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O black/JJ/O townships/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O huge/JJ/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG flag/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O black/JJ/O ,/,/O green/JJ/O and/CC/O gold/JJ/O stripes/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O hoisted/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O rickety/JJ/O gate/NN/O at/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O modest/JJ/O house/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O street/NN/O out/IN/O front/NN/O ,/,/O boys/NNS/O displayed/VBD/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG colors/NNS/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O shirts/NNS/O ,/,/O caps/NNS/O and/CC/O scarves/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O happy/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O the/DT/O spirit/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O looking/VBG/O dapper/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O gray/JJ/O suit/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O crowd/NN/O outside/IN/O his/PRP$/O home/NN/O shouted/VBD/O ``/``/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O man/NN/O shot/VBD/O his/PRP$/O fists/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O inspired/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O mood/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O laws/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O land/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG remains/VBZ/O an/DT/O illegal/JJ/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O in/IN/O Lusaka/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Zambia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O unconditional/JJ/O release/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O seven/CD/O leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O once/RB/O formed/VBD/O the/DT/O intellectual/JJ/O and/CC/O organizational/JJ/O core/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O de/FW/O facto/FW/O unbanning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O movement/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O rebirth/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O internal/JJ/O wing/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O government/NN/O can/MD/O never/RB/O put/VB/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG back/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O bottle/NN/O again/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Cassim/NNP/B-PERSON Saloojee/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O veteran/JJ/O anti-apartheid/NN/O activist/NN/O on/IN/O hand/NN/O to/TO/O welcome/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O Things/NNS/O have/VBP/O gone/VBN/O too/RB/O far/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O them/PRP/O now/RB/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O turning/VBG/O back/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
There/EX/O was/VBD/O certainly/RB/O no/RB/O stopping/VBG/O the/DT/O tide/NN/O of/IN/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG emotion/NN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O jammed/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Holy/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG Anglican/NNP/I-ORG Church/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Soweto/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O what/WP/O became/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG rally/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O in/IN/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Deafening/VBG/O chants/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Umkhonto/NNP/B-ORG we/PRP/I-ORG Sizwe/NNP/I-ORG ''/''/O shook/VBD/O the/DT/O church/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O seven/CD/O aging/VBG/O men/NNS/O vowed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O continue/VB/O its/PRP$/O fight/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O policies/NNS/O of/IN/O racial/JJ/O segregation/NN/O on/IN/O all/DT/O fronts/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O armed/VBN/O struggle/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O they/PRP/O called/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O release/VB/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Mandela/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O leading/VBG/O figure/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O jailed/VBN/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O and/CC/O remains/VBZ/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O ././O
President/NNP/O F.W./NNP/B-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON Klerk/NNP/I-PERSON released/VBD/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG men/NNS/O --/:/O along/IN/O with/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O founding/VBG/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Pan/NNP/I-ORG Africanist/NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O rival/JJ/O liberation/NN/O group/NN/O --/:/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O create/VB/O a/DT/O climate/NN/O of/IN/O trust/NN/O and/CC/O peace/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O his/PRP$/O government/NN/O can/MD/O begin/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O black/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O over/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O constitution/NN/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O giving/VBG/O blacks/NNS/O a/DT/O voice/NN/O in/IN/O national/JJ/O government/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Pretoria/NNP/B-GPE may/MD/O instead/RB/O be/VB/O creating/VBG/O a/DT/O climate/NN/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O turmoil/NN/O and/CC/O uncertainty/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O racially/RB/O divided/VBN/O country/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O other/JJ/O repressive/JJ/O governments/NNS/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O have/VBP/O recently/RB/O discovered/VBN/O ,/,/O initial/JJ/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O open/VB/O up/RP/O society/NN/O can/MD/O create/VB/O a/DT/O momentum/NN/O for/IN/O radical/JJ/O change/NN/O that/WDT/O becomes/VBZ/O difficult/JJ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O not/RB/O impossible/JJ/O ,/,/O to/TO/O control/VB/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O days/NNS/O go/VBP/O by/IN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O government/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O ever/RB/O more/RBR/O hard/RB/O pressed/VBN/O to/TO/O justify/VB/O the/DT/O continued/VBN/O imprisonment/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mandela/NNP/B-PERSON as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O continued/VBN/O banning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O enforcement/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O emergency/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yield/VB/O on/IN/O these/DT/O matters/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O eventually/RB/O begin/VB/O talking/VBG/O directly/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O expectations/NNS/O and/CC/O promise/NN/O raised/VBN/O by/IN/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O releases/NNS/O will/MD/O turn/VB/O to/TO/O disillusionment/NN/O and/CC/O unrest/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O newly/RB/O released/VBN/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O also/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O under/IN/O enormous/JJ/O pressure/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O watching/VBG/O closely/RB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O if/IN/O their/PRP$/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O townships/NNS/O leads/VBZ/O to/TO/O increased/VBN/O anti-government/NN/O protests/NNS/O and/CC/O violence/NN/O ;/:/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O ,/,/O Pretoria/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O use/VB/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O reason/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Mandela/NNP/B-PERSON behind/IN/O bars/NNS/O ././O
Pretoria/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O forgotten/VBN/O why/WRB/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O all/DT/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O life/NN/O imprisonment/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O place/NN/O :/:/O for/IN/O sabotage/NN/O and/CC/O conspiracy/NN/O to/TO/O overthrow/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O figuring/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O releases/NNS/O could/MD/O create/VB/O a/DT/O split/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O internal/JJ/O and/CC/O external/JJ/O wings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O between/IN/O the/DT/O newly/RB/O freed/VBN/O leaders/NNS/O and/CC/O those/DT/O activists/NNS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O emerged/VBN/O as/IN/O leaders/NNS/O inside/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O during/IN/O their/PRP$/O imprisonment/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O head/VB/O off/RP/O any/DT/O divisions/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mandela/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O before/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O released/VBN/O ,/,/O instructed/VBD/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O report/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG headquarters/NN/O in/IN/O Lusaka/NNP/B-GPE as/RB/O soon/RB/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Mokaba/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG South/NNP/I-ORG African/NNP/I-ORG Youth/NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O expecting/VBG/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O act/VB/O like/IN/O leaders/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
They/PRP/O never/RB/O considered/VBD/O themselves/PRP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O anything/NN/O else/RB/O ././O
At/IN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O 's/POS/O rally/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O called/VBD/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O followers/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O firm/JJ/O ,/,/O yet/RB/O disciplined/VBN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O apartheid/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O emphasize/VBP/O discipline/NN/O because/IN/O we/PRP/O know/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O ,/,/O very/RB/O sensitive/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Andrew/NNP/B-PERSON Mlangeni/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O another/DT/O early/JJ/O Umkhonto/NNP/B-ORG leader/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O 63/CD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O see/VB/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Mandela/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O all/PDT/O our/PRP$/O comrades/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O prison/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O if/IN/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O disciplined/VBN/O we/PRP/O may/MD/O not/RB/O see/VB/O them/PRP/O here/RB/O with/IN/O us/PRP/O ././O
