It/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O so/RB/O long/JJ/O ago/IN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O radio/NN/O network/NN/O funded/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Congress/NNP/B-ORG --/:/O and/CC/O originally/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O was/VBD/O accused/VBN/O by/IN/O officials/NNS/O here/RB/O of/IN/O employing/VBG/O propagandists/NNS/O ,/,/O imperialists/NNS/O and/CC/O spies/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O network/NN/O has/VBZ/O opened/VBN/O a/DT/O news/NN/O bureau/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Hungarian/JJ/O capital/NN/O ././O
Employees/NNS/O held/VBD/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O house/NN/O to/TO/O celebrate/VB/O and/CC/O even/RB/O hung/VBD/O out/RP/O a/DT/O sign/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O Szabad/NNP/B-ORG Europa/NNP/I-ORG Radio/NNP/I-ORG ''/''/O --/:/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O network/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O anywhere/RB/O else/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC Bloc/NNP/I-LOC that/WDT/O will/MD/O have/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O rapid/JJ/O changes/NNS/O brought/VBD/O on/RP/O by/IN/O glasnost/NN/O and/CC/O open/JJ/O borders/NNS/O are/VBP/O altering/VBG/O the/DT/O network/NN/O 's/POS/O life/NN/O in/IN/O more/JJR/O ways/NNS/O than/IN/O one/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O danger/NN/O of/IN/O suffering/VBG/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O success/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O network/NN/O currently/RB/O can/MD/O operate/VB/O freely/RB/O in/IN/O Budapest/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O so/RB/O can/MD/O others/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O competition/NN/O for/IN/O listeners/NNS/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O tougher/JJR/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O ways/NNS/O than/IN/O when/WRB/O broadcasting/NN/O here/RB/O was/VBD/O strictly/RB/O controlled/VBN/O ././O
Instead/RB/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O denounced/VBN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O evil/JJ/O agent/NN/O of/IN/O imperialism/NN/O ,/,/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O draw/VB/O the/DT/O criticism/NN/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O programs/NNS/O are/VBP/O too/RB/O tame/JJ/O ,/,/O even/RB/O boring/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O Hungarian/NNP/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O radio/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O reporters/NNS/O seem/VBP/O better/RB/O informed/VBN/O and/CC/O more/RBR/O critical/JJ/O about/IN/O about/IN/O what/WP/O 's/VBZ/O going/VBG/O on/RP/O here/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O media/NNS/O explosion/NN/O ././O
Boys/NNS/O on/IN/O busy/JJ/O street/NN/O corners/NNS/O peddle/VBP/O newspapers/NNS/O of/IN/O every/DT/O political/JJ/O stripe/NN/O ././O
Newsstands/NNS/O are/VBP/O packed/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O colorful/JJ/O array/NN/O of/IN/O magazines/NNS/O ././O
Radio/NN/O and/CC/O television/NN/O are/VBP/O getting/VBG/O livelier/JJR/O and/CC/O bolder/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG British/NNP/I-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG broadcast/NN/O over/IN/O Hungarian/JJ/O airwaves/NNS/O ,/,/O though/IN/O only/RB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O hours/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O each/DT/O in/IN/O Hungarian/NNP/O ././O
Australian/JJ/O press/NN/O magnate/NN/O Rupert/NNP/B-PERSON Murdoch/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O bought/VBN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O stakes/NNS/O in/IN/O two/CD/O popular/JJ/O and/CC/O gossipy/JJ/O Hungarian/JJ/O newspapers/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Maxwell/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O let/VBN/O it/PRP/O be/VB/O known/VBN/O here/RB/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O thinking/VBG/O about/IN/O similar/JJ/O moves/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O plan/VB/O to/TO/O fade/VB/O away/RB/O ././O
With/IN/O its/PRP$/O mission/NN/O for/IN/O free/JJ/O speech/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O capitalist/NN/O way/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O network/NN/O 's/POS/O staff/NN/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O plenty/RB/O to/TO/O do/VB/O --/:/O in/IN/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC ``/``/I-LOC Great/NNP/I-LOC Eastern/NNP/I-LOC Beyond/NNP/I-LOC ././O ''/''/O
Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O sister/NN/O station/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Liberty/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O cut/VB/O back/RP/O their/PRP$/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 19/CD/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O daily/JJ/O broadcasts/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O source/NN/O of/IN/O news/NN/O for/IN/O 60/CD/O million/CD/O listeners/NNS/O in/IN/O 23/CD/O exotic/JJ/O tongues/NNS/O :/:/O from/IN/O Bulgarian/NNP/O and/CC/O Belorussian/NNP/O to/TO/O Kazakh/NNP/O and/CC/O Kirghiz/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O establishment/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O bureau/NN/O in/IN/O Warsaw/NNP/O Pact/NNP/O territory/NN/O shows/VBZ/O the/DT/O depth/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Months/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Hungarian/NNP/O Communist/NNP/B-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O rename/VB/O itself/PRP/O Socialist/JJ/B-ORG and/CC/O try/VB/O to/TO/O look/VB/O more/RBR/O appealing/JJ/O to/TO/O voters/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O rulers/NNS/O were/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O look/VB/O more/RBR/O hospitable/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O proved/VBD/O a/DT/O perfect/JJ/O time/NN/O for/IN/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O ask/VB/O for/IN/O permission/NN/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O office/NN/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O did/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Hungarian/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNPS/I-ORG approve/VB/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG new/JJ/O location/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Telecommunications/NNPS/I-ORG did/VBD/O something/NN/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O amazing/JJ/O :/:/O ``/``/O They/PRP/O found/VBD/O us/PRP/O four/CD/O phone/NN/O lines/NNS/O in/IN/O central/JJ/O Budapest/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Geza/NNP/B-PERSON Szocs/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG correspondent/NN/O who/WP/O helped/VBD/O organize/VB/O the/DT/O Budapest/NNP/B-GPE location/NN/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O miracle/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O far/JJ/O cry/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O network/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O overcome/VB/O jamming/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O frequencies/NNS/O and/CC/O intimidation/NN/O of/IN/O local/JJ/O correspondents/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O who/WP/O filed/VBD/O reports/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O network/NN/O by/IN/O phone/NN/O ,/,/O secret/JJ/O messengers/NNS/O or/CC/O letters/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O network/NN/O 's/POS/O Hungarian/JJ/O listeners/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O owe/VBP/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG loyalty/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O responsible/JJ/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O ways/NNS/O for/IN/O keeping/VBG/O hope/NN/O alive/JJ/O through/IN/O what/WP/O one/CD/O writer/NN/O here/RB/O calls/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O Dark/NNP/O Ages/NNPS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 20th/JJ/O Century/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O During/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O have/VBP/O sat/VBN/O up/IN/O until/IN/O late/JJ/O at/IN/O night/NN/O listening/VBG/O to/TO/O our/PRP$/O radios/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O writer/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O were/VBD/O some/DT/O very/RB/O brave/JJ/O broadcasts/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O listeners/NNS/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O brave/JJ/O ././O
Through/IN/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O post-World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O period/NN/O ,/,/O listening/VBG/O to/TO/O Western/JJ/O broadcasts/NNS/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O crime/NN/O in/IN/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O we/PRP/O listen/VBP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC station/NN/O ,/,/O my/PRP$/O mother/NN/O still/RB/O gets/VBZ/O nervous/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O Budapest/NNP/B-GPE translator/NN/O ././O
``/``/O She/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O down/RP/O the/DT/O volume/NN/O and/CC/O close/VB/O the/DT/O curtains/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Hungarian/JJ/O radio/NN/O often/RB/O saves/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O most/RBS/O politically/RB/O outspoken/JJ/O broadcasts/NNS/O for/IN/O around/IN/O midnight/NN/O ././O
Television/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O rather/RB/O tame/JJ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O entered/VBN/O the/DT/O running/VBG/O with/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O program/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O The/NNP/O End/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Day/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O comes/VBZ/O on/RP/O after/IN/O 11/CD/O p.m/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O talk/NN/O show/NN/O with/IN/O opposition/NN/O leaders/NNS/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O experts/NNS/O who/WP/O discuss/VBP/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O domestic/JJ/O problems/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O foreign/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
Those/DT/O who/WP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O hear/VB/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O radical/JJ/O views/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O get/VB/O up/RB/O at/IN/O five/CD/O on/IN/O Sunday/NNP/O morning/NN/O for/IN/O ``/``/O Sunday/NNP/O Journal/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O on/IN/O Hungarian/NNP/B-ORG Radio/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O competitive/JJ/O spirit/NN/O is/VBZ/O clearly/RB/O influencing/VBG/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O beef/VB/O up/RP/O programs/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O host/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O lighten/VB/O up/RP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O traditional/JJ/O diet/NN/O of/IN/O politics/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O program/NN/O for/IN/O women/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O science/NN/O show/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O younger/JJR/O listeners/NNS/O ,/,/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG intersperses/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O in/IN/O Western/JJ/O rock/NN/O groups/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Pet/NNP/I-ORG Shop/NNP/I-ORG Boys/NNPS/I-ORG are/VBP/O big/JJ/O this/DT/O year/NN/O in/IN/O Budapest/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O starving/VBG/O for/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O news/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Deak/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O student/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Every/DT/O moment/NN/O we/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O know/VB/O everything/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
