The/DT/O first/JJ/O major/JJ/O event/NN/O this/DT/O morning/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE stock/NN/O and/CC/O futures/NNS/O trading/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O pause/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Mercantile/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O aim/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O interruption/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O the/DT/O opening/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O hammered/VBN/O by/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O volatile/JJ/O move/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O added/VBD/O computer/NN/O capacity/NN/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O huge/JJ/O surges/NNS/O in/IN/O trading/NN/O volume/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O ``/``/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O ''/''/O have/VBP/O yet/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O evaluated/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O deeper/JJR/O market/NN/O plunge/NN/O today/NN/O could/MD/O give/VB/O them/PRP/O their/PRP$/O first/JJ/O test/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O further/JJ/O slide/NN/O also/RB/O would/MD/O resurrect/VB/O debate/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O host/NN/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O sweeping/VBG/O changes/NNS/O proposed/VBN/O --/:/O but/CC/O not/RB/O implemented/VBN/O --/:/O after/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O crash/NN/O ././O
Most/RBS/O notably/RB/O ,/,/O several/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O regulatory/JJ/O steps/NNS/O recommended/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Brady/NNP/I-ORG Task/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O analyzed/VBD/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O be/VB/O revived/VBN/O --/:/O especially/RB/O because/IN/O that/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O the/DT/O Treasury/NN/B-ORG secretary/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O controversial/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON recommendations/NNS/O involved/VBD/O establishing/VBG/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O overarching/VBG/O regulator/NN/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O crucial/JJ/O cross-market/JJ/O questions/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O setting/VBG/O consistent/JJ/O margin/NN/O requirements/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O futures/NNS/O markets/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O for/IN/O the/DT/O moment/NN/O ,/,/O attention/NN/O focuses/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O reforms/NNS/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O put/VBN/O into/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O market/NN/O regulators/NNS/O and/CC/O participants/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O worked/VBD/O as/RB/O intended/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O the/DT/O fire/NN/O but/CC/O you/PRP/O know/VBP/O what/WP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Howard/NNP/B-PERSON Dubnow/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O floor/NN/O broker/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG governor/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O was/VBD/O no/DT/O panic/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O system/NN/O worked/VBD/O the/DT/O way/NN/O we/PRP/O devised/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O work/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O programs/NNS/O are/VBP/O considered/VBN/O by/IN/O many/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O cause/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O post-crash/JJ/O reforms/NNS/O began/VBD/O with/IN/O calls/NNS/O to/TO/O remake/VB/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O and/CC/O wound/VBD/O up/RP/O a/DT/O year/NN/O later/RB/O with/IN/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O rather/RB/O technical/JJ/O adjustments/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O October/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O just/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O drop/NN/O ,/,/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O awash/JJ/O in/IN/O talk/NN/O of/IN/O sweeping/VBG/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O are/VBP/O structured/VBN/O and/CC/O regulated/VBN/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O that/IN/O grand/JJ/O agenda/NN/O was/VBD/O whittled/VBN/O down/RB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O soften/VB/O big/JJ/O stock/NN/O drops/NNS/O by/IN/O interrupting/VBG/O trading/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O market/NN/O players/NNS/O time/NN/O to/TO/O pause/VB/O and/CC/O reconsider/VB/O positions/NNS/O ././O
Few/JJ/O changes/NNS/O were/VBD/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O are/VBP/O regulated/VBN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O outset/NN/O the/DT/O prime/JJ/O target/NN/O was/VBD/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O much/RB/O discussed/VBN/O but/CC/O little/RB/O understood/VBN/O on/IN/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG Hill/NNP/I-ORG ././O
And/CC/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O much/JJ/O criticism/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG system/NN/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O stock/NN/O trades/NNS/O flow/VB/O through/IN/O specialists/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O market/NN/O makers/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG Brady/NNP/I-ORG Task/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG powerful/JJ/O analysis/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O crash/NN/O was/VBD/O released/VBN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O immediately/RB/O reshaped/VBD/O the/DT/O reformers/NNS/O '/POS/O agenda/NN/O ././O
Only/RB/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O of/IN/O those/DT/O recommendations/NNS/O ever/RB/O was/VBD/O implemented/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG held/VBD/O the/DT/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON recommendations/NNS/O at/IN/O arm/NN/O 's/POS/O length/NN/O and/CC/O named/VBD/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O panel/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/B-ORG Working/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNPS/I-ORG --/:/O to/TO/O review/VB/O its/PRP$/O analysis/NN/O and/CC/O those/DT/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O crash/NN/O studies/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O May/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Working/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O made/VBD/O up/RP/O of/IN/O representatives/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Commodity/NNP/I-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG Trading/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O finally/RB/O endorsed/VBD/O only/JJ/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O several/JJ/O more/JJR/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O arguments/NNS/O among/IN/O various/JJ/O stock/NN/O exchanges/NNS/O and/CC/O futures/NNS/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O were/VBD/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O notable/JJ/O suspending/VBG/O trading/NN/O after/IN/O 250/CD/O and/CC/O 400/CD/O point/NN/O drops/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Industrial/NNP/O Average/NNP/O ././O
Privately/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O free/JJ/O marketeers/NNS/O dismissed/VBD/O such/JJ/O mechanisms/NNS/O as/IN/O sops/NNS/O to/TO/O interventionists/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O ''/''/O set/VBN/O to/TO/O soften/VB/O big/JJ/O drops/NNS/O :/:/O
--/:/O If/IN/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Industrials/NNPS/I-ORG fall/VBP/O 25/CD/O points/NNS/O at/IN/O opening/NN/O ,/,/O contract/NN/O trading/NN/O pauses/VBZ/O for/IN/O 10/CD/O minutes/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG program/NN/O trades/NNS/O are/VBP/O diverted/VBN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O computer/NN/O file/NN/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O buy/VB/O and/CC/O sell/VB/O orders/NNS/O ././O
--/:/O If/IN/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Industrials/NNPS/I-ORG fall/VBP/O 250/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O trading/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG halts/VBZ/O for/IN/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O ././O
--/:/O If/IN/O DJIA/NNP/O drops/VBZ/O 400/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG halts/VBZ/O trading/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O hours/NNS/O ././O
Brady/NNP/B-ORG Task/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG recommendations/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Jan./NNP/O 1988/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O :/:/O
--/:/O Establish/VB/O an/DT/O overarching/VBG/O regulator/NN/O for/IN/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O
--/:/O Make/VB/O margins/NNS/O consistent/JJ/O across/IN/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O futures/NNS/O markets/NNS/O
SEC/NNP/B-ORG proposals/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O May/NNP/O 1988/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O :/:/O
--/:/O Require/VB/O prompt/JJ/O reports/NNS/O of/IN/O large/JJ/O securities/NNS/O trades/NNS/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Opposed/VBN/O by/IN/O new/JJ/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
--/:/O Give/VB/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG authority/NN/O to/TO/O halt/VB/O securities/NNS/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O also/RB/O opposed/VBN/O by/IN/O new/JJ/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Congressional/JJ/O proposal/NN/O :/:/O
--/:/O Create/VB/O a/DT/O task/NN/O force/NN/O to/TO/O review/VB/O current/JJ/O state/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O securities/NNS/O markets/NNS/O and/CC/O securities/NNS/O laws/NNS/O ././O
Breaking/VBG/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O television/NN/O monopoly/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O gained/VBN/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O show/VB/O world/NN/O programming/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O American/JJ/O films/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O must/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O a/DT/O monopoly/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O must/MD/O be/VB/O freedom/NN/O of/IN/O choice/NN/O for/IN/O both/DT/O journalists/NNS/O and/CC/O viewers/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Nikolai/NNP/B-PERSON I./NNP/I-PERSON Lutsenko/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Nika/NNP/B-ORG TV/NN/I-ORG company/NN/O ,/,/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O weekly/JJ/O newspaper/NN/O Nedelya/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O programming/NN/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O provincial/JJ/O cities/NNS/O and/CC/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O regularly/RB/O in/IN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O newspaper/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lutsenko/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O Nedelya/NNP/B-ORG that/IN/O he/PRP/O recently/RB/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O pick/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O show/VB/O 5,000/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE films/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Nedelya/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O article/NN/O was/VBD/O accompanied/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O picture/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lutsenko/NNP/B-PERSON interviewing/VBG/O singer/NN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Denver/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Even/RB/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O independent/JJ/O of/IN/O official/JJ/O television/NN/O ,/,/O Nika/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O have/VB/O an/DT/O oversight/NN/O board/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O include/VB/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Communist/NNP/O youth/NN/O league/NN/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE National/NNP/B-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Mineworkers/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O about/IN/O 10,000/CD/O diamond/NN/O miners/NNS/O struck/VBN/O for/IN/O higher/JJR/O wages/NNS/O at/IN/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG Consolidated/NNP/I-ORG Mines/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG
De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O workers/NNS/O at/IN/O five/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O mines/NNS/O were/VBD/O on/IN/O strike/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O said/VBD/O was/VBD/O peaceful/JJ/O ,/,/O with/IN/O orderly/JJ/O picketing/NN/O occurring/VBG/O at/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mines/NNS/O ././O
Tsuruo/NNP/B-PERSON Yamaguchi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O secretary/NN/O general/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Socialist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O acknowledged/VBD/O that/IN/O nine/CD/O party/NN/O lawmakers/NNS/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O donations/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O pachinko/NN/O association/NN/O totaling/VBG/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O yen/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O about/IN/O $/$/O 55,000/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O donations/NNS/O were/VBD/O legal/JJ/O and/CC/O none/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O members/NNS/O acted/VBD/O to/TO/O favor/VB/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Wide/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Nature/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Argentina/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE were/VBD/O doing/VBG/O too/RB/O little/JJ/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O illegal/JJ/O trade/NN/O in/IN/O endangered/VBN/O wildlife/NN/O across/IN/O their/PRP$/O borders/NNS/O ././O
Fund/NNP/O official/NN/O Simon/NNP/B-PERSON Lyster/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O world/NN/O trade/NN/O in/IN/O wildlife/NN/O was/VBD/O estimated/VBN/O to/TO/O total/VB/O $/$/O 5/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O business/NN/O annually/RB/O ././O
Small/JJ/O wonder/NN/O that/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Labor/NNP/B-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG wants/VBZ/O credit/NN/O controls/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O hours/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O party/NN/O launched/VBD/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O affinity/NN/O credit/NN/O card/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Tories/NNS/B-ORG raised/VBD/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O base/NN/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O ././O
Labor/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Visa/NNP/B-ORG card/NN/O is/VBZ/O believed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O first/RB/O linked/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O British/JJ/O political/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
Labor/NNP/B-ORG gets/VBZ/O 25/CD/O pence/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O 39/CD/O cents/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O for/IN/O every/DT/O 100/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O about/IN/O $/$/O 155/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O that/IN/O a/DT/O user/NN/O charges/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O card/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O official/JJ/O China/NNP/B-ORG Daily/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O retail/JJ/O prices/NNS/O of/IN/O non-staple/JJ/O foods/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O risen/VBN/O since/IN/O last/JJ/O December/NNP/O but/CC/O acknowledged/VBD/O that/DT/O huge/JJ/O government/NN/O subsidies/NNS/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O main/JJ/O factor/NN/O in/IN/O keeping/VBG/O prices/NNS/O down/IN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Statistical/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG found/VBD/O that/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O yuan/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 270/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O was/VBD/O spent/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O half/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O for/IN/O pork/NN/O subsidies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O newspaper/NN/O quoted/VBD/O experts/NNS/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O subsidies/NNS/O would/MD/O cause/VB/O the/DT/O difference/NN/O between/IN/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O real/JJ/O values/NNS/O of/IN/O commodities/NNS/O to/TO/O ``/``/O become/VB/O very/RB/O unreasonable/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O reduce/VB/O needed/VBN/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O already/RB/O difficult/JJ/O state/NN/O budget/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O aim/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O austerity/NN/O measures/NNS/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O slice/VB/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O soared/VBD/O to/TO/O 20.7/CD/O %/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Economists/NNS/O now/RB/O predict/VBP/O the/DT/O growth/NN/O rate/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O about/IN/O 11.5/CD/O %/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O statue/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O brainchild/NN/O of/IN/O Sik/NNP/B-PERSON Chi/NNP/I-PERSON Wan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Po/NNP/I-ORG Lin/NNP/I-ORG Monastery/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O prosperous/JJ/O place/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O also/RB/O need/VBP/O some/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O religious/JJ/O symbol/NN/O ././O
