Giant/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Beverly/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNPS/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O collection/NN/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE producer/NN/O Burt/NNP/B-PERSON Sugarman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O give/VB/O a/DT/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O halting/VBG/O its/PRP$/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Aspen/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
Giant/NNP/B-ORG agreed/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O ././O
