The/DT/O toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O were/VBD/O pushed/VBN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O border/NN/O by/IN/O rising/VBG/O labor/NN/O and/CC/O land/NN/O costs/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O colony/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O foreign/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O ,/,/O cite/VBP/O uncertainty/NN/O about/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O steps/NNS/O were/VBD/O partly/RB/O prompted/VBN/O by/IN/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O deterioration/NN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O conditions/NNS/O in/IN/O southern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O easy/JJ/O to/TO/O duplicate/VB/O quickly/RB/O the/DT/O manufacturing/VBG/O capacity/NN/O built/VBN/O up/IN/O in/IN/O southern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE during/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O decade/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O supply/NN/O of/IN/O cheap/JJ/O labor/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O access/NN/O to/TO/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE port/NN/O ,/,/O airport/NN/O ,/,/O banks/NNS/O and/CC/O support/NN/O industries/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O printing/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O made/VBN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Guangdong/NNP/B-GPE province/NN/O a/DT/O premier/NN/O manufacturing/NN/O site/NN/O ././O
Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE trade/NN/O figures/NNS/O illustrate/VBP/O the/DT/O toy/JJ/O makers/NNS/O '/POS/O reliance/NN/O on/IN/O factories/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O border/NN/O ././O
Manufacturers/NNS/O say/VBP/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O immediate/JJ/O substitute/NN/O for/IN/O southern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O 120,000/CD/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O employed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O toy/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
Several/JJ/O big/JJ/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O established/VBN/O manufacturing/VBG/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O in/IN/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O including/VBG/O Matchbox/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Wah/NNP/B-ORG Shing/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Kader/NNP/B-ORG Industrial/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O toy/NN/O manufacturer/NN/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ting/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE Philippines/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O studied/VBN/O ././O
Worries/NNS/O about/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE came/VBD/O just/RB/O as/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE toy/NN/O industry/NN/O was/VBD/O recovering/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O 1987/CD/O sales/NNS/O slump/NN/O and/CC/O bankruptcy/NN/O filings/NNS/O by/IN/O two/CD/O major/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O ,/,/O Worlds/NNPS/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Wonder/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Coleco/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE manufacturers/NNS/O say/VBP/O large/JJ/O debt/NN/O writeoffs/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O financial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O resulting/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O difficulties/NNS/O chastened/VBD/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O tighten/VB/O credit/NN/O policies/NNS/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O management/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O industry/NN/O regards/VBZ/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O and/CC/O this/DT/O year/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O period/NN/O of/IN/O recovery/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O lead/VB/O to/TO/O improved/VBN/O results/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O closest/JJS/O thing/NN/O the/DT/O colony/NN/O 's/POS/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE mega-hit/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O Teenage/NNP/O Mutant/NNP/O Ninja/NNP/O Turtles/NNPS/O series/NN/O of/IN/O action/NN/O figures/NNS/O manufactured/VBN/O by/IN/O Playmates/NNPS/B-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Other/JJ/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE manufacturers/NNS/O expect/VBP/O their/PRP$/O results/NNS/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O only/RB/O slightly/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O from/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Nintendo/NNP/B-ORG buyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O little/JJ/O money/NN/O left/VBN/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O on/IN/O other/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O toy/JJ/O makers/NNS/O '/POS/O problems/NNS/O started/VBD/O well/RB/O before/IN/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O overstrained/VBN/O infrastructure/NN/O and/CC/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O austerity/NN/O programs/NNS/O launched/VBN/O late/JJ/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O complain/VBP/O that/DT/O electricity/NN/O in/IN/O Guangdong/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O provided/VBN/O only/RB/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O down/IN/O from/IN/O five/CD/O days/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O province/NN/O 's/POS/O rapid/JJ/O industrialization/NN/O has/VBZ/O outstripped/VBN/O its/PRP$/O generating/NN/O capacity/NN/O ././O
Manufacturers/NNS/O are/VBP/O upgrading/VBG/O standby/JJ/O power/NN/O plants/NNS/O ././O
Bank/NN/O credit/NN/O for/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE investments/NNS/O all/DT/O but/CC/O dried/VBD/O up/IN/O following/VBG/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O ././O
They/PRP/O say/VBP/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O is/VBZ/O widening/VBG/O and/CC/O the/DT/O country/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O short/JJ/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O hamper/VB/O production/NN/O in/IN/O Guangdong/NNP/B-GPE ././O
