When/WRB/O China/NNP/B-GPE opened/VBD/O its/PRP$/O doors/NNS/O to/TO/O foreign/JJ/O investors/NNS/O in/IN/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O toy/JJ/O makers/NNS/O from/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE were/VBD/O among/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O to/TO/O march/VB/O in/IN/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O about/IN/O 75/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O '/POS/O products/NNS/O being/VBG/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Toys/NNPS/B-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON Ting/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O has/VBZ/O suggested/VBN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O sourcing/VBG/O label/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O Made/VBN/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Companies/NNPS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O were/VBD/O pushed/VBN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O border/NN/O by/IN/O rising/VBG/O labor/NN/O and/CC/O land/NN/O costs/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O colony/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shootings/NNS/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE toy/NN/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O worrying/VBG/O about/IN/O its/PRP$/O strong/JJ/O dependence/NN/O on/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Although/IN/O the/DT/O manufacturers/NNS/O stress/VBP/O that/IN/O production/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O affected/VBN/O by/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O political/JJ/O turmoil/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O additional/JJ/O sites/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O foreign/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O ,/,/O cite/VBP/O uncertainty/NN/O about/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Nobody/NN/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O all/PDT/O his/PRP$/O eggs/NNS/O in/IN/O one/CD/O basket/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Yeh/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O International/NNP/B-ORG Matchbox/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O Matchbox/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O leading/VBG/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O were/VBD/O setting/VBG/O up/RP/O factories/NNS/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O especially/RB/O in/IN/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O long/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O massacre/NN/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O steps/NNS/O were/VBD/O partly/RB/O prompted/VBN/O by/IN/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O deterioration/NN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O conditions/NNS/O in/IN/O southern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O
By/IN/O diversifying/VBG/O supply/NN/O sources/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O toy/JJ/O makers/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O intend/VB/O to/TO/O withdraw/VB/O from/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O manufacturers/NNS/O and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O easy/JJ/O to/TO/O duplicate/VB/O quickly/RB/O the/DT/O manufacturing/VBG/O capacity/NN/O built/VBN/O up/RP/O in/IN/O southern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE during/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O decade/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O supply/NN/O of/IN/O cheap/JJ/O labor/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O access/NN/O to/TO/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE port/NN/O ,/,/O airport/NN/O ,/,/O banks/NNS/O and/CC/O support/NN/O industries/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O printing/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O made/VBN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Guangdong/NNP/B-GPE province/NN/O a/DT/O premier/NN/O manufacturing/NN/O site/NN/O ././O
``/``/O South/NNP/B-LOC China/NNP/I-LOC is/VBZ/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O competitive/JJ/O source/NN/O of/IN/O toys/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Hu/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Wah/NNP/B-ORG Shing/NNP/I-ORG Toys/NNPS/I-ORG Consolidated/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE trade/NN/O figures/NNS/O illustrate/VBP/O the/DT/O toy/JJ/O makers/NNS/O '/POS/O reliance/NN/O on/IN/O factories/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O border/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O exports/NNS/O of/IN/O domestically/RB/O produced/VBN/O toys/NNS/O and/CC/O games/NNS/O fell/VBD/O 19/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O HK$/$/O 10.05/CD/O billion/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 1.29/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
But/CC/O re-exports/NNS/O ,/,/O mainly/RB/O from/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O jumped/VBD/O 75/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O HK$/$/O 15.92/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O 1989/CD/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O seven/CD/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O domestic/JJ/O exports/NNS/O fell/VBD/O 29/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O HK$/$/O 3.87/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O while/IN/O re-exports/NNS/O rose/VBD/O 56/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O HK$/$/O 11.28/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Manufacturers/NNS/O say/VBP/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O immediate/JJ/O substitute/NN/O for/IN/O southern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O 120,000/CD/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O employed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O toy/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
``/``/O For/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O it/PRP/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ,/,/O China/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O supplier/NN/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Edmund/NNP/B-PERSON Young/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Perfecta/NNP/B-ORG Enterprises/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O big/JJ/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O to/TO/O move/VB/O across/IN/O the/DT/O border/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O meantime/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O manufacturers/NNS/O and/CC/O buyers/NNS/O seek/VBP/O new/JJ/O sites/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O focusing/VBG/O mainly/RB/O on/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Several/JJ/O big/JJ/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O established/VBN/O manufacturing/VBG/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O in/IN/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O including/VBG/O Matchbox/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Wah/NNP/B-ORG Shing/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Kader/NNP/B-ORG Industrial/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O toy/NN/O manufacturer/NN/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ting/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE Philippines/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O studied/VBN/O ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG set/VBD/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O its/PRP$/O internal/JJ/O trade/NN/O barriers/NNS/O in/IN/O 1992/CD/O ,/,/O several/JJ/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Portugal/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O possible/JJ/O manufacturing/VBG/O sites/NNS/O ././O
Worries/NNS/O about/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE came/VBD/O just/RB/O as/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE toy/NN/O industry/NN/O was/VBD/O recovering/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O 1987/CD/O sales/NNS/O slump/NN/O and/CC/O bankruptcy/NN/O filings/NNS/O by/IN/O two/CD/O major/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O ,/,/O Worlds/NNPS/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Wonder/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Coleco/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE manufacturers/NNS/O say/VBP/O large/JJ/O debt/NN/O writeoffs/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O financial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O resulting/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O difficulties/NNS/O chastened/VBD/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O tighten/VB/O credit/NN/O policies/NNS/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O management/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O industry/NN/O regards/VBZ/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O and/CC/O this/DT/O year/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O period/NN/O of/IN/O recovery/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O lead/VB/O to/TO/O improved/VBN/O results/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O long/VBP/O for/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O mega-hit/JJ/O ''/''/O toy/NN/O to/TO/O excite/VB/O retail/JJ/O sales/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE biggest/JJS/O market/NN/O for/IN/O toys/NNS/O and/CC/O games/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O closest/JJS/O thing/NN/O the/DT/O colony/NN/O 's/POS/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE mega-hit/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O Teenage/NNP/O Mutant/NNP/O Ninja/NNP/O Turtles/NNPS/O series/NN/O of/IN/O action/NN/O figures/NNS/O manufactured/VBN/O by/IN/O Playmates/NNPS/B-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Should/MD/O sales/NNS/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O strong/JJ/O through/IN/O the/DT/O Christmas/NNP/O season/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O accounts/VBZ/O for/IN/O about/IN/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE retail/JJ/O toy/NN/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Kwan/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O Ninja/NNP/O Turtles/NNPS/O could/MD/O make/VB/O 1989/CD/O a/DT/O record/NN/O sales/NNS/O year/NN/O for/IN/O Playmates/NNPS/B-ORG ././O
Other/JJ/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE manufacturers/NNS/O expect/VBP/O their/PRP$/O results/NNS/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O only/RB/O slightly/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O from/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Nintendo/NNP/B-ORG buyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O little/JJ/O money/NN/O left/VBN/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O on/IN/O other/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O toy/JJ/O makers/NNS/O '/POS/O problems/NNS/O started/VBD/O well/RB/O before/IN/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O overstrained/VBN/O infrastructure/NN/O and/CC/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O austerity/NN/O programs/NNS/O launched/VBN/O late/JJ/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Toy/NN/O makers/NNS/O complain/VBP/O that/DT/O electricity/NN/O in/IN/O Guangdong/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O provided/VBN/O only/RB/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O down/IN/O from/IN/O five/CD/O days/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O province/NN/O 's/POS/O rapid/JJ/O industrialization/NN/O has/VBZ/O outstripped/VBN/O its/PRP$/O generating/NN/O capacity/NN/O ././O
Manufacturers/NNS/O are/VBP/O upgrading/VBG/O standby/JJ/O power/NN/O plants/NNS/O ././O
Bank/NN/O credit/NN/O for/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE investments/NNS/O all/DT/O but/CC/O dried/VBD/O up/RP/O following/VBG/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O ././O
They/PRP/O say/VBP/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O is/VBZ/O widening/VBG/O and/CC/O the/DT/O country/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O short/JJ/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O hamper/VB/O production/NN/O in/IN/O Guangdong/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O whether/IN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O control/NN/O or/CC/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O want/NN/O exports/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Kwan/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Playmates/NNPS/B-ORG ././O
