The/DT/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O 540/CD/O new/JJ/O primary/JJ/O jet/NN/O trainers/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O value/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O between/IN/O 1994/CD/O and/CC/O 2004/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O Lockheed/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O in/IN/O Burbank/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O other/JJ/O companies/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O competing/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Air/NNP/B-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG contract/NN/O ././O
