American/NNP/B-ORG Physicians/NNPS/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O purchased/VBD/O about/IN/O 42/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Prime/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 5/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG provides/VBZ/O a/DT/O variety/NN/O of/IN/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O doctors/NNS/O and/CC/O hospitals/NNS/O ././O
Prime/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Bedminster/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O provides/VBZ/O management/NN/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O cardiac/JJ/O rehabilitation/NN/O clinics/NNS/O and/CC/O diagnostic/JJ/O imaging/NN/O centers/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBD/O June/NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O Prime/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O a/DT/O net/JJ/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 3/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 13.8/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
