Antonio/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Savoca/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 66/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Atlantic/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Savoca/NNP/B-PERSON succeeds/VBZ/O William/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Borten/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O personal/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ././O
Sequa/NNP/B-ORG makes/VBZ/O and/CC/O repairs/VBZ/O jet/NN/O engines/NNS/O ././O
