In/IN/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O appease/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE regulators/NNS/O '/POS/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O Goldsmith/NNP/B-PERSON acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG ,/,/O Sir/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O August/NNP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG to/TO/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG if/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O successful/JJ/O in/IN/O acquiring/VBG/O B.A.T/NNP/B-ORG ././O
As/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG Investments/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Sir/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O acquisition/NN/O vehicle/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O Claude/NNP/B-PERSON Bebear/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O group/NN/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O obtained/VBN/O assurances/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O banks/NNS/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O Cie/NNP/B-ORG ././I-ORG Financiere/NNP/I-ORG de/NNP/I-ORG Paribas/NNP/I-ORG that/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O provide/VB/O the/DT/O loan/NN/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O financing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O banking/VBG/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O are/VBP/O Credit/NNP/B-ORG Lyonnais/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG Generale/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O BankAmerica/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Citicorp/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O non-insurance/NN/O ''/''/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O beer/NN/O company/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O include/VB/O any/DT/O pieces/NNS/O of/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O put/VB/O any/DT/O burden/NN/O on/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O amended/VBN/O filings/NNS/O also/RB/O point/VBP/O out/RP/O that/DT/O under/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O an/DT/O absolute/JJ/O obligation/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG to/TO/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG upon/IN/O an/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O B.A.T/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O hope/VBP/O that/DT/O with/IN/O what/WP/O we/PRP/O did/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O regulators/NNS/O will/MD/O not/RB/O need/VB/O to/TO/O evaluate/VB/O Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O directly/RB/O look/VB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O because/IN/O Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O an/DT/O owner/NN/O of/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG at/IN/O anytime/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Bebear/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Any/DT/O change/NN/O of/IN/O control/NN/O in/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O approval/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O commissioners/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O nine/CD/O states/NNS/O where/WRB/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O related/VBN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O incorporated/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O amended/VBN/O filings/NNS/O were/VBD/O required/VBN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O agreement/NN/O between/IN/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O reflect/VB/O the/DT/O extension/NN/O that/IN/O Sir/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON received/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O under/IN/O British/JJ/O takeover/NN/O rules/NNS/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O his/PRP$/O proposed/VBN/O acquisition/NN/O ././O
Hoylake/NNP/B-ORG dropped/VBD/O its/PRP$/O initial/JJ/O #/#/O 13.35/CD/O billion/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 20.71/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O takeover/NN/O bid/NN/O after/IN/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O the/DT/O extension/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O launch/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O bid/NN/O if/IN/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O propsed/VBN/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG to/TO/O Axa/NNP/B-ORG receives/VBZ/O regulatory/JJ/O approval/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O B.A.T/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O amended/VBN/O filings/NNS/O that/IN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O would/MD/O appear/VB/O that/IN/O nothing/NN/O substantive/JJ/O has/VBZ/O changed/VBN/O ././O
That/DT/O dividend/NN/O is/VBZ/O almost/RB/O double/RB/O the/DT/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O currently/RB/O taken/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG by/IN/O B.A.T/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O added/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O severe/JJ/O implications/NNS/O for/IN/O Farmers/NNPS/B-ORG '/POS/O policy/NN/O holders/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
To/TO/O fend/VB/O off/RP/O Sir/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O advances/NNS/O ,/,/O B.A.T/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O proposed/VBN/O a/DT/O sweeping/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O pare/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O tobacco/NN/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O concern/NN/O ././O
