Lomas/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O assisted/VBN/O by/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O Equitable/NNP/B-ORG Lomas/NNP/I-ORG Leasing/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O several/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O apparently/RB/O without/IN/O success/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O and/CC/O mortgage/NN/O banking/NN/O concern/NN/O had/VBD/O hoped/VBN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O proceeds/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O debt/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O filed/VBD/O for/IN/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O under/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O Sept./NNP/O 24/CD/O to/TO/O give/VB/O it/PRP/O additional/JJ/O time/NN/O to/TO/O work/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O restructure/VB/O its/PRP$/O $/$/O 1.45/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O senior/JJ/O debt/NN/O ././O
Lomas/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O bonds/NNS/O and/CC/O equity/NN/O in/IN/O Lomas/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O continue/VB/O as/IN/O Lomas/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O investment/NN/O banker/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O creditor/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O chose/VBD/O Lazard/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O Lazard/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O investors/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE leasing/NN/O company/NN/O ././O
