Greece/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O second/JJ/O bout/NN/O of/IN/O general/JJ/O elections/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O is/VBZ/O slated/VBN/O for/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 5/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O mid-June/NNP/O round/NN/O of/IN/O voting/NN/O ,/,/O Greeks/NNPS/O gave/VBD/O no/DT/O clear/JJ/O mandate/NN/O to/TO/O any/DT/O single/JJ/O political/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O point/NN/O of/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O catharsis/NN/O was/VBD/O overdue/JJ/O by/IN/O decades/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O reduced/VBN/O to/TO/O buzzword/NN/O status/NN/O in/IN/O ex/JJ/O parte/NN/O pledges/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O transmogrified/VBD/O into/IN/O a/DT/O promised/VBN/O assault/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O targets/NNS/O primarily/RB/O for/IN/O political/JJ/O gains/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O justice/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Koskotas/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O credibility/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O at/IN/O best/JJS/O ,/,/O problematic/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O ample/JJ/O motive/NN/O to/TO/O shift/VB/O the/DT/O blame/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O testimony/NN/O has/VBZ/O also/RB/O been/VBN/O found/VBN/O less/RBR/O than/IN/O forthright/JJ/O on/IN/O numerous/JJ/O points/NNS/O ././O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-ORG Democracy/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Communist/NNP/O parties/NNS/O herald/VBP/O his/PRP$/O assertions/NNS/O as/IN/O proof/NN/O of/IN/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG complicity/NN/O ././O
Among/IN/O unanswered/JJ/O questions/NNS/O are/VBP/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Papandreou/NNP/B-PERSON received/VBD/O $/$/O 23/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O stolen/VBN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Crete/NNP/I-ORG funds/NNS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 734,000/CD/O in/IN/O bribes/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O contended/VBN/O ;/:/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O ordered/VBD/O state/NN/O agencies/NNS/O to/TO/O deposit/VB/O some/DT/O $/$/O 57/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Koskotas/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O bank/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O skim/VB/O off/RP/O the/DT/O interest/NN/O ;/:/O and/CC/O ,/,/O what/WP/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O cut/NN/O was/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 210/CD/O million/CD/O Mr./NNP/O Koskotas/NNP/B-PERSON pinched/VBD/O ././O
Two/CD/O former/JJ/O ministers/NNS/O were/VBD/O so/RB/O heavily/RB/O implicated/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Koskotas/NNP/B-PERSON affair/NN/O that/IN/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O of/IN/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG voted/VBD/O to/TO/O refer/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O special/JJ/O court/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O eluding/VBG/O parliamentary/JJ/O probe/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O case/NN/O of/IN/O millions/NNS/O of/IN/O drachmas/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Koskotas/NNP/B-PERSON funneled/VBD/O into/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG Democracy/NNP/I-ORG coffers/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O investigation/NN/O produced/VBD/O only/RB/O circumstantial/JJ/O evidence/NN/O and/CC/O ``/``/O indications/NNS/O ''/''/O that/IN/O point/NN/O to/TO/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O not/RB/O clinching/VBG/O proof/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O another/DT/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O Greeks/NNPS/O were/VBD/O told/VBN/O how/WRB/O their/PRP$/O national/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O EYP/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O regularly/RB/O monitored/VBD/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O conversations/NNS/O of/IN/O prominent/JJ/O figures/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O key/JJ/O opposition/NN/O politicians/NNS/O ,/,/O journalists/NNS/O and/CC/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG cabinet/NN/O members/NNS/O ././O
Despite/IN/O convincing/JJ/O arguments/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O never/RB/O established/VBN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Papandreou/NNP/B-PERSON personally/RB/O ordered/VBD/O or/CC/O directed/VBD/O the/DT/O wiretaps/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O central/JJ/O weakness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O scandals/NNS/O ''/''/O debates/NNS/O was/VBD/O pointed/VBN/O up/RP/O especially/RB/O well/RB/O when/WRB/O discussions/NNS/O focused/VBD/O on/IN/O arms/NNS/O deals/NNS/O and/CC/O kickbacks/NNS/O ././O
Naturally/RB/O ,/,/O neither/CC/O General/NNP/B-ORG Dynamics/NNP/I-ORG nor/CC/O Dassault/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O be/VB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O hamper/VB/O its/PRP$/O prospective/JJ/O future/NN/O dealings/NNS/O by/IN/O making/VBG/O disclosures/NNS/O of/IN/O sums/NNS/O paid/VBN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O or/CC/O not/RB/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O various/JJ/O Greek/JJ/O officials/NNS/O for/IN/O services/NNS/O rendered/VBN/O ././O
So/IN/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mitsotakis/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O communist/NN/O chums/NNS/O may/MD/O have/VB/O unwittingly/RB/O served/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Papandreou/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O moral/JJ/O victory/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O platter/JJ/O :/:/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O whether/IN/O guilty/JJ/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ,/,/O can/MD/O now/RB/O traipse/VB/O the/DT/O countryside/NN/O condemning/VBG/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O affair/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O witch/NN/O hunt/NN/O at/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Papandreou/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O expense/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O while/IN/O verbal/JJ/O high/JJ/O jinks/NNS/O alone/RB/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O help/VB/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG regain/VB/O power/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Papandreou/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O never/RB/O be/VB/O underestimated/VBN/O ././O
Then/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O buttress/VB/O his/PRP$/O credibility/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O left/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O enticed/VBD/O some/DT/O smaller/JJR/O leftist/JJ/O parties/NNS/O to/TO/O stand/VB/O for/IN/O election/NN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG banner/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O balance/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O hopes/NNS/O of/IN/O gaining/VBG/O some/DT/O disaffected/JJ/O centrist/JJ/O votes/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O managed/VBD/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O New/NNP/B-ORG Democracy/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG representative/NN/O and/CC/O known/VBN/O political/JJ/O enemy/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mitsotakis/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Crucial/JJ/O as/IN/O these/DT/O elections/NNS/O are/VBP/O for/IN/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O pressing/VBG/O issues/NNS/O of/IN/O state/NN/O are/VBP/O getting/VBG/O lost/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O shuffle/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O future/JJ/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG participation/NN/O remains/VBZ/O unsure/JJ/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ././O
Greece/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O must/MD/O revamp/VB/O major/JJ/O pieces/NNS/O of/IN/O legislation/NN/O in/IN/O preparation/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O 1992/CD/O targets/NNS/O of/IN/O heightened/VBN/O Common/NNP/O Market/NNP/O cooperation/NN/O ././O
Greece/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O bilateral/JJ/O relations/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE need/VBP/O attention/NN/O soon/RB/O as/IN/O well/RB/O ././O
For/IN/O one/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O accord/NN/O concerning/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O bases/NNS/O in/IN/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE lapses/VBZ/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Negotiations/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O agreement/NN/O were/VBD/O frozen/VBN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O June/NNP/O elections/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O clock/NN/O is/VBZ/O running/VBG/O ././O
Another/DT/O matter/NN/O of/IN/O concern/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O extradition/NN/O of/IN/O Mohammed/NNP/B-PERSON Rashid/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Palestinian/JJ/O terrorist/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O wanted/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O the/DT/O 1982/CD/O bombing/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Pan/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Airways/NNPS/I-ORG flight/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Greek/NNP/O courts/NNS/O have/VBP/O decided/VBN/O in/IN/O favor/NN/O of/IN/O extradition/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Rashid/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O awaits/VBZ/O final/JJ/O approval/NN/O from/IN/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O next/JJ/O justice/NN/O minister/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Greeks/NNPS/O seem/VBP/O barely/RB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O importance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O litmus/NN/O test/NN/O of/IN/O whether/IN/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O be/VB/O counted/VBN/O in/RB/O or/CC/O out/RB/O for/IN/O international/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O combat/VB/O terrorism/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O force/VB/O new/JJ/O elections/NNS/O early/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O by/IN/O frustrating/VBG/O the/DT/O procedures/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O election/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O republic/NN/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O ././O
New/NNP/B-ORG Democracy/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O once/RB/O again/RB/O glaringly/RB/O underestimated/VBN/O the/DT/O opponent/NN/O and/CC/O linked/VBN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O prospects/NNS/O to/TO/O negative/JJ/O reaction/NN/O against/IN/O PASOK/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O forgetting/VBG/O to/TO/O tend/VB/O to/TO/O either/CC/O program/NN/O clarity/NN/O or/CC/O the/DT/O rectification/NN/O of/IN/O internal/JJ/O squabbles/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Papandreou/NNP/B-PERSON ?/./O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O exactly/RB/O sitting/VBG/O pretty/RB/O at/IN/O this/DT/O stage/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O since/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O undoubtedly/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O proficient/JJ/O bull/NN/O slingers/NNS/O who/WP/O ever/RB/O raked/VBD/O muck/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O far/RB/O wiser/JJR/O to/TO/O view/VB/O him/PRP/O as/IN/O sidelined/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O certainly/RB/O not/RB/O yet/RB/O eliminated/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carpenter/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O regional/JJ/O correspondent/NN/O for/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Review/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O lived/VBN/O in/IN/O Athens/NNP/B-GPE since/IN/O 1981/CD/O ././O
