U.S./NNP/B-GPE OFFICIALS/NNS/O MOVED/VBD/O to/TO/O head/VB/O off/RP/O any/DT/O repeat/NN/O of/IN/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O today/NN/O following/VBG/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O plunge/NN/O in/IN/O stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
Fed/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON signaled/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O was/VBD/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O inject/VB/O massive/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O money/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O banking/NN/O system/NN/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O crisis/NN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O officials/NNS/O also/RB/O mapped/VBN/O out/RP/O plans/NNS/O ,/,/O though/IN/O they/PRP/O kept/VBD/O their/PRP$/O moves/NNS/O quiet/JJ/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O more/RBR/O jittery/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG industrials/NNS/O skidded/VBD/O 190.58/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 2569.26/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O junk/NN/O bond/NN/O market/NN/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O standstill/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Treasury/NN/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O soared/VBD/O and/CC/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O fell/VBD/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O dropped/VBD/O early/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O by/IN/O late/JJ/O morning/NN/O were/VBD/O turning/VBG/O around/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O was/VBD/O trading/VBG/O sharply/RB/O lower/JJR/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Many/JJ/O banks/NNS/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O back/VB/O the/DT/O $/$/O 6.79/CD/O billion/CD/O transaction/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O bankers/NNS/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O from/IN/O any/DT/O unwillingness/NN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O takeovers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O surge/NN/O in/IN/O producer/NN/O prices/NNS/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O followed/VBD/O three/CD/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O declines/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O analysts/NNS/O were/VBD/O divided/VBN/O on/IN/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O 0.9/CD/O %/NN/O jump/NN/O signaled/VBD/O a/DT/O severe/JJ/O worsening/NN/O of/IN/O inflation/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O retail/JJ/O sales/NNS/O grew/VBD/O 0.5/CD/O %/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNPS/I-ORG signaled/VBD/O that/IN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O five/CD/O North/NNP/O American/NNP/O assembly/NN/O plants/NNS/O may/MD/O close/VB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1990s/CD/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O tries/VBZ/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O excess/JJ/O capacity/NN/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O entangled/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O legal/JJ/O battle/NN/O over/IN/O movie/NN/O producers/NNS/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Gruber/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Jon/NNP/B-PERSON Peters/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O fight/NN/O could/MD/O set/VB/O back/RP/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE movie/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O offer/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O include/VB/O Bonwit/NNP/B-ORG Teller/NNP/I-ORG or/CC/O B./NNP/B-ORG Altman/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG strike/NN/O is/VBZ/O starting/VBG/O to/TO/O affect/VB/O airlines/NNS/O ././O
America/NNP/B-ORG West/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Friday/NNP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O postpone/VB/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O service/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE because/IN/O of/IN/O delays/NNS/O in/IN/O receiving/VBG/O aircraft/NN/O from/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O steel/NN/O quota/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O significantly/RB/O ././O
Markets/NNS/O --/:/O
Stocks/NNS/O :/:/O Volume/NN/O 251,170,000/CD/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG industrials/NNS/O 2569.26/CD/O ,/,/O off/IN/O 190.58/CD/O ;/:/O transportation/NN/O 1406.29/CD/O ,/,/O off/IN/O 78.06/CD/O ;/:/O utilities/NNS/O 211.96/CD/O ,/,/O off/IN/O 7.29/CD/O ././O
Bonds/NNS/O :/:/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Treasury/NNP/B-ORG index/NN/O 3421.29/CD/O ,/,/O up/IN/O
Commodities/NNS/O :/:/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG futures/NNS/O index/NN/O 129.87/CD/O ,/,/O up/IN/O 0.01/CD/O ;/:/O spot/NN/O index/NN/O 129.25/CD/O ,/,/O up/IN/O 0.28/CD/O ././O
Dollar/NN/O :/:/O 142.10/CD/O yen/NN/O ,/,/O off/IN/O 2.07/CD/O ;/:/O 1.8740/CD/O marks/NNS/O ,/,/O off/IN/O 0.0343/CD/O ././O
