In/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Siemens/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O hold/VB/O 74.9/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O Matsushita/NNP/B-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ,/,/O Matsushita/NNP/B-ORG Electronic/NNP/I-ORG Components/NNPS/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O 25.1/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O basic/JJ/O agreement/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O was/VBD/O announced/VBN/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O Siemens/NNP/B-ORG Matsushita/NNP/I-ORG Components/NNPS/I-ORG G.m.b/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG H/NN/I-ORG ././I-ORG
It/PRP/O will/MD/O have/VB/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NNS/O in/IN/O Munich/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Matsushita/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O share/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O will/MD/O rise/VB/O to/TO/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O Oct./NNP/O 1/CD/O ,/,/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O the/DT/O following/VBG/O Oct./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
Siemens/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O retain/VB/O majority/NN/O voting/VBG/O rights/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O parent/NN/O companies/NNS/O forecast/VBP/O sales/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O of/IN/O around/IN/O 750/CD/O million/CD/O marks/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Matsushita/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Sales/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O rise/VB/O to/TO/O one/CD/O billion/CD/O marks/NNS/O after/IN/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O production/NN/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Austria/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE ././O
