And/CC/O for/IN/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ABC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O negotiated/VBN/O with/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE studios/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O futile/JJ/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O that/DT/O ././O
But/CC/O with/IN/O foreign/JJ/O companies/NNS/O snapping/VBG/O up/RP/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE movie/NN/O studios/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O are/VBP/O pressing/VBG/O their/PRP$/O fight/NN/O harder/RBR/O than/IN/O ever/RB/O ././O
They/PRP/O hope/VBP/O the/DT/O foreign/JJ/O deals/NNS/O will/MD/O divide/VB/O the/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE opposition/NN/O and/CC/O prod/VB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O push/VB/O for/IN/O ending/VBG/O federal/JJ/O rules/NNS/O that/WDT/O prohibit/VBP/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O from/IN/O grabbing/VBG/O a/DT/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O rerun/NN/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O owning/VBG/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shows/NNS/O they/PRP/O put/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O network/NN/O executives/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O admit/VBP/O privately/RB/O that/DT/O victory/NN/O --/:/O either/CC/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O in/IN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O highly/RB/O doubtful/JJ/O any/DT/O time/NN/O soon/RB/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O that/DT/O deal/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O revived/VBN/O ,/,/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O another/DT/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O doors/NNS/O are/VBP/O open/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O an/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O '/POS/O push/NN/O may/MD/O only/RB/O aggravate/VB/O an/DT/O increasingly/RB/O bitter/JJ/O rift/NN/O between/IN/O them/PRP/O and/CC/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE studios/NNS/O ././O
Few/JJ/O people/NNS/O privy/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O expect/VBP/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O to/TO/O budge/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O networks/NNS/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O uninhibited/JJ/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O authority/NN/O ''/''/O over/IN/O what/WDT/O shows/NNS/O get/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O ,/,/O charges/VBZ/O Motion/NNP/B-ORG Picture/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Valenti/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O vociferous/JJ/O opponent/NN/O of/IN/O rescinding/VBG/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O why/WRB/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O part/NN/O ,/,/O must/MD/O stay/VB/O in/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Studio/NN/O executives/NNS/O in/IN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O -/:/O including/JJ/O officials/NNS/O at/IN/O Paramount/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Fries/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG --/:/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O interviewed/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Valenti/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O ,/,/O asserts/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O whole/JJ/O production/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O a/DT/O man/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O side/NN/O of/IN/O preserving/VBG/O ''/''/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O ././O
Such/JJ/O proclamations/NNS/O leave/VBP/O network/NN/O officials/NNS/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O doubtful/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O will/MD/O bend/VB/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O an/DT/O incentive/NN/O to/TO/O negotiate/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O network/NN/O executive/NN/O ././O
``/``/O And/CC/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O indication/NN/O that/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O address/VB/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O it/PRP/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Indeed/RB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O repeatedly/RB/O it/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O no/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mess/NN/O ,/,/O urging/VBG/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O license/VBP/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O air/NN/O shows/NNS/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O work/VB/O out/RP/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O compromise/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O recent/JJ/O developments/NNS/O have/VBP/O made/VBN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O --/:/O and/CC/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG President/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O particular/JJ/O --/:/O ever/RB/O more/RBR/O adamant/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O must/MD/O be/VB/O unshackled/JJ/O to/TO/O survive/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O latest/JJS/O provocation/NN/O :/:/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG plan/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNPS/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 3.4/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O independent/JJ/O producer/NN/O Guber/NNP/B-ORG Peters/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O He/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O that/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O meantime/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O hoping/VBG/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O buying/NN/O
An/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O counters/NNS/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Holston/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O lament/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O entirely/RB/O consistent/JJ/O ''/''/O with/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG plans/NNS/O because/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE rules/NNS/O would/MD/O limit/VB/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O involvement/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG deal/NN/O so/RB/O severely/RB/O as/IN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ``/``/O light/JJ/O years/NNS/O away/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O type/NN/O of/IN/O unrestrained/JJ/O deals/NNS/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG --/:/O and/CC/O everyone/NN/O else/RB/O except/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O networks/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Big/NNP/O Three/CD/O 's/POS/O drumbeat/NN/O for/IN/O deregulation/NN/O began/VBD/O intensifying/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG went/VBD/O ahead/RB/O with/IN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O spoke/VBD/O up/RP/O again/RB/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG bid/NN/O for/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O announced/VBN/O ././O
With/IN/O a/DT/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG deal/NN/O ,/,/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O move/VB/O into/IN/O uncharted/JJ/O territory/NN/O --/:/O possibly/RB/O raising/VBG/O hackles/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O and/CC/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O never/RB/O really/RB/O been/VBN/O tested/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Lilley/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O top/JJ/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O spent/VBD/O years/NNS/O lobbying/VBG/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O lifted/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O now/RB/O runs/VBZ/O Policy/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O consulting/VBG/O to/TO/O media/NNS/O companies/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O raised/VBD/O objections/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O 's/POS/O syndication/NN/O operations/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O spun/VBN/O off/IN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O firm/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O network/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O direct/JJ/O stake/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O such/JJ/O convolutions/NNS/O would/MD/O still/RB/O block/VB/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O from/IN/O grabbing/VBG/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O chunk/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O riches/NN/O of/IN/O syndication/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O networks/NNS/O admit/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O chances/NNS/O of/IN/O getting/VBG/O the/DT/O relief/NN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O are/VBP/O slim/JJ/O --/:/O for/IN/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O ././O
Six/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O tantalizingly/RB/O close/JJ/O ././O
Various/JJ/O evidence/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O Brookings/NNP/B-ORG Institution/NNP/I-ORG study/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O 800/CD/O series/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O had/VBD/O aired/VBN/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O partly/RB/O owned/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1960s/CD/O ,/,/O showed/VBD/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O wield/VB/O undue/JJ/O control/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O studios/NNS/O as/IN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O alleged/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG effort/NN/O collapsed/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O networks/NNS/O and/CC/O studios/NNS/O have/VBP/O bickered/VBN/O ever/RB/O since/IN/O ././O
Network/NN/O officials/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O talks/NNS/O may/MD/O hope/VB/O the/DT/O foreign/JJ/O influx/NN/O builds/VBZ/O more/JJR/O support/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O that/DT/O seems/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O falters/VBZ/O :/:/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O about/IN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O program/NN/O quality/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O clout/NN/O given/VBN/O its/PRP$/O fund/NN/O raising/NN/O for/IN/O senators/NNS/O and/CC/O representatives/NNS/O overseeing/VBG/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Markey/NNP/B-PERSON hopes/VBZ/O this/DT/O pushes/VBZ/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O and/CC/O studios/NNS/O to/TO/O work/VB/O it/PRP/O out/RP/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O at/IN/O the/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O new/JJ/O Chairman/NNP/O Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Sikes/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O he/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O to/TO/O hammer/VB/O out/RP/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O plan/NN/O ././O
