The/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O urging/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O give/VB/O states/NNS/O more/JJR/O leeway/NN/O to/TO/O restrict/VB/O abortions/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O minors/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O without/IN/O the/DT/O consent/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O parents/NNS/O ././O
Solicitor/NNP/O General/NNP/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON Starr/NNP/I-PERSON argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O 1973/CD/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG decision/NN/O ,/,/O Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./CC/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O recognizing/VBG/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O right/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O incorrect/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O was/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O in/IN/O 1976/CD/O to/TO/O rule/VB/O that/IN/O minors/NNS/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O that/WDT/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O absolutely/RB/O vetoed/VBN/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O parents/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O filed/VBD/O the/DT/O brief/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O appeal/NN/O involving/VBG/O a/DT/O Minnesota/NNP/B-GPE law/NN/O that/WDT/O requires/VBZ/O that/IN/O both/DT/O parents/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O minor/NN/O be/VB/O notified/VBN/O before/IN/O she/PRP/O may/MD/O have/VB/O an/DT/O abortion/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O urged/VBD/O the/DT/O justices/NNS/O to/TO/O adopt/VB/O a/DT/O legal/JJ/O standard/NN/O suggested/VBN/O by/IN/O Chief/NNP/O Justice/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Rehnquist/NNP/I-PERSON last/JJ/O July/NNP/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O upheld/VBD/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O abortion/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O much/RB/O easier/JJR/O standard/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O state/NN/O to/TO/O satisfy/VB/O than/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG test/NN/O since/IN/O 1973/CD/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O requires/VBZ/O a/DT/O state/NN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O compelling/JJ/O ''/''/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O restricting/VBG/O abortion/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O Hodgson/NNP/B-PERSON vs./CC/O Minnesota/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O argued/VBN/O Nov./NNP/O 29/CD/O ././O
