Atco/NNP/B-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O utilities/NNS/O arm/NN/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O building/VBG/O new/JJ/O electric/JJ/O power/NN/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O one/CD/O billion/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 851/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Great/NNP/B-GPE Britain/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O elsewhere/RB/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O projects/NNS/O are/VBP/O big/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O C$/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O plus/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Richardson/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O go/VB/O into/IN/O them/PRP/O alone/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Utilities/NNP/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG equity/NN/O stake/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O small/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Ideally/RB/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O 'd/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O operator/NN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O of/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O equity/NN/O investor/NN/O ././O
Our/PRP$/O long/JJ/O suit/NN/O is/VBZ/O our/PRP$/O proven/JJ/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O ''/''/O power/NN/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Richardson/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O n't/RB/O offer/VB/O specifics/NNS/O regarding/VBG/O Atco/NNP/B-ORG 's/VBZ/O proposed/VBN/O British/JJ/O project/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O compete/VB/O for/IN/O customers/NNS/O with/IN/O two/CD/O huge/JJ/O British/JJ/O power/NN/O generating/NN/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O formed/VBN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O privatize/VB/O its/PRP$/O massive/JJ/O water/NN/O and/CC/O electric/JJ/O utilities/NNS/O ././O
Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O government/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O about/RB/O #/#/O 20/CD/O billion/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 31.05/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O from/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O giant/JJ/O water/NN/O and/CC/O electric/JJ/O utilities/NNS/O ,/,/O beginning/VBG/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O planned/JJ/O electric/JJ/O utility/NN/O sale/NN/O ,/,/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O alone/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O #/#/O 13/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O public/JJ/O offering/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O independent/JJ/O generators/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O for/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O customers/NNS/O until/IN/O 1994/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O for/IN/O another/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O between/IN/O 1994/CD/O and/CC/O 1998/CD/O ././O
Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Utilities/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O 1988/CD/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O C$/$/O 1.16/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O mainly/RB/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O and/CC/O electric/JJ/O utility/NN/O businesses/NNS/O in/IN/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O serves/VBZ/O about/RB/O 800,000/CD/O customers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O move/NN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O to/TO/O deregulate/VB/O the/DT/O generation/NN/O of/IN/O electricity/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Richardson/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Utilities/NNP/I-ORG hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O capitalize/VB/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O thrust/NN/O on/IN/O our/PRP$/O utility/NN/O side/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Utilities/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O also/RB/O mulling/VBG/O projects/NNS/O in/IN/O underdeveloped/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O though/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O specific/JJ/O ././O
Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Utilities/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O alone/RB/O in/IN/O exploring/VBG/O power/NN/O generation/NN/O opportunities/NNS/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O anticipation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O privatization/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O certainly/RB/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O some/DT/O power/NN/O generating/NN/O projects/NNS/O in/IN/O England/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Stram/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O corporate/JJ/O strategy/NN/O and/CC/O corporate/JJ/O planning/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O Enron/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O producer/NN/O and/CC/O pipeline/NN/O operator/NN/O ././O
