Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON Granville/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
I/PRP/O see/VBP/O no/DT/O major/JJ/O support/NN/O until/IN/O 2200/CD/O ././O
Elaine/NNP/B-PERSON Garzarelli/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
A/DT/O quantitative/JJ/O analyst/NN/O with/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Garzarelli/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O warned/VBN/O clients/NNS/O to/TO/O take/VB/O their/PRP$/O money/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O big/JJ/O drop/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O a/DT/O crash/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O October/NNP/O massacre/NN/O ''/''/O like/IN/O those/DT/O that/WDT/O occurred/VBD/O in/IN/O 1978/CD/O and/CC/O 1979/CD/O ././O
Ned/NNP/B-PERSON Davis/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O fall/NN/O marks/VBZ/O the/DT/O start/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O bear/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Davis/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Ned/NNP/B-ORG Davis/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
There/EX/O was/VBD/O tremendous/JJ/O public/JJ/O enthusiasm/NN/O for/IN/O stock/NN/O mutual/JJ/O funds/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O hundred/CD/O billion/CD/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O stock/NN/O was/VBD/O subject/JJ/O ''/''/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O ././O
Today/NN/O could/MD/O even/RB/O be/VB/O an/DT/O up/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Davis/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O major/JJ/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O agree/VBP/O to/TO/O refrain/VB/O from/IN/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O the/DT/O downturn/NN/O to/TO/O carry/VB/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Industrial/NNP/O Average/NNP/O down/RB/O to/TO/O around/IN/O 2000/CD/O sometime/RB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Leon/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Cooperman/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
Mr./NNP/O Cooperman/NNP/B-PERSON sees/VBZ/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O time/NN/O to/TO/O pick/VB/O up/RP/O bargains/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O any/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O rush/VB/O ././O
He/PRP/O ticks/VBZ/O off/RP/O several/JJ/O major/JJ/O differences/NNS/O between/IN/O now/RB/O and/CC/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Kenneth/NNP/I-PERSON Galbraith/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
Mario/NNP/B-PERSON Gabelli/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE money/NN/O manager/NN/O Mario/NNP/B-PERSON Gabelli/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O expert/NN/O at/IN/O spotting/VBG/O takeover/NN/O candidates/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O takeovers/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O totally/RB/O gone/VBN/O ././O
These/DT/O sorts/NNS/O of/IN/O takeovers/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O require/VB/O junk/NN/O bonds/NNS/O or/CC/O big/JJ/O bank/NN/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O so/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gabelli/NNP/B-PERSON figures/NNS/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O ././O
He/PRP/O thinks/VBZ/O another/DT/O crash/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O unlikely/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O nibbling/VBG/O at/IN/O ''/''/O selected/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O during/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O plunge/NN/O ././O
Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Rogers/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
He/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O ``/``/O economic/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O financial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ''/''/O ahead/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O fairly/RB/O strong/JJ/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rogers/NNP/B-PERSON wo/MD/O n't/RB/O decide/VB/O what/WP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O today/NN/O until/IN/O he/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O how/WRB/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE markets/NNS/O go/VBP/O ././O
Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Curzio/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
Many/JJ/O people/NNS/O now/RB/O claim/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O predicted/VBN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
Queens/NNP/B-GPE newsletter/NN/O writer/NN/O Francis/NNP/B-PERSON X./NNP/I-PERSON Curzio/NNP/I-PERSON actually/RB/O did/VBD/O it/PRP/O :/:/O He/PRP/O stated/VBD/O in/IN/O writing/NN/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O 1987/CD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Industrial/NNP/O Average/NNP/O was/VBD/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O decline/VB/O about/RB/O 500/CD/O points/NNS/O the/DT/O following/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Curzio/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O what/WP/O happens/VBZ/O now/RB/O will/MD/O depend/VB/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O deal/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Frank/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Terrizzi/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON
Stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O ``/``/O would/MD/O still/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O go/VB/O down/RB/O some/DT/O additional/JJ/O amount/NN/O before/IN/O we/PRP/O become/VBP/O positive/JJ/O on/IN/O stocks/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Terrizzi/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O managing/VBG/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Cincinnati/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O manages/VBZ/O about/RB/O $/$/O 1.8/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O drew/VBD/O stiff/JJ/O criticism/NN/O from/IN/O many/JJ/O clients/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O pulled/VBD/O entirely/RB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O stocks/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O beginning/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O thus/RB/O missed/VBD/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O rally/NN/O ././O
Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O keeping/VBG/O its/PRP$/O money/NN/O entirely/RB/O in/IN/O cash/NN/O equivalents/NNS/O ,/,/O primarily/RB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bills/NNS/O ././O
