GM/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O under/IN/O intense/JJ/O pressure/NN/O to/TO/O close/VB/O factories/NNS/O that/WDT/O became/VBD/O unprofitable/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O giant/JJ/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O 's/POS/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O share/NN/O skidded/VBD/O during/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O decade/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O currently/RB/O using/VBG/O about/RB/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O North/JJ/O American/JJ/O vehicle/NN/O capacity/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O vowed/VBN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O run/VB/O at/IN/O 100/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O capacity/NN/O by/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
One/CD/O reason/NN/O is/VBZ/O mounting/VBG/O competition/NN/O from/IN/O new/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O car/NN/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O are/VBP/O pouring/VBG/O out/RP/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O one/CD/O million/CD/O vehicles/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O at/IN/O costs/NNS/O lower/JJR/O than/IN/O GM/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O match/VB/O ././O
GM/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O get/VB/O their/PRP$/O strategy/NN/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O capacity/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O work/NN/O force/NN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O before/IN/O those/DT/O talks/NNS/O begin/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O GM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O moves/NNS/O are/VBP/O coming/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O when/WRB/O UAW/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O silence/VB/O dissidents/NNS/O who/WP/O charge/VBP/O the/DT/O union/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O passive/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O face/NN/O of/IN/O GM/NNP/B-ORG layoffs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O let/VB/O word/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O shutdowns/NNS/O and/CC/O product/NN/O reassignments/NNS/O trickle/VBP/O out/RP/O in/IN/O separate/JJ/O communiques/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O affected/JJ/O plants/NNS/O showed/VBD/O ``/``/O disarray/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O an/DT/O ``/``/O inability/NN/O or/CC/O unwillingness/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O consistent/JJ/O information/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Yokich/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
That/DT/O means/VBZ/O two/CD/O plants/NNS/O --/:/O one/CD/O in/IN/O Scarborough/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ontario/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O in/IN/O Lordstown/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O probably/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O shut/VBN/O down/RP/O after/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1991/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O shutdowns/NNS/O will/MD/O idle/VB/O about/RB/O 3,000/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O assembly/NN/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O about/JJ/O 2,500/CD/O workers/NNS/O in/IN/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Workers/NNS/O at/IN/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O Van/NNP/B-GPE Nuys/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Pontiac/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O were/VBD/O told/VBN/O their/PRP$/O facilities/NNS/O are/VBP/O no/RB/O longer/RBR/O being/NN/O considered/VBN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O generation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Pontiac/NNP/B-ORG Firebird/NNP/O and/CC/O Chevrolet/NNP/B-ORG Camaro/NNP/O muscle/NN/O cars/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O announcement/NN/O left/VBD/O union/NN/O officials/NNS/O in/IN/O Van/NNP/B-GPE Nuys/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE uncertain/JJ/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O futures/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Van/NNP/B-GPE Nuys/NNP/I-GPE plant/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O employs/VBZ/O about/RB/O 3,000/CD/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O product/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O after/IN/O 1993/CD/O ././O
Jerry/NNP/B-PERSON Shrieves/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O UAW/NNP/B-ORG local/JJ/O president/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O facility/NN/O was/VBD/O asked/VBN/O to/TO/O draw/VB/O up/RP/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O working/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O flex/JJ/O plant/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O could/MD/O build/VB/O several/JJ/O different/JJ/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O products/NNS/O on/IN/O short/JJ/O notice/NN/O to/TO/O satisfy/VB/O demand/NN/O ././O
Union/NN/O officials/NNS/O have/VB/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O beating/NN/O politically/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ././O
