But/CC/O it/PRP/O remains/VBZ/O involved/JJ/O in/IN/O programs/NNS/O with/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O and/CC/O Delta/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Lines/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Industry/NN/O estimates/NNS/O put/VBD/O Avis/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O annual/JJ/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O five/CD/O programs/NNS/O at/IN/O between/IN/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 14/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Avis/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O specify/VB/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O three/CD/O airlines/NNS/O being/VBG/O dropped/VBN/O account/NN/O for/IN/O ``/``/O far/RB/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O half/DT/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O total/NN/O ././O
Budget/NNP/B-ORG Rent/NNP/I-ORG a/DT/I-ORG Car/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O National/NNP/B-ORG Car/NNP/I-ORG Rental/NNP/I-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Minneapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O both/DT/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O suit/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O see/VB/O how/WRB/O this/DT/O news/NN/O by/IN/O Hertz/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Avis/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O not/RB/O benefit/VB/O Budget/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Wilson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Budget/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O marketing/NN/O planning/NN/O ././O
Northwest/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Midway/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O two/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O five/CD/O airlines/NNS/O with/IN/O which/WDT/O Budget/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O agreements/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O month/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Hertz/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Park/NNP/B-GPE Ridge/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O drop/VB/O its/PRP$/O marketing/NN/O agreements/NNS/O at/IN/O year/NN/O end/NN/O with/IN/O Delta/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O America/NNP/B-ORG West/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Continental/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O pacts/NNS/O with/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O UAL/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O USAir/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ended/VBN/O .../:/O sometime/RB/O after/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 31/CD/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Hertz/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O annual/JJ/O fees/NNS/O to/TO/O those/DT/O airlines/NNS/O amounted/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O redeemed/VBN/O awards/NNS/O topped/VBD/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O and/CC/O competitors/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O doubt/VBP/O the/DT/O numbers/NNS/O were/VBD/O that/RB/O high/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O 've/VBP/O been/VBN/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O get/VB/O their/PRP$/O costs/NNS/O down/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O fairly/RB/O sensible/JJ/O way/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
