Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O proposed/VBD/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Bermuda/NNP/B-GPE concern/NN/O ,/,/O potentially/RB/O exempting/VBG/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O liability/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O smelter/NN/O 's/POS/O cleanup/NN/O costs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O EPA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O made/VBD/O certain/JJ/O voluntary/JJ/O undertakings/NNS/O with/IN/O respect/NN/O to/TO/O intercorporate/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O entered/VBN/O into/IN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O and/CC/O consent/NN/O decree/NN/O are/VBP/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O court/NN/O approval/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG added/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O will/MD/O seek/VB/O to/TO/O recover/VB/O equitable/JJ/O contribution/NN/O from/IN/O others/NNS/O for/IN/O both/CC/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O and/CC/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O liabilities/NNS/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O incur/VB/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Superfund/NNP/B-ORG law/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG must/MD/O give/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O 45/CD/O days/NNS/O '/POS/O advance/JJ/O written/JJ/O notice/NN/O before/IN/O issuing/VBG/O any/DT/O dividends/NNS/O on/IN/O common/JJ/O stock/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O net/JJ/O worth/NN/O can/MD/O not/RB/O fall/VB/O below/IN/O $/$/O 185/CD/O million/CD/O after/IN/O the/DT/O dividends/NNS/O are/VBP/O issued/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O that/DT/O agreement/NN/O only/RB/O become/VBP/O effective/JJ/O the/DT/O date/NN/O of/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O reorganization/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O we/PRP/O anticipate/VBP/O will/MD/O occur/VB/O sometime/RB/O in/IN/O early/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Lawrence/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Mehl/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O ././O
Gulf/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O net/JJ/O worth/NN/O after/IN/O those/DT/O transaction/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O meeting/NN/O for/IN/O shareholders/NNS/O in/IN/O early/JJ/O 1990/CD/O to/TO/O vote/VB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O proposed/VBN/O reorganization/NN/O ././O
