The/DT/O $/$/O 409/CD/O million/CD/O bid/NN/O includes/VBZ/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O estimated/JJ/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O secured/JJ/O liabilities/NNS/O on/IN/O those/DT/O properties/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O those/DT/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O bid/NN/O ././O
Hooker/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O philosophy/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O build/VB/O and/CC/O sell/VB/O ././O
L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O operating/VBG/O with/IN/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O creditors/NNS/O under/IN/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O ././O
Sanford/NNP/B-PERSON Sigoloff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O yet/RB/O seen/VBN/O the/DT/O bid/NN/O but/CC/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O review/VB/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O bring/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O attention/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O creditors/NNS/O committee/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Thornton/NNP/B-GPE mall/NN/O opened/VBD/O Sept./NNP/O 19/CD/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Bigg/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O hypermarket/NN/O as/IN/O its/PRP$/O anchor/NN/O ;/:/O the/DT/O Columbia/NNP/B-GPE mall/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O Nov./NNP/O 15/CD/O ././O
Hoare/NNP/B-ORG Govett/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O acting/VBG/O as/IN/O the/DT/O consortium/NN/O 's/POS/O investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O grew/VBD/O modestly/RB/O until/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O position/NN/O in/IN/O Hooker/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O acquired/VBN/O by/IN/O Australian/JJ/O developer/NN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Herscu/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O currently/RB/O Hooker/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG chain/NN/O is/VBZ/O currently/RB/O being/VBG/O offered/VBN/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O by/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Reached/VBN/O in/IN/O Honolulu/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Shidler/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O the/DT/O various/JJ/O Hooker/NNP/B-ORG malls/NNS/O can/MD/O become/VB/O profitable/JJ/O with/IN/O new/JJ/O management/NN/O ././O
