The/DT/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O a/DT/O wonderful/JJ/O botanical/JJ/O garden/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O zoo/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O charming/JJ/O Little/NNP/B-LOC Italy/NNP/I-LOC -LRB-/-LRB-/O on/IN/O Arthur/NNP/B-FAC Avenue/NNP/I-FAC -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Yankees/NNPS/B-ORG ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O having/VBG/O been/VBN/O subjected/VBN/O to/TO/O news/NN/O footage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O devastated/JJ/O South/NNP/B-GPE Bronx/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O look/VBP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O borough/NN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O Tom/NNP/B-PERSON Wolfe/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Sherman/NNP/B-PERSON McCoy/NNP/I-PERSON did/VBD/O in/IN/O ``/``/O Bonfire/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Vanities/NNS/O ''/''/O --/:/O as/IN/O a/DT/O wrong/JJ/O turn/NN/O into/IN/O hell/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Laura/NNP/B-PERSON Cunningham/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Bronx/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O her/PRP$/O childhood/NN/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O the/DT/O '50s/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O something/NN/O else/RB/O altogether/RB/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Cunningham/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O novelist/NN/O and/CC/O playwright/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O vivid/JJ/O and/CC/O dramatically/RB/O outsized/JJ/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O recall/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O transforms/VBZ/O her/PRP/O ``/``/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O the/DT/O emotions/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O place/NN/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O flats/NNS/O of/IN/O mediocrity/NN/O are/VBP/O only/RB/O relieved/VBN/O by/IN/O steep/JJ/O descents/NNS/O into/IN/O hysteria/NN/O ''/''/O into/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE ``/``/I-GPE Babylonian/NNP/I-GPE Bronx/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O world/NN/O simmering/VBG/O with/IN/O sex/NN/O and/CC/O death/NN/O and/CC/O intrigue/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Cunningham/NNP/B-PERSON the/DT/O architectural/JJ/O discombobulation/NN/O matched/VBD/O the/DT/O discrepancy/NN/O she/PRP/O felt/VBD/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC AnaMor/NNP/I-FAC Towers/NNP/I-FAC as/IN/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O girl/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O .../:/O outwardly/RB/O ordinary/JJ/O ,/,/O inwardly/RB/O ornate/JJ/O ,/,/O owing/VBG/O all/DT/O inspiration/NN/O to/TO/O heathen/JJ/O cultures/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Little/NNP/B-PERSON Lily/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Cunningham/NNP/B-PERSON calls/VBZ/O herself/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O ,/,/O really/RB/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O ordinary/JJ/O ././O
She/PRP/O was/VBD/O raised/VBN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O eight/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O by/IN/O her/PRP$/O mother/NN/O ,/,/O Rosie/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whom/WP/O she/PRP/O remembers/VBZ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O loving/JJ/O liar/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O realigned/VBD/O history/NN/O to/TO/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O father/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O live/VB/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
Rosie/NNP/B-PERSON reinvented/VBD/O this/DT/O man/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O may/MD/O or/CC/O may/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O known/VBN/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O child/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O war/NN/O hero/NN/O for/IN/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O benefit/NN/O ././O
Rosie/NN/B-PERSON died/VBD/O young/JJ/O and/CC/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O remembered/VBN/O her/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O romantic/JJ/O figure/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O interfere/VB/O much/RB/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O child/NN/O 's/POS/O education/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O games/NNS/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE children/NNS/O played/VBD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O holding/VBG/O kids/NNS/O down/RP/O and/CC/O stripping/VBG/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O seem/VB/O tame/JJ/O by/IN/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O crack/NN/O standards/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Ms./NNP/O Cunningham/NNP/B-PERSON makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O all/DT/O sound/VB/O like/IN/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O adventure/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Without/IN/O official/JJ/O knowledge/NN/O of/IN/O sex/NN/O or/CC/O death/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O flirted/VBD/O with/IN/O both/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O writes/VBZ/O ././O
She/PRP/O analyzed/VBD/O families/NNS/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O sleeping/NN/O arrangements/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O friend/NN/O Susan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O parents/NNS/O kept/VBD/O reminding/VBG/O her/PRP/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O unwanted/JJ/O ,/,/O slept/VBD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O narrow/JJ/O bed/NN/O wedged/VBN/O into/IN/O her/PRP$/O parents/NNS/O '/POS/O bedroom/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O though/IN/O she/PRP/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O temporary/JJ/O visitor/NN/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O friend/NN/O Diana/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O father/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O professional/JJ/O thief/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O bedrooms/NNS/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
Maybe/RB/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON became/VBD/O so/RB/O obsessed/JJ/O with/IN/O where/WRB/O people/NNS/O slept/VBD/O and/CC/O how/WRB/O because/IN/O her/PRP$/O own/JJ/O arrangements/NNS/O kept/VBD/O shifting/VBG/O ././O
When/WRB/O Rosie/NNP/B-PERSON died/VBD/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O uncles/NNS/O moved/VBD/O in/RP/O --/:/O and/CC/O let/VB/O her/PRP/O make/VB/O the/DT/O sleeping/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O household/NN/O arrangements/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O painted/VBD/O the/DT/O apartment/NN/O orange/JJ/O ,/,/O pink/JJ/O and/CC/O white/JJ/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O instructions/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O came/VBD/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O strangeness/NN/O honestly/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O book/NN/O loses/VBZ/O some/DT/O momentum/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON becomes/VBZ/O more/RBR/O preoccupied/JJ/O with/IN/O dating/VBG/O boys/NNS/O and/CC/O less/RBR/O with/IN/O her/PRP/O delightfully/RB/O weird/JJ/O family/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O part/NN/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O 's/POS/O much/JJ/O pleasure/NN/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O saucy/JJ/O ,/,/O poignant/JJ/O probe/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O mysteries/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Babylonian/NNP/I-GPE Bronx/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O figures/VBZ/O in/IN/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Jay/NNP/I-PERSON Friedman/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON latest/JJS/O novel/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O flashes/VBZ/O back/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-GPE New/NNP/I-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/O the/DT/O '50s/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O both/DT/O the/DT/O past/NN/O and/CC/O present/JJ/O worlds/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Current/JJ/O Climate/NN/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Atlantic/NNP/B-ORG Monthly/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O 200/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 18.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O feel/VBP/O cramped/JJ/O and/CC/O static/JJ/O ././O
For/IN/O his/PRP$/O sixth/JJ/O novel/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Friedman/NNP/B-PERSON tried/VBD/O to/TO/O resuscitate/VB/O the/DT/O protagonist/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O 1972/CD/O work/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O About/IN/O Harry/NNP/O Towns/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
Harry/NNP/B-PERSON fondly/RB/O remembers/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O old/JJ/O ''/''/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O '70s/NNS/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O people/NNS/O like/IN/O his/PRP$/O friend/NN/O Travis/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O psychiatrist/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O date/NN/O to/TO/O analyze/VB/O what/WP/O Travis/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O doing/VBG/O wrong/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O An/DT/O L.A./NNP/B-GPE solution/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O explains/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Friedman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Line/NN/O by/IN/O line/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Friedman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O weary/JJ/O cynicism/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O amusing/JJ/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O riffing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE social/JJ/O scheme/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O way/NN/O people/NNS/O size/VBP/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O up/RP/O ,/,/O immediately/RB/O canceling/VBG/O the/DT/O desperate/JJ/O ones/NNS/O who/WP/O merely/RB/O almost/RB/O made/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O take/VB/O too/RB/O many/JJ/O lines/NNS/O to/TO/O figure/VB/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON out/RP/O ././O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O bore/NN/O ././O
