RJR/NNP/B-ORG Nabisco/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O disbanding/VBG/O its/PRP$/O division/NN/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O buying/VBG/O network/NN/O advertising/NN/O time/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O a/DT/O month/NN/O after/IN/O moving/VBG/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O 14/CD/O employees/NNS/O to/TO/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE from/IN/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O found/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O media/NNS/O purchases/NNS/O that/IN/O an/DT/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O could/MD/O do/VB/O just/RB/O as/RB/O good/JJ/O a/DT/O job/NN/O at/IN/O significantly/RB/O lower/JJR/O cost/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O specify/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG spends/VBZ/O on/IN/O network/NN/O television/NN/O time/NN/O ././O
An/DT/O executive/NN/O close/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O spending/VBG/O about/RB/O $/$/O 140/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O network/NN/O television/NN/O time/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O down/RB/O from/IN/O roughly/RB/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O broadcast/NN/O group/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE until/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O previous/JJ/O management/NN/O moved/VBD/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O headquarters/NN/O before/IN/O this/DT/O summer/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O employee/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O said/VBD/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG moved/VBD/O 11/CD/O employees/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O back/RB/O to/TO/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE in/IN/O September/NNP/O because/IN/O ``/``/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O future/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O hired/VBD/O three/CD/O more/JJR/O buyers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O wooing/VBG/O them/PRP/O from/IN/O jobs/NNS/O with/IN/O advertising/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O moved/VBD/O the/DT/O 11/CD/O employees/NNS/O to/TO/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE last/JJ/O month/NN/O because/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O had/VBD/O then/RB/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O purchasing/VBG/O ad/NN/O time/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O '/POS/O upcoming/JJ/O season/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O studies/NNS/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O on/IN/O closing/VBG/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O until/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O president/NN/O ,/,/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Chrisanthopoulos/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O office/NN/O Friday/NNP/O afternoon/NN/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
