``/``/O No/DT/O one/NN/O can/MD/O predict/VB/O exactly/RB/O what/WP/O will/MD/O happen/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG side/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Minority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Dole/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Kan/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O need/VB/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O capital/NN/O gains/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
House/NNP/B-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Leon/NNP/B-PERSON Panetta/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O If/IN/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O signal/NN/O that/WDT/O comes/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O help/VB/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O deal/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Opponents/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cut/NN/O are/VBP/O playing/VBG/O hardball/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O a/DT/O senior/JJ/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Ways/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Means/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O where/WRB/O tax/NN/O legislation/NN/O originates/VBZ/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O ``/``/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O another/DT/O tax/NN/O bill/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O carry/VB/O a/DT/O gains/NNS/O tax/NN/O cut/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Such/JJ/O legislation/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O enacted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
Senators/NNS/O hope/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O those/DT/O cuts/NNS/O will/MD/O pressure/VB/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O streamlined/JJ/O bill/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG appears/VBZ/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O join/VB/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O key/NN/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG Republicans/NNPS/O are/VBP/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O acquiesce/VB/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG colleagues/NNS/O '/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O many/JJ/O pet/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Although/IN/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O encouraged/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG action/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Chairman/NNP/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Rostenkowski/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ill/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Ways/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Means/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O uncertain/JJ/O whether/IN/O a/DT/O clean/JJ/O bill/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O achieved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O upcoming/JJ/O conference/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
Another/DT/O big/JJ/O question/NN/O hovering/VBG/O over/IN/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O is/VBZ/O what/WP/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON thinks/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bentsen/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O hopes/VBZ/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O consider/VB/O that/DT/O measure/NN/O soon/RB/O ././O
Asked/VBN/O why/WRB/O senators/NNS/O were/VBD/O giving/VBG/O up/RP/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Mexico/NNP/I-GPE Sen./NNP/O Pete/NNP/B-PERSON Domenici/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ranking/JJ/O Republican/NNP/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O looking/VBG/O like/IN/O idiots/NNS/O ././O
Things/NNS/O had/VBD/O just/RB/O gone/VBN/O too/RB/O far/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Sen./NNP/O Dole/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O move/NN/O required/VBD/O sacrifice/NN/O by/IN/O every/DT/O senator/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O dropped/VBD/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O Finance/NNP/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O increased/VBN/O the/DT/O income/NN/O threshold/NN/O beyond/IN/O which/WDT/O senior/JJ/O citizens/NNS/O have/VBP/O their/PRP$/O Social/NNP/B-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG benefits/NNS/O reduced/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O drops/VBZ/O a/DT/O provision/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O permitted/VBN/O corporations/NNS/O to/TO/O use/VB/O excess/JJ/O pension/NN/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O health/NN/O benefits/NNS/O for/IN/O current/JJ/O retirees/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O stricken/VBN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O fivefold/JJ/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O maximum/JJ/O Occupational/NNP/B-ORG Safety/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG penalties/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O raised/VBN/O $/$/O 65/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O provision/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O the/DT/B-ORG Social/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG an/DT/O independent/JJ/O agency/NN/O was/VBD/O excised/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O approval/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG bill/NN/O was/VBD/O especially/RB/O sweet/JJ/O for/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O proposed/VBN/O the/DT/O streamlining/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O deficit/NN/O reduction/NN/O bill/NN/O contains/VBZ/O $/$/O 5.3/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O tax/NN/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O $/$/O 26/CD/O billion/CD/O over/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
--/:/O Require/VB/O mutual/JJ/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O include/VB/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O taxable/JJ/O income/NN/O dividends/NNS/O paid/VBN/O to/TO/O them/PRP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O date/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O dividends/NNS/O are/VBP/O declared/VBN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O received/VBN/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O the/DT/O day/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O enacted/VBN/O ././O
--/:/O Close/VB/O a/DT/O loophole/NN/O regarding/VBG/O employee/NN/O stock/NN/O ownership/NN/O plans/NNS/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O June/NNP/O 6/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O exploited/VBN/O by/IN/O investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O in/IN/O corporate/JJ/O takeovers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O repeals/VBZ/O a/DT/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O exclusion/NN/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O banks/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O interest/NN/O from/IN/O loans/NNS/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O securities/NNS/O for/IN/O an/DT/O ESOP/NNP/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O ESOP/NNP/O owns/VBZ/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O employer/NN/O 's/POS/O stock/NN/O ././O
--/:/O Raise/VB/O $/$/O 851/CD/O million/CD/O by/IN/O suspending/VBG/O for/IN/O one/CD/O year/NN/O an/DT/O automatic/JJ/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O airport/NN/O and/CC/O airway/NN/O taxes/NNS/O ././O
--/:/O Speed/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O collection/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O payroll/NN/O tax/NN/O from/IN/O large/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O August/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ././O
--/:/O Withhold/VB/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O paychecks/NNS/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O farm/NN/O workers/NNS/O currently/RB/O exempt/JJ/O from/IN/O withholding/NN/O ././O
--/:/O Change/VB/O the/DT/O collection/NN/O of/IN/O gasoline/NN/O excise/NN/O taxes/NNS/O to/TO/O weekly/RB/O from/IN/O semimonthly/RB/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
--/:/O Restrict/VB/O the/DT/O ability/NN/O of/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O owners/NNS/O to/TO/O escape/VB/O taxes/NNS/O by/IN/O swapping/VBG/O one/CD/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O property/NN/O for/IN/O another/DT/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O selling/VBG/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O cash/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O also/RB/O includes/VBZ/O spending/NN/O cuts/NNS/O and/CC/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O fees/NNS/O ././O
Among/IN/O its/PRP$/O provisions/NNS/O :/:/O
--/:/O Reduction/NNP/O of/IN/O Medicare/NNP/B-ORG spending/NN/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O by/IN/O some/DT/O $/$/O 2.8/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O by/IN/O curbing/VBG/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O reimbursements/NNS/O to/TO/O physicians/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O plan/NN/O would/MD/O impose/VB/O a/DT/O brief/JJ/O freeze/NN/O on/IN/O physician/NN/O fees/NNS/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
--/:/O Removal/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Postal/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG operating/NN/O budget/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O budget/NN/O ,/,/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O deficit/NN/O by/IN/O $/$/O 1.77/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O similar/JJ/O provision/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG version/NN/O ././O
--/:/O Increases/NNS/O in/IN/O Nuclear/NNP/B-ORG Regulatory/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG fees/NNS/O totaling/VBG/O $/$/O 54/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
--/:/O Direction/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Coast/NNP/I-ORG Guard/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O collect/VB/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O users/NNS/O of/IN/O Coast/NNP/B-ORG Guard/NNP/I-ORG services/NNS/O ././O
--/:/O Raising/VBG/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 43/CD/O million/CD/O by/IN/O increasing/VBG/O existing/JJ/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG fees/NNS/O and/CC/O penalties/NNS/O and/CC/O establishing/VBG/O new/JJ/O fees/NNS/O for/IN/O amateur/JJ/O radio/NN/O operators/NNS/O ,/,/O ship/NN/O stations/NNS/O and/CC/O mobile/JJ/O radio/NN/O facilities/NNS/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Yang/NNP/I-PERSON contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
