Time/NNP/B-ORG magazine/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O move/NN/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O of/IN/O wooing/VBG/O new/JJ/O subscribers/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O lowering/VBG/O its/PRP$/O circulation/NN/O guarantee/NN/O to/TO/O advertisers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O consecutive/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O increasing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O subscription/NN/O rates/NNS/O and/CC/O cutting/VBG/O back/RP/O on/IN/O merchandise/NN/O giveaways/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O announcement/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O staff/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O executives/NNS/O at/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG weekly/JJ/O magazine/NN/O said/VBD/O Time/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O ``/``/O dramatically/RB/O de-emphasize/VB/O ''/''/O its/PRP$/O use/NN/O of/IN/O electronic/JJ/O giveaways/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O telephones/NNS/O in/IN/O television/NN/O subscription/NN/O drives/NNS/O ;/:/O cut/VB/O the/DT/O circulation/NN/O it/PRP/O guarantees/VBZ/O advertisers/NNS/O by/IN/O 300,000/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O four/CD/O million/CD/O ;/:/O and/CC/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O annual/JJ/O subscription/NN/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 4/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 55/CD/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O because/IN/O the/DT/O guaranteed/VBN/O circulation/NN/O base/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O lowered/VBN/O ,/,/O ad/NN/O rates/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O effectively/RB/O 7.5/CD/O %/NN/O higher/JJR/O per/IN/O subscriber/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Heinemann/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Time/NNP/B-ORG associate/JJ/O publisher/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Reader/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Digest/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG McCall/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O most/RBS/O recently/RB/O News/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG TV/NNP/B-ORG Guide/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O have/VBP/O cut/VBN/O their/PRP$/O massive/JJ/O circulation/NN/O rate/NN/O bases/NNS/O to/TO/O eliminate/VB/O marginal/JJ/O circulation/NN/O and/CC/O hold/VB/O down/RP/O rates/NNS/O for/IN/O advertisers/NNS/O ././O
Besides/RB/O ,/,/O Time/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O think/VBP/O selling/VBG/O a/DT/O news/NN/O magazine/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O clock/NN/O radio/NN/O is/VBZ/O tacky/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O Giveaways/NNS/O just/RB/O give/VBP/O people/NNS/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O image/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Heinemann/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O perception/NN/O takes/VBZ/O the/DT/O focus/NN/O off/IN/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Time/NNP/B-ORG magazine/NN/O executives/NNS/O predictably/RB/O paint/VBP/O the/DT/O circulation/NN/O cut/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O show/NN/O of/IN/O strength/NN/O and/CC/O actually/RB/O a/DT/O benefit/NN/O to/TO/O advertisers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O doing/VBG/O is/VBZ/O screening/VBG/O out/RP/O the/DT/O readers/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O only/RB/O casually/RB/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O and/CC/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O really/RB/O read/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Heinemann/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O create/VB/O quality/NN/O and/CC/O involvement/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
However/RB/O ,/,/O Time/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O used/VBD/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O explanation/NN/O when/WRB/O in/IN/O October/NNP/O 1988/CD/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O cut/VBD/O its/PRP$/O guaranteed/VBN/O circulation/NN/O from/IN/O 4.6/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O 4.3/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
And/CC/O Time/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O paid/JJ/O circulation/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Audit/NNP/B-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Circulations/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O dropped/VBD/O 7.3/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 4,393,237/CD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ended/VBD/O June/NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Time/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O received/VBN/O well/RB/O ,/,/O once/RB/O again/RB/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O terrific/JJ/O for/IN/O advertisers/NNS/O to/TO/O know/VB/O the/DT/O reader/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O paying/VBG/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Drexler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O national/JJ/O media/NNS/O director/NN/O at/IN/O Bozell/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ad/NN/O agency/NN/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O few/JJ/O drops/NNS/O in/IN/O circulation/NN/O are/VBP/O of/IN/O no/DT/O consequence/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O show/NN/O of/IN/O weakness/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O improving/VBG/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O circulation/NN/O while/IN/O insuring/VBG/O their/PRP$/O profits/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Heinemann/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O represent/VBP/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O focus/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O industry/NN/O :/:/O a/DT/O magazine/NN/O 's/POS/O net/JJ/O revenue/NN/O per/IN/O subscriber/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O the/DT/O actual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O subscribers/NNS/O after/IN/O discounts/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O premiums/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O stripped/VBN/O away/RP/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O are/VBP/O we/PRP/O getting/VBG/O from/IN/O each/DT/O reader/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Heinemann/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Both/DT/O magazines/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O announce/VB/O their/PRP$/O ad/NN/O rates/NNS/O and/CC/O circulation/NN/O levels/NNS/O for/IN/O 1990/CD/O within/IN/O a/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
