When/WRB/O Justice/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Brennan/NNP/I-PERSON marks/VBZ/O the/DT/O start/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O 34th/JJ/O year/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG today/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O occasion/NN/O will/MD/O differ/VB/O sharply/RB/O from/IN/O previous/JJ/O anniversaries/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O tenure/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O role/NN/O reversal/NN/O holds/VBZ/O true/JJ/O ,/,/O as/IN/O well/RB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O three/CD/O liberal/JJ/O and/CC/O moderate/JJ/O allies/NNS/O ,/,/O Justices/NNP/O Thurgood/NNP/B-PERSON Marshall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON Blackmun/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Stevens/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O are/VBP/O these/DT/O four/CD/O players/NNS/O ,/,/O three/CD/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O 80s/NNS/O ,/,/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O assume/VB/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O role/NN/O after/IN/O 88/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O collectively/RB/O ,/,/O of/IN/O service/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O court/NN/O ?/./O
Every/DT/O indication/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O four/CD/O are/VBP/O prepared/JJ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O this/DT/O new/JJ/O role/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O frustrations/NNS/O that/WDT/O go/VBP/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O in/IN/O different/JJ/O ways/NNS/O ././O
Justices/NNPS/O Brennan/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Stevens/NNP/B-PERSON appear/VBP/O philosophical/JJ/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ;/:/O Justices/NNPS/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Blackmun/NNP/B-PERSON appear/VBP/O fighting/NN/O mad/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O four/CD/O justices/NNS/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O newcomers/NNS/O to/TO/O dissent/NN/O ,/,/O often/RB/O joining/VBG/O forces/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O decade/NN/O to/TO/O criticize/VB/O the/DT/O court/NN/O 's/POS/O conservative/JJ/O drift/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O always/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O years/NNS/O past/JJ/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O bucked/VBN/O the/DT/O trend/NN/O and/CC/O have/VBP/O been/VBP/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O pick/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O fifth/JJ/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O eke/VB/O out/RP/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O major/JJ/O victories/NNS/O in/IN/O civil/JJ/O rights/NNS/O and/CC/O liberties/NNS/O cases/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O change/NN/O is/VBZ/O most/RBS/O dramatic/JJ/O for/IN/O Justice/NNP/O Brennan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O survivor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1960s/NNS/O liberal/JJ/O majority/NN/O under/IN/O Chief/NNP/O Justice/NNP/O Earl/NNP/B-PERSON Warren/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O seven/CD/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG terms/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O fall/NN/O of/IN/O 1962/CD/O through/IN/O the/DT/O spring/NN/O of/IN/O 1967/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O height/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON Court/NNP/O 's/POS/O power/NN/O ,/,/O Justice/NNP/O Brennan/NNP/B-PERSON cast/VBD/O only/RB/O 25/CD/O dissenting/JJ/O votes/NNS/O in/IN/O 555/CD/O cases/NNS/O decided/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Justice/NNP/O Brennan/NNP/B-PERSON foresaw/VBD/O his/PRP$/O new/JJ/O role/NN/O ,/,/O strongly/RB/O defending/VBG/O the/DT/O importance/NN/O of/IN/O dissents/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O 1985/CD/O speech/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Each/DT/O time/NN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O revisits/VBZ/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O justices/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O dissent/NN/O to/TO/O reconsider/VB/O the/DT/O fundamental/JJ/O questions/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O rethink/VB/O the/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O winning/VBG/O side/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1960s/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O knew/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O tables/NNS/O might/MD/O turn/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O now/RB/O knows/VBZ/O how/WRB/O Justice/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Harlan/NNP/I-PERSON felt/VBD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O reference/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O conservative/JJ/O justice/NN/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O frequent/JJ/O dissenter/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON Court/NNP/O 's/POS/O opinions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O could/MD/O sweep/VB/O it/PRP/O under/IN/O the/DT/O rug/NN/O and/CC/O hide/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O speech/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Justice/NNP/O Brennan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O considers/VBZ/O dissents/NNS/O highly/RB/O important/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O point/NN/O that/DT/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O escaped/VBN/O legal/JJ/O scholars/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Brennan/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O speaking/VBG/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O dissents/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O distant/JJ/O future/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Justice/NNP/O Blackmun/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O turn/VB/O 81/CD/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O seems/VBZ/O feisty/JJ/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O new/JJ/O role/NN/O ././O
Associates/NNS/O say/VBP/O he/PRP/O takes/VBZ/O some/DT/O defeats/NNS/O more/RBR/O personally/RB/O than/IN/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O attempts/NNS/O to/TO/O curtail/VB/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O first/RB/O recognized/VBN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O 1973/CD/O opinion/NN/O ,/,/O Roe/NNP/B-PERSON vs./IN/O Wade/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Friends/NNS/O and/CC/O associates/NNS/O who/WP/O saw/VBD/O Justice/NNP/O Blackmun/NNP/B-PERSON during/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O no/DT/O more/RBR/O discouraged/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O than/IN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O his/PRP$/O outlook/NN/O improved/VBD/O after/IN/O successful/JJ/O cataract/NN/O surgery/NN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O his/PRP$/O level/NN/O of/IN/O frustration/NN/O showed/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O ,/,/O impassioned/JJ/O speech/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O lawyers/NNS/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O concluded/VBD/O his/PRP$/O remarks/NNS/O by/IN/O quoting/VBG/O ,/,/O emotionally/RB/O and/CC/O at/IN/O some/DT/O length/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O those/DT/O present/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Luther/NNP/I-PERSON King/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O famous/JJ/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O Have/VBP/O a/DT/O Dream/NN/O ''/''/O speech/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O 1963/CD/O March/NNP/O on/IN/O Washington/NNP/O ././O
Justice/NNP/O Stevens/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 69/CD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O probably/RB/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O philosophical/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O dissenters/NNS/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O role/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O least/JJS/O liberal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O four/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O also/RB/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O enjoys/VBZ/O the/DT/O intellectual/JJ/O challenge/NN/O of/IN/O arguing/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O majority/NN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O others/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O role/NN/O these/DT/O four/CD/O dissenters/NNS/O are/VBP/O assuming/VBG/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O familiar/JJ/O one/CD/O in/IN/O modern/JJ/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG history/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O differs/VBZ/O in/IN/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O way/NN/O from/IN/O recent/JJ/O history/NN/O ,/,/O court/NN/O watchers/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O dissenters/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON Court/NNP/O were/VBD/O often/RB/O defending/VBG/O a/DT/O legal/JJ/O legacy/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O inherited/VBD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Prof./NNP/O A.E./NNP/B-PERSON Dick/NNP/I-PERSON Howard/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Virginia/NNP/I-ORG Law/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O the/DT/O dissenters/NNS/O today/NN/O are/VBP/O defending/VBG/O a/DT/O legacy/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O created/VBD/O ././O
