Financial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG purchased/VBD/O the/DT/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O alleged/VBD/O ,/,/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Boesky/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG negotiated/VBD/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O for/IN/O Vagabond/NNP/B-ORG Hotels/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O purchase/VB/O a/DT/O 51/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O for/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 34/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Vagabond/NNP/B-ORG Hotels/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Boesky/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O currently/RB/O is/VBZ/O serving/VBG/O a/DT/O prison/NN/O term/NN/O for/IN/O securities/NNS/O violations/NNS/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O at/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O seen/VBN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O thus/RB/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 33/CD/O million/CD/O compensatory/JJ/O damages/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O seeks/VBZ/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O punitive/JJ/O damages/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O named/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O is/VBZ/O Ivan/NNP/B-ORG F./NNP/I-ORG Boesky/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Northview/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O successor/NN/O company/NN/O to/TO/O Vagabonds/NNP/B-ORG Hotels/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Northview/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O located/VBN/O ././O
Financial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O the/DT/O bonds/NNS/O after/IN/O a/DT/O representative/NN/O of/IN/O Ivan/NNP/B-ORG F./NNP/I-ORG Boesky/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG visited/VBD/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O November/NNP/O 1983/CD/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O Financial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG could/MD/O improve/VB/O its/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O by/IN/O purchasing/VBG/O the/DT/O bonds/NNS/O ././O
Shortly/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O visit/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Boesky/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG representives/NNS/O had/VBD/O met/VBN/O with/IN/O Financial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O signed/VBN/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O of/IN/O intent/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O 51/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O was/VBD/O canceled/VBN/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O 1984/CD/O ././O
Financial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG purchased/VBD/O the/DT/O bonds/NNS/O in/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 70/CD/O different/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O in/IN/O 1984/CD/O and/CC/O since/IN/O then/RB/O has/VBZ/O realized/VBN/O $/$/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O losses/NNS/O on/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
