Interprovincial/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O oil/NN/O pipeline/NN/O operator/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O transporter/NN/O of/IN/O crude/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O revised/VBN/O industry/NN/O forecasts/NNS/O indicate/VBP/O that/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O oil/NN/O output/NN/O will/MD/O total/VB/O about/RB/O 1.64/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O by/IN/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O lower/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O previous/JJ/O estimate/NN/O ././O
Canadian/JJ/O crude/NN/O production/NN/O averaged/VBD/O about/RB/O 1.69/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O during/IN/O 1989/CD/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O ,/,/O about/RB/O 1/CD/O %/NN/O below/IN/O the/DT/O 1988/CD/O level/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Watkins/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O volume/NN/O on/IN/O Interprovincial/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O system/NN/O is/VBZ/O down/RB/O about/RB/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O since/IN/O January/NNP/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O further/RBR/O ,/,/O making/VBG/O expansion/NN/O unnecessary/JJ/O until/IN/O perhaps/RB/O the/DT/O mid-1990s/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O producers/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O outlook/NN/O for/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O is/VBZ/O better/JJR/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O for/IN/O oil/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O have/VBP/O shifted/VBN/O their/PRP$/O exploration/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O budgets/NNS/O accordingly/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O active/JJ/O drilling/NN/O rigs/NNS/O in/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O down/RB/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O completed/VBN/O oil/NN/O wells/NNS/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O down/RB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O increasing/VBG/O focus/NN/O on/IN/O gas/NN/O exploration/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Feick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O crude/JJ/O oil/NN/O with/IN/O Calgary/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Independent/NNP/I-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O group/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Watkins/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O production/NN/O decline/NN/O is/VBZ/O shrinking/VBG/O output/NN/O of/IN/O light/JJ/O crude/NN/O from/IN/O mature/JJ/O ,/,/O conventional/JJ/O fields/NNS/O in/IN/O western/JJ/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Interprovincial/NNP/B-ORG transports/VBZ/O about/RB/O 75/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O crude/NN/O produced/VBN/O in/IN/O western/JJ/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O almost/RB/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Interprovincial/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O total/JJ/O volume/NN/O consists/VBZ/O of/IN/O light/JJ/O crude/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lichtblau/NNP/B-PERSON stressed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O delay/NN/O of/IN/O Interprovincial/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O proposed/VBN/O expansion/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O by/IN/O itself/PRP/O increase/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE dependence/NN/O on/IN/O offshore/JJ/O crude/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O since/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O imports/NNS/O are/VBP/O limited/VBN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O by/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O falling/VBG/O output/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O system/NN/O currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O capacity/NN/O of/IN/O 1.55/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
