SOUTH/NNP/B-GPE AFRICA/NNP/I-GPE FREED/VBD/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O seven/CD/O other/JJ/O political/JJ/O prisoners/NNS/O ././O
Thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O supporters/NNS/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O brandishing/VBG/O flags/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O outlawed/VBN/O African/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O gave/VBD/O the/DT/O anti-apartheid/JJ/O activists/NNS/O a/DT/O tumultuous/JJ/O reception/NN/O upon/IN/O their/PRP$/O return/NN/O to/TO/O black/JJ/O townships/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O releases/NNS/O ,/,/O announced/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O by/IN/O President/NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON Klerk/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O were/VBD/O viewed/VBN/O as/IN/O Pretoria/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O tacit/JJ/O legalization/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mandela/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O considered/VBN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O prominent/JJ/O leader/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O remains/VBZ/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE reported/VBD/O that/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O tons/NNS/O of/IN/O goods/NNS/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O widespread/JJ/O shortages/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O were/VBD/O piled/VBN/O up/RP/O at/IN/O ports/NNS/O and/CC/O rail/NN/O depots/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O food/NN/O shipments/NNS/O were/VBD/O rotting/VBG/O because/RB/O of/IN/O a/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O and/CC/O equipment/NN/O to/TO/O move/VB/O the/DT/O cargo/NN/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON indicated/VBD/O there/EX/O might/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O room/NN/O for/IN/O flexibility/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O of/IN/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O poor/JJ/O women/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O vicitims/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O reiterated/VBD/O his/PRP$/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O such/JJ/O funding/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O expressed/VBD/O hope/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O president/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O a/DT/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O also/RB/O renewed/VBD/O a/DT/O call/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O ouster/NN/O of/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O minors/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O without/IN/O the/DT/O consent/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O parents/NNS/O ././O
Ten/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O governors/NNS/O ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O called/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O justices/NNS/O to/TO/O reject/VB/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O limit/VB/O abortions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O FBI/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O authority/NN/O to/TO/O seize/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE fugitives/NNS/O overseas/RB/O without/IN/O the/DT/O permission/NN/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O governments/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O device/NN/O was/VBD/O replaced/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O spacecraft/NN/O 's/POS/O five/CD/O astronauts/NNS/O are/VBP/O to/TO/O dispatch/VB/O the/DT/O Galileo/NNP/O space/NN/O probe/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O exploration/NN/O mission/NN/O to/TO/O Jupiter/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Roh/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O facing/VBG/O calls/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O reduction/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE military/JJ/O forces/NNS/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O with/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON tomorrow/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O address/VB/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O session/NN/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Communist/JJ/O leadership/NN/O voted/VBD/O to/TO/O purge/VB/O the/DT/O party/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O hostile/JJ/O and/CC/O anti-party/JJ/O elements/NNS/O ''/''/O and/CC/O wealthy/JJ/O private/JJ/O businessmen/NNS/O ,/,/O whom/WP/O they/PRP/O called/VBD/O exploiters/NNS/O ././O
Hundreds/NNP/O of/IN/O East/NNP/O Germans/NNPS/O flocked/VBD/O to/TO/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Embassy/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O bringing/VBG/O to/TO/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 1,200/CD/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O emigres/NNS/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O flee/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O beginning/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
Zaire/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O President/NNP/O Mobutu/NNP/B-PERSON met/VBD/O in/IN/O southern/JJ/O France/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O Angolan/JJ/O rebel/NN/O leader/NN/O Savimbi/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O senior/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE envoy/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O revive/VB/O an/DT/O accord/NN/O to/TO/O end/VB/O Angola/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O civil/JJ/O war/NN/O ././O
Details/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ,/,/O described/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O Zairean/JJ/O official/NN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O very/RB/O delicate/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
He/PRP/O made/VBD/O his/PRP$/O remarks/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG gathering/NN/O in/IN/O Baghdad/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Lebanese/JJ/O Christian/JJ/O lawmakers/NNS/O presented/VBN/O to/TO/O Arab/NNP/O mediators/NNS/O at/IN/O talks/NNS/O in/IN/O Saudi/NNP/B-GPE Arabia/NNP/I-GPE proposals/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O timetable/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O withdrawal/NN/O of/IN/O Syria/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O forces/NNS/O from/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE ././O
A/DT/O plan/NN/O currently/RB/O under/IN/O study/NN/O gives/VBZ/O Damascus/NNP/B-GPE two/CD/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O pull/VB/O back/RB/O to/TO/O eastern/JJ/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O starting/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O Beirut/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O legislature/NN/O increases/VBZ/O political/JJ/O power/NN/O for/IN/O Moslems/NNPS/O ././O
