Of/IN/O all/DT/O the/DT/O ethnic/JJ/O tensions/NNS/O in/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O troublesome/JJ/O right/RB/O now/RB/O ?/./O
A/DT/O good/JJ/O bet/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O tension/NN/O between/IN/O blacks/NNPS/O and/CC/O Jews/NNPS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O is/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON the/DT/O star/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Chicken/NNP/O Soup/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O also/RB/O the/DT/O inheritor/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O comedic/JJ/O tradition/NN/O dating/VBG/O back/RB/O to/TO/O ``/``/O Duck/NNP/O Soup/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O currently/RB/O a/DT/O man/NN/O in/IN/O hot/JJ/O water/NN/O ././O
Here/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O neutral/JJ/O language/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O gist/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remarks/NNS/O ,/,/O quoted/VBN/O first/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Village/NNP/I-ORG Voice/NNP/I-ORG while/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O paid/JJ/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Rudolph/NNP/B-PERSON Giuliani/NNP/I-PERSON mayoral/JJ/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O then/RB/O in/IN/O Newsweek/NNP/B-ORG after/IN/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O parted/VBD/O company/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O many/JJ/O Jewish/JJ/O voters/NNS/O feel/VBP/O guilty/JJ/O toward/IN/O blacks/NNS/O ,/,/O so/IN/O they/PRP/O support/VBP/O black/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O uncritically/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O many/JJ/O black/JJ/O voters/NNS/O feel/VBP/O bitter/JJ/O about/IN/O racial/JJ/O discrimination/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O they/PRP/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O support/VBP/O black/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O uncritically/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Jews/NNPS/O have/VBP/O contributed/VBN/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O black/JJ/O causes/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O than/IN/O vice/FW/O versa/FW/O ././O
Of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O not/RB/O use/VB/O neutral/JJ/O language/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O practitioner/NN/O of/IN/O ethnic/JJ/O humor/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O days/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Borscht/NNP/I-LOC Belt/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O live/JJ/O television/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O nightclub/NN/O circuit/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON instinctively/RB/O reached/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O vernacular/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Jews/NNPS/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O sick/JJ/O with/IN/O complexes/NNS/O ''/''/O ;/:/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O called/VBD/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Dinkins/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Giuliani/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O black/JJ/O opponent/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O a/DT/O fancy/JJ/O shvartze/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O mustache/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O used/VBN/O less/RBR/O derogatory/JJ/O language/NN/O to/TO/O articulate/VB/O his/PRP$/O amateur/JJ/O analysis/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O voting/NN/O behavior/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O fellow/NN/O New/NNP/O Yorkers/NNP/O ,/,/O would/MD/O the/DT/O water/NN/O be/VB/O quite/RB/O so/RB/O hot/JJ/O ?/./O
It/PRP/O probably/RB/O would/MD/O ,/,/O because/IN/O few/JJ/O or/CC/O none/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O upset/JJ/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remarks/NNS/O have/VBP/O bothered/VBN/O to/TO/O distinguish/VB/O between/IN/O the/DT/O substance/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O comments/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O used/VBD/O insulting/JJ/O language/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O critics/NNS/O have/VBP/O implied/VBN/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O type/NN/O of/IN/O ethnic/JJ/O humor/NN/O is/VBZ/O itself/PRP/O a/DT/O form/NN/O of/IN/O racism/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE state/NN/O counsel/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O NAACP/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O ``/``/O like/IN/O a/DT/O dinosaur/NN/O ././O
People/NNS/O are/VBP/O fast/RB/O leaving/VBG/O the/DT/O place/NN/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O stuck/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O latter/JJ/O typically/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O humor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O underdog/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O perfected/VBN/O by/IN/O both/DT/O blacks/NNPS/O and/CC/O Jews/NNPS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O minstrel/NN/O and/CC/O vaudeville/NN/O stage/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O means/NN/O of/IN/O mocking/VBG/O their/PRP$/O white/JJ/O and/CC/O gentile/JJ/O audiences/NNS/O along/IN/O with/IN/O themselves/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O wielded/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O pro/NN/O like/IN/O Jackie/NNP/B-PERSON Mason/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O constructive/JJ/O form/NN/O of/IN/O mischief/NN/O ././O
Why/WRB/O constructive/JJ/O ?/./O
Because/IN/O despite/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O prattle/NN/O about/IN/O comedy/NN/O and/CC/O politics/NNS/O not/RB/O mixing/VBG/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O similar/JJ/O in/IN/O one/CD/O respect/NN/O :/:/O Both/DT/O can/MD/O serve/VB/O as/IN/O mechanisms/NNS/O for/IN/O easing/VBG/O tensions/NNS/O and/CC/O facilitating/VBG/O the/DT/O co-existence/NN/O of/IN/O groups/NNS/O in/IN/O conflict/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON Kristol/NNP/I-PERSON wrote/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG just/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON donnybrook/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Perhaps/RB/O intolerance/NN/O would/MD/O not/RB/O boil/VB/O over/RP/O with/IN/O such/JJ/O intensity/NN/O if/IN/O honest/JJ/O differences/NNS/O were/VBD/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O simmer/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O group/NN/O conflicts/NNS/O still/RB/O exist/VBP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O as/IN/O undeniably/RB/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O if/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O type/NN/O of/IN/O ethnic/JJ/O humor/NN/O is/VBZ/O passe/JJ/O ,/,/O then/RB/O what/WP/O other/JJ/O means/NNS/O do/VBP/O we/PRP/O have/VB/O for/IN/O letting/VBG/O off/RP/O steam/NN/O ?/./O
Do/VB/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O the/DT/O TV/NN/O sitcom/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O that/DT/O happens/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O genre/NN/O that/IN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O desperate/JJ/O need/NN/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O everybody/NN/O and/CC/O offend/VB/O nobody/NN/O ,/,/O resembles/VBZ/O politics/NNS/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O comedy/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O these/DT/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O the/DT/O differences/NNS/O that/WDT/O make/VBP/O headlines/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O ``/``/O Chicken/NNP/O Soup/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON plays/VBZ/O Jackie/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Jewish/JJ/O bachelor/NN/O courting/VBG/O Maddie/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/B-PERSON Lynn/NNP/I-PERSON Redgrave/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O Irish/JJ/O widow/NN/O and/CC/O mother/NN/O of/IN/O three/CD/O ,/,/O against/IN/O the/DT/O wishes/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O mother/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Rita/NNP/B-PERSON Karin/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O her/PRP$/O brother/NN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Brandon/NNP/B-PERSON Maggart/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/POS/O worth/JJ/O noting/VBG/O that/IN/O both/DT/O disapproving/JJ/O relatives/NNS/O are/VBP/O immigrants/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O both/DT/O speak/VBP/O with/IN/O strong/JJ/O accents/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O do/VBP/O Jackie/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Maddie/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
It/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O obvious/JJ/O that/IN/O ``/``/O Chicken/NNP/O Soup/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O made/VBN/O from/IN/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O recipe/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O a/DT/O safe/JJ/O one/CD/O --/:/O imagine/VB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O romance/NN/O in/IN/O question/NN/O were/VBD/O between/IN/O an/DT/O Orthodox/NNP/O Jew/NNP/O and/CC/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Nation/NNP/O of/IN/O Islam/NNP/O ././O
Back/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1920s/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O play/NN/O and/CC/O movie/NN/O versions/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Abie/NNP/O 's/POS/O Irish/NNP/O Rose/NNP/O ''/''/O made/VBD/O the/DT/O theme/NN/O of/IN/O courtship/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O assimilated/JJ/O offspring/NN/O of/IN/O Jewish/JJ/O and/CC/O Irish/JJ/O immigrants/NNS/O so/RB/O popular/JJ/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O author/NN/O ,/,/O Anne/NNP/B-PERSON Nichols/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O lost/VBD/O a/DT/O plagiarism/NN/O suit/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O grounds/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O plot/NN/O has/VBZ/O entered/VBN/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O domain/NN/O ././O
Clearly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O question/NN/O with/IN/O ``/``/O Chicken/NNP/O Soup/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O pot/NN/O will/MD/O boil/VB/O over/RP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O whether/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O simmer/VB/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
So/IN/O far/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O bubbles/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O few/JJ/O and/CC/O far/RB/O between/RB/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O tendency/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O sitcoms/NNS/O ,/,/O ever/RB/O since/IN/O the/DT/O didactic/JJ/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O Norman/NNP/B-PERSON Lear/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O to/TO/O preach/VB/O about/IN/O social/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
To/TO/O some/DT/O extent/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O tendency/NN/O emerges/VBZ/O whenever/WRB/O the/DT/O show/NN/O tries/VBZ/O to/TO/O enlighten/VB/O us/PRP/O about/IN/O ethnic/JJ/O stereotypes/NNS/O by/IN/O reversing/VBG/O them/PRP/O ././O
Even/RB/O more/RBR/O problematic/JJ/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O incompatibility/NN/O between/IN/O sitcom/NN/O preachiness/NN/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O comic/JJ/O persona/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O too/RB/O often/RB/O ,/,/O these/DT/O routines/NNS/O lack/VBP/O spark/NN/O because/IN/O this/DT/O sitcom/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O all/DT/O sitcoms/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O timid/JJ/O about/IN/O confronting/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O trade/NN/O -/:/O ethnic/JJ/O differences/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O racial/JJ/O tensions/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O cool/VB/O down/RP/O ,/,/O not/RB/O heat/VB/O up/RP/O ,/,/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O simmer/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O suggesting/VBG/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O stop/VB/O requiring/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O interrupt/VB/O his/PRP$/O classic/JJ/O shtik/NN/O with/IN/O some/DT/O line/NN/O about/IN/O ``/``/O caring/VBG/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O people/NNS/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O sound/VB/O shmaltzy/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O lips/NNS/O of/IN/O Miss/NNP/B-PERSON America/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
At/IN/O your/PRP$/O age/NN/O ,/,/O Jackie/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O you/PRP/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O know/VB/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O soup/NN/O without/IN/O turning/VBG/O up/RP/O the/DT/O flame/NN/O ././O
