When/WRB/O the/DT/O news/NN/O broke/VBD/O of/IN/O an/DT/O attempted/JJ/O coup/NN/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Dodd/NNP/I-PERSON called/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O a/DT/O briefing/NN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O `/``/O follow/VB/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O '/''/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O shows/VBZ/O how/WRB/O far/RB/O Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Turner/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Cable/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Network/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O come/VBN/O since/IN/O its/PRP$/O birth/NN/O nine/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O considered/VBN/O the/DT/O laughingstock/NN/O of/IN/O television/NN/O news/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O bigger/JJR/O ,/,/O faster/JJR/O and/CC/O more/RBR/O profitable/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O news/NN/O divisions/NNS/O of/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O major/JJ/O broadcast/NN/O networks/NNS/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O niche/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O network/NN/O of/IN/O record/NN/O ''/''/O during/IN/O major/JJ/O crises/NNS/O draws/VBZ/O elite/JJ/O audiences/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O for/IN/O all/PDT/O its/PRP$/O success/NN/O ,/,/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O hit/VBN/O a/DT/O plateau/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O viewership/NN/O soars/NNS/O when/WRB/O big/JJ/O news/NN/O breaks/VBZ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O ebbs/VBZ/O during/IN/O periods/NNS/O of/IN/O calm/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Just/RB/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O on/IN/O 24/CD/O hours/NNS/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O longer/RBR/O bulletin/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Ed/NNP/B-PERSON Turner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O news/NN/O gathering/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O no/DT/O relation/NN/O to/TO/O Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Turner/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O live/VB/O on/IN/O that/DT/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O paying/VBG/O higher/JJR/O salaries/NNS/O --/:/O after/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O scrimping/VBG/O --/:/O to/TO/O lure/VB/O and/CC/O keep/VB/O experienced/JJ/O staffers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O next/JJ/O stage/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O opinion/NN/O leaders/NNS/O who/WP/O use/VBP/O us/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O point/NN/O of/IN/O reference/NN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O a/DT/O point/NN/O of/IN/O reference/NN/O at/IN/O ordinary/JJ/O dinner/NN/O tables/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Jon/NNP/B-PERSON Petrovich/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Headline/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sister/NN/O network/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O easy/JJ/O ././O
Networks/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O other/JJ/O consumer/NN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O develop/VBP/O images/NNS/O in/IN/O peoples/NNS/O '/POS/O minds/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O easy/JJ/O to/TO/O change/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O takes/VBZ/O money/NN/O that/IN/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O programs/NNS/O and/CC/O hire/VB/O talent/NN/O that/IN/O viewers/NNS/O will/MD/O tune/VB/O in/RP/O specially/RB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O ././O
Already/RB/O ,/,/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O facing/VBG/O stronger/JJR/O competition/NN/O from/IN/O Financial/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Network/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Consumer/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Business/NNP/B-ORG Channel/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O both/DT/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O more/JJR/O general/JJ/O news/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O ././O
CNN/NNP/B-ORG wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O change/VB/O its/PRP$/O viewers/NNS/O '/POS/O habits/NNS/O ././O
CNN/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O viewer/NN/O habits/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O molded/VBN/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O format/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O strategy/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O TV/NN/O wire/NN/O service/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O focused/VBD/O on/IN/O building/NN/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O news/NN/O bureaus/NN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ,/,/O so/RB/O as/IN/O events/NNS/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O go/VB/O live/JJ/O quicker/RBR/O and/CC/O longer/RBR/O than/IN/O other/JJ/O networks/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O filled/VBD/O its/PRP$/O daily/JJ/O schedule/NN/O with/IN/O newscasts/NNS/O called/VBN/O ``/``/O Daybreak/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O ``/``/O Daywatch/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O ``/``/O Newsday/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Newsnight/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O the/DT/O shows/NNS/O varied/VBD/O little/JJ/O in/IN/O content/NN/O ,/,/O personality/NN/O or/CC/O look/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O goal/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O create/VB/O more/JJR/O programs/NNS/O with/IN/O an/DT/O individual/JJ/O identity/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Amos/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O programming/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O exploring/VBG/O other/JJ/O original/JJ/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O similar/JJ/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O ``/``/O Larry/NNP/O King/NNP/O Live/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Crossfire/NNP/O ''/''/O talk/NN/O shows/VBZ/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O executives/NNS/O hope/VBP/O will/MD/O keep/VB/O people/NNS/O tuned/VBN/O in/RP/O ././O
Until/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O featured/VBN/O its/PRP$/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE gossip/NN/O show/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O evening/NN/O period/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O are/VBP/O skeptical/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O evening/NN/O news/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O slated/VBN/O as/IN/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O stage/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O big/JJ/O push/NN/O into/IN/O investigative/JJ/O journalism/NN/O ././O
CNN/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O hope/VBP/O the/DT/O headlines/NNS/O created/VBN/O by/IN/O such/JJ/O scoops/NNS/O will/MD/O generate/VB/O excitement/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O ``/``/O branded/JJ/O ''/''/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O ``/``/O 60/NNP/O Minutes/NNP/O ''/''/O did/VBD/O so/RB/O well/RB/O for/IN/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG ././O
CNN/NNP/B-ORG recently/RB/O gave/VBD/O most/JJS/O employees/NNS/O raises/NNS/O of/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O still/RB/O drastically/RB/O underpaid/JJ/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Mosettig/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O my/PRP$/O wire/NN/O service/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O on/IN/O top/NN/O of/IN/O everything/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O really/RB/O got/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O people/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
