The/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O retailer/NN/O ASKO/NNP/B-ORG Deutsche/NNP/I-ORG Kaufhaus/NNP/I-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O challenge/VB/O the/DT/O legality/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O widely/RB/O employed/VBN/O anti-takeover/JJ/O defense/NN/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNPS/B-GPE ././O
Up/IN/O to/TO/O now/RB/O only/JJ/O specific/JJ/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O these/DT/O defenses/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O challenged/VBN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O unsuccessfully/RB/O ,/,/O ASKO/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Dutch/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O noted/VBD/O ././O
Speaking/VBG/O through/IN/O its/PRP$/O Dutch/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O ,/,/O ASKO/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O disclosed/VBD/O it/PRP/O holds/VBZ/O a/DT/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Ahold/NNP/B-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O previously/RB/O thought/VBN/O ASKO/NNP/B-ORG held/VBD/O a/DT/O 13.6/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O accumulated/VBN/O since/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
He/PRP/O termed/VBD/O ASKO/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O legal/JJ/O actions/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O unproductive/JJ/O ''/''/O to/TO/O international/JJ/O cooperation/NN/O among/IN/O European/JJ/O retailers/NNS/O ././O
