Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Upsala/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Sweden/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O charged/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O against/IN/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG that/IN/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O AMVISC/NNP/O product/NN/O line/NN/O infringes/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG patent/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O products/NNS/O contribute/VBP/O about/RB/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O of/IN/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
MedChem/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O scheduled/VBD/O a/DT/O conference/NN/O for/IN/O next/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O --/:/O to/TO/O set/VB/O a/DT/O date/NN/O for/IN/O proceedings/NNS/O on/IN/O Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O motion/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O preliminary/JJ/O injunction/NN/O ././O
