MedChem/NNP/B-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG District/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O challenge/NN/O by/IN/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O the/DT/O validity/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE patent/NN/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O ``/``/O without/IN/O merit/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Upsala/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Sweden/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O charged/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O against/IN/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG that/IN/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O AMVISC/NNP/O product/NN/O line/NN/O infringes/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG patent/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O its/PRP$/O lawsuit/NN/O ,/,/O Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O unspecified/JJ/O damages/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O preliminary/JJ/O injunction/NN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG from/IN/O selling/VBG/O the/DT/O AMVISC/NNP/O products/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O products/NNS/O contribute/VBP/O about/RB/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O of/IN/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBN/O Aug./NNP/O 31/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O MedChem/NNP/B-ORG earned/VBD/O $/$/O 2.9/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 72/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O ,/,/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 17.4/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O ``/``/O all/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O options/NNS/O in/IN/O light/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O appeal/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
MedChem/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O scheduled/VBD/O a/DT/O conference/NN/O for/IN/O next/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O --/:/O to/TO/O set/VB/O a/DT/O date/NN/O for/IN/O proceedings/NNS/O on/IN/O Pharmacia/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O motion/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O preliminary/JJ/O injunction/NN/O ././O
