Diamond/NNP/B-ORG Shamrock/NNP/I-ORG Offshore/NNP/I-ORG Partners/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O discovered/VBN/O gas/NN/O offshore/RB/O Louisiana/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Diamond/NNP/B-ORG Shamrock/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O operator/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O 100/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O well/NN/O ././O
Diamond/NNP/B-ORG Shamrock/NNP/I-ORG Offshore/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG stock/NN/O rose/VBD/O 12.5/CD/O cents/NNS/O Friday/NNP/O to/TO/O close/VB/O at/IN/O $/$/O 8.25/CD/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG composite/JJ/O trading/NN/O ././O
