After/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O talks/NNS/O ,/,/O plans/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O are/VBP/O sufficiently/RB/O advanced/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O French/JJ/O and/CC/O British/JJ/O government/NN/O clearance/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O venture/NN/O would/MD/O strengthen/VB/O the/DT/O rapidly/RB/O growing/VBG/O ties/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O help/VB/O make/VB/O them/PRP/O a/DT/O leading/JJ/O force/NN/O in/IN/O European/JJ/O defense/NN/O contracting/NN/O ././O
Just/RB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O they/PRP/O announced/VBD/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O make/VB/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Ferranti/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Signal/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O smaller/JJR/O British/JJ/O defense/NN/O contractor/NN/O rocked/VBN/O by/IN/O alleged/JJ/O accounting/NN/O fraud/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O weeks/NNS/O before/IN/O GEC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O potential/JJ/O partners/NNS/O decide/VBP/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O bid/VB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O source/NN/O indicated/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O consortium/NN/O bid/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O would/MD/O diminish/VB/O GEC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O direct/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O Ferranti/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O might/MD/O consequently/RB/O appease/VB/O ministry/NN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O British/NNP/B-ORG Aerospace/NNP/I-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O appeared/VBD/O unperturbed/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O fight/NN/O with/IN/O GEC/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O Ferranti/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O Competition/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O name/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O game/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
At/IN/O least/JJS/O one/CD/O potential/JJ/O GEC/NNP/B-ORG partner/NN/O ,/,/O Matra/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O insists/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O Ferranti/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O nothing/NN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O about/IN/O this/DT/O affair/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O concern/VB/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Matra/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O said/VBD/O Sunday/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O missile/NN/O venture/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O British/NNP/B-ORG Aerospace/NNP/I-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O needed/JJ/O response/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O ``/``/O new/JJ/O environment/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O defense/NN/O contracting/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O venture/NN/O 's/POS/O importance/NN/O for/IN/O Thomson/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O great/JJ/O ././O
Thomson/NNP/B-ORG feels/VBZ/O the/DT/O future/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O defense/NN/O business/NN/O depends/VBZ/O on/IN/O building/VBG/O cooperation/NN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O Europeans/NNPS/O ././O
In/IN/O missiles/NNS/O ,/,/O Thomson/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O already/RB/O overshadowed/VBN/O by/IN/O British/NNP/B-ORG Aerospace/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O home/NN/O rival/NN/O ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Aerospatiale/NNP/B-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ;/:/O to/TO/O better/RBR/O compete/VB/O ,/,/O Thomson/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O need/VBP/O a/DT/O partnership/NN/O ././O
Annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O British/NNP/B-ORG Aerospace/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG missile/NN/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O about/RB/O #/#/O 950/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Thomson/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
