James/NNP/B-PERSON Robinson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 57/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O elected/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O magnetic/JJ/O recording/NN/O heads/NNS/O for/IN/O disk/NN/O drives/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Amperex/NNP/B-ORG Electronics/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O division/NN/O of/IN/O North/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Philips/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O itself/PRP/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O N.V/NNP/B-ORG ././I-ORG Philips/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNPS/B-GPE ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Lawson/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 68/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O acting/JJ/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O since/IN/O June/NNP/O 14/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O ././O
