New/JJ/O federal/JJ/O legislation/NN/O requires/VBZ/O that/IN/O all/DT/O thrifts/NNS/O divest/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O speculative/JJ/O securities/NNS/O over/IN/O a/DT/O period/NN/O of/IN/O years/NNS/O ././O
Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Savings/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O available/JJ/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O downgrade/NN/O ././O
FRANKLIN/NNP/B-ORG SAVINGS/NNP/I-ORG ASSOCIATION/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O Ottawa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kan./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O --/:/O
The/DT/O rating/NN/O concern/NN/O said/VBD/O Franklin/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ``/``/O troubled/JJ/O diversification/NN/O record/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O securities/NNS/O business/NN/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O downgrade/NN/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O the/DT/O troubles/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O L.F./NNP/B-ORG Rothschild/NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O possible/JJ/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O subsidiaries/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O perhaps/RB/O had/VBD/O concern/NN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O getting/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O all/PDT/O these/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Franklin/NNP/B-ORG President/NNP/O Duane/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Hall/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O premature/JJ/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O part/NN/O ././O
