Ms./NNP/O Cunningham/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O novelist/NN/O and/CC/O playwright/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O vivid/JJ/O and/CC/O dramatically/RB/O outsized/JJ/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O recall/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O transforms/VBZ/O her/PRP/O ``/``/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O the/DT/O emotions/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O place/NN/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O flats/NNS/O of/IN/O mediocrity/NN/O are/VBP/O only/RB/O relieved/VBN/O by/IN/O steep/JJ/O descents/NNS/O into/IN/O hysteria/NN/O ''/''/O into/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE ``/``/I-GPE Babylonian/NNP/I-GPE Bronx/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O world/NN/O simmering/VBG/O with/IN/O sex/NN/O and/CC/O death/NN/O and/CC/O intrigue/NN/O ././O
Little/NNP/B-PERSON Lily/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Cunningham/NNP/B-PERSON calls/VBZ/O herself/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O ,/,/O really/RB/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O ordinary/JJ/O ././O
She/PRP/O was/VBD/O raised/VBN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O eight/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O by/IN/O her/PRP$/O mother/NN/O ,/,/O Rosie/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whom/WP/O she/PRP/O remembers/VBZ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O loving/JJ/O liar/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O realigned/VBD/O history/NN/O to/TO/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O father/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O live/VB/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
Rosie/NNP/B-PERSON reinvented/VBD/O this/DT/O man/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O may/MD/O or/CC/O may/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O known/VBN/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O child/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O war/NN/O hero/NN/O for/IN/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O benefit/NN/O ././O
Rosie/NN/B-PERSON died/VBD/O young/JJ/O and/CC/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O remembered/VBN/O her/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O romantic/JJ/O figure/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O interfere/VB/O much/RB/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O child/NN/O 's/POS/O education/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O ././O
She/PRP/O analyzed/VBD/O families/NNS/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O sleeping/NN/O arrangements/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O friend/NN/O Susan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O parents/NNS/O kept/VBD/O reminding/VBG/O her/PRP/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O unwanted/JJ/O ,/,/O slept/VBD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O narrow/JJ/O bed/NN/O wedged/VBN/O into/IN/O her/PRP$/O parents/NNS/O '/POS/O bedroom/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O though/IN/O she/PRP/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O temporary/JJ/O visitor/NN/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O friend/NN/O Diana/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O father/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O professional/JJ/O thief/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O bedrooms/NNS/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
They/PRP/O painted/VBD/O the/DT/O apartment/NN/O orange/JJ/O ,/,/O pink/JJ/O and/CC/O white/JJ/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O instructions/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O came/VBD/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O strangeness/NN/O honestly/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O book/NN/O loses/VBZ/O some/DT/O momentum/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Lily/NNP/B-PERSON becomes/VBZ/O more/RBR/O preoccupied/JJ/O with/IN/O dating/VBG/O boys/NNS/O and/CC/O less/RBR/O with/IN/O her/PRP/O delightfully/RB/O weird/JJ/O family/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O figures/VBZ/O in/IN/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Jay/NNP/I-PERSON Friedman/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON latest/JJS/O novel/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O flashes/VBZ/O back/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-GPE New/NNP/I-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/O the/DT/O '50s/NNS/O ././O
Harry/NNP/B-PERSON fondly/RB/O remembers/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O old/JJ/O ''/''/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O '70s/NNS/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O people/NNS/O like/IN/O his/PRP$/O friend/NN/O Travis/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O psychiatrist/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O date/NN/O to/TO/O analyze/VB/O what/WP/O Travis/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O doing/VBG/O wrong/JJ/O ././O
Line/NN/O by/IN/O line/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Friedman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O weary/JJ/O cynicism/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O amusing/JJ/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O riffing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE social/JJ/O scheme/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O way/NN/O people/NNS/O size/VBP/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O up/RP/O ,/,/O immediately/RB/O canceling/VBG/O the/DT/O desperate/JJ/O ones/NNS/O who/WP/O merely/RB/O almost/RB/O made/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O bore/NN/O ././O
