The/DT/O broken/JJ/O purchase/NN/O appears/VBZ/O as/IN/O additional/JJ/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O trouble/NN/O at/IN/O Imperial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O withdrew/VBD/O its/PRP$/O application/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Office/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Thrift/NNP/I-ORG Supervision/NNP/I-ORG because/IN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O informal/JJ/O notice/NN/O that/IN/O Imperial/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O thrift/NN/O unit/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O Community/NNP/O Reinvestment/NNP/O Act/NNP/O requirements/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Community/NNP/O Reinvestment/NNP/O Act/NNP/O requires/VBZ/O savings/NNS/O and/CC/O loan/NN/O associations/NNS/O to/TO/O lend/VB/O money/NN/O in/IN/O amounts/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O areas/NNS/O where/WRB/O deposits/NNS/O are/VBP/O received/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O ,/,/O announced/VBN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O included/VBN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 146/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O deposits/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O five/CD/O outlets/NNS/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O San/NNP/B-LOC Joaquin/NNP/I-LOC Valley/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Valley/NNP/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O expected/VBD/O to/TO/O post/VB/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O pretax/JJ/O gain/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O save/VB/O about/RB/O $/$/O 2/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O operating/NN/O costs/NNS/O annually/RB/O ././O
Valley/NNP/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Friday/NNP/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O another/DT/O buyer/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O branches/NNS/O or/CC/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O with/IN/O Imperial/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O Community/NNP/O Reinvestment/NNP/O Act/NNP/O requirements/NNS/O ././O
Valley/NNP/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 3.3/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Van/NNP/B-GPE Nuys/NNP/I-GPE ././O
