The/DT/O following/JJ/O were/VBD/O among/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O offerings/NNS/O and/CC/O pricings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O non-U.S./JJ/B-GPE capital/NN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O terms/NNS/O and/CC/O syndicate/NN/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O compiled/VBN/O by/IN/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Jones/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNP/I-ORG Report/NNP/I-ORG :/:/O
Dow/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
$/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O 8.55/CD/O %/NN/O senior/JJ/O notes/NNS/O due/JJ/O Oct./NNP/O 15/CD/O ,/,/O 2009/CD/O ,/,/O priced/VBN/O at/IN/O par/NN/O ././O
Centel/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
$/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O 9/CD/O %/NN/O debentures/NNS/O due/JJ/O Oct./NNP/O 15/CD/O ,/,/O 2019/CD/O ,/,/O priced/VBN/O at/IN/O 99.943/CD/O to/TO/O yield/VB/O 9.008/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Federal/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Loan/NNP/I-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
Federal/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Loan/NNP/I-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
$/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O Remic/NNP/O mortgage/NN/O securities/NNS/O offered/VBN/O by/IN/O Citicorp/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Pricing/NN/O details/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O immediately/RB/O available/JJ/O ././O
Federal/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Loan/NNP/I-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
$/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O stripped/JJ/O mortgage/NN/O securities/NNS/O underwritten/VBN/O by/IN/O BT/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O collateral/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O sold/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O thrift/NN/O institution/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O were/VBD/O no/DT/O major/JJ/O Eurobond/NNP/O or/CC/O foreign/JJ/O bond/NN/O offerings/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC Friday/NNP/O ././O
