Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG reportedly/RB/O began/VBD/O shipping/VBG/O these/DT/O tools/NNS/O in/IN/O 1984/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O acknowledged/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O discussing/VBG/O the/DT/O allegations/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Italian/JJ/O government/NN/O and/CC/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O confirm/VB/O any/DT/O details/NNS/O ././O
Italian/JJ/O President/NNP/O Francesco/NNP/B-PERSON Cossiga/NNP/I-PERSON promised/VBD/O a/DT/O quick/JJ/O investigation/NN/O into/IN/O whether/IN/O Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG broke/VBD/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG rules/NNS/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O his/PRP$/O attention/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Italian/JJ/O leader/NN/O 's/POS/O visit/NN/O here/RB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
Olivetti/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O denied/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O violated/VBD/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG rules/NNS/O ,/,/O asserting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O reported/JJ/O shipments/NNS/O were/VBD/O properly/RB/O licensed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Italian/JJ/O authorities/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O that/IN/O a/DT/O story/NN/O like/IN/O this/DT/O breaks/VBZ/O just/RB/O before/IN/O every/DT/O important/JJ/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG meeting/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE lobbyist/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE computer/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON moved/VBD/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O direction/NN/O of/IN/O gradual/JJ/O liberalization/NN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O a/DT/O North/NNP/B-ORG Atlantic/NNP/I-ORG Treaty/NNP/I-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG meeting/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O allow/VB/O some/DT/O exceptions/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG embargo/NN/O of/IN/O strategic/JJ/O goods/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O more/RBR/O recently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG openly/RB/O feuded/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O extent/NN/O to/TO/O which/WDT/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O liberalize/VB/O exports/NNS/O of/IN/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bloc/NN/B-LOC ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O these/DT/O agencies/NNS/O generally/RB/O agree/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O cautious/JJ/O about/IN/O any/DT/O further/JJ/O liberalization/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O evidence/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O program/NN/O to/TO/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O illegally/RB/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O acquire/VB/O Western/JJ/O technology/NN/O has/VBZ/O diminished/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
