Call/VB/O it/PRP/O the/DT/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O too/RB/O broke/JJ/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O ''/''/O defense/NN/O ././O
Lawyers/NNS/O for/IN/O dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O insolvent/JJ/O savings/NNS/O and/CC/O loan/NN/O associations/NNS/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O tack/NN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O defuse/VB/O suits/NNS/O filed/VBN/O by/IN/O borrowers/NNS/O ,/,/O developers/NNS/O and/CC/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O one/CD/O federal/JJ/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O has/VBZ/O signaled/VBN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O entertain/VB/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O renewed/VBN/O their/PRP$/O arguments/NNS/O in/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O eight/CD/O other/JJ/O states/NNS/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O defense/NN/O is/VBZ/O permitted/VBN/O under/IN/O state/NN/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O dismissal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pending/VBG/O suits/NNS/O could/MD/O go/VB/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O way/NN/O toward/IN/O clearing/VBG/O court/NN/O dockets/NNS/O in/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O FSLIC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O massive/JJ/O legal/JJ/O bills/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O topped/VBD/O $/$/O 73/CD/O million/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Sunbelt/NNP/B-ORG foreclosed/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O ranch/NN/O ././O
Sunbelt/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O FSLIC/NNP/B-ORG argued/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Fifth/NNP/I-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Appeals/NNP/I-ORG ``/``/O that/IN/O there/EX/O will/MD/O never/RB/O be/VB/O any/DT/O assets/NNS/O with/IN/O which/WDT/O to/TO/O satisfy/VB/O a/DT/O judgment/NN/O against/IN/O Sunbelt/NNP/B-ORG Savings/NNP/I-ORG nor/CC/O any/DT/O means/NNS/O to/TO/O collect/VB/O from/IN/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O party/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O FSLIC/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O If/IN/O true/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O court/NN/O wrote/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O this/DT/O contention/NN/O would/MD/O justify/VB/O dismissal/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O actions/NNS/O on/IN/O prudential/JJ/O grounds/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O the/DT/O court/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O lacked/VBD/O enough/RB/O financial/JJ/O information/NN/O about/IN/O Sunbelt/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O FSLIC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O sent/VBD/O the/DT/O cases/NNS/O back/RB/O to/TO/O federal/JJ/O district/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Haworth/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O for/IN/O Sunbelt/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O file/VB/O a/DT/O brief/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O urging/VBG/O the/DT/O district/NN/O judge/NN/O to/TO/O dismiss/VB/O the/DT/O suits/NNS/O ,/,/O because/IN/O Sunbelt/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O liabilities/NNS/O exceeded/VBD/O its/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O by/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O when/WRB/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O closed/VBD/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O for/IN/O Triland/NNP/B-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O developer/NN/O of/IN/O Valley/NNP/B-FAC Ranch/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O dismisses/VBZ/O such/JJ/O arguments/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O defense/NN/O du/FW/O jour/FW/O ././O ''/''/O
Attorney/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Jackson/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE says/VBZ/O a/DT/O judgment/NN/O for/IN/O Triland/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O be/VB/O satisfied/JJ/O in/IN/O ways/NNS/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O a/DT/O monetary/JJ/O award/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O reversal/NN/O of/IN/O Sunbelt/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O foreclosure/NN/O on/IN/O Valley/NNP/B-FAC Ranch/NNP/I-FAC ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O asking/VBG/O the/DT/O court/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O things/NNS/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O grant/VB/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O thrill/NN/O of/IN/O victory/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 'd/MD/O take/VB/O the/DT/B-FAC Valley/NNP/I-FAC Ranch/NNP/I-FAC free/JJ/O and/CC/O clear/JJ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O booby/JJ/O prize/NN/O ././O
