Food/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O Jeff/NNP/B-PERSON Nesbit/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O has/VBZ/O turned/VBN/O over/RP/O evidence/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O criminal/JJ/O investigation/NN/O concerning/VBG/O Vitarine/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceuticals/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O in/IN/O Baltimore/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Neither/DT/O Vitarine/NNP/B-ORG nor/CC/O any/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Springfield/NNP/B-GPE Gardens/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O officials/NNS/O or/CC/O employees/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O any/DT/O crimes/NNS/O ././O
Vitarine/NNP/B-ORG won/VBD/O approval/NN/O to/TO/O market/VB/O a/DT/O version/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O blood/NN/O pressure/NN/O medicine/NN/O but/CC/O acknowledged/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O substituted/VBD/O a/DT/O SmithKline/NNP/B-ORG Beecham/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG product/NN/O as/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O in/IN/O tests/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nesbit/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O asked/VBN/O Bolar/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceutical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O recall/VB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O retail/JJ/O level/NN/O its/PRP$/O urinary/JJ/O tract/NN/O antibiotic/NN/O ././O
Bolar/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O criminal/JJ/O investigation/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Inspector/NNP/O General/NNP/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Human/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O only/RB/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O recall/VB/O two/CD/O strengths/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O version/NN/O of/IN/O Macrodantin/NNP/O ``/``/O as/RB/O far/RB/O down/RB/O as/IN/O direct/JJ/O customers/NNS/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O wholesalers/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Nesbit/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Bolar/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Copiague/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O earlier/RBR/O began/VBD/O a/DT/O voluntary/JJ/O recall/NN/O of/IN/O both/DT/O its/PRP$/O 100/CD/O milligram/NN/O and/CC/O 50/CD/O milligram/NN/O versions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O ././O
