With/IN/O economic/JJ/O tension/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE worsening/VBG/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O Japanese/VBP/O had/VBD/O feared/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O visit/NN/O from/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Trade/NNP/O Representative/NNP/O Carla/NNP/B-PERSON Hills/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
They/PRP/O expected/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O barrage/NN/O of/IN/O demands/NNS/O that/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE do/VB/O something/NN/O quickly/RB/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O first/JJ/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O trade/NN/O negotiator/NN/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O completely/RB/O different/JJ/O tone/NN/O from/IN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O 's/POS/O visit/NN/O by/IN/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Mosbacher/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mosbacher/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O for/IN/O concrete/JJ/O results/NNS/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O spring/NN/O in/IN/O negotiations/NNS/O over/IN/O fundamental/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O business/NN/O practices/NNS/O that/WDT/O supposedly/RB/O inhibit/VBP/O free/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O such/JJ/O results/NNS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O measurable/JJ/O in/IN/O dollars/NNS/O and/CC/O cents/NNS/O ''/''/O in/IN/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O with/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O speaking/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O breakfast/NN/O meeting/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Chamber/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O Saturday/NNP/O ,/,/O stressed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O objective/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O to/TO/O get/VB/O definitive/JJ/O action/NN/O by/IN/O spring/NN/O or/CC/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O rather/RB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O blueprint/NN/O for/IN/O action/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
She/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O expected/VBD/O ``/``/O perhaps/RB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O down/JJ/O payment/NN/O .../:/O some/DT/O small/JJ/O step/NN/O to/TO/O convince/VB/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O people/NNS/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O moving/VBG/O in/IN/O earnest/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
How/WRB/O such/JJ/O remarks/NNS/O translate/VBP/O into/IN/O policy/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O become/VB/O clear/JJ/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O ././O
American/JJ/O and/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O officials/NNS/O offered/VBD/O several/JJ/O theories/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O difference/NN/O in/IN/O approach/NN/O betwen/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Mosbacher/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Many/JJ/O called/VBD/O it/PRP/O simply/RB/O a/DT/O contrast/NN/O in/IN/O styles/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O some/DT/O saw/VBD/O it/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O classic/JJ/O negotiating/NN/O tactic/NN/O ././O
Others/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O may/MD/O feel/VB/O the/DT/O rhetoric/NN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O hand/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O some/DT/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O reflected/VBD/O the/DT/O growing/VBG/O debate/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O pursuing/VBG/O free/JJ/O trade/NN/O with/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE versus/IN/O some/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O managed/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
Asked/VBD/O to/TO/O compare/VB/O her/PRP/O visit/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Mosbacher/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON replied/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O hear/VB/O every/DT/O word/NN/O he/PRP/O spoke/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O as/IN/O a/DT/O general/JJ/O proposition/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O very/RB/O consistent/JJ/O trade/NN/O strategy/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Yet/RB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O one/CD/O American/JJ/O official/NN/O who/WP/O sat/VBD/O in/RP/O with/IN/O her/PRP/O during/IN/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O her/PRP$/O tone/NN/O often/RB/O was/VBD/O surprisingly/RB/O ``/``/O conciliatory/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O my/PRP$/O line/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O very/RB/O consistent/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O at/IN/O a/DT/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O Saturday/NNP/O afternoon/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O painted/VBN/O sometimes/RB/O as/IN/O ferocious/JJ/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O because/IN/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O ferocious/JJ/O list/NN/O of/IN/O statutes/NNS/O to/TO/O implement/VB/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O feel/VB/O very/RB/O ferocious/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O feel/VB/O either/CC/O hard/JJ/O or/CC/O soft/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O feel/VBP/O committed/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O program/NN/O of/IN/O opening/VBG/O markets/NNS/O and/CC/O expanding/VBG/O trade/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
When/WRB/O she/PRP/O met/VBD/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O press/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON firmly/RB/O reiterated/VBD/O the/DT/O need/NN/O for/IN/O progress/NN/O in/IN/O removing/VBG/O barriers/NNS/O to/TO/O trade/NN/O in/IN/O forest/NN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O satellites/NNS/O and/CC/O supercomputers/NNS/O ,/,/O three/CD/O areas/NNS/O targeted/VBN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Super/NNP/O 301/NNP/O provision/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1988/CD/O trade/NN/O bill/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O highlighted/VBD/O exclusionary/JJ/O business/NN/O practices/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O has/VBZ/O identified/VBN/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O imbalance/NN/O was/VBD/O mainly/RB/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O macroeconomic/JJ/O factors/NNS/O and/CC/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O tackled/VBN/O by/IN/O setting/VBG/O quantitative/JJ/O targets/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O her/PRP$/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O for/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O reporters/NNS/O ,/,/O one/CD/O economics/NN/O journalist/NN/O summed/VBD/O up/RP/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O relief/NN/O ././O
``/``/O My/PRP$/O impression/NN/O was/VBD/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O scary/JJ/O old/JJ/O lady/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O drawing/VBG/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O nervous/JJ/O chuckles/NNS/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O relieved/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O are/VBP/O beautiful/JJ/O and/CC/O gentle/JJ/O and/CC/O intelligent/JJ/O and/CC/O a/DT/O person/NN/O of/IN/O integrity/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O remarks/NNS/O did/VBD/O raise/NN/O questions/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O among/IN/O some/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O ,/,/O about/IN/O what/WP/O exactly/RB/O her/PRP$/O stance/NN/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE access/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O semiconductor/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE share/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O market/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O stuck/JJ/O around/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O Americans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O interpreted/VBN/O a/DT/O 1986/CD/O agreement/NN/O as/IN/O assuring/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O a/DT/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O by/IN/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O have/VBP/O denied/VBN/O making/VBG/O any/DT/O such/JJ/O promise/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O news/NN/O conferences/NNS/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O do/VB/O much/RB/O better/RBR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O she/PRP/O stressed/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O against/IN/O managed/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O will/MD/O not/RB/O enter/VB/O into/IN/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O that/WDT/O stipulates/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
