A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Information/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O by/IN/O two/CD/O units/NNS/O of/IN/O Morris/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG seeks/VBZ/O restitution/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O 's/VBZ/O about/RB/O $/$/O 3/CD/O million/CD/O purchase/NN/O price/NN/O and/CC/O cancellation/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O software/NN/O license/NN/O provided/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Morris/NNP/B-ORG units/NNS/O to/TO/O Information/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O alleged/JJ/O failure/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O royalties/NNS/O ././O
Information/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O complaints/NNS/O ,/,/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O without/IN/O merit/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O units/NNS/O that/WDT/O filed/VBD/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O are/VBP/O Southeastern/NNP/B-ORG Newspapers/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Florida/NNP/B-ORG Publishing/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
