A/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG franchisees/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O formed/VBD/O an/DT/O association/NN/O to/TO/O oppose/VB/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE financier/NN/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON Posner/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O restaurant/NN/O chain/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O decision/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O move/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O escalating/VBG/O battle/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O franchisees/NNS/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Posner/NNP/B-PERSON that/WDT/O began/VBD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ././O
DWG/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O holding/NN/O company/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Posner/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
One/CD/O week/NN/O later/RB/O ,/,/O Leonard/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Roberts/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O fired/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O dispute/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Posner/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O franchisees/NNS/O ,/,/O owners/NNS/O or/CC/O operators/NNS/O of/IN/O 1,000/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1,900/CD/O franchised/JJ/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O concluded/VBN/O that/IN/O continued/JJ/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG by/IN/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON Posner/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O totally/RB/O unacceptable/JJ/O to/TO/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O extremely/RB/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O cause/VB/O irreparable/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O system/NN/O ././O
