Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Seelenfreund/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 52/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O processor/NN/O of/IN/O prescription/NN/O claims/NNS/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Field/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 55/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Field/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O McKesson/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O resigning/VBG/O that/DT/O post/NN/O after/IN/O a/DT/O dispute/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O over/IN/O corporate/JJ/O strategy/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Seelenfreund/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O McKesson/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O in/IN/O those/DT/O roles/NNS/O ././O
PCS/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O named/VBD/O Rex/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Malson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 57/CD/O ,/,/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O at/IN/O McKesson/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ,/,/O filling/VBG/O the/DT/O seat/NN/O vacated/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Field/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Messrs./NNP/O Malson/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Seelenfreund/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O directors/NNS/O of/IN/O McKesson/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O 86/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O PCS/NNP/B-ORG ././O
