Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O first/JJ/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O trade/NN/O negotiator/NN/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O completely/RB/O different/JJ/O tone/NN/O from/IN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O 's/POS/O visit/NN/O by/IN/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Mosbacher/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mosbacher/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O for/IN/O concrete/JJ/O results/NNS/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O spring/NN/O in/IN/O negotiations/NNS/O over/IN/O fundamental/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O business/NN/O practices/NNS/O that/WDT/O supposedly/RB/O inhibit/VBP/O free/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O such/JJ/O results/NNS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O measurable/JJ/O in/IN/O dollars/NNS/O and/CC/O cents/NNS/O ''/''/O in/IN/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O with/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
American/JJ/O and/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O officials/NNS/O offered/VBD/O several/JJ/O theories/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O difference/NN/O in/IN/O approach/NN/O betwen/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Mosbacher/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Many/JJ/O called/VBD/O it/PRP/O simply/RB/O a/DT/O contrast/NN/O in/IN/O styles/NNS/O ././O
Others/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O may/MD/O feel/VB/O the/DT/O rhetoric/NN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O hand/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O feel/VB/O very/RB/O ferocious/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O feel/VB/O either/CC/O hard/JJ/O or/CC/O soft/JJ/O ././O
She/PRP/O highlighted/VBD/O exclusionary/JJ/O business/NN/O practices/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O has/VBZ/O identified/VBN/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O imbalance/NN/O was/VBD/O mainly/RB/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O macroeconomic/JJ/O factors/NNS/O and/CC/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O tackled/VBN/O by/IN/O setting/VBG/O quantitative/JJ/O targets/NNS/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON '/POS/O remarks/NNS/O did/VBD/O raise/NN/O questions/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O among/IN/O some/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O ,/,/O about/IN/O what/WP/O exactly/RB/O her/PRP$/O stance/NN/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE access/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O semiconductor/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE share/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O market/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O stuck/JJ/O around/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O Americans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O interpreted/VBN/O a/DT/O 1986/CD/O agreement/NN/O as/IN/O assuring/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O a/DT/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O by/IN/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O have/VBP/O denied/VBN/O making/VBG/O any/DT/O such/JJ/O promise/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O will/MD/O not/RB/O enter/VB/O into/IN/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O that/WDT/O stipulates/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
