This/DT/O small/JJ/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE suburb/NN/O 's/POS/O got/VBD/O trouble/NN/O ././O
Trouble/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O capital/JJ/O T/NN/O and/CC/O that/DT/O rhymes/VBZ/O with/IN/O P/NN/O and/CC/O that/DT/O stands/VBZ/O for/IN/O pool/NN/O ././O
More/RBR/O than/IN/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Prof./NNP/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON Hill/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O con/JJ/O man/NN/O in/IN/O Meredith/NNP/B-PERSON Willson/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O The/DT/O Music/NN/O Man/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O warned/VBD/O the/DT/O citizens/NNS/O of/IN/O River/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O against/IN/O the/DT/O game/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O kindred/JJ/O spirits/NNS/O on/IN/O Addison/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O town/NN/O council/NN/O have/VBP/O barred/VBN/O the/DT/O town/NN/O 's/POS/O fanciest/JJS/O hotel/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Grand/NNP/I-ORG Kempinski/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O from/IN/O installing/VBG/O three/CD/O free/JJ/O pool/NN/O tables/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O lounge/NN/O ././O
Mayor/NNP/O Lynn/NNP/B-PERSON Spruill/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O two/CD/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O council/NN/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O worried/JJ/O about/IN/O setting/VBG/O a/DT/O precedent/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O permit/VB/O pool/NN/O halls/NNS/O along/IN/O Addison/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O main/JJ/O street/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O mayor/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O admonition/NN/O that/WDT/O bears/VBZ/O a/DT/O rhythmic/JJ/O resemblance/NN/O to/TO/O Prof./NNP/O Hill/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ,/,/O warned/VBD/O that/IN/O ``/``/O alcohol/NN/O leads/VBZ/O to/TO/O betting/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O leads/VBZ/O to/TO/O fights/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O council/NN/O 's/POS/O action/NN/O is/VBZ/O yet/RB/O another/DT/O blow/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O sport/NN/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O fans/NNS/O claim/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O maligned/VBN/O unjustly/RB/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Obviously/RB/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O in/IN/O touch/NN/O with/IN/O what/WP/O 's/VBZ/O going/VBG/O on/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Tom/NNP/B-PERSON Manske/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Pocket/NNP/I-ORG Billiards/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ././O
With/IN/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O tougher/JJR/O drunk/JJ/O driving/NN/O laws/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O people/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O just/RB/O sit/VB/O around/RB/O and/CC/O drink/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Besides/IN/O ,/,/O rowdy/JJ/O behavior/NN/O seems/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Grand/NNP/I-ORG Kempinski/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O where/WRB/O rooms/NNS/O average/VBP/O $/$/O 200/CD/O a/DT/O night/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O cheap/JJ/O mixed/JJ/O drinks/NNS/O go/VBP/O for/IN/O $/$/O 3.50/CD/O a/DT/O pop/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Addison/NNP/B-GPE council/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O buy/VB/O those/DT/O arguments/NNS/O ././O
Introducing/VBG/O pool/NN/O ,/,/O argued/VBD/O Councilwoman/NNP/O Riley/NNP/B-PERSON Reinker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O dangerous/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O open/VB/O a/DT/O can/NN/O of/IN/O worms/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Addison/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O no/DT/O stranger/NN/O to/TO/O cans/NNS/O of/IN/O worms/NNS/O ,/,/O either/RB/O ././O
After/IN/O its/PRP$/O previous/JJ/O mayor/NN/O committed/VBD/O suicide/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O disclosed/VBD/O that/IN/O town/NN/O officials/NNS/O regularly/RB/O voted/VBD/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O projects/NNS/O ,/,/O gave/VBD/O special/JJ/O favors/NNS/O to/TO/O developer/NN/O friends/NNS/O and/CC/O dipped/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O town/NN/O 's/POS/O coffers/NNS/O for/IN/O trips/NNS/O and/CC/O retreats/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O revelations/NNS/O embarrassed/VBD/O town/NN/O officials/NNS/O ,/,/O although/IN/O they/PRP/O argued/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O as/RB/O severe/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O suggested/VBD/O ././O
Now/RB/O comes/VBZ/O the/DT/O pool/NN/O flap/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O some/DT/O people/NNS/O worried/JJ/O about/IN/O something/NN/O pretty/RB/O ridiculous/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Councilman/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Nolan/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O thought/VBD/O this/DT/O was/VBD/O all/DT/O taken/VBN/O care/NN/O of/IN/O in/IN/O `/``/O The/DT/O Music/NN/O Man/NN/O ././O
