The/DT/O woman/NN/O won/VBD/O the/DT/O bet/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O militant/JJ/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O American/JJ/O TV/NN/O imports/NNS/O has/VBZ/O come/VBN/O from/IN/O French/JJ/O television/NN/O and/CC/O movie/NN/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O demanded/VBN/O quotas/NNS/O ensuring/VBG/O that/IN/O a/DT/O full/JJ/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O TV/NN/O shows/NNS/O be/VB/O produced/VBN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
A/DT/O glance/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O television/NN/O listings/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O twists/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O European/JJ/O television/NN/O dial/NN/O suggest/VBP/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O why/WRB/O ././O
A/DT/O Flemish/JJ/O game/NN/O show/NN/O has/VBZ/O as/RB/O its/PRP$/O host/NN/O a/DT/O Belgian/NNP/O pretending/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O Italian/JJ/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O favorite/JJ/O shows/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Fantastico/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O tepid/JJ/O variety/NN/O show/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O popular/JJ/O that/IN/O viewers/NNS/O clamored/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O a/DT/O chocolate/NN/O product/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Cacao/NNP/O Fantastico/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O whose/WP$/O praises/NNS/O were/VBD/O sung/VBN/O each/DT/O week/NN/O by/IN/O dancing/VBG/O showgirls/NNS/O --/:/O even/RB/O though/IN/O the/DT/O product/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O exist/VB/O ././O
A/DT/O celebrity/NN/O guest/NN/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Ambassador/NNP/O to/TO/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Burt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O also/RB/O won/VBD/O a/DT/O bet/NN/O that/IN/O someone/NN/O could/MD/O pile/VB/O up/RP/O $/$/O 150/CD/O worth/NN/O of/IN/O quarters/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O slanted/JJ/O coin/NN/O ././O
European/JJ/O programs/NNS/O usually/RB/O target/VBP/O only/RB/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O local/JJ/O audience/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O often/RB/O only/RB/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O ././O
Mega-hits/NNS/O in/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE rarely/RB/O make/VBP/O it/PRP/O even/RB/O to/TO/O France/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Great/NNP/B-GPE Britain/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O almost/RB/O never/RB/O show/VBP/O up/RP/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE screens/NNS/O ././O
Attempts/NNS/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O ``/``/O pan-European/JJ/O ''/''/O programs/NNS/O have/VBP/O generally/RB/O resulted/VBN/O in/IN/O disappointment/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Jeux/FW/O Sans/FW/O Frontieres/FW/O ,/,/O ''/''/O where/WRB/O villagers/NNS/O from/IN/O assorted/JJ/O European/JJ/O countries/NNS/O make/VBP/O fools/NNS/O of/IN/O themselves/PRP/O performing/VBG/O pointless/JJ/O tasks/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O hit/NN/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O cream/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O crop/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O literary/JJ/O dramas/NN/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O shown/VBN/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE public/JJ/O television/NN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O Masterpiece/NNP/O Theater/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O make/VBP/O up/RP/O a/DT/O relatively/RB/O small/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O British/JJ/O air/NN/O time/NN/O ././O
Most/JJS/O British/JJ/O programming/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O an/DT/O acquired/JJ/O taste/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O One/CD/O Man/NN/O and/CC/O His/PRP$/O Dog/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O herding/NN/O contest/NN/O among/IN/O sheep/NN/O dogs/NNS/O ././O
European/JJ/O drama/NN/O has/VBZ/O had/VBN/O better/JJR/O ,/,/O though/IN/O still/RB/O mixed/JJ/O ,/,/O fortunes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O popular/JJ/O such/JJ/O shows/NNS/O focus/VBP/O on/IN/O narrow/JJ/O national/JJ/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
Italy/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/RBS/O popular/JJ/O series/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O drama/NN/O called/VBN/O ``/``/O La/FW/O Piovra/FW/O ,/,/O ''/''/O or/CC/O ``/``/O The/NNP/O Octopus/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O chronicles/VBZ/O the/DT/O fight/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O idealistic/JJ/O young/JJ/O investigator/NN/O in/IN/O Palermo/NNP/B-GPE against/IN/O the/DT/O Mafia/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Spain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/RBS/O popular/JJ/O mini-series/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O Juncal/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O story/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O aging/VBG/O bullfighter/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O and/CC/O huge/JJ/O appetite/NN/O for/IN/O programming/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O financially/RB/O struggling/VBG/O station/NN/O offers/VBZ/O programs/NNS/O obviously/RB/O made/VBN/O available/JJ/O cheaply/RB/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O boss/NN/O 's/POS/O other/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
