``/``/O There/EX/O are/VBP/O some/DT/O very/RB/O significant/JJ/O issues/NNS/O out/RB/O there/RB/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O deficit/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O ,/,/O our/PRP$/O relations/NNS/O with/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O major/JJ/O initiatives/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O that/DT/O initiative/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O shot/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O agenda/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O hours/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O dropped/VBD/O 190/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
Politicians/NNS/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O finger/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O blame/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O many/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O doubt/VBP/O that/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O singly/RB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O 's/POS/O woes/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Butcher/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O comments/NNS/O make/VBP/O one/CD/O thing/NN/O clear/JJ/O :/:/O Some/DT/O on/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O wonder/VBP/O if/IN/O anyone/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O economic/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
Consider/VB/O this/DT/O :/:/O
``/``/O We/PRP/O simply/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O strong/JJ/O leadership/NN/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O deficit/NN/O and/CC/O make/VB/O tough/JJ/O choices/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O House/NNP/B-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Leon/NNP/B-PERSON Panetta/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O on/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ``/``/O Meet/NNP/O the/DT/O Press/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
--/:/O For/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O been/VBN/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O semi-public/JJ/O battle/NN/O over/IN/O international/JJ/O economic/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O push/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O lower/RBR/O ;/:/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O resisting/VBG/O ././O
--/:/O The/DT/O administration/NN/O has/VBZ/O sent/VBN/O out/RP/O confusing/JJ/O signals/NNS/O about/IN/O its/PRP$/O response/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O spate/NN/O of/IN/O airline/NN/O takeovers/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Transportation/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Sam/NNP/B-PERSON Skinner/NNP/I-PERSON forced/VBD/O Northwest/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O reduce/VB/O a/DT/O stake/NN/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O KLM/NNP/B-ORG Royal/NNP/I-ORG Dutch/NNP/I-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O since/RB/O run/VBN/O into/IN/O opposition/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG over/IN/O that/DT/O decision/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O kept/VBN/O mum/JJ/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O his/PRP$/O decision/NN/O might/MD/O affect/VB/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O stake/NN/O by/IN/O British/NNP/B-ORG Airways/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O uncertainty/NN/O about/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O anti-takeover/JJ/O policy/NN/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O that/IN/O financing/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG takeover/NN/O fell/VBD/O through/RP/O --/:/O the/DT/O event/NN/O that/WDT/O triggered/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O drop/NN/O ././O
Then/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O debate/NN/O was/VBD/O behind/IN/O schedule/NN/O and/CC/O automatic/JJ/O spending/JJ/O cuts/NNS/O were/VBD/O within/IN/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O taking/VBG/O hold/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O locked/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O battle/NN/O over/IN/O international/JJ/O economic/JJ/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O at/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O with/IN/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O officials/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O barring/VBG/O further/JJR/O drops/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O outcome/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O likely/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Everybody/NN/O thought/VBD/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O repetition/NN/O of/IN/O 1929/CD/O ,/,/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Rep./NNP/O Panetta/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O happen/VB/O ././O
They/PRP/O learned/VBD/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O survive/VB/O it/PRP/O without/IN/O much/JJ/O problem/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O privately/RB/O agree/VBP/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Panetta/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O precipitous/JJ/O drop/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O force/VB/O the/DT/O president/NN/O and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O take/VB/O a/DT/O much/JJ/O harder/JJR/O look/NN/O at/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O that/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O will/MD/O be/VB/O plenty/NN/O of/IN/O blame/NN/O to/TO/O go/VB/O around/RP/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O underlying/JJ/O concern/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O --/:/O and/CC/O there/RB/O should/MD/O be/VB/O -/:/O that/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O gone/VBN/O far/RB/O enough/RB/O in/IN/O cutting/VBG/O this/DT/O deficit/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O unwilling/JJ/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O asked/VBD/O us/PRP/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Lloyd/NNP/B-PERSON Bentsen/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Asked/VBN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O agreed/VBD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O curtly/RB/O replied/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O adminstration/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O speak/VB/O for/IN/O itself/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Senate/NNP/B-ORG Republicans/NNPS/O expressed/VBD/O the/DT/O hope/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O House/NN/B-ORG would/MD/O follow/VB/O the/DT/O lead/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O a/DT/O variety/NN/O of/IN/O spending/NN/O measures/NNS/O and/CC/O tax/NN/O breaks/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O increased/VBN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O deficit/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O market/NN/O needs/VBZ/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O signal/NN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O serious/JJ/O about/IN/O deficit/NN/O reduction/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O way/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Representatives/NNPS/I-ORG to/TO/O strip/VB/O their/PRP$/O bill/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O similar/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON Rudman/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O N.H/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
No/DT/O one/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O blame/NN/O for/IN/O provoking/VBG/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O some/DT/O players/NNS/O were/VBD/O quick/JJ/O to/TO/O seize/VB/O the/DT/O moment/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Investors/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O holding/VBG/O assets/NNS/O in/IN/O anticipation/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O favorable/JJ/O time/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O spooked/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
