Now/RB/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O fence/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O since/IN/O January/NNP/O that/IN/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O thought/VBN/O stocks/NNS/O are/VBP/O worth/JJ/O owning/NN/O ././O
Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O confirm/VB/O the/DT/O move/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O stock/NN/O purchases/NNS/O were/VBD/O thought/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O begun/VBN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O timed/VBD/O to/TO/O coincide/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O maturity/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O of/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bills/NNS/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O half/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O portfolio/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O remain/VB/O invested/VBN/O in/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bills/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O being/VBG/O ././O
Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O executives/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O believed/VBD/O that/DT/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O $/$/O 900/CD/O million/CD/O buy/NN/O program/NN/O was/VBD/O carried/VBN/O out/RP/O by/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
As/IN/O reported/VBN/O ,/,/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG bought/VBD/O shares/NNS/O Tuesday/NNP/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O customer/NN/O strategy/NN/O shift/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O the/DT/O broker/NN/O 's/POS/O client/NN/O was/VBD/O said/VBD/O then/RB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O Japanese/NNP/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG declined/VBD/O comment/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O broker/NN/O winning/VBG/O the/DT/O business/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O charge/VB/O commissions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O instead/RB/O profits/VBZ/O by/IN/O buying/VBG/O or/CC/O selling/VBG/O for/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O overall/JJ/O package/NN/O price/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O puts/VBZ/O the/DT/O broker/NN/O at/IN/O risk/NN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O rising/VBG/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O sell/NN/O signal/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O sent/VBD/O a/DT/O bearish/JJ/O chill/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O came/VBD/O when/WRB/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O computer/NN/O found/VBD/O that/IN/O stocks/NNS/O were/VBD/O overpriced/VBN/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O bonds/NNS/O and/CC/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bills/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Industrial/NNP/O Average/NNP/O stood/VBD/O at/IN/O about/IN/O 2200/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Dow/NNP/O average/NN/O now/RB/O stands/VBZ/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O higher/JJR/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O portfolio/NN/O of/IN/O Treasurys/NNPS/O produced/VBD/O a/DT/O return/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 6/CD/O %/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O three/CD/O quarters/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O computer/NN/O 's/POS/O miscalculation/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O painful/JJ/O for/IN/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Almost/RB/O any/DT/O money/NN/O manager/NN/O holding/VBG/O stocks/NNS/O has/VBZ/O turned/VBN/O in/RP/O better/JJR/O results/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O played/VBN/O it/PRP/O safe/JJ/O with/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bills/NNS/O ././O
So/RB/O why/WRB/O does/VBZ/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O computer/NN/O like/IN/O stocks/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O at/IN/O 2653.28/CD/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O closed/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O at/IN/O 2200/CD/O ?/./O
``/``/O With/IN/O the/DT/O decline/NN/O in/IN/O stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O continued/VBD/O low/JJ/O or/CC/O stable/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O stocks/NNS/O are/VBP/O representing/VBG/O a/DT/O better/JJR/O value/NN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG President/NNP/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Terrizzi/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O about/IN/O 140/CD/O points/NNS/O lower/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O peak/NN/O of/IN/O 2791.41/CD/O reached/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O industrial/JJ/O average/NN/O Oct./NNP/O 9/CD/O ././O
Are/VBP/O those/DT/O declines/NNS/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O signal/VB/O a/DT/O partial/JJ/O return/NN/O to/TO/O stocks/NNS/O ?/./O
Mr./NNP/O Terrizzi/NNP/B-PERSON wo/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O specifically/RB/O ,/,/O explaining/VBG/O that/IN/O if/IN/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O move/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O take/VB/O about/IN/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O the/DT/O loose/JJ/O ends/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O ././O
During/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O buyer/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O clout/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O end/VB/O up/RP/O driving/VBG/O up/RP/O the/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O stocks/NNS/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O tipped/VBD/O its/PRP$/O hand/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O computer/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O model/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O certain/JJ/O trigger/NN/O point/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O says/VBZ/O switch/VB/O ,/,/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG switches/VBZ/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O competitors/NNS/O say/VBP/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O any/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O return/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O risk/NN/O losing/VBG/O business/NN/O by/IN/O continuing/VBG/O to/TO/O remain/VB/O fully/RB/O invested/VBN/O in/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bills/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Terrizzi/NNP/B-PERSON confirms/VBZ/O some/DT/O clients/NNS/O have/VBP/O left/VBN/O Renaissance/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O no/DT/O major/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O has/VBZ/O added/VBN/O new/JJ/O accounts/NNS/O ././O
