PWA/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O by/IN/O spring/NN/O 1992/CD/O all/DT/O 15/CD/O passenger/NN/O planes/NNS/O it/PRP/O acquired/VBD/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O 248/CD/O million/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollar/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 211.6/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O Wardair/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ireland/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O current/JJ/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O used/VBN/O aircraft/NN/O is/VBZ/O strong/JJ/O ,/,/O partly/RB/O because/IN/O surging/VBG/O orders/NNS/O for/IN/O new/JJ/O aircraft/NNS/O have/VBP/O lengthened/VBN/O waiting/NN/O lists/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O predicted/VBD/O that/IN/O PWA/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O have/VB/O little/JJ/O difficulty/NN/O attracting/VBG/O prospective/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O see/VB/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O debt/NN/O reduction/NN/O exercise/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O focused/VBN/O on/IN/O streamlining/VBG/O ''/''/O PWA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O fleet/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O training/NN/O and/CC/O aircraft/NN/O servicing/NN/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O analyst/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O five/CD/O leased/VBN/O units/NNS/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O delivered/VBN/O in/IN/O 1991/CD/O ././O
