The/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O asking/VBG/O grant/NN/O recipients/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O for/IN/O comments/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O until/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 15/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O researchers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Lithox/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O receive/VB/O a/DT/O royalty/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O if/IN/O their/PRP$/O research/NN/O yields/VBZ/O a/DT/O commercial/JJ/O product/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O stakes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O controversy/NN/O are/VBP/O large/JJ/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O deals/NNS/O involved/VBD/O transactions/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O scientific/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O or/CC/O researchers/NNS/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O commercialize/VB/O their/PRP$/O work/NN/O in/IN/O return/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O equity/NN/O stake/NN/O or/CC/O royalties/NNS/O ././O
Investors/NNS/O were/VBD/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O gamble/VB/O on/IN/O new/JJ/O technologies/NNS/O because/IN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O exclusive/JJ/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O those/DT/O technologies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Avalon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O invested/VBD/O $/$/O 14/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O Athena/NNP/B-ORG Neurosciences/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE San/NNP/I-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O license/VB/O and/CC/O develop/VB/O technology/NN/O for/IN/O delivery/NN/O of/IN/O drugs/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O brain/NN/O ././O
Athena/NNP/B-ORG eventually/RB/O acquired/VBD/O exclusive/JJ/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O currently/RB/O is/VBZ/O developing/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O proposed/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O could/MD/O also/RB/O delay/VB/O commercialization/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O force/VB/O small/JJ/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O waste/VB/O scarce/JJ/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O entrepreneurs/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Universities/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O MIT/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O a/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O act/VB/O as/IN/O brokers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O individual/JJ/O scientists/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Katherine/NNP/B-PERSON Bick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O oversees/VBZ/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG grants/NNS/O program/NN/O as/IN/O its/PRP$/O deputy/NN/O director/NN/O for/IN/O extramural/JJ/O research/NN/O ././O
NIH/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O members/NNS/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O guidelines/NNS/O are/VBP/O essential/JJ/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O the/DT/O escalation/NN/O of/IN/O problems/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O already/RB/O begun/VBN/O to/TO/O surface/VB/O in/IN/O scientific/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O congressional/JJ/O subcommitee/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O investigating/VBG/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O abuse/NN/O from/IN/O researchers/NNS/O holding/VBG/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O companies/NNS/O exploiting/VBG/O their/PRP$/O research/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O predictions/NNS/O of/IN/O doom/NN/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O premature/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/I-ORG San/NNP/I-ORG Francisco/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O also/RB/O circulating/VBG/O a/DT/O memo/NN/O among/IN/O its/PRP$/O scientific/JJ/O faculty/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O restrict/VB/O contact/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O damage/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O done/VBN/O ././O
