Two/CD/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O chemical/NN/O companies/NNS/O announced/VBD/O steps/NNS/O that/WDT/O apparently/RB/O are/VBP/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O the/DT/O chemical/NN/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O standing/NN/O among/IN/O environmental/JJ/O groups/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O general/JJ/O public/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O April/NNP/O ,/,/O Hoechst/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O CFCs/NNPS/O in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O production/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O product/NN/O by/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O by/IN/O 1993/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hilger/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Hoechst/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O invest/VB/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O marks/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 27.2/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O a/DT/O plant/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O a/DT/O substitute/NN/O product/NN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O developed/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O says/VBZ/O is/VBZ/O unchlorinated/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O plant/NN/O ,/,/O likely/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O 10,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Hoechst/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O produce/VB/O about/IN/O 62,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O of/IN/O CFCs/NNS/O in/IN/O factories/NNS/O in/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Brazil/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Of/IN/O Hoechst/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 40.9/CD/O billion/CD/O marks/NNS/O in/IN/O group/NN/O sales/NNS/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O marks/NNS/O came/VBD/O from/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O CFCs/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O BASF/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O large/JJ/O chemicals/NNS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O formed/VBD/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O division/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O study/VB/O the/DT/O environmental/JJ/O impact/NN/O of/IN/O plastics/NNS/O and/CC/O will/MD/O investigate/VB/O all/DT/O possibilities/NNS/O of/IN/O recycling/VBG/O plastics/NNS/O ././O
