Adolph/NNP/B-ORG Coors/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Coors/NNP/B-ORG Brewing/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O will/MD/O test/VB/O market/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O of/IN/O bottled/JJ/O water/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NN/O beginning/VBG/O early/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Coors/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O hoping/VBG/O to/TO/O become/VB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O distribute/VB/O bottled/JJ/O water/NN/O nationwide/JJ/O ././O
Perrier/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O sold/VBN/O by/IN/O Perrier/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Source/NNP/B-ORG Perrier/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Evian/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O sold/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O BSN/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O distributed/VBN/O to/TO/O urban/JJ/O areas/NNS/O nationally/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O are/VBP/O less/RBR/O available/JJ/O in/IN/O rural/JJ/O communities/NNS/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O water/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O Coors/NNP/O Rocky/NNP/O Mountain/NNP/O Sparkling/NNP/O Water/NNP/O and/CC/O will/MD/O come/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O mountain/NN/O spring/NN/O as/IN/O water/NN/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O Coors/NNP/B-ORG beer/NN/O ././O
