Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG governors/NNS/O endorse/VBP/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O by/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Neal/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.C./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O require/VB/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O pursue/VB/O policies/NNS/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O eliminating/VBG/O inflation/NN/O within/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Such/PDT/O a/DT/O deadline/NN/O is/VBZ/O attainable/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Neal/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O subcommittee/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG chief/NN/O opposed/VBD/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O -/:/O introduced/VBN/O by/IN/O Reps./NNPS/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON Hamilton/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ind./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Byron/NNP/B-PERSON Dorgan/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.D./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O --/:/O that/IN/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O would/MD/O require/VB/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O disclose/VB/O all/DT/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O moves/NNS/O immediately/RB/O and/CC/O increase/VB/O outside/JJ/O scrutiny/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O interpreted/VBN/O as/IN/O great/JJ/O conflicts/NNS/O are/VBP/O relatively/RB/O minor/JJ/O issues/NNS/O of/IN/O tactics/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O elaborate/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O other/JJ/O words/NNS/O ,/,/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O lower/JJR/O and/CC/O unemployment/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O higher/JJR/O for/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O repeatedly/RB/O said/VBN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O goal/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O inflation/NN/O ,/,/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O ``/``/O whatever/WDT/O losses/NNS/O are/VBP/O incurred/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pursuing/NN/O of/IN/O price/NN/O stability/NN/O would/MD/O surely/RB/O be/VB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O made/VBN/O up/RP/O in/IN/O increased/VBN/O output/NN/O thereafter/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O warned/VBD/O that/IN/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O conquer/VB/O inflation/NN/O would/MD/O fail/VB/O --/:/O and/CC/O could/MD/O produce/VB/O ``/``/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O financial/JJ/O crunch/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O unless/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O accompanied/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O deficit/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O causes/VBZ/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O borrow/VB/O heavily/RB/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Neal/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O bill/NN/O originally/RB/O called/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O inflation/NN/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O one/CD/O percentage/NN/O point/NN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O for/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O a/DT/O zero/CD/O inflation/NN/O rate/NN/O thereafter/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O altered/VBD/O the/DT/O wording/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O endorsement/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O so/RB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O given/VBN/O little/JJ/O chance/NN/O of/IN/O passage/NN/O ././O
