Mr./NNP/O Manzanec/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O succeeds/VBZ/O retiring/VBG/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Dixon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O gas/NN/O supply/NN/O ,/,/O regulatory/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O transportation/NN/O and/CC/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O Panhandle/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG Pipe/NNP/I-ORG Line/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Trunkline/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG Transmission/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Algonquin/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG Transmission/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
All/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O units/NNS/O of/IN/O Panhandle/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O acquired/VBD/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
