The/DT/O recent/JJ/O bids/NNS/O for/IN/O United/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG have/VBP/O led/VBN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O move/VB/O with/IN/O supersonic/JJ/O speed/NN/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O incumbent/JJ/O airline/NN/O managements/NNS/O ././O
Transportation/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Sam/NNP/B-PERSON Skinner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O earlier/RBR/O fueled/VBD/O the/DT/O anti-takeover/JJ/O fires/NNS/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O quasi-xenophobic/JJ/O attacks/NNS/O on/IN/O foreign/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE carriers/NNS/O ,/,/O now/RB/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O would/MD/O further/RB/O disturb/VB/O the/DT/O jittery/JJ/O capital/NN/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Texas/NNP/B-GPE Rep./NNP/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON Bartlett/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O 40,000/CD/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG workers/NNS/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O district/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O good/JJ/O politics/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O bad/JJ/O law/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
