ARTICLE/NN/O I/NN/O ,/,/O SECTION/NN/O 7/CD/O ,/,/O CLAUSE/NN/O 2/CD/O :/:/O
Every/DT/O Bill/NN/O which/WDT/O shall/MD/O have/VB/O passed/VBN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Representatives/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O shall/MD/O ,/,/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O becomes/VBZ/O a/DT/O Law/NNP/O ,/,/O be/VB/O presented/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O President/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE ;/:/O If/IN/O he/PRP/O approve/VB/O he/PRP/O shall/MD/O sign/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O if/IN/O not/RB/O he/PRP/O shall/MD/O return/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O Objections/NNS/O to/TO/O that/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O shall/MD/O have/VB/O originated/VBN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O shall/MD/O enter/VB/O the/DT/O Objections/NNS/O at/IN/O large/JJ/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O Journal/NN/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O proceed/VB/O to/TO/O reconsider/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
If/IN/O after/IN/O such/JJ/O Reconsideration/NN/O two/CD/O thirds/NNS/O of/IN/O that/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG shall/MD/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O the/DT/O Bill/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O shall/MD/O be/VB/O sent/VBN/O ,/,/O together/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Objections/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O House/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O by/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O shall/MD/O likewise/RB/O be/VB/O reconsidered/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O if/IN/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O two/CD/O thirds/NNS/O of/IN/O that/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O it/PRP/O shall/MD/O become/VB/O a/DT/O Law/NN/O .../:/O ././O
ARTICLE/NN/O I/NN/O ,/,/O SECTION/NN/O 7/CD/O ,/,/O CLAUSE/NN/O 3/CD/O :/:/O
Every/DT/O Order/NN/O ,/,/O Resolution/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O Vote/NN/O to/TO/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O Concurrence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O House/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Representatives/NNPS/I-ORG may/MD/O be/VB/O necessary/JJ/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O except/IN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O Adjournment/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O shall/MD/O be/VB/O presented/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O President/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE ;/:/O and/CC/O before/IN/O the/DT/O Same/JJ/O shall/MD/O take/VB/O Effect/NN/O ,/,/O shall/MD/O be/VB/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O or/CC/O being/VBG/O disapproved/VBN/O by/IN/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O shall/MD/O be/VB/O repassed/VBN/O by/IN/O two/CD/O thirds/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O House/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Representatives/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Rules/NNPS/O and/CC/O Limitations/NNPS/O prescribed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Case/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Bill/NN/O ././O
Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O Quayle/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Budget/NNP/O Director/NNP/O Darman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O recently/RB/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O joined/VBN/O the/DT/O search/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O came/VBD/O up/RP/O again/RB/O when/WRB/O Marlin/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzwater/NNP/I-PERSON explained/VBD/O the/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O argument/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O provisions/NNS/O above/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG press/NN/O corps/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O harder/JJR/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O anyone/NN/O yet/RB/O understands/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O fight/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O constitutional/JJ/O prerogatives/NNS/O is/VBZ/O about/IN/O politics/NNS/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O about/IN/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O 1974/CD/O budget/NN/O ``/``/O reform/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O passed/VBN/O over/IN/O President/NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O veto/NN/O ,/,/O took/VBD/O away/RP/O the/DT/O presidential/JJ/O impoundment/NN/O power/NN/O ,/,/O thereby/RB/O introducing/VBG/O monstrous/JJ/O CRs/NNS/O and/CC/O eviscerating/VBG/O the/DT/O presidential/JJ/O veto/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Glazier/NNP/B-PERSON discovered/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Founders/NNS/O had/VBD/O worried/VBN/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG might/MD/O take/VB/O the/DT/O President/NNP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O loop/NN/O ././O
Article/NN/O I/NN/O ,/,/O Section/NN/O 7/CD/O ,/,/O Clause/NN/O 3/CD/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O whether/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O called/VBN/O an/DT/O ``/``/O order/NN/O ,/,/O resolution/NN/O or/CC/O vote/NN/O ''/''/O or/CC/O anything/NN/O else/RB/O ,/,/O Presidents/NNS/O must/MD/O have/VB/O the/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O veto/VB/O ././O
Labeling/VBG/O an/DT/O omnibus/JJ/O budget/NN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O bill/NN/O ''/''/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O deprive/VB/O the/DT/O President/NNP/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O power/NN/O to/TO/O veto/NN/O items/NNS/O ././O
Finding/VBG/O a/DT/O test/NN/O case/NN/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O hard/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O something/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O said/VBD/O for/IN/O picking/VBG/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O one/CD/O possible/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O the/DT/O perfect/JJ/O case/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG blinked/VBD/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O court/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O worried/VBD/O about/IN/O an/DT/O Interior/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG directive/NN/O to/TO/O log/VB/O all/DT/O communications/NNS/O with/IN/O Members/NNS/O or/CC/O their/PRP$/O staffs/NNS/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG inserted/VBD/O the/DT/O following/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O Interior/NNP/B-ORG appropriation/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O None/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O available/JJ/O under/IN/O this/DT/O title/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O prepare/VB/O reports/NNS/O on/IN/O contacts/NNS/O between/IN/O employees/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Dept./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Interior/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Members/NNS/O and/CC/O committees/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O their/PRP$/O staff/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG warned/VBD/O that/IN/O this/DT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O unconstitutional/JJ/O usurpation/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O power/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O means/VBZ/O Interior/JJ/B-ORG contacts/NNS/O can/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O logged/VBN/O only/RB/O on/IN/O one/CD/O day/NN/O --/:/O a/DT/O Sunday/NNP/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O already/RB/O passed/VBN/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O another/DT/O unconstitutional/JJ/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Dingell/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O again/RB/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O the/DT/O Fairness/NNP/O Doctrine/NNP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O dead/JJ/O ././O
President/NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON vetoed/VBD/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O violation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ``/``/O Fairness/NNP/O ''/''/O Doctrine/NNP/O 's/POS/O enthusiasts/NNS/O are/VBP/O incumbents/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG who/WP/O know/VBP/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O squelch/VBP/O lively/JJ/O discussions/NNS/O on/IN/O broadcasts/NNS/O ,/,/O deterring/VBG/O feisty/JJ/O challengers/NNS/O ././O
Commenting/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O mess/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O perception/NN/O out/IN/O there/RB/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O fault/NN/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
And/CC/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O look/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O leadership/NN/O and/CC/O ask/VB/O them/PRP/O why/WRB/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O perception/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Exactly/RB/O right/RB/O ././O
Senator/NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Inouye/NNP/I-PERSON agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O close/VB/O some/DT/O bases/NNS/O in/IN/O Hawaii/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O goodies/NNS/O as/IN/O $/$/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O parking/NN/O lot/NN/O at/IN/O Walter/NNP/B-ORG Reed/NNP/I-ORG Hospital/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Conference/NN/O negotiator/NN/O Rep./NNP/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Hefner/NNP/I-PERSON pulled/VBD/O down/RP/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O military/JJ/O bases/NNS/O for/IN/O North/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O graciously/RB/O allowed/VBN/O Senator/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Sasser/NNP/I-PERSON $/$/O 70/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O bases/NNS/O in/IN/O Tennessee/NNP/B-GPE ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O take/VB/O the/DT/O Constitution/NNP/O in/IN/O one/CD/O hand/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O budget/NN/O ax/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O and/CC/O get/VB/O to/TO/O work/VB/O ././O
He/PRP/O should/MD/O chop/VB/O out/RP/O both/DT/O unconstitutional/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O and/CC/O budget/NN/O pork/NN/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O have/VB/O lost/VBN/O any/DT/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O discipline/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O the/DT/O country/NN/O must/MD/O learn/VB/O to/TO/O live/VB/O forever/RB/O with/IN/O this/DT/O mess/NN/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O the/DT/O power/NN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O how/WRB/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE works/VBZ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O only/RB/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O use/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
