The/DT/O expected/VBN/O Canadian/JJ/O move/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O welcomed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O even/RB/O though/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O opposed/VBN/O such/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE actions/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O embargo/NN/O against/IN/O Cuba/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O invasion/NN/O of/IN/O Grenada/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Contra/NNP/B-ORG guerrillas/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O though/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O has/VBZ/O supported/VBN/O Canadian/JJ/O membership/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE priority/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O might/MD/O not/RB/O side/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Americans/NNPS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O reason/NN/O why/WRB/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O membership/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O OAS/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O ,/,/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O item/NN/O high/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE agenda/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Allan/NNP/B-PERSON Gotlieb/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O Canadian/JJ/O ambassador/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O application/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O announced/VBN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O by/IN/O Canadian/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Brian/NNP/B-PERSON Mulroney/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O attending/VBG/O a/DT/O centenary/JJ/O celebration/NN/O of/IN/O Costa/NNP/O Rican/NNP/O democracy/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O a/DT/O larger/JJR/O and/CC/O more/RBR/O beneficial/JJ/O role/NN/O to/TO/O play/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hemisphere/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Mulroney/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O recently/RB/O ././O
Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O at/IN/O times/NNS/O ,/,/O could/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O awkward/JJ/O OAS/NNP/B-ORG partner/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE if/IN/O its/PRP$/O United/NNP/B-ORG Nations/NNPS/I-ORG voting/NN/O record/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O indication/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O U.N./NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Assembly/NNP/I-ORG votes/VBZ/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE voted/VBD/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE only/RB/O 63/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
France/NNP/B-GPE voted/VBD/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 76/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 79/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 83/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Latin/NNPS/O Americans/NNPS/O see/VBP/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O a/DT/O non-interventionist/JJ/O power/NN/O that/WDT/O respects/VBZ/O their/PRP$/O sovereignty/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O OAS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O tries/VBZ/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O peace/NN/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O development/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O Americas/NNPS/B-LOC ,/,/O is/VBZ/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O find/VB/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE political/JJ/O crisis/NN/O ././O
Cuba/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O suspended/VBN/O from/IN/O OAS/NNP/B-ORG membership/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O organization/NN/O 's/POS/O members/NNS/O are/VBP/O discussing/VBG/O Cuba/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O reinstatement/NN/O ././O
