Rochester/NNP/B-ORG Telephone/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Viroqua/NNP/B-ORG Telephone/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Viroqua/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wis/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Viroqua/NNP/B-ORG serves/VBZ/O about/IN/O 3,000/CD/O access/NN/O lines/NNS/O in/IN/O western/JJ/O Wisconsin/NNP/B-GPE ././O
