The/DT/O two/CD/O lawmakers/NNS/O sparred/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O highly/RB/O personal/JJ/O fashion/NN/O ,/,/O violating/VBG/O usual/JJ/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG decorum/NN/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O hearing/VBG/O this/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O opposition/NN/O first/JJ/O hand/NN/O during/IN/O meetings/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O with/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O senators/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O trend/NN/O is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O advocates/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O cut/NN/O less/RBR/O optimistic/JJ/O about/IN/O success/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O significant/JJ/O factor/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O capitalgains/NNS/O debate/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O extent/NN/O to/TO/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O a/DT/O purely/RB/O political/JJ/O battle/NN/O between/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Majority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O clear/JJ/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O wavering/VBG/O colleagues/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O important/JJ/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O personally/RB/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Mitchell/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O leading/VBG/O Democrats/NNPS/O plan/VBP/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O up/IN/O the/DT/O heat/NN/O again/RB/O by/IN/O holding/VBG/O a/DT/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O to/TO/O bash/VB/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ././O
Gerald/NNP/B-PERSON F./NNP/I-PERSON Seib/NNP/I-PERSON contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O immigration/NN/O authorities/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O found/VBD/O 658/CD/O more/JJR/O Chinese/NNP/O among/IN/O Vietnamese/JJ/O boat/NN/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O bringing/VBG/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Chinese/NNP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O posing/VBG/O as/IN/O Vietnamese/JJ/O refugees/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O 1,642/CD/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O send/VB/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNP/O back/RB/O home/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O negotiating/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O government/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Chinese/NNP/O were/VBD/O among/IN/O 3,372/CD/O boat/NN/O people/NNS/O supposedly/RB/O from/IN/O Vietnam/NNP/B-GPE who/WP/O arrived/VBD/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O 219/CD/O for/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Second/JJ/O in/IN/O command/NN/O from/IN/O 1979/CD/O to/TO/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Verne/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O a/DT/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE court/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O great/JJ/O disorder/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O reigned/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O led/VBD/O her/PRP/O into/IN/O temptation/NN/O ././O
Tony/NNP/B-PERSON Lambert/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Verne/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O successor/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O mint/NN/O 's/POS/O losses/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O theft/NN/O run/VBP/O into/IN/O the/DT/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O francs/NNS/O ././O
El/NNP/B-GPE Salvador/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O destroying/VBG/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 1.6/CD/O million/CD/O pounds/NNS/O of/IN/O food/NN/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O rotted/VBN/O in/IN/O government/NN/O warehouses/NNS/O ,/,/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O Supply/NNP/B-ORG Regulator/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O to/TO/O burn/VB/O rice/NN/O ,/,/O corn/NN/O and/CC/O beans/NNS/O that/WDT/O spoiled/VBD/O because/IN/O of/IN/O neglect/NN/O and/CC/O corruption/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O Christian/NNP/O Democrat/NNP/O government/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O information/NN/O service/NN/O SISAL/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Another/DT/O 250/CD/O Libyans/NNPS/O were/VBD/O already/RB/O in/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O stage/VB/O a/DT/O day/NN/O of/IN/O mourning/VBG/O for/IN/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O colonial/NN/O rule/NN/O between/IN/O 1911/CD/O and/CC/O 1943/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Tripoli/NNP/B-GPE says/VBZ/O Rome/NNP/B-GPE kidnapped/VBD/O 5,000/CD/O Libyans/NNPS/O and/CC/O deported/VBD/O them/PRP/O as/RB/O forced/VBN/O labor/NN/O ././O
Libya/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O revolutionary/JJ/O Committees/NNS/O have/VBP/O threatened/VBN/O attacks/NNS/O on/IN/O Italians/NNPS/O if/IN/O Rome/NNP/B-GPE does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O pay/VB/O compensation/NN/O ././O
Canadian/NNP/O Indians/NNPS/O are/VBP/O taking/VBG/O five/CD/O countries/NNS/O to/TO/O court/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O low/JJ/O military/JJ/O flights/NNS/O over/IN/O their/PRP$/O homes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Dutch/NNP/I-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Representatives/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Inuit/NNP/O and/CC/O Cree/NNP/O peoples/NNS/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O Quebec/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Labrador/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O northeastern/JJ/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE told/VBD/O the/DT/O ministry/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O planned/VBN/O action/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O ministry/NN/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
They/PRP/O also/RB/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O a/DT/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG training/NN/O base/NN/O being/VBG/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Canadian/NNP/I-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O against/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE Netherlands/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O ministry/NN/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE suspended/VBD/O imports/NNS/O of/IN/O French/NNP/O mushrooms/NNS/O after/IN/O finding/VBG/O some/DT/O contaminated/VBN/O by/IN/O radiation/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O official/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Welfare/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O testing/VBG/O imported/VBN/O food/NN/O from/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC since/IN/O the/DT/O April/NNP/O 1986/CD/O Chernobyl/NNP/B-GPE accident/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Venice/NNP/B-GPE city/NN/O council/NN/O is/VBZ/O battling/VBG/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O tap/VB/O huge/JJ/O gas/NN/O fields/NNS/O off/IN/O the/DT/O coast/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O says/VBZ/O will/MD/O speed/VB/O up/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O slow/JJ/O sinking/NN/O into/IN/O its/PRP$/O lagoon/NN/O ././O
Alarmed/JJ/O councilors/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O project/NN/O could/MD/O jeopardize/VB/O costly/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O ,/,/O or/CC/O slow/VB/O down/IN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O subsidence/NN/O that/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O Venice/NNP/B-GPE subject/JJ/O to/TO/O regular/JJ/O and/CC/O destructive/JJ/O flooding/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O council/NN/O unanimously/RB/O opposed/VBD/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O of/IN/O AGIP/NNP/B-ORG pumping/VBG/O out/IN/O the/DT/O methane/NN/O gas/NN/O and/CC/O swiftly/RB/O appealed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Giulio/NNP/B-PERSON Andreotti/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O yet/RB/O to/TO/O reply/VB/O ././O
AGIP/NNP/B-ORG refused/VBD/O to/TO/O reconsider/VB/O and/CC/O says/VBZ/O drilling/NN/O is/VBZ/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O start/VB/O early/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Thieves/NNS/O stole/VBD/O a/DT/O 12th/JJ/O century/NN/O fresco/NN/O from/IN/O an/DT/O abandoned/VBN/O church/NN/O in/IN/O Camerino/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O by/IN/O removing/VBG/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O wall/NN/O on/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O work/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O painted/VBN/O ,/,/O police/NNS/O said/VBD/O .../:/O ././O
The/DT/O vehicle/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O top/JJ/O speed/NN/O of/IN/O 65/CD/O miles/NNS/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O and/CC/O requires/VBZ/O recharging/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O standard/JJ/O wall/NN/O socket/NN/O every/DT/O 100/CD/O miles/NNS/O ././O
