Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Breeden/NNP/I-PERSON had/VBD/O n't/RB/O noticed/VBN/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O new/JJ/O desk/NN/O had/VBD/O just/RB/O four/CD/O telephone/NN/O lines/NNS/O and/CC/O one/CD/O phone/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O ,/,/O after/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O only/RB/O his/PRP$/O second/JJ/O full/JJ/O day/NN/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O lines/NNS/O became/VBD/O painfully/RB/O apparent/JJ/O ././O
With/IN/O other/JJ/O anxious/JJ/O calls/NNS/O pouring/VBG/O in/IN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O recalls/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O either/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O disconnect/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG or/CC/O go/VB/O out/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O 's/POS/O desk/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O happen/VB/O again/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O all/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O ``/``/O command/NN/O center/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O office/NN/O layout/NN/O illustrate/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O stance/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O top/JJ/O securities/NNS/O regulator/NN/O ././O
Like/IN/O his/PRP$/O predecessor/NN/O ,/,/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Ruder/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O faced/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O crisis/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O markets/NNS/O soon/RB/O after/IN/O coming/VBG/O into/IN/O office/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O unlike/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ruder/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O during/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O damaged/VBD/O himself/PRP/O by/IN/O saying/VBG/O rather/RB/O offhandedly/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O closed/VBN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O turning/VBG/O the/DT/O market/NN/O drop/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O advantage/NN/O ,/,/O using/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O further/VB/O his/PRP$/O agenda/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
More/RBR/O broadly/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O ``/``/O modernize/VB/O ''/''/O regulation/NN/O by/IN/O eliminating/VBG/O barriers/NNS/O between/IN/O commercial/JJ/O and/CC/O investment/JJ/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O by/IN/O helping/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE financial/JJ/O firms/NNS/O compete/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O global/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O unlike/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ruder/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O position/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O somewhere/RB/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O agenda/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG aide/NN/O who/WP/O worked/VBD/O closely/RB/O with/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O savvy/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O ways/NNS/O of/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O waiting/VBG/O to/TO/O see/VB/O the/DT/O results/NNS/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O pending/VBG/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG studies/NNS/O of/IN/O junk/NN/O market/NN/O liquidity/NN/O and/CC/O disclosure/NN/O rules/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O kept/VBN/O a/DT/O close/JJ/O wrap/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O names/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O under/IN/O consideration/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O crucial/JJ/O post/NN/O of/IN/O enforcement/NN/O director/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O job/NN/O vacant/JJ/O since/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG seems/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O let/VB/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O chairman/NN/O have/VBP/O his/PRP$/O way/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O while/NN/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O during/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O confirmation/NN/O hearing/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O senators/NNS/O asked/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O introduce/VB/O his/PRP$/O children/NNS/O three/CD/O separate/JJ/O times/NNS/O --/:/O more/RBR/O often/RB/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O asked/VBD/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O qualifications/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O ././O
Not/RB/O everyone/NN/O has/VBZ/O jumped/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON bandwagon/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Some/DT/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE contend/VBP/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O too/RB/O soon/RB/O to/TO/O tell/VB/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O help/VB/O or/CC/O hinder/VB/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O this/DT/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O test/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O congressional/JJ/O aide/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O fairly/RB/O stressful/JJ/O weekend/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O my/PRP$/O sense/NN/O is/VBZ/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O had/VBN/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Breeden/NNP/I-PERSON there/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O much/RB/O of/IN/O a/DT/O difference/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
For/IN/O some/DT/O at/IN/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O agency/NN/O that/WDT/O covets/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O independence/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O be/VB/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE insider/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O note/VBP/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O adorned/VBN/O his/PRP$/O office/NN/O with/IN/O five/CD/O photos/NNS/O of/IN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O featuring/VBG/O the/DT/O First/NNP/O Dog/NNP/O ,/,/O Millie/NNP/O ././O
They/PRP/O worry/VBP/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O will/MD/O roll/VB/O over/RP/O when/WRB/O told/VBN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O so/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON already/RB/O has/VBZ/O shown/VBN/O an/DT/O eagerness/NN/O to/TO/O run/VB/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG his/PRP$/O way/NN/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O Monday/NNP/O market/NN/O rebound/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG exchange/NN/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O told/VBD/O Cable/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Network/NNP/I-ORG viewers/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O industrial/JJ/O average/NN/O had/VBD/O turned/VBN/O down/RB/O 70/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O showed/VBD/O the/DT/O DJIA/NNP/O up/RB/O 30/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON instructed/VBD/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG staffers/NNS/O to/TO/O inform/VB/O the/DT/O network/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O airing/VBG/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O number/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O plunge/NN/O that/WDT/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O happen/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O use/VB/O a/DT/O far/RB/O more/RBR/O catastrophic/JJ/O event/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE earthquake/NN/O --/:/O to/TO/O move/VB/O another/DT/O rule/NN/O change/NN/O past/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Though/IN/O obscure/JJ/O to/TO/O most/JJS/O investors/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O list/VB/O options/NNS/O on/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O one/CD/O exchange/NN/O has/VBZ/O aroused/VBN/O much/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O mainly/RB/O because/IN/O regional/JJ/O exchanges/NNS/O fear/VBP/O the/DT/O change/NN/O could/MD/O bankrupt/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
Congressmen/NNS/O raised/VBD/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O yesterday/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O hearing/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O not/RB/O missing/VBG/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O press/VB/O his/PRP$/O agenda/NN/O ,/,/O cited/VBD/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O event/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O contended/VBD/O ,/,/O simply/RB/O shows/VBZ/O the/DT/O ``/``/O vulnerability/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O listings/NNS/O on/IN/O only/JJ/O one/CD/O exchange/NN/O ././O
