Labor/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON Dole/NNP/I-PERSON named/VBD/O a/DT/O mediator/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O resolve/VB/O the/DT/O lengthy/JJ/O labor/NN/O dispute/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Mine/NNP/I-ORG Workers/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O Pittston/NNP/B-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Previous/JJ/O talks/NNS/O between/IN/O Pittston/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Greenwich/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O union/NN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O sporadic/JJ/O and/CC/O unsuccessful/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O union/NN/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O strike/NN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O after/IN/O Pittston/NNP/B-ORG refused/VBD/O to/TO/O sign/VB/O the/DT/O UMW/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O national/JJ/O labor/NN/O pact/NN/O ././O
Pittston/NNP/B-ORG seeks/VBZ/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O health/NN/O and/CC/O pension/NN/O benefits/NNS/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ././O
No/DT/O schedule/NN/O for/IN/O formal/JJ/O talks/NNS/O was/VBD/O set/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O meetings/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O soon/RB/O ././O
