In/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O home/NN/O improvement/NN/O items/NNS/O have/VBP/O sagged/VBN/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O big/JJ/O ticket/NN/O durable/JJ/O goods/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O show/NN/O also/RB/O signals/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O return/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O television/NN/O celebrity/NN/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O public/JJ/O television/NN/O station/NN/O WGBH/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE fired/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON after/IN/O a/DT/O sponsor/NN/O protested/VBD/O some/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O numerous/JJ/O commercial/JJ/O endorsements/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O host/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O This/NNP/O Old/NNP/O House/NNP/O ''/''/O became/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG top/JJ/O 10/CD/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O airing/VBG/O weekly/RB/O on/IN/O about/IN/O 300/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O network/NN/O 's/POS/O stations/NNS/O and/CC/O seen/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O average/NN/O of/IN/O 12/CD/O million/CD/O viewers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O ecstatic/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O change/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O new/JJ/O syndicated/VBN/O program/NN/O is/VBZ/O called/VBN/O ``/``/O Home/NNP/O Again/NNP/O with/IN/O Bob/NNP/O Vila/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON criticized/VBD/O his/PRP$/O old/JJ/O show/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O continuing/VBG/O with/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O host/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Public/NNP/O TV/NNP/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O fantasy/NN/O land/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
While/IN/O Sears/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O brouhaha/NN/O over/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O commercial/JJ/O endorsements/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O building/VBG/O a/DT/O fence/NN/O around/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O affections/NNS/O ././O
His/PRP$/O contract/NN/O makes/VBZ/O him/PRP/O ``/``/O exclusive/JJ/O ''/''/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Sears/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O home/NN/O improvement/NN/O marketing/NN/O campaigns/NNS/O ././O
His/PRP$/O other/JJ/O agreements/NNS/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O products/NNS/O have/VBP/O expired/VBN/O ././O
Little/JJ/O matter/NN/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Vila/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O complains/VBZ/O that/IN/O ``/``/O public/JJ/O TV/NN/O never/RB/O paid/VBD/O me/PRP/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 40,000/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O compensation/NN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Sears/NNP/B-ORG contract/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O multimillion/NN/O dollar/NN/O deal/NN/O ././O
