One/CD/O day/NN/O after/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG made/VBD/O top/JJ/O management/NN/O changes/NNS/O and/CC/O disclosed/VBD/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O business/NN/O tie/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O stock/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O trade/VB/O and/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O forecast/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O significant/JJ/O ''/''/O drop/NN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O in/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O core/NN/O product/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O disclosure/NN/O came/VBD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O after/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG alerted/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O that/IN/O trading/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O resume/VB/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O stock/NN/O until/IN/O additional/JJ/O information/NN/O about/IN/O developments/NNS/O was/VBD/O provided/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O would/MD/O resume/VB/O trading/VBG/O of/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG stock/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
Delmed/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O and/CC/O sells/VBZ/O peritoneal/JJ/O dialysis/NN/O products/NNS/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O treating/VBG/O kidney/NN/O disease/NN/O ,/,/O on/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O announced/VBD/O the/DT/O resignations/NNS/O of/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Ehrlich/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O of/IN/O Leslie/NNP/B-PERSON I./NNP/I-PERSON Shapiro/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O were/VBD/O succeeded/VBN/O by/IN/O executives/NNS/O of/IN/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O about/IN/O 45/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O current/JJ/O distribution/NN/O arrangement/NN/O ends/VBZ/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O although/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O some/DT/O supplies/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O peritoneal/JJ/O dialysis/NN/O products/NNS/O to/TO/O National/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O West/NNP/O German/NNP/O pharmaceutical/JJ/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O discussing/VBG/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O buy/VB/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG stock/NN/O for/IN/O cash/NN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O its/PRP$/O beneficial/JJ/O ownership/NN/O to/TO/O between/IN/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O also/RB/O would/MD/O combine/VB/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Delmed/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O say/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O still/RB/O would/MD/O infuse/VB/O cash/NN/O into/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG but/CC/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O originally/RB/O expected/VBN/O ././O
Delmed/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O would/MD/O receive/VB/O the/DT/O North/NNP/O American/NNP/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O certain/JJ/O Fresenius/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG products/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O option/NN/O for/IN/O Delmed/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Ogden/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O no/DT/O discussions/NNS/O about/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O sale/NN/O are/VBP/O under/IN/O way/NN/O ././O
