But/CC/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O giant/NN/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O lost/VBN/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O key/NN/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O archrival/JJ/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Kodak/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Rochester/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O had/VBD/O bid/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O business/NN/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Armonk/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O loss/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O setback/NN/O to/TO/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O pointed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG contract/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O example/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O success/NN/O in/IN/O systems/NNS/O integration/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O emerging/VBG/O business/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O computer/NN/O makers/NNS/O or/CC/O consultants/NNS/O provide/VBP/O turnkey/NN/O communications/NNS/O and/CC/O computing/VBG/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O major/JJ/O corporations/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O in/IN/O negotiation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O why/WRB/O we/PRP/O went/VBD/O with/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O data/NNS/O center/NN/O management/NN/O .../:/O and/CC/O now/RB/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O voice/NN/O and/CC/O data/NNS/O telecommunications/NNS/O ././O
