This/DT/O year/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O 75th/JJ/O anniversary/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O some/DT/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG think/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O time/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O a/DT/O fresh/JJ/O look/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O 75/CD/O years/NNS/O there/RB/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O things/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O worth/JJ/O reexamining/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O regional/JJ/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG setup/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O may/MD/O be/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O date/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O earlier/JJR/O years/NNS/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O have/VB/O seemed/VBN/O reasonable/JJ/O to/TO/O give/VB/O Richmond/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O bank/NN/O and/CC/O allow/VB/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE only/RB/O a/DT/O branch/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE bank/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O times/NNS/O have/VBP/O changed/VBN/O ././O
Maybe/RB/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O regional/JJ/O system/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O anachronism/NN/O ;/:/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O after/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O national/JJ/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O beginning/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O treasury/NN/O secretary/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O comptroller/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O were/VBD/O both/DT/O ex/FW/O officio/FW/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O 1935/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O find/VB/O someone/NN/O or/CC/O something/NN/O to/TO/O blame/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Great/NNP/O Depression/NNP/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O both/PDT/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O comptroller/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
Carter/NNP/B-PERSON Glass/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O treasury/NN/O secretary/NN/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O then/RB/O back/RB/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O probably/RB/O influenced/VBD/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O he/PRP/O felt/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O deal/NN/O of/IN/O power/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O somehow/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O thing/NN/O ././O
Times/NNS/O have/VBP/O changed/VBN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Byron/NNP/B-PERSON Dorgan/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.D/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O has/VBZ/O introduced/VBN/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O co-sponsored/VBN/O by/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON Hamilton/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ind./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O put/VB/O the/DT/O treasury/NN/O secretary/NN/O back/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O doubt/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O change/NN/O would/MD/O accomplish/VB/O much/RB/O but/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O in/IN/O 1935/CD/O ,/,/O would/MD/O be/VB/O doing/VBG/O something/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O far/RB/O no/DT/O one/NN/O has/VBZ/O suggested/VBN/O putting/VBG/O the/DT/O comptroller/NN/O back/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Brady/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O incumbent/JJ/O treasury/NN/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O of/IN/O course/NN/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O like/VB/O it/PRP/O much/RB/O ././O
Like/IN/O most/JJS/O treasury/NN/O secretaries/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON takes/VBZ/O a/DT/O keen/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O monetary/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O ,/,/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O taking/VBG/O an/DT/O especially/RB/O keen/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O board/NN/O matters/NNS/O even/RB/O before/IN/O he/PRP/O went/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O treasury/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O October/NNP/O 1987/CD/O market/NN/O crash/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O citizen/NN/O headed/VBD/O a/DT/O presidential/JJ/O commission/NN/O that/WDT/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O what/WP/O went/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O and/CC/O what/WP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O done/VBN/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O 's/POS/O recommendations/NNS/O was/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O probably/RB/O the/DT/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O should/MD/O coordinate/VB/O regulation/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O plenty/NN/O of/IN/O responsibilities/NNS/O in/IN/O times/NNS/O of/IN/O market/NN/O turmoil/NN/O and/CC/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O again/RB/O in/IN/O 1989/CD/O it/PRP/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O handled/VBN/O them/PRP/O well/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O he/PRP/O thought/VBD/O government/NN/O agencies/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O market/NN/O drop/NN/O were/VBD/O better/RB/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O coordinate/VB/O their/PRP$/O actions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O left/VBN/O no/DT/O doubt/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O still/RB/O likes/VBZ/O the/DT/O ideas/NNS/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O advanced/VBD/O nearly/RB/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
In/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O moreover/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O joined/VBN/O other/JJ/O administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O in/IN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O urge/VB/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG toward/IN/O lower/JJR/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O urging/VBG/O admittedly/RB/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O gentle/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG Post/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O early/JJ/O October/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O be/VB/O slightly/RB/O more/RBR/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O curbing/VBG/O inflation/NN/O than/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O may/MD/O put/VB/O slightly/RB/O more/JJR/O emphasis/NN/O on/IN/O spurring/VBG/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O least/JJS/O some/DT/O economists/NNS/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O argue/VB/O that/IN/O inflation/NN/O deserves/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O emphasis/NN/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O the/DT/B-ORG St./NNP/I-ORG Louis/NNP/I-ORG Fed/NNP/I-ORG held/VBD/O a/DT/O conference/NN/O to/TO/O assess/VB/O the/DT/O system/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O 75/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Equally/RB/O importantly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O treasury/NN/O secretary/NN/O has/VBZ/O spearheaded/VBN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE dollar/NN/O down/RP/O by/IN/O shopping/VBG/O avidly/RB/O for/IN/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O yen/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O treasury/NN/O can/MD/O do/VB/O something/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O hope/NN/O of/IN/O success/NN/O it/PRP/O needs/VBZ/O help/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O helping/VBG/O ,/,/O but/CC/O apparently/RB/O not/RB/O especially/RB/O eagerly/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O intervening/VBG/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O currency/NN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O all/RB/O right/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O through/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O appeared/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ``/``/O sterilizing/VBG/O ''/''/O the/DT/O intervention/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O other/JJ/O words/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O offsetting/VBG/O purchases/NNS/O of/IN/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O yen/NN/O by/IN/O buying/VBG/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O domestic/JJ/O money/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O sterilized/VBN/O intervention/NN/O may/MD/O have/VB/O some/DT/O effect/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O traders/NNS/O see/VBP/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O market/NN/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O make/VB/O them/PRP/O tread/VB/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O carefully/RB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O fear/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O may/MD/O do/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O generally/RB/O accepted/VBN/O that/IN/O sterilized/VBN/O intervention/NN/O has/VBZ/O little/RB/O or/CC/O no/DT/O lasting/JJ/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O currency/NN/O values/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O August/NNP/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O have/VB/O stopped/VBN/O sterilizing/VBG/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O much/JJ/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O highly/RB/O volatile/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O let/VBN/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O slip/VBP/O slightly/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O reason/NN/O was/VBD/O dollar/NN/O intervention/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O gloomy/JJ/O reports/NNS/O on/IN/O manufacturing/VBG/O employment/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O the/DT/O Friday/NNP/O 13/CD/O market/NN/O drop/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O associates/NNS/O know/VBP/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Feldstein/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O argued/VBD/O forcefully/RB/O that/IN/O a/DT/O government/NN/O that/WDT/O wants/VBZ/O steady/JJ/O ,/,/O stable/JJ/O exchange/NN/O rates/NNS/O might/MD/O try/VB/O some/DT/O steady/JJ/O stable/JJ/O economic/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Trying/VBG/O to/TO/O manage/VB/O exchange/NN/O rates/NNS/O to/TO/O some/DT/O desired/VBN/O level/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O would/MD/O mean/VB/O diverting/VBG/O monetary/JJ/O and/CC/O fiscal/JJ/O policies/NNS/O from/IN/O their/PRP$/O customary/JJ/O roles/NNS/O and/CC/O thereby/RB/O risking/VBG/O excessive/JJ/O inflation/NN/O and/CC/O unemployment/NN/O and/CC/O inadequate/JJ/O capital/NN/O formation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O more/RBR/O we/PRP/O think/VBP/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O we/PRP/O suspect/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O indeed/RB/O have/VB/O enough/JJ/O power/NN/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O already/RB/O is/VBZ/O ././O
