Protective/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O will/MD/O start/VB/O coming/VBG/O down/RB/O within/IN/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O industry/NN/O next/IN/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O big/JJ/O industrial/JJ/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O insurance/NN/O from/IN/O carriers/NNS/O in/IN/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O EC/NNP/B-ORG country/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Windsor/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O first/JJ/O step/NN/O toward/IN/O establishing/VBG/O a/DT/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O European/JJ/O market/NN/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O most/JJS/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE insurers/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O rushed/VBN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O business/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC because/IN/O they/PRP/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O European/JJ/O market/NN/O will/MD/O still/RB/O be/VB/O dominated/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O domestic/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kiep/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O sought/VBD/O the/DT/O combination/NN/O because/IN/O ``/``/O all/DT/O our/PRP$/O large/JJ/O clients/NNS/O in/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O becoming/VBG/O European/NNP/O companies/NNS/O or/CC/O multinational/JJ/O companies/NNS/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O expect/VB/O an/DT/O insurance/NN/O broker/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O them/PRP/O as/RB/O well/RB/O in/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O in/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Beatrice/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Garcia/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
