The/DT/O proposal/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O immediately/RB/O rebuffed/VBN/O by/IN/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG parent/NN/O ,/,/O DWG/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Renee/NNP/B-PERSON Mottram/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O at/IN/O DWG/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O suitor/NN/O ,/,/O Stevric/NNP/B-ORG Equity/NNP/I-ORG Ventures/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O of/IN/O Mineola/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O characterized/VBD/O its/PRP$/O proposal/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O first/RB/O truly/RB/O independent/JJ/O offer/NN/O which/WDT/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O pit/VB/O one/CD/O interest/NN/O group/NN/O against/IN/O another/DT/O within/IN/O the/DT/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O franchisee/NN/O community/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O DWG/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Fla./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O financeer/NN/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON Posner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O rejected/VBD/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG franchisees/NNS/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Since/IN/O then/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O group/NN/O of/IN/O franchisees/NNS/O has/VBZ/O banded/VBN/O together/RB/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O wrestle/VB/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Posner/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Arby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O marketing/NN/O ,/,/O franchising/VBG/O and/CC/O service/NN/O company/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O 2,100/CD/O restaurants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O ././O
Stevric/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O principals/NNS/O ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Steven/NNP/B-PERSON Buckley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O led/VBD/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O group/NN/O that/WDT/O acquired/VBD/O the/DT/O Nathan/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Famous/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG restaurant/NN/O chain/NN/O and/CC/O subsequently/RB/O served/VBD/O as/IN/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O officers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
