Castle/NNP/B-ORG Harlan/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE merchant/NN/O bank/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Quantum/NNP/B-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O combination/NN/O of/IN/O cash/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O of/IN/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O liabilities/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O balance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O liabilities/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O transferred/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
Quantum/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O equity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O necessary/JJ/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O confirmation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O ././O
Castle/NNP/B-ORG Harlan/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Quantum/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O filed/VBN/O within/IN/O 60/CD/O days/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Bankruptcy/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Pittsburgh/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O certain/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O obtaining/VBG/O financing/NN/O ././O
Castle/NNP/B-ORG Harlan/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/DT/O such/JJ/O financing/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O being/VBG/O sought/VBN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O a/DT/O formal/JJ/O proposal/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O to/TO/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O trustee/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG creditors/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O ././O
Sharon/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Farrell/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O filed/VBD/O for/IN/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O maninstays/NNS/O of/IN/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE financier/NN/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON Posner/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O empire/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Posner/NNP/B-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O April/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O remains/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O wields/VBZ/O little/JJ/O power/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Quantum/NNP/B-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O $/$/O 2.1/CD/O billion/CD/O investment/NN/O fund/NN/O managed/VBN/O by/IN/O Soros/NNP/B-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Quantum/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O unsecured/JJ/O creditor/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Castle/NNP/B-ORG Harlan/NNP/I-ORG group/NN/O includes/VBZ/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Sieckman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O chief/NN/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Wolfgang/NNP/B-PERSON Jansen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
Executives/NNS/O at/IN/O Sharon/NNP/B-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O trustee/NN/O ,/,/O F.E./NNP/B-PERSON Agnew/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O unavailable/JJ/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
