At/IN/O the/DT/O core/NN/O of/IN/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O stands/VBZ/O a/DT/O hotel/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O oh/UH/O ,/,/O yes/UH/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O casino/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O all/DT/O ././O
Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O seen/VBN/O nothing/NN/O quite/RB/O like/IN/O it/PRP/O before/IN/O ././O
Now/RB/O the/DT/O Mirage/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Circus/NNP/B-ORG Circus/NNP/I-ORG Enterprises/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG $/$/O 290/CD/O million/CD/O Excalibur/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O going/VBG/O up/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O Excalibur/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O castlelike/JJ/O hotel/NN/O ,/,/O jousting/VBG/O tournaments/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O Arthurian/JJ/O attractions/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O up/IN/O to/TO/O 30,000/CD/O visitors/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O opens/VBZ/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Smaller/JJR/O projects/NNS/O swell/VBP/O the/DT/O figure/NN/O to/TO/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Still/RB/O other/JJ/O projects/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O announced/VBN/O but/CC/O not/RB/O yet/RB/O started/VBN/O could/MD/O put/VB/O expenditures/NNS/O above/IN/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Wynn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O owns/VBZ/O 29.4/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Golden/NNP/B-ORG Nugget/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG shares/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Mirage/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O projects/NNS/O will/MD/O help/VB/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE attract/VB/O a/DT/O whole/JJ/O new/JJ/O generation/NN/O of/IN/O visitors/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O create/VBP/O a/DT/O wonderment/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O create/VBP/O something/NN/O so/RB/O exciting/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O dreams/VBZ/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O part/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O then/RB/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O come/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O projects/NNS/O already/RB/O under/IN/O construction/NN/O will/MD/O increase/VB/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE supply/NN/O of/IN/O hotel/NN/O rooms/NNS/O by/IN/O 11,795/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O nearly/RB/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 75,500/CD/O ././O
By/IN/O a/DT/O rule/NN/O of/IN/O thumb/NN/O of/IN/O 1.5/CD/O new/JJ/O jobs/NNS/O for/IN/O each/DT/O new/JJ/O hotel/NN/O room/NN/O ,/,/O Clark/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE will/MD/O have/VB/O nearly/RB/O 18,000/CD/O new/JJ/O jobs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O county/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1988/CD/O had/VBD/O 307,000/CD/O jobs/NNS/O ,/,/O 95,400/CD/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O tourist/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
Projects/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O talking/VBG/O or/CC/O blueprint/NN/O stage/NN/O would/MD/O add/VB/O a/DT/O further/JJR/O 48,000/CD/O rooms/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O 40,000/CD/O newcomers/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O are/VBP/O settling/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Las/NNP/I-LOC Vegas/NNP/I-LOC Valley/NNP/I-LOC ././O
But/CC/O Nevada/NNP/B-GPE state/NN/O labor/NN/O economists/NNS/O think/VBP/O a/DT/O shortage/NN/O is/VBZ/O probable/JJ/O ././O
Nobody/NN/O yet/RB/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O calculated/VBN/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O slot/NN/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O crap/NN/O tables/NNS/O or/CC/O roulette/NN/O wheels/NNS/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE will/MD/O add/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O enormous/JJ/O store/NN/O that/IN/O Lady/NNP/B-PERSON Luck/NNP/I-PERSON already/RB/O guards/VBZ/O here/RB/O ,/,/O much/RB/O less/JJR/O the/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O impact/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O growth/NN/O on/IN/O schools/NNS/O and/CC/O municipal/JJ/O services/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Traffic/NN/O is/VBZ/O certainly/RB/O a/DT/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O is/VBZ/O pollution/NN/O ,/,/O water/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O adequate/JJ/O labor/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Sain/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Las/NNP/I-ORG Vegas/NNP/I-ORG Convention/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Visitors/NNPS/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG ././O
City/NN/O fathers/NNS/O have/VBP/O managed/VBN/O to/TO/O push/VB/O through/RP/O projects/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O crucial/JJ/O for/IN/O tourist/NN/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O expansion/NN/O of/IN/O McCarran/NNP/B-FAC International/NNP/I-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O the/DT/O 44/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE tourists/NNS/O who/WP/O fly/VBP/O here/RB/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O one/CD/O means/NNS/O of/IN/O transport/NN/O or/CC/O another/DT/O ,/,/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 18/CD/O million/CD/O people/NNS/O will/MD/O visit/VB/O the/DT/O city/NN/O ././O
Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE promises/VBZ/O ,/,/O or/CC/O threatens/VBZ/O ,/,/O to/TO/O become/VB/O a/DT/O giant/JJ/O carnival/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O rooms/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O had/VBN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 45/CD/O a/DT/O day/NN/O or/CC/O less/JJR/O ,/,/O for/IN/O visitors/NNS/O uninspired/JJ/O solely/RB/O by/IN/O gambling/VBG/O ././O
Caesars/NNP/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O defend/VB/O its/PRP$/O august/JJ/O reputation/NN/O by/IN/O sinking/VBG/O $/$/O 190/CD/O million/CD/O into/IN/O its/PRP$/O opulent/JJ/O Caesars/NNP/B-ORG Palace/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O next/JJ/O door/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O Mirage/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O adding/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O shopping/NN/O area/NN/O reminiscent/NN/O of/IN/O Rodeo/NNP/B-FAC Drive/NNP/I-FAC ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Flamingo/NNP/I-ORG Hilton/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Imperial/NNP/B-ORG Palace/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Frontier/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O are/VBP/O pouring/VBG/O millions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O into/IN/O facelifts/NNS/O ,/,/O new/JJ/O room/NN/O towers/NNS/O and/CC/O casino/NN/O floor/NN/O space/NN/O just/RB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O up/IN/O ././O
Where/WRB/O 's/VBZ/O this/DT/O huge/JJ/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O investment/NN/O capital/NN/O coming/VBG/O from/IN/O ?/./O
Golden/NNP/B-ORG Nugget/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG first/JJ/O casino/NN/O client/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O borrowed/VBN/O on/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 600/CD/O million/CD/O worth/NN/O of/IN/O mortgage/NN/O notes/NNS/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O private/JJ/O investors/NNS/O by/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O build/VB/O the/DT/O Mirage/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Other/JJ/O casino/NN/O owners/NNS/O ,/,/O Circus/NNP/B-ORG Circus/NNP/I-ORG among/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O financing/VBG/O their/PRP$/O expansion/NN/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O cash/NN/O and/CC/O revolving/VBG/O credit/NN/O lines/NNS/O from/IN/O local/JJ/O lenders/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Interstate/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Nevada/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Will/MD/O the/DT/O investments/NNS/O pay/VB/O off/IN/O ?/./O
The/DT/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE tourism/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O persuades/VBZ/O lenders/NNS/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O ././O
Casino/NN/O revenues/NNS/O and/CC/O hotel/NN/O occupancy/NN/O rates/NNS/O are/VBP/O high/JJ/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O tourists/NNS/O left/VBD/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O 's/POS/O casinos/NNS/O ,/,/O nearly/RB/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O people/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Nevada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O gambling/VBG/O industry/NN/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O barely/RB/O tapped/VBN/O the/DT/O potentially/RB/O huge/JJ/O family/NN/O trade/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O build/VBP/O a/DT/O better/JJR/O mousetrap/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O catch/VB/O more/JJR/O mice/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Fred/NNP/B-PERSON Benninger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O MGM/NNP/B-ORG Grand/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Ellen/NNP/B-PERSON Cokely/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O tourist/NN/O from/IN/O Alton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ill./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O seems/VBZ/O inclined/VBN/O to/TO/O agree/VB/O ././O
``/``/O Two/CD/O generations/NNS/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O Dad/NNP/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE by/IN/O himself/PRP/O for/IN/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O diversion/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Van/NNP/B-PERSON Heffner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Nevada/NNP/I-ORG Hotel/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Motel/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O One/CD/O generation/NN/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O Mom/NN/O joined/VBD/O Dad/NNP/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O '90s/NNS/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O headed/VBN/O toward/IN/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O resort/NN/O environment/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Casinos/NNS/O today/NN/O offer/VBP/O bowling/VBG/O alleys/NNS/O ,/,/O water/NN/O parks/NNS/O ,/,/O golf/NN/O courses/NNS/O ,/,/O tennis/NN/O courts/NNS/O ,/,/O lush/JJ/O swimming/NN/O pools/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O diversions/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O more/RBR/O such/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O designed/VBN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O emphasis/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O family/NN/O trade/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O tourists/NNS/O in/IN/O search/NN/O of/IN/O naughtier/JJR/O fun/NN/O than/IN/O gambling/VBG/O seem/VBP/O certain/JJ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O with/IN/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE call/JJ/O girls/NNS/O remaining/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O scene/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O serious/JJ/O economic/JJ/O downturn/NN/O ,/,/O pessimists/NNS/O observe/VBP/O ,/,/O could/MD/O hurt/VB/O the/DT/O expansionists/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O naysayers/NNS/O '/POS/O voices/NNS/O are/VBP/O drowned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O roar/NN/O of/IN/O cement/NN/O mixers/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O clanging/NN/O of/IN/O construction/NN/O cranes/NNS/O along/IN/O the/DT/O Strip/NNP/B-LOC ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O place/NN/O for/IN/O pedestrians/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O at/IN/O 7:30/CD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O morning/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O construction/NN/O choked/VBD/O traffic/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O famous/JJ/O Four/CD/B-LOC Corners/NNPS/I-LOC intersection/NN/O to/TO/O one/CD/O lane/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O taxi/NN/O passenger/NN/O found/VBD/O it/PRP/O faster/JJR/O to/TO/O abandon/VB/O the/DT/O cab/NN/O and/CC/O walk/NN/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O destination/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ferocious/JJ/O competition/NN/O probably/RB/O will/MD/O drive/VB/O some/DT/O poorly/RB/O managed/VBN/O properties/NNS/O into/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O or/CC/O new/JJ/O ownership/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O happened/VBN/O before/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O Dunes/NNPS/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Aladdin/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Riviera/NNP/B-ORG were/VBD/O all/DT/O acquired/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O present/JJ/O owners/NNS/O from/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O proceedings/NNS/O spawned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O recession/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/CD/O ././O
Yet/RB/O that/DT/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O discouraged/VBN/O investors/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O have/VBP/O bought/VBN/O big/JJ/O chunks/NNS/O of/IN/O Strip/NNP/B-LOC property/NN/O for/IN/O what/WP/O may/MD/O turn/VB/O into/IN/O another/DT/O wave/NN/O of/IN/O building/VBG/O ././O
Atlantic/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE casino/NN/O owner/NN/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Trump/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O scouting/VBG/O the/DT/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE market/NN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O eye/NN/O toward/IN/O building/VBG/O an/DT/O appropriately/RB/O spectacular/JJ/O place/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O new/JJ/O projects/NNS/O began/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Strip/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O expansion/NN/O squeezed/VBD/O smaller/JJR/O competitors/NNS/O ././O
Since/IN/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O motel/NN/O rooms/NNS/O has/VBZ/O fallen/VBN/O by/IN/O 17,000/CD/O ././O
Skeptics/NNS/O wonder/VBP/O whether/IN/O mega-resorts/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Mirage/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O squeeze/VB/O a/DT/O profit/NN/O from/IN/O their/PRP$/O cash/NN/O flow/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Mirage/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O cost/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O day/NN/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wynn/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O confident/JJ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O produce/VB/O a/DT/O healthy/JJ/O profit/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O some/DT/O securities/NNS/O analysts/NNS/O doubt/VBP/O it/PRP/O ././O
Bally/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O decline/VBP/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O ././O
Only/RB/O now/RB/O is/VBZ/O it/PRP/O undergoing/VBG/O a/DT/O badly/RB/O needed/VBN/O facelift/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O great/JJ/O location/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O have/VB/O some/DT/O real/JJ/O problems/NNS/O when/WRB/O everyone/NN/O around/IN/O them/PRP/O opens/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Lee/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG analyst/NN/O ././O
Older/JJR/O properties/NNS/O that/WDT/O still/RB/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O 1950s/CD/O image/NN/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O vulnerable/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O what/WP/O you/PRP/O are/VBP/O ,/,/O bigger/JJR/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O you/PRP/O better/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O it/PRP/O 'll/MD/O sure/RB/O make/VB/O you/PRP/O poorer/JJR/O ././O ''/''/O
Circus/NNP/B-ORG Circus/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG flagship/NN/O casino/NN/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O the/DT/O envy/NN/O of/IN/O competitors/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O vacuum/VB/O cash/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O pockets/NNS/O of/IN/O vacationing/VBG/O families/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Circus/NNP/I-ORG Circus/NNP/I-ORG lures/VBZ/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O low/JJ/O room/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O inexpensive/JJ/O buffets/NNS/O and/CC/O entertainment/NN/O for/IN/O children/NNS/O at/IN/O no/DT/O extra/JJ/O charge/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O Excalibur/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O also/RB/O appeal/VB/O to/TO/O families/NNS/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O castle/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Schaeffer/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O compelling/JJ/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O folk/NN/O architecture/NN/O ever/RB/O built/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O casino/NN/O owners/NNS/O have/VBP/O resisted/VBN/O the/DT/O temptation/NN/O to/TO/O add/VB/O rooms/NNS/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O spending/VBG/O to/TO/O reinforce/VB/O the/DT/O identity/NN/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O believe/VBP/O attracts/VBZ/O their/PRP$/O customers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O More/JJR/O rooms/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O answer/NN/O for/IN/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Caesars/NNP/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Gluck/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
While/IN/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O hotel/NN/O is/VBZ/O building/VBG/O a/DT/O retail/JJ/O complex/NN/O in/IN/O Beverly/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNP/I-GPE style/NN/O and/CC/O redoing/VBG/O existing/VBG/O rooms/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O decreased/VBN/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O rooms/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O combined/VBN/O into/IN/O suites/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O rollers/NNS/O ././O
Caesars/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O a/DT/O specialty/NN/O of/IN/O catering/NN/O to/TO/O high/JJ/O rollers/NNS/O from/IN/O abroad/RB/O ,/,/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O being/VBG/O aggressively/RB/O courted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Mirage/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Las/NNP/I-ORG Vegas/NNP/I-ORG Hilton/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
Other/JJ/O ,/,/O smaller/JJR/O concerns/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O pursuing/VBG/O market/NN/O niches/NNS/O --/:/O Hawaiian/JJ/O tourists/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O still/RB/O room/NN/O for/IN/O boutique/NN/O properties/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Barrett/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O MarCor/NNP/B-ORG Resorts/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O proliferation/NN/O of/IN/O tourist/NN/O distractions/NNS/O ,/,/O Las/NNP/O Vegans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O forgot/VBN/O that/IN/O gambling/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O town/NN/O is/VBZ/O all/DT/O about/IN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O days/NNS/O when/WRB/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O thrust/NN/O of/IN/O casinos/NNS/O was/VBD/O all/DT/O high/JJ/O rollers/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O no/DT/O windows/NNS/O and/CC/O clocks/NNS/O and/CC/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O red/JJ/O and/CC/O black/JJ/O decor/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O gone/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Sain/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/O visitors/NNS/O '/POS/O bureau/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O 93/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O tourists/NNS/O still/RB/O come/VBN/O for/IN/O gambling/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O lose/VB/O sight/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O ././O
