HEALTH/NN/O CLUBS/NNS/O gear/VBP/O up/IN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O graying/VBG/O clientele/NN/O ././O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Hays/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O ProBody/NNP/B-ORG Fitness/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O notes/VBZ/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O ``/``/O wash/NN/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O progress/NN/O ././O
People/NNS/O on/IN/O fixed/VBN/O incomes/NNS/O get/VBP/O a/DT/O break/NN/O at/IN/O Espre/NNP/B-ORG ;/:/O over/IN/O 55/CD/O wins/NNS/O a/DT/O 45/CD/O %/NN/O discount/NN/O at/IN/O Anaheim/NNP/B-ORG Imperial/NNP/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Spa/NNP/I-ORG ././O
A/DT/O committee/NN/O of/IN/O gem/NN/O dealers/NNS/O investigates/VBZ/O the/DT/O source/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O ``/``/O hot/JJ/O ''/''/O blue/JJ/O topaz/NN/O stones/NNS/O recently/RB/O reported/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE jewelry/NN/O manufacturer/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O licensing/VBG/O importers/NNS/O but/CC/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O currently/RB/O monitor/VB/O imports/NNS/O ././O
Topaz/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O translucent/JJ/O mineral/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O often/RB/O whitish/JJ/O when/WRB/O taken/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O ground/NN/O ,/,/O can/MD/O be/VB/O turned/VBN/O blue/JJ/O by/IN/O irradiation/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O transforms/VBZ/O it/PRP/O into/IN/O a/DT/O gemstone/NN/O that/WDT/O looks/VBZ/O like/IN/O an/DT/O aquamarine/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O jewelers/NNS/O have/VBP/O Geiger/NNP/B-PERSON counters/NNS/O to/TO/O measure/VB/O topaz/NN/O radiation/NN/O ././O
CAPITAL/NN/O TRAVELS/VBZ/O to/TO/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC as/IN/O 1992/CD/O unification/NN/O nears/VBZ/O ././O
Boston/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Advent/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG raises/VBZ/O $/$/O 230/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE pension/NN/O funds/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
European/JJ/O venture/NN/O capital/NN/O funds/NNS/O total/JJ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 14/CD/O billion/CD/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O growing/VBG/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O annually/RB/O ././O
Continentals/NNS/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O strongest/JJS/O growth/NN/O area/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O southern/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O most/RBS/O often/RB/O mentioned/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O future/JJ/O economic/JJ/O hot/JJ/O spots/NNS/O ././O
Favored/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O include/VBP/O media/NNS/O ,/,/O telecommunications/NNS/O and/CC/O retailing/NN/O ././O
AN/DT/O AIDS/NNP/O DIRECTORY/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Foundation/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG AIDS/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG rates/VBZ/O and/CC/O reviews/VBZ/O educational/JJ/O materials/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O distributor/NN/O is/VBZ/O R.R./NNP/B-ORG Bowker/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
SUSPECT/JJ/O ``/``/O SALES/NNS/O ''/''/O ads/NNS/O are/VBP/O challenged/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Better/NNP/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Metropolitan/NNP/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O bureau/NN/O found/VBD/O that/IN/O only/RB/O two/CD/O of/IN/O six/CD/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE furniture/NN/O stores/NNS/O could/MD/O prove/VB/O their/PRP$/O presale/NN/O prices/NNS/O were/VBD/O higher/JJR/O ././O
RADIO/NNP/O MALAISE/NNP/O draws/VBZ/O the/DT/O ear/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
AM/NNP/O radio/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O losing/VBG/O listeners/NNS/O to/TO/O FM/NNP/O channels/NNS/O since/IN/O the/DT/O 1970s/CD/O ,/,/O approaches/VBZ/O the/DT/O 1990s/CD/O with/IN/O a/DT/O diminished/JJ/O voice/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG plans/NNS/O to/TO/O hear/VB/O a/DT/O day/NN/O of/IN/O testimony/NN/O Nov./NNP/O 16/CD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O plight/NN/O of/IN/O AM/NNP/O radio/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O commission/NN/O believes/VBZ/O that/IN/O improving/VBG/O AM/NNP/O service/NN/O would/MD/O broaden/VB/O listening/NN/O selections/NNS/O and/CC/O increase/VB/O options/NNS/O for/IN/O advertisers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O issues/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O thought/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O important/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O new/JJ/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON Sikes/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O AM/NNP/O broadcaster/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O native/JJ/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O FM/NNP/O radio/NN/O band/NN/O ,/,/O considered/VBN/O technically/RB/O superior/JJ/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O carry/VB/O stereo/JJ/O broadcasts/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O cornered/VBN/O the/DT/O airwaves/NNS/O for/IN/O delivering/VBG/O music/NN/O ././O
AM/NNP/O stereo/NN/O remains/VBZ/O largely/RB/O undeveloped/JJ/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O lacks/VBZ/O a/DT/O uniform/JJ/O delivery/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Broadcasters/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O June/NNP/O adopted/VBD/O an/DT/O agenda/NN/O for/IN/O revitalizing/VBG/O AM/NNP/O radio/NN/O that/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O pursuing/VBG/O further/JJR/O FCC/NNP/B-ORG action/NN/O on/IN/O selecting/VBG/O an/DT/O AM/NNP/O stereo/JJ/O standard/NN/O and/CC/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O law/NN/O requiring/VBG/O all/DT/O stereo/NN/O receivers/NNS/O to/TO/O include/VB/O AM/NNP/O stereo/JJ/O ././O
Listeners/NNS/O turned/VBD/O to/TO/O radios/NNS/O run/VBN/O on/IN/O batteries/NNS/O for/IN/O news/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE earthquake/NN/O and/CC/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O cut/VBD/O power/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
Lee/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O jeans/NNS/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O celebrates/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O 100th/JJ/O anniversary/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O hardcover/NN/O yearbook/NN/O featuring/VBG/O photos/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 10,000/CD/O employees/NNS/O ././O
