Call/VB/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON office/NN/O in/IN/O downtown/NN/O Fort/NNP/B-GPE Worth/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O receptionist/NN/O still/RB/O answers/VBZ/O the/DT/O phone/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Speaker/NNP/O Wright/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O office/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O former/JJ/O congressman/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O speaker/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG after/IN/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O dealings/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ensconced/VBN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O district/NN/O office/NN/O ,/,/O maintained/VBN/O by/IN/O taxpayers/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O allowance/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O negotiating/VBG/O a/DT/O rich/JJ/O book/NN/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O boot/NN/O ././O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Deaver/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG aide/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O recent/JJ/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O teeming/VBG/O ranks/NNS/O of/IN/O fallen/VBN/O politicians/NNS/O and/CC/O officials/NNS/O earning/VBG/O their/PRP$/O way/NN/O as/IN/O lobbyists/NNS/O and/CC/O consultants/NNS/O here/RB/O ././O
Surviving/VBG/O scandal/NN/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O a/DT/O rite/NN/O of/IN/O political/JJ/O passage/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O glut/NN/O of/IN/O scandal/NN/O has/VBZ/O blunted/VBN/O this/DT/O town/NN/O 's/POS/O sensibility/NN/O ././O
Let/VB/O the/DT/O president/NN/O demand/VB/O strict/JJ/O new/JJ/O ethics/NNS/O rules/NNS/O :/:/O With/IN/O four/CD/O sitting/VBG/O House/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O sexual/JJ/O misdeeds/NNS/O ,/,/O amid/IN/O the/DT/O unfolding/VBG/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O and/CC/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Wright/NNP/B-PERSON debacle/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O slightly/RB/O dulled/VBN/O by/IN/O scandal/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O political/JJ/O humorist/NN/O Art/NNP/B-PERSON Buchwald/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O now/RB/O takes/VBZ/O something/NN/O really/RB/O weird/JJ/O to/TO/O inspire/VB/O public/JJ/O outrage/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O many/JJ/O have/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O These/DT/O people/NNS/O bounce/VBP/O back/RB/O more/RBR/O resiliently/RB/O than/IN/O regular/JJ/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE writer/NN/O Suzanne/NNP/B-PERSON Garment/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O history/NN/O of/IN/O post-Watergate/JJ/O scandal/NN/O ././O
Given/VBN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O penchant/NN/O for/IN/O book/NN/O writing/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O surprising/JJ/O that/IN/O none/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O masters/NNS/O of/IN/O scandal/NN/O survival/NN/O have/VBP/O yet/RB/O published/VBN/O a/DT/O guide/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O art/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O emerging/VBG/O protocol/NN/O --/:/O indeed/RB/O ,/,/O an/DT/O etiquette/NN/O --/:/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O ././O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O :/:/O
Pretend/VB/O Nothing/NN/O Happened/VBD/O
As/IN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O were/VBD/O still/RB/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O old/JJ/O job/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Wright/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O by/IN/O resigning/VBG/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O title/NN/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O forced/VBN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O job/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O law/NN/O enjoys/VBZ/O a/DT/O $/$/O 120,000/CD/O annual/JJ/O office/NN/O expense/NN/O allowance/NN/O ,/,/O three/CD/O paid/VBN/O staffers/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 67,000/CD/O for/IN/O stationery/NN/O and/CC/O telephones/NNS/O and/CC/O continued/VBN/O use/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O franking/NN/O privilege/NN/O ././O
Not/RB/O to/TO/O mention/VB/O a/DT/O generous/JJ/O federal/JJ/O pension/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O busy/JJ/O schedule/NN/O of/IN/O speaking/NN/O engagements/NNS/O at/IN/O $/$/O 10,000/CD/O a/DT/O pop/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O tony/JJ/O places/NNS/O including/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Yale/NNP/I-ORG Political/NNP/I-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O as/RB/O busy/JJ/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O as/RB/O speaker/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O reports/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Wright/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O administrative/JJ/O aide/NN/O ,/,/O Larry/NNP/B-PERSON Shannon/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Atone/VB/O
On/IN/O the/DT/O edge/NN/O of/IN/O fashionable/JJ/O Georgetown/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O chic/JJ/O office/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O river/NN/O view/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O corporate/JJ/O clients/NNS/O whom/WP/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O name/VB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O reclaim/VB/O his/PRP$/O reputation/NN/O as/IN/O one/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O savviest/JJS/O image/NN/O makers/NNS/O in/IN/O town/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O few/JJ/O mementos/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O days/NNS/O as/IN/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG deputy/NN/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O staff/NN/O and/CC/O confidant/NN/O of/IN/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Nancy/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O feel/VBP/O better/RB/O than/IN/O I/PRP/O ever/RB/O have/VBP/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O life/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON confessed/VBD/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O alcoholism/NN/O during/IN/O his/PRP$/O trial/NN/O on/IN/O perjury/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O renaissance/NN/O :/:/O an/DT/O appearance/NN/O on/IN/O ABC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ``/``/O Nightline/NNP/O ''/''/O for/IN/O a/DT/O show/NN/O on/IN/O pack/NN/O journalism/NN/O ././O
Host/NNP/O Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Koppel/NNP/I-PERSON introduced/VBD/O him/PRP/O as/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O master/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Reagan/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O with/IN/O nary/PDT/O a/DT/O mention/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O conviction/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O on/IN/O perjury/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Finding/NNP/O God/NNP/O
``/``/O When/WRB/O someone/NN/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O `/``/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O turned/VBN/O to/TO/O God/NNP/O ,/,/O '/''/O everybody/NN/O lays/VBZ/O off/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O observes/VBZ/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Mankiewicz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE hand/NN/O and/CC/O former/JJ/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Kennedy/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Thus/RB/O have/VBP/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Colson/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Jeb/NNP/B-PERSON Magruder/NNP/I-PERSON launched/VBN/O successful/JJ/O post-Watergate/JJ/O careers/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O pulpit/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O always/RB/O work/VB/O so/RB/O smoothly/RB/O ././O
After/IN/O allegations/NNS/O surfaced/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O 1985/CD/O divorce/NN/O contest/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O beaten/VBN/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG enforcement/NN/O chief/NN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Fedders/NNP/I-PERSON retreated/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Trappist/JJ/B-ORG monastery/NN/O in/IN/O rural/JJ/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
From/IN/O time/NN/O to/TO/O time/NN/O he/PRP/O returns/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O monastery/NN/O for/IN/O prayer/NN/O ,/,/O meditation/NN/O and/CC/O pro/FW/O bono/FW/O legal/JJ/O work/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Fedders/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O philosophical/JJ/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O travails/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O whole/JJ/O experience/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O for/IN/O internal/JJ/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O a/DT/O psychoanalyst/NN/O five/CD/O mornings/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O surrendered/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O circumstances/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Fedders/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O word/NN/O surrender/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O precise/JJ/O psychoanalytic/JJ/O meaning/NN/O ././O
My/PRP$/O universe/NN/O has/VBZ/O changed/VBN/O ././O
I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O enjoying/VBG/O my/PRP$/O life/NN/O and/CC/O who/WP/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O today/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O aspect/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O a/DT/O mega-lawyer/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O as/RB/O important/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Do/VB/O n't/RB/O Linger/VB/O
``/``/O The/DT/O best/JJS/O thing/NN/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O do/VB/O is/VBZ/O get/VB/O off/IN/O the/DT/O screen/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Buchwald/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Nobody/NN/O proved/VBD/O that/IN/O more/RBR/O masterfully/RB/O than/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Coelho/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Democratic/JJ/O majority/NN/O whip/NN/O ././O
Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Rather/NNP/I-PERSON served/VBD/O as/IN/O emcee/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O Helps/VBZ/O to/TO/O Be/VB/O Male/NN/O
Male/JJ/O scandal/NN/O victims/NNS/O invariably/RB/O fare/VBP/O better/RBR/O ././O
Anne/NNP/B-PERSON Burford/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O EPA/NNP/B-ORG chief/NN/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O under/IN/O fire/NN/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O during/IN/O a/DT/O flap/NN/O with/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O kayoed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O confrontation/NN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O never/RB/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O official/JJ/O wrondgoing/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O help/VB/O when/WRB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O charged/VBN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O then/RB/O cleared/VBN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O on/IN/O allegations/NNS/O of/IN/O public/JJ/O drunkenness/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O cut/VBD/O my/PRP$/O losses/NNS/O and/CC/O ran/VBD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O from/IN/O her/PRP$/O new/JJ/O home/NN/O in/IN/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O busy/JJ/O remodeling/VBG/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Burford/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O bitter/JJ/O over/IN/O the/DT/O overwhelming/JJ/O legal/JJ/O expenses/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O clearing/VBG/O her/PRP$/O name/NN/O ././O
``/``/O My/PRP$/O husband/NN/O was/VBD/O instantly/RB/O impoverished/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O very/JJ/O act/NN/O of/IN/O marrying/VBG/O me/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Another/DT/O former/JJ/O EPA/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O ,/,/O Rita/NNP/B-PERSON Lavelle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O struggling/VBG/O after/IN/O her/PRP$/O conviction/NN/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O on/IN/O perjury/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O she/PRP/O could/MD/O do/VB/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O herself/PRP/O back/RB/O to/TO/O where/WRB/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O her/PRP$/O lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Bierbower/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O could/MD/O say/VB/O she/PRP/O survived/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O easy/JJ/O on/IN/O her/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
No/DT/O book/NN/O contracts/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O dangled/VBN/O before/IN/O Deborah/NNP/B-PERSON Gore/NNP/I-PERSON Dean/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O reigning/VBG/O queen/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ././O
Donna/NNP/B-PERSON Rice/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Hart/NNP/I-PERSON fame/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O obtain/VB/O a/DT/O book/NN/O contract/NN/O and/CC/O lost/VBD/O her/PRP/O modeling/NN/O contract/NN/O for/IN/O ``/``/O No/NNP/O Excuses/NNPS/O ''/''/O jeans/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O back/RB/O in/IN/O jail/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O on/IN/O shoplifting/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Be/VB/O the/DT/O Star/NN/O
Central/JJ/O figures/NNS/O --/:/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Nixon/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O usually/RB/O fare/VBP/O better/RBR/O than/IN/O those/DT/O with/IN/O supporting/VBG/O roles/NNS/O ././O
Yet/RB/O his/PRP$/O co-defendant/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O --/:/O also/RB/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O military/JJ/O officer/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O of/IN/O Oliver/NNP/B-PERSON North/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O busily/RB/O and/CC/O profitably/RB/O burnishing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O involvement/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O affair/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O accounts/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O difference/NN/O ?/./O
Mr./NNP/O Secord/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O performance/NN/O was/VBD/O decidedly/RB/O less/RBR/O inspiring/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O North/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O in/IN/O heavy/JJ/O demand/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O speaker/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O fees/NNS/O reported/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O range/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O 750/CD/O people/NNS/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O in/IN/O a/DT/O remote/JJ/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE town/NN/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O for/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O family/NN/O tribute/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O North/NNP/B-PERSON given/VBN/O by/IN/O two/CD/O dozen/NN/O conservative/JJ/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
If/IN/O Sex/NN/O Is/VBZ/O Involved/VBN/O ,/,/O All/DT/O Bets/NNS/O Are/VBP/O Off/IN/O
Sex/NN/O scandals/NNS/O make/VBP/O people/NNS/O look/VB/O careless/JJ/O and/CC/O silly/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O sins/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O laughed/VBN/O at/IN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O wicked/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O foolish/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Mankiewicz/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Gerry/NNP/B-PERSON Studds/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O handily/RB/O re-elected/JJ/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O candor/NN/O with/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O handled/VBD/O revelations/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O sex/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O male/JJ/O congressional/JJ/O page/NN/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bauman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O conservative/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O deserted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O wing/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Conservatives/NNS/O shoot/VBP/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O establishment/NN/O is/VBZ/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O forgive/VB/O sexual/JJ/O misadventures/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O private/JJ/O sector/NN/O sometimes/RB/O will/MD/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Tower/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O womanizing/VBG/O and/CC/O boozing/VBG/O during/IN/O his/PRP$/O unsuccessful/JJ/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O confirmation/NN/O as/IN/O secretary/NN/O of/IN/O defense/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O writing/VBG/O a/DT/O book/NN/O ,/,/O serving/VBG/O on/IN/O an/DT/O elite/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O advisory/JJ/O board/NN/O and/CC/O consulting/VBG/O for/IN/O an/DT/O array/NN/O of/IN/O corporate/JJ/O clients/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O British/JJ/O publishing/NN/O mogul/NN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Maxwell/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Become/VB/O a/DT/O Lobbyist/NN/O
When/WRB/O all/DT/O else/RB/O fails/VBZ/O ,/,/O Gucci/NNP/B-PERSON Gulch/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O the/DT/O fabled/JJ/O halls/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Capitol/NNP/O inhabited/VBN/O by/IN/O lobbyists/NNS/O and/CC/O their/PRP$/O imported/VBN/O shoes/NNS/O --/:/O offers/VBZ/O a/DT/O welcome/JJ/O environment/NN/O for/IN/O fallen/VBN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O become/VBD/O pseudo-lobbyists/NNS/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Mack/NNP/I-PERSON promptly/RB/O quit/VBD/O his/PRP$/O job/NN/O last/JJ/O spring/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O Speaker/NNP/O Wright/NNP/B-PERSON amid/IN/O public/JJ/O outrage/NN/O over/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mack/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O violent/JJ/O attack/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O young/JJ/O woman/NN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O 19/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ././O
After/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O in/IN/O seclusion/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mack/NNP/B-PERSON opened/VBD/O a/DT/O consulting/VBG/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O to/TO/O enable/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O directly/RB/O lobby/VB/O ;/:/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O require/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O his/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O by/IN/O registering/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O lobbyist/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mack/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O talks/VBZ/O to/TO/O ``/``/O 30/CD/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O week/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Misery/NN/O Loves/VBZ/O Company/NN/O
Other/JJ/O scandal/NN/O survivors/NNS/O are/VBP/O sometimes/RB/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O source/NN/O of/IN/O solace/NN/O ././O
Each/DT/O time/NN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O scandal/NN/O hits/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O pulls/VBZ/O the/DT/O scabs/NNS/O off/IN/O your/PRP$/O knees/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON home/NN/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O troubles/NNS/O erupted/VBD/O was/VBD/O former/JJ/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON aide/NN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Ehrlichman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whom/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON scarcely/RB/O knew/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O reassured/VBD/O me/PRP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O hurricane/NN/O would/MD/O end/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON recalls/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bauman/NNP/B-PERSON received/VBD/O an/DT/O encouraging/JJ/O letter/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O recognized/VBN/O master/NN/O of/IN/O scandal/NN/O survival/NN/O ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Nixon/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Bauman/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O If/IN/O things/NNS/O get/VBP/O really/RB/O tough/JJ/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O can/MD/O always/RB/O auction/VB/O it/PRP/O off/RP/O at/IN/O Sotheby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ././O
