Hale/NNP/B-PERSON Milgrim/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 41/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O marketing/NN/O at/IN/O Elecktra/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG Records/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O entertainment/NN/O concern/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Milgrim/NNP/B-PERSON succeeds/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Berman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
