Furukawa/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O production/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O memory/NN/O devices/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O scale/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
As/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O move/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O affiliated/VBN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE company/NN/O ,/,/O International/NNP/B-ORG Components/NNP/I-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O purchased/VBD/O a/DT/O Mexican/JJ/O plant/NN/O formerly/RB/O belonging/VBG/O to/TO/O KSI/NNP/B-ORG Disc/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O price/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Together/RB/O with/IN/O two/CD/O existing/VBG/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Furukawa/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O expand/VB/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O local/JJ/O monthly/JJ/O production/NN/O of/IN/O memory/NN/O disks/NNS/O to/TO/O 1.4/CD/O million/CD/O sheets/NNS/O from/IN/O 800,000/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Furukawa/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O raise/VB/O production/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O plant/NN/O outside/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O 300,000/CD/O sheets/NNS/O monthly/JJ/O from/IN/O 100,000/CD/O ././O
Furukawa/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O is/VBZ/O strengthening/VBG/O as/RB/O related/VBN/O computer/NN/O technology/NN/O gains/VBZ/O in/IN/O sophistication/NN/O and/CC/O quality/NN/O ././O
