Western/JJ/O European/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O who/WP/O favor/VBP/O speedy/JJ/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O monetary/JJ/O union/NN/O are/VBP/O adding/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O argument/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O arsenal/NN/O :/:/O the/DT/O dizzying/VBG/O political/JJ/O changes/NNS/O under/IN/O way/NN/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ././O
French/NNP/O President/NNP/O Francois/NNP/B-PERSON Mitterrand/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Jacques/NNP/B-PERSON Delors/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Spanish/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Felipe/NNP/B-PERSON Gonzalez/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O have/VBP/O begun/VBN/O linking/VBG/O the/DT/O rapid/JJ/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O speed/VB/O up/RP/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O stressing/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O way/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC to/TO/O help/VB/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC is/VBZ/O to/TO/O move/VB/O faster/RBR/O towards/IN/O Western/NNP/O European/NNP/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O monetary/JJ/O unity/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O only/JJ/O response/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O challenge/NN/O being/VBG/O presented/VBN/O to/TO/O us/PRP/O by/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Mitterrand/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Parliament/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Strasbourg/NNP/B-GPE yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O reinforce/VB/O and/CC/O accelerate/VB/O the/DT/O union/NN/O and/CC/O cohesion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Mitterrand/NNP/B-PERSON proposed/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O conference/NN/O be/VB/O convened/VBN/O next/JJ/O fall/NN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O treaty/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG allowing/VBG/O a/DT/O European/JJ/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O treaty/NN/O be/VB/O ratified/VBN/O by/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mitterrand/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O proposed/VBD/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O ``/``/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG ''/''/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O channel/VB/O development/NN/O money/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ././O
One/CD/O basis/NN/O for/IN/O linking/VBG/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC is/VBZ/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O that/IN/O integrating/VBG/O 110/CD/O million/CD/O Eastern/JJ/O Europeans/NNPS/O with/IN/O 320/CD/O million/CD/O Western/JJ/O Europeans/NNPS/O is/VBZ/O primarily/RB/O the/DT/O task/NN/O of/IN/O Europeans/NNPS/O ,/,/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O obvious/JJ/O strategic/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O interest/NN/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O a/DT/O European/JJ/O strategist/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE tends/VBZ/O to/TO/O look/VB/O at/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC -LCB-/-LRB-/O not/RB/O including/VBG/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE -RCB-/-RRB-/O as/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC looks/VBZ/O at/IN/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC :/:/O important/JJ/O but/CC/O far/RB/O away/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O for/IN/O us/PRP/O in/IN/O Western/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O these/DT/O are/VBP/O Europeans/NNPS/O next/JJ/O door/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O natural/JJ/O division/NN/O of/IN/O labor/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Francois/NNP/B-PERSON Heisbourg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Strategic/NNP/I-ORG Studies/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE more/RBR/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O strategic/JJ/O issues/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Western/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC more/RBR/O involved/VBN/O with/IN/O specific/JJ/O aid/NN/O measures/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/O designation/NN/O at/IN/O July/NNP/O 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O summit/NN/O of/IN/O major/JJ/O industrialized/VBN/O nations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG EC/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O coordinator/NN/O of/IN/O Western/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O a/DT/O first/JJ/O step/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O division/NN/O is/VBZ/O dictated/VBN/O by/IN/O economics/NNS/O :/:/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O net/JJ/O exporter/NN/O of/IN/O capital/NN/O while/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O British/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O are/VBP/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O link/VB/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O need/VBP/O a/DT/O Western/JJ/O Ostpolitik/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Roper/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Royal/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE longstanding/JJ/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O diplomatic/JJ/O opening/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ././O
He/PRP/O notes/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Marshall/NNP/O Plan/NNP/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE aid/NN/O to/TO/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ``/``/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O throw/VB/O money/NN/O at/IN/O post-war/JJ/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O liberalized/VBD/O and/CC/O opened/VBD/O up/RP/O those/DT/O markets/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O French/JJ/O analysis/NN/O goes/VBZ/O further/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O have/VBP/O finally/RB/O concluded/VBN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O all/DT/O want/VBP/O perestroika/FW/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Soviet/JJ/O leader/NN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O economic/JJ/O restructuring/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Hubert/NNP/B-PERSON Vedrine/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O security/NN/O adviser/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Mitterrand/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O drawn/VBN/O the/DT/O operational/JJ/O policy/NN/O conclusions/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O that/IN/O with/IN/O communism/NN/O collapsing/VBG/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON scrambling/VBG/O to/TO/O rejuvenate/VB/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Our/PRP$/O interest/NN/O lies/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O controlled/VBN/O transformation/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O contained/VBN/O nuclear/JJ/O reaction/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O we/PRP/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O help/VB/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O not/RB/O just/RB/O with/IN/O words/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Managing/VBG/O change/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O require/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O more/JJR/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O prominent/JJ/O role/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O especially/RB/O in/IN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O German/JJ/O reunification/NN/O ././O
Thierry/NNP/B-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON Montbrial/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG French/NNP/I-ORG Institutue/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O clear/JJ/O what/WP/O ,/,/O exactly/RB/O ,/,/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE wants/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O doubts/VBZ/O a/DT/O Bismarckian/JJ/O super/JJ/O state/NN/O will/MD/O emerge/VB/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O dominate/VB/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O but/CC/O warns/VBZ/O of/IN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O risk/NN/O of/IN/O profound/JJ/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG from/IN/O a/DT/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O strong/JJ/O ,/,/O even/RB/O if/IN/O democratic/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O to/TO/O talk/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Germans/NNPS/O ,/,/O now/RB/O ,/,/O frankly/RB/O and/CC/O raise/VB/O these/DT/O future/JJ/O risks/NNS/O with/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O There/EX/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O message/NN/O from/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O on/IN/O offer/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O want/VBP/O reassurance/NN/O we/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O try/VB/O to/TO/O undermine/VB/O or/CC/O destroy/VB/O the/DT/O Warsaw/NNP/O Pact/NNP/O .../:/O ././O
In/IN/O return/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O France/NNP/B-GPE could/MD/O keep/VB/O their/PRP$/O nuclear/JJ/O weapons/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O Once/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O feel/VBP/O comfortable/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O that/RB/O much/RB/O easier/JJR/O to/TO/O make/VB/O more/JJR/O progress/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O social/JJ/O reforms/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O starting/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ././O
