C.B./NNP/B-PERSON Rogers/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O business/NN/O information/NN/O concern/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rogers/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 60/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O succeeds/VBZ/O J.V./NNP/B-PERSON White/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 64/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O committee/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O chief/NN/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O appointed/VBN/O ././O
