The/DT/O problem/NN/O for/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O weigh/VB/O what/WP/O China/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O saying/VBG/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O people/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O conciliatory/JJ/O message/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O delivering/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O move/NN/O apparently/RB/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O heading/VBG/O off/RP/O new/JJ/O punitive/JJ/O legislation/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON sent/VBD/O an/DT/O indirect/JJ/O signal/NN/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE via/IN/O T.D./NNP/B-PERSON Lee/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG physicist/NN/O who/WP/O met/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O Chinese/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O he/PRP/O met/VBD/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O his/PRP$/O return/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O president/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNPS/O ``/``/O made/VBD/O statements/NNS/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O that/IN/O I/PRP/O regard/VBP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O first/JJ/O step/NN/O toward/IN/O reconciliation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O communication/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON brought/VBD/O represents/VBZ/O the/DT/O softer/JJR/O line/NN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O hoping/VBG/O to/TO/O hear/VB/O from/IN/O Chinese/JJ/O officials/NNS/O since/IN/O the/DT/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O massacre/NN/O of/IN/O pro-democracy/JJ/O demonstrators/NNS/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O leader/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON informed/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O expressed/VBD/O some/DT/O regret/NN/O for/IN/O what/WP/O had/VBD/O happened/VBN/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O conceded/VBD/O that/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O officials/NNS/O bore/VBD/O some/DT/O responsibility/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O him/PRP/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O should/MD/O not/RB/O mind/VB/O those/DT/O who/WP/O participated/VBD/O in/IN/O demonstrations/NNS/O ,/,/O signed/VBD/O anti-government/NN/O materials/NNS/O and/CC/O went/VBD/O on/IN/O hunger/NN/O strikes/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON added/VBD/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O that/IN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O really/RB/O made/VBD/O mistakes/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O must/MD/O not/RB/O shirk/VB/O our/PRP$/O responsibility/NN/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O just/RB/O blame/VB/O the/DT/O demonstrators/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O reported/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O president/NN/O that/IN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O meeting/NN/O ,/,/O Communist/NNP/B-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG chief/NN/O Jiang/NNP/B-PERSON Zemin/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O leadership/NN/O ``/``/O looked/VBD/O kindly/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O students/NNS/O who/WP/O took/VBD/O part/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O demonstrations/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Jiang/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O pledged/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNP/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O publish/VB/O ``/``/O very/RB/O soon/RB/O ''/''/O a/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O killed/VBN/O ././O
And/CC/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O physicist/NN/O that/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O very/RB/O much/RB/O concerned/VBN/O ''/''/O about/IN/O the/DT/O deaths/NNS/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O arranged/VBN/O aid/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O victims/NNS/O '/POS/O families/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O transmitted/VBD/O my/PRP$/O conversations/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O Prof./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O acting/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O messenger/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Chinese/NNPS/O never/RB/O asked/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O convey/VB/O their/PRP$/O statements/NNS/O to/TO/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG spontaneously/RB/O invited/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O so/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lee/NNP/B-PERSON concedes/VBZ/O the/DT/O statements/NNS/O made/VBN/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O are/VBP/O far/RB/O different/JJ/O from/IN/O others/NNS/O being/VBG/O issued/VBN/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O attributes/VBZ/O that/DT/O to/TO/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O ``/``/O very/RB/O complex/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sources/NNS/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O fairly/RB/O conciliatory/JJ/O comments/NNS/O will/MD/O prod/VB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O be/VB/O cautious/JJ/O about/IN/O further/JJ/O sanctions/NNS/O against/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O president/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O legislative/JJ/O sanctions/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE official/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O he/PRP/O may/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O choice/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Beijing/NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O said/VBN/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O step/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O of/IN/O arrests/NNS/O and/CC/O intimidation/NN/O against/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O participated/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O demonstrations/NNS/O ././O
Sentences/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O stiff/JJ/O ././O
Nor/CC/O has/VBZ/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE hinted/VBN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O citizens/NNS/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O publish/VB/O the/DT/O identities/NNS/O of/IN/O those/DT/O killed/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O man/NN/O gunned/VBN/O down/RP/O by/IN/O a/DT/O stray/JJ/O bullet/NN/O while/IN/O cycling/VBG/O to/TO/O work/NN/O carries/VBZ/O ,/,/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O death/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O official/JJ/O stigma/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O counterrevolutionary/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O official/JJ/O rhetoric/NN/O is/VBZ/O hostile/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE frequently/RB/O lambastes/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Embassy/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O harboring/VBG/O astrophysicist/NN/O Fang/NNP/B-PERSON Lizhi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O dissident/NN/O who/WP/O took/VBD/O refuge/NN/O there/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O massacre/NN/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O crush/VB/O China/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O interfere/VB/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O internal/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Zhu/NNP/B-PERSON Qizhen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O new/JJ/O ambassador/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O left/VBD/O for/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O soon/RB/O hashing/VBG/O out/RP/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O for/IN/O sanctions/NNS/O legislation/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O be/VB/O attached/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG authorization/NN/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O veto/VB/O ././O
A/DT/O congressional/JJ/O staffer/NN/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O drafting/VBG/O the/DT/O sanctions/NNS/O says/VBZ/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O mirror/VB/O those/DT/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON enacted/VBN/O shortly/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O massacre/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O as/IN/O legislative/JJ/O action/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O carry/VB/O greater/JJR/O weight/NN/O and/CC/O would/MD/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O rescind/VB/O ././O
Codifying/VBG/O those/DT/O sanctions/NNS/O could/MD/O prompt/VB/O Chinese/JJ/O retaliation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O hoping/VBG/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O that/IN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O cooler/JJR/O heads/NNS/O prevail/VBP/O ././O
