In/IN/O Geneva/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O world/NN/O trade/NN/O talks/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O held/VBN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O General/NNP/O Agreement/NNP/O on/IN/O Tariffs/NNPS/O and/CC/O Trade/NNP/O ,/,/O or/CC/O GATT/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG called/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE proposal/NN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O step/NN/O backward/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O minister/NN/O of/IN/O agriculture/NN/O ,/,/O forestry/NN/O and/CC/O fisheries/NNS/O told/VBD/O a/DT/O committee/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O parliament/NN/O that/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O was/VBD/O impractical/JJ/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O heavily/RB/O subsidize/VB/O its/PRP$/O rice/NN/O farmers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O American/JJ/O proposal/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O an/DT/O adequate/JJ/O basis/NN/O for/IN/O negotiation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O ././O
EC/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O irked/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O set/VBN/O a/DT/O specific/JJ/O timetable/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O insisting/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O elimination/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O export/NN/O subsides/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O just/JJ/O reduction/NN/O ././O
EC/NNP/B-ORG Agriculture/NNP/I-ORG Commissioner/NNP/O Ray/NNP/B-PERSON MacSharry/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE plan/NN/O ``/``/O calls/VBZ/O into/IN/O question/NN/O ''/''/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O reached/VBN/O by/IN/O world/NN/O negotiators/NNS/O last/JJ/O April/NNP/O in/IN/O Geneva/NNP/B-GPE seeking/VBG/O ``/``/O substantial/JJ/O progressive/JJ/O reductions/NNS/O in/IN/O agricultural/JJ/O support/NN/O and/CC/O protection/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE Deputy/NNP/O Trade/NNP/B-ORG Representative/NNP/O Jules/NNP/B-PERSON Katz/NNP/I-PERSON replied/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O was/VBD/O entirely/RB/O consistent/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O April/NNP/O accord/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O surprised/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O reaction/NN/O ,/,/O calling/VBG/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O vehement/JJ/O ,/,/O even/RB/O frenetic/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Ambassador/NNP/O Katz/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O open/JJ/O to/TO/O discussing/VBG/O particular/JJ/O problems/NNS/O of/IN/O developing/VBG/O countries/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE argues/VBZ/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O plan/NN/O would/MD/O ease/VB/O the/DT/O transition/NN/O to/TO/O freer/JJR/O agriculture/NN/O trade/NN/O by/IN/O converting/VBG/O certain/JJ/O non-tariff/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O into/IN/O tariffs/NNS/O that/WDT/O ,/,/O together/RB/O with/IN/O existing/VBG/O tariffs/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O would/MD/O be/VB/O phased/VBN/O out/RP/O over/IN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O strongly/RB/O opposed/VBN/O to/TO/O converting/VBG/O agricultural/JJ/O supports/NNS/O into/IN/O tariffs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE package/NN/O also/RB/O says/VBZ/O countries/NNS/O could/MD/O temporarily/RB/O raise/VB/O tariffs/NNS/O on/IN/O certain/JJ/O products/NNS/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O experience/VBP/O an/DT/O unusually/RB/O heavy/JJ/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O imports/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O establish/VB/O procedures/NNS/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O countries/NNS/O from/IN/O using/VBG/O health/NN/O and/CC/O sanitation/NN/O rules/NNS/O to/TO/O impede/VB/O trade/NN/O arbitrarily/RB/O ././O
Seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O allay/VB/O European/JJ/O concerns/NNS/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Agriculture/NNP/O Secretary/NNP/O Clayton/NNP/B-PERSON Yeutter/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE plan/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O ``/``/O put/VB/O farmers/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ''/''/O but/CC/O would/MD/O encourage/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O ``/``/O grow/VB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O desire/VBP/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O government/NN/O wants/VBZ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O population/NN/O of/IN/O 320/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O 8.5/CD/O million/CD/O farmers/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O population/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 245/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O only/RB/O two/CD/O million/CD/O farmers/NNS/O ././O
