Two/CD/O recent/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O by/IN/O federal/JJ/O courts/NNS/O cast/VBD/O judges/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O odd/JJ/O role/NN/O of/IN/O telling/VBG/O authors/NNS/O how/WRB/O they/PRP/O should/MD/O write/VB/O history/NN/O and/CC/O biography/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O decisions/NNS/O deserve/VBP/O more/JJR/O attention/NN/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O received/VBN/O from/IN/O scholars/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O from/IN/O journalists/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hubbard/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O died/VBD/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O bequeathed/VBD/O the/DT/O copyrights/NNS/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O writings/NNS/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O church/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O licensed/VBD/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O New/NNP/B-ORG Era/NNP/I-ORG Publications/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Danish/JJ/O corporation/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O distinguished/VBD/O the/DT/O two/CD/O cases/NNS/O :/:/O In/IN/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Leval/NNP/B-PERSON noted/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O quotations/NNS/O were/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O enlivening/VBG/O the/DT/O biography/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O of/IN/O proving/VBG/O points/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O case/NN/O went/VBD/O on/IN/O appeal/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Second/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG ././O
This/DT/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O for/IN/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Oakes/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O court/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/NN/O judge/NN/O ././O
Decisions/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Second/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG itself/PRP/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Oakes/NNP/B-PERSON continued/VBD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O recognized/VBN/O that/IN/O public/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O subject/JJ/O matter/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O indispensability/NN/O in/IN/O particular/JJ/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O verbatim/JJ/O quotations/NNS/O are/VBP/O vital/JJ/O components/NNS/O of/IN/O fair/JJ/O use/NN/O ././O
Judges/NNPS/O Oakes/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Leval/NNP/B-PERSON understand/VBP/O the/DT/O requirements/NNS/O of/IN/O historical/JJ/O scholarship/NN/O ././O
Judges/NNPS/O Miner/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Altimari/NNP/B-PERSON do/VBP/O not/RB/O appear/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O clue/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O courts/NNS/O have/VBP/O not/RB/O defined/VBN/O ``/``/O minimal/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O publishers/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O understand/VBP/O ,/,/O take/VBP/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O mean/VB/O about/IN/O 50/CD/O words/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O second/JJ/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O handed/VBN/O down/IN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Appeals/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ninth/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O another/DT/O blow/NN/O against/IN/O scholarship/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O articles/NNS/O were/VBD/O largely/RB/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O interviews/NNS/O Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O taped/VBN/O with/IN/O Jeffrey/NNP/B-PERSON Masson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O psychoanalyst/NN/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O served/VBN/O as/IN/O projects/NNS/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Freud/NNP/I-ORG Archives/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON then/RB/O brought/VBD/O a/DT/O libel/NN/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Yorker/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Knopf/NNP/B-ORG ././O
No/DT/O such/JJ/O statement/NN/O appears/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O tapes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O majority/NN/O cited/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remark/NN/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O me/PRP/O alone/RB/O .../:/O against/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O analytic/JJ/O world/NN/O ''/''/O as/IN/O warrant/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON fabrication/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O majority/NN/O decision/NN/O contended/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O phrase/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O rational/JJ/O interpretation/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O description/NN/O of/IN/O himself/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O private/JJ/O asset/NN/O but/CC/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O liability/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O Anna/NNP/B-PERSON Freud/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O that/IN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O defamatory/JJ/O ././O
We/PRP/O now/RB/O know/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O words/NNS/O were/VBD/O not/RB/O always/RB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O historical/JJ/O profession/NN/O will/MD/O survive/VB/O these/DT/O decisions/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Schlesinger/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O Albert/NNP/B-PERSON Schweitzer/NNP/I-PERSON professor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O humanities/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O a/DT/O winner/NN/O of/IN/O Pulitzer/NNP/O Prizes/NNPS/O in/IN/O history/NN/O and/CC/O biography/NN/O ././O
