Mr./NNP/O Evans/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O stay/VB/O until/IN/O a/DT/O successor/NN/O is/VBZ/O found/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O later/RB/O than/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O relationship/NN/O between/IN/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Australian/JJ/O company/NN/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O quickly/RB/O deteriorating/VBG/O ././O
On/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 19/CD/O ,/,/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O about/IN/O to/TO/O default/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 5.9/CD/O million/CD/O payment/NN/O owed/VBN/O to/TO/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O connection/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O television/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O arrange/VB/O financing/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O early/RB/O on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 19/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O of/IN/O two/CD/O hectic/JJ/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O board/NN/O meetings/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Evans/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O believed/VBD/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O forthcoming/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O recommended/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O file/NN/O for/IN/O protection/NN/O under/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O before/IN/O the/DT/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG deadline/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O source/NN/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O sessions/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O three/CD/O members/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Australian/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O overrode/VBD/O him/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Evans/NNP/B-PERSON resigned/VBD/O ././O
Later/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O source/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O board/NN/O reversed/VBD/O itself/PRP/O ,/,/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O file/VB/O for/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O protection/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O asked/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Evans/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O stay/VB/O on/IN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Evans/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O the/DT/O board/NN/O he/PRP/O needed/VBD/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O to/TO/O think/VB/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Evans/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O a/DT/O restructuring/VBG/O plan/NN/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O sell/VB/O off/RP/O assets/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O indicated/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O cut/VB/O back/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O working/VBG/O capital/NN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O supply/VB/O to/TO/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG shareholder/NN/O filed/VBD/O suit/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE charging/VBG/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O misleading/VBG/O shareholders/NNS/O about/IN/O Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG financial/JJ/O position/NN/O ././O
Qintex/NNP/B-ORG Australia/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O seen/VBN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O ././O
