The/DT/O former/JJ/O congressman/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O speaker/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG after/IN/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O dealings/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ensconced/VBN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O district/NN/O office/NN/O ,/,/O maintained/VBN/O by/IN/O taxpayers/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O allowance/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O negotiating/VBG/O a/DT/O rich/JJ/O book/NN/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O boot/NN/O ././O
Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Deaver/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG aide/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O recent/JJ/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O teeming/VBG/O ranks/NNS/O of/IN/O fallen/VBN/O politicians/NNS/O and/CC/O officials/NNS/O earning/VBG/O their/PRP$/O way/NN/O as/IN/O lobbyists/NNS/O and/CC/O consultants/NNS/O here/RB/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O busy/JJ/O schedule/NN/O of/IN/O speaking/NN/O engagements/NNS/O at/IN/O $/$/O 10,000/CD/O a/DT/O pop/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O tony/JJ/O places/NNS/O including/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Yale/NNP/I-ORG Political/NNP/I-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O few/JJ/O mementos/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O days/NNS/O as/IN/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG deputy/NN/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O staff/NN/O and/CC/O confidant/NN/O of/IN/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Nancy/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON confessed/VBD/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O alcoholism/NN/O during/IN/O his/PRP$/O trial/NN/O on/IN/O perjury/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O renaissance/NN/O :/:/O an/DT/O appearance/NN/O on/IN/O ABC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ``/``/O Nightline/NNP/O ''/''/O for/IN/O a/DT/O show/NN/O on/IN/O pack/NN/O journalism/NN/O ././O
Host/NNP/O Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Koppel/NNP/I-PERSON introduced/VBD/O him/PRP/O as/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O master/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Reagan/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O with/IN/O nary/PDT/O a/DT/O mention/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O conviction/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O on/IN/O perjury/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Fedders/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O philosophical/JJ/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O travails/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O a/DT/O psychoanalyst/NN/O five/CD/O mornings/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
My/PRP$/O universe/NN/O has/VBZ/O changed/VBN/O ././O
I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O enjoying/VBG/O my/PRP$/O life/NN/O and/CC/O who/WP/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O today/NN/O ././O
Nobody/NN/O proved/VBD/O that/IN/O more/RBR/O masterfully/RB/O than/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Coelho/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Democratic/JJ/O majority/NN/O whip/NN/O ././O
Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Rather/NNP/I-PERSON served/VBD/O as/IN/O emcee/NN/O ././O
Anne/NNP/B-PERSON Burford/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O EPA/NNP/B-ORG chief/NN/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O under/IN/O fire/NN/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O during/IN/O a/DT/O flap/NN/O with/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O kayoed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O confrontation/NN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O never/RB/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O official/JJ/O wrondgoing/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Burford/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O bitter/JJ/O over/IN/O the/DT/O overwhelming/JJ/O legal/JJ/O expenses/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O clearing/VBG/O her/PRP$/O name/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O former/JJ/O EPA/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O ,/,/O Rita/NNP/B-PERSON Lavelle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O struggling/VBG/O after/IN/O her/PRP$/O conviction/NN/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O on/IN/O perjury/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
No/DT/O book/NN/O contracts/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O dangled/VBN/O before/IN/O Deborah/NNP/B-PERSON Gore/NNP/I-PERSON Dean/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O reigning/VBG/O queen/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ././O
Donna/NNP/B-PERSON Rice/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Hart/NNP/I-PERSON fame/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O obtain/VB/O a/DT/O book/NN/O contract/NN/O and/CC/O lost/VBD/O her/PRP/O modeling/NN/O contract/NN/O for/IN/O ``/``/O No/NNP/O Excuses/NNPS/O ''/''/O jeans/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O back/RB/O in/IN/O jail/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O on/IN/O shoplifting/NN/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Secord/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O performance/NN/O was/VBD/O decidedly/RB/O less/RBR/O inspiring/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O North/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O in/IN/O heavy/JJ/O demand/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O speaker/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O fees/NNS/O reported/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O range/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bauman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O conservative/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O deserted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O wing/NN/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Tower/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O womanizing/VBG/O and/CC/O boozing/VBG/O during/IN/O his/PRP$/O unsuccessful/JJ/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O confirmation/NN/O as/IN/O secretary/NN/O of/IN/O defense/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O become/VBD/O pseudo-lobbyists/NNS/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Mack/NNP/I-PERSON promptly/RB/O quit/VBD/O his/PRP$/O job/NN/O last/JJ/O spring/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O Speaker/NNP/O Wright/NNP/B-PERSON amid/IN/O public/JJ/O outrage/NN/O over/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Mack/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O violent/JJ/O attack/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O young/JJ/O woman/NN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O 19/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON home/NN/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O troubles/NNS/O erupted/VBD/O was/VBD/O former/JJ/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON aide/NN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Ehrlichman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whom/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Deaver/NNP/B-PERSON scarcely/RB/O knew/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bauman/NNP/B-PERSON received/VBD/O an/DT/O encouraging/JJ/O letter/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O recognized/VBN/O master/NN/O of/IN/O scandal/NN/O survival/NN/O ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Nixon/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
