Terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O accord/NN/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O unit/NN/O has/VBZ/O 6,000/CD/O customers/NNS/O and/CC/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O one/CD/O analyst/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O 1988/CD/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 85/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O widely/RB/O expected/VBN/O ,/,/O Bell/NNP/B-ORG Atlantic/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O buying/VBG/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG customer/NN/O base/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O approximately/RB/O 100/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE maintenance/NN/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O about/IN/O 33/CD/O cities/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O maintenance/NN/O services/NNS/O for/IN/O customers/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Cyber/NNP/O product/NN/O line/NN/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O sold/VBD/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O unit/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC for/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Lawrence/NNP/B-PERSON Perlman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O maintenance/NN/O business/NN/O no/RB/O longer/JJR/O fits/VBZ/O into/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O strategy/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O data/NNS/O solutions/NNS/O company/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
