I/PRP/O read/VBP/O the/DT/O exerpts/NNS/O of/IN/O Wayne/NNP/B-PERSON Angell/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON exchange/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Gosbank/NNP/B-ORG representative/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O Put/VB/O the/DT/O Soviet/NNP/O Economy/NNP/O on/IN/O Golden/NNP/O Rails/NNPS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O editorial/NN/O page/NN/O ,/,/O Oct./NNP/O 5/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O with/IN/O great/JJ/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O since/IN/O the/DT/O gold/JJ/O standard/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O areas/NNS/O of/IN/O research/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Angell/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O incorrect/JJ/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O states/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE large/JJ/O gold/NN/O reserves/NNS/O would/MD/O give/VB/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O great/JJ/O power/NN/O to/TO/O establish/VB/O credibility/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
During/IN/O the/DT/O latter/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 19th/JJ/O century/NN/O ,/,/O Russia/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O gold/JJ/O standard/NN/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O gold/JJ/O reserves/NNS/O representing/VBG/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 100/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O outstanding/JJ/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O no/DT/O one/CD/O outside/NN/O Russia/NNP/B-GPE used/VBD/O rubles/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O on/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O hand/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O gold/JJ/O reserves/NNS/O that/WDT/O averaged/VBD/O about/IN/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O outstanding/JJ/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG notes/NNS/O were/VBD/O accepted/VBN/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O success/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O British/NNP/O gold/NN/O standard/NN/O was/VBD/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O independent/JJ/O private/JJ/O banking/NN/O and/CC/O common/JJ/O law/NN/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O the/DT/O choice/NN/O of/IN/O gold/NN/O for/IN/O valuing/VBG/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O coincidence/NN/O that/IN/O from/IN/O 1844/CD/O to/TO/O 1914/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O private/JJ/O bank/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O was/VBD/O never/RB/O devalued/VBN/O and/CC/O payment/NN/O of/IN/O gold/NN/O for/IN/O pound/NN/O notes/NNS/O was/VBD/O never/RB/O suspended/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O with/IN/O the/DT/O subsequent/JJ/O nationalization/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG England/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O was/VBD/O devalued/VBN/O with/IN/O increasing/VBG/O frequency/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O use/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O medium/NN/O of/IN/O exchange/NN/O declined/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE should/MD/O keep/VB/O these/DT/O lessons/NNS/O in/IN/O mind/NN/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O seeks/VBZ/O to/TO/O establish/VB/O the/DT/O ruble/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O currency/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O way/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O ruble/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O international/JJ/O currency/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O reserves/NNS/O of/IN/O gold/NN/O and/CC/O earning/VBG/O assets/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Swiss/NNP/O bank/NN/O with/IN/O distributions/NNS/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O Swiss/NNP/O laws/NNS/O ././O
Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Petruzzi/NNP/I-PERSON
Professor/NNP/O of/IN/O Taxation/NNP/O
California/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG
Fullerton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
