John/NNP/B-PERSON Padovan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 51/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O a/DT/O deputy/NN/O chairman/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Padovan/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O currently/RB/O a/DT/O director/NN/O at/IN/O Barclays/NNP/B-ORG de/NNP/I-ORG Zoete/NNP/I-ORG Wedd/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Pimlott/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O McCarthy/NNP/B-PERSON join/VBP/O Barclay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG from/IN/O Kleinwort/NNP/B-ORG Benson/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG where/WRB/O they/PRP/O served/VBD/O as/IN/O directors/NNS/O ././O
