Two/CD/O recent/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O by/IN/O federal/JJ/O courts/NNS/O cast/VBD/O judges/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O odd/JJ/O role/NN/O of/IN/O telling/VBG/O authors/NNS/O how/WRB/O they/PRP/O should/MD/O write/VB/O history/NN/O and/CC/O biography/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O decisions/NNS/O deserve/VBP/O more/JJR/O attention/NN/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O received/VBN/O from/IN/O scholars/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O from/IN/O journalists/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hubbard/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O died/VBD/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O bequeathed/VBD/O the/DT/O copyrights/NNS/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O writings/NNS/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O church/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O licensed/VBD/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O New/NNP/B-ORG Era/NNP/I-ORG Publications/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Danish/JJ/O corporation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O publisher/NN/O argued/VBD/O in/IN/O response/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O fair/JJ/O use/NN/O ''/''/O statute/NN/O permits/VBZ/O quotation/NN/O ``/``/O for/IN/O purposes/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O criticism/NN/O ,/,/O comment/NN/O ,/,/O news/NN/O reporting/NN/O ,/,/O teaching/NN/O ,/,/O .../:/O scholarship/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O research/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
District/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG Judge/NNP/O Pierre/NNP/B-PERSON Leval/NNP/I-PERSON denied/VBD/O the/DT/O injunction/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O ground/NN/O that/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG Era/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O its/PRP$/O claim/NN/O within/IN/O a/DT/O reasonable/JJ/O time/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O doctrine/NN/O lawyers/NNS/O call/VBP/O ``/``/O laches/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O merits/NNS/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Leval/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O written/VBN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O serious/JJ/O book/NN/O of/IN/O responsible/JJ/O historical/JJ/O criticism/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Verbatim/JJ/O quotation/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O believed/VBD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O justified/VBN/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O prove/VB/O points/NNS/O the/DT/O author/NN/O had/VBD/O asserted/VBN/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hubbard/NNP/B-PERSON --/:/O mendacity/NN/O ,/,/O bigotry/NN/O ,/,/O paranoia/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O unlovely/JJ/O traits/NNS/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O persuasively/RB/O demonstrated/VBN/O without/IN/O use/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hubbard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O own/JJ/O words/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Judge/NNP/O Leval/NNP/B-PERSON felt/VBD/O constrained/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O earlier/JJR/O decision/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Second/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG forbidding/VBG/O a/DT/O biographer/NN/O of/IN/O J.D./NNP/B-PERSON Salinger/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O quote/VB/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O personal/JJ/O letters/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O distinguished/VBD/O the/DT/O two/CD/O cases/NNS/O :/:/O In/IN/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Leval/NNP/B-PERSON noted/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O quotations/NNS/O were/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O enlivening/VBG/O the/DT/O biography/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O of/IN/O proving/VBG/O points/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O the/DT/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON decision/NN/O created/VBD/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O presumption/NN/O against/IN/O fair/JJ/O use/NN/O of/IN/O unpublished/JJ/O materials/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O proper/JJ/O remedy/NN/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Leval/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O lay/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O suit/NN/O for/IN/O damages/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O in/IN/O an/DT/O injunction/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O case/NN/O went/VBD/O on/IN/O appeal/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Second/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O conclude/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O two/CD/O judges/NNS/O wrote/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O that/IN/O laches/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O sole/JJ/O bar/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O issuance/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O injunction/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
This/DT/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O for/IN/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Oakes/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O court/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/NN/O judge/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O powerful/JJ/O separate/JJ/O opinion/NN/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Oakes/NNP/B-PERSON further/RB/O distinguished/VBD/O the/DT/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O by/IN/O pointing/VBG/O out/RP/O that/IN/O a/DT/O living/VBG/O person/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O had/VBD/O privacy/NN/O rights/NNS/O that/WDT/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O apply/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O dead/JJ/O man/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hubbard/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O thought/VBD/O that/IN/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON might/MD/O by/IN/O being/VBG/O taken/VBN/O in/IN/O another/DT/O factual/JJ/O context/NN/O come/VBN/O back/RB/O to/TO/O haunt/VB/O us/PRP/O ././O
This/DT/O case/NN/O realizes/VBZ/O that/DT/O concern/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Decisions/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Second/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG itself/PRP/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Oakes/NNP/B-PERSON continued/VBD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O recognized/VBN/O that/IN/O public/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O subject/JJ/O matter/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O indispensability/NN/O in/IN/O particular/JJ/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O verbatim/JJ/O quotations/NNS/O are/VBP/O vital/JJ/O components/NNS/O of/IN/O fair/JJ/O use/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O injunction/NN/O Judges/NNP/O Miner/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Altimari/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O so/RB/O readily/RB/O have/VB/O granted/VBN/O had/VBD/O New/NNP/B-ORG Era/NNP/I-ORG sued/VBN/O in/IN/O time/NN/O ?/./O
Suppression/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Oakes/NNP/B-PERSON observed/VBD/O ,/,/O would/MD/O operate/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O prior/JJ/O restraint/NN/O and/CC/O thus/RB/O involve/VB/O the/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O here/RB/O Judge/NNP/O Oakes/NNP/B-PERSON went/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O question/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Responsible/JJ/O biographers/NNS/O and/CC/O historians/NNS/O constantly/RB/O use/VBP/O primary/JJ/O sources/NNS/O ,/,/O letters/NNS/O ,/,/O diaries/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O memoranda/NNS/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O irresponsible/JJ/O to/TO/O ignore/VB/O such/JJ/O sources/NNS/O of/IN/O information/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O scholars/NNS/O in/IN/O fulfilling/VBG/O their/PRP$/O responsibility/NN/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O claim/VB/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O invade/VB/O every/DT/O collection/NN/O of/IN/O papers/NNS/O that/WDT/O bears/VBZ/O upon/IN/O their/PRP$/O topics/NNS/O of/IN/O investigation/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O of/IN/O course/NN/O they/PRP/O agree/VBP/O that/IN/O people/NNS/O can/MD/O impose/VB/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O papers/NNS/O ,/,/O whether/IN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O possession/NN/O or/CC/O as/RB/O donated/VBN/O or/CC/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O libraries/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O when/WRB/O responsible/JJ/O scholars/NNS/O gain/VBP/O legitimate/JJ/O access/NN/O to/TO/O unpublished/JJ/O materials/NNS/O ,/,/O copyright/NN/O should/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O permitted/VBN/O to/TO/O deny/VB/O them/PRP/O use/NN/O of/IN/O quotations/NNS/O that/WDT/O help/VBP/O to/TO/O establish/VB/O historical/JJ/O points/NNS/O ././O
Judges/NNPS/O Oakes/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Leval/NNP/B-PERSON understand/VBP/O the/DT/O requirements/NNS/O of/IN/O historical/JJ/O scholarship/NN/O ././O
Judges/NNPS/O Miner/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Altimari/NNP/B-PERSON do/VBP/O not/RB/O appear/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O clue/NN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O moment/NN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O judges/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O matters/NNS/O stand/VBP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON ruling/NN/O ,/,/O torn/VBN/O from/IN/O context/NN/O and/CC/O broadly/RB/O construed/VBN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O controlling/VBG/O ././O
If/IN/O an/DT/O author/NN/O quotes/VBZ/O ``/``/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O minimal/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O ''/''/O of/IN/O unpublished/JJ/O copyrighted/VBN/O materials/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Salinger/NNP/B-PERSON decision/NN/O had/VBD/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ``/``/O he/PRP/O deserves/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O enjoined/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O courts/NNS/O have/VBP/O not/RB/O defined/VBN/O ``/``/O minimal/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O publishers/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O understand/VBP/O ,/,/O take/VBP/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O mean/VB/O about/IN/O 50/CD/O words/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O second/JJ/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O handed/VBN/O down/RP/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Appeals/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ninth/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O another/DT/O blow/NN/O against/IN/O scholarship/NN/O ././O
Janet/NNP/B-PERSON Malcolm/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O professional/JJ/O writer/NN/O on/IN/O psychiatric/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ,/,/O wrote/VBD/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O articles/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Yorker/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O later/RB/O published/VBN/O in/IN/O book/NN/O form/NN/O by/IN/O Knopf/NNP/B-ORG under/IN/O the/DT/O title/NN/O ``/``/O In/NNP/O the/DT/O Freud/NNP/O Archives/NNPS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O articles/NNS/O were/VBD/O largely/RB/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O interviews/NNS/O Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O taped/VBN/O with/IN/O Jeffrey/NNP/B-PERSON Masson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O psychoanalyst/NN/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O served/VBN/O as/IN/O projects/NNS/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Freud/NNP/I-ORG Archives/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON then/RB/O brought/VBD/O a/DT/O libel/NN/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Yorker/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Knopf/NNP/B-ORG ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O figure/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O to/TO/O prove/VB/O malice/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O as/IN/O proof/NN/O of/IN/O malice/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON contended/VBD/O that/IN/O defamatory/JJ/O quotations/NNS/O ascribed/VBN/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O by/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON were/VBD/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O fabricated/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O quotes/NNS/O could/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O found/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O tapes/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O two/CD/O judges/NNS/O who/WP/O decided/VBD/O the/DT/O case/NN/O for/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP$/O publishers/NNS/O conceded/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O assume/VBP/O the/DT/O quotations/NNS/O were/VBD/O deliberately/RB/O altered/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
For/IN/O all/DT/O historians/NNS/O and/CC/O most/JJS/O journalists/NNS/O ,/,/O this/DT/O admission/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O sufficient/JJ/O to/TO/O condemn/VB/O the/DT/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON articles/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Judge/NNP/O Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON Alarcon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O joined/VBN/O by/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Cynthia/NNP/B-PERSON Holcomb/NNP/I-PERSON Hall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O took/VBD/O the/DT/O astonishing/JJ/O position/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O perfectly/RB/O OK/JJ/O to/TO/O fabricate/VB/O quotations/NNS/O so/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O judge/NN/O finds/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O fabrications/NNS/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O alter/VB/O substantive/JJ/O content/NN/O or/CC/O are/VBP/O rational/JJ/O interpretations/NNS/O of/IN/O ambiguous/JJ/O remarks/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O his/PRP$/O eloquent/JJ/O dissent/NN/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Alex/NNP/B-PERSON Kozinski/NNP/I-PERSON observed/VBD/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O writer/NN/O uses/VBZ/O quotation/NN/O marks/NNS/O in/IN/O reporting/VBG/O what/WP/O someone/NN/O has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O reader/NN/O assumes/VBZ/O that/IN/O these/DT/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O speaker/NN/O 's/POS/O precise/JJ/O words/NNS/O or/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O his/PRP$/O words/NNS/O purged/VBN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O uh/UH/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O you/PRP/O know/VBP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O grammatical/JJ/O error/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O judges/NNS/O have/VBP/O an/DT/O obligation/NN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O to/TO/O safeguard/VB/O freedom/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O deliberately/RB/O alter/VB/O quotations/NNS/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O view/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O concomitant/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O press/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O wrote/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON described/VBD/O himself/PRP/O as/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O greatest/JJS/O analyst/NN/O who/WP/O ever/RB/O lived/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
No/DT/O such/JJ/O statement/NN/O appears/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O tapes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O majority/NN/O cited/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O remark/NN/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O me/PRP/O alone/RB/O .../:/O against/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O analytic/JJ/O world/NN/O ''/''/O as/IN/O warrant/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON fabrication/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Kozinski/NNP/B-PERSON noted/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O context/NN/O shows/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O me/PRP/O alone/JJ/O ''/''/O remark/NN/O referred/VBD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O alleged/JJ/O pre-eminence/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O profession/NN/O but/CC/O to/TO/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O particular/JJ/O issue/NN/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O shared/VBN/O by/IN/O anyone/NN/O else/RB/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON describing/VBG/O himself/PRP/O as/IN/O ``/``/O an/DT/O intellectual/JJ/O gigolo/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Again/RB/O ,/,/O no/DT/O such/JJ/O statement/NN/O appears/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O tapes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O majority/NN/O decision/NN/O contended/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O phrase/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O rational/JJ/O interpretation/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Masson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O description/NN/O of/IN/O himself/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O private/JJ/O asset/NN/O but/CC/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O liability/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O Anna/NNP/B-PERSON Freud/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O that/IN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O defamatory/JJ/O ././O
Judge/NNP/O Kozinski/NNP/B-PERSON found/VBD/O the/DT/O derivation/NN/O entirely/RB/O strained/VBN/O and/CC/O writes/VBZ/O that/IN/O ``/``/O for/IN/O an/DT/O academic/JJ/O to/TO/O refer/VB/O to/TO/O himself/PRP/O as/IN/O an/DT/O intellectual/JJ/O gigolo/NN/O is/VBZ/O .../:/O a/DT/O devastating/JJ/O admission/NN/O of/IN/O professional/JJ/O dishonesty/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O Janet/NNP/B-PERSON Malcolm/NNP/I-PERSON who/WP/O calls/VBZ/O him/PRP/O such/JJ/O :/:/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O words/NNS/O reveal/VBP/O this/DT/O psychological/JJ/O profile/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
We/PRP/O now/RB/O know/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O words/NNS/O were/VBD/O not/RB/O always/RB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O sacred/JJ/O rule/NN/O of/IN/O journalism/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Hersey/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O writer/NN/O must/MD/O not/RB/O invent/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Should/MD/O the/DT/O green/JJ/O light/NN/O Judges/NNPS/O Alarcon/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Hall/NNP/B-PERSON have/VB/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O fabrication/NN/O of/IN/O quotations/NNS/O become/VB/O standard/JJ/O practice/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O notably/RB/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O journalism/NN/O for/IN/O historians/NNS/O --/:/O and/CC/O for/IN/O citizens/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Kozinski/NNP/B-PERSON put/VBD/O it/PRP/O :/:/O ``/``/O To/TO/O invoke/VB/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O deliberately/RB/O distort/VB/O what/WP/O someone/NN/O else/RB/O has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O assert/VB/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O lie/VB/O in/IN/O print/NN/O .../:/O ././O
Masson/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O lost/VBN/O his/PRP$/O case/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O defendants/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O profession/NN/O to/TO/O which/WDT/O they/PRP/O belong/VBP/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O lost/VBN/O far/RB/O more/RBR/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O historical/JJ/O profession/NN/O will/MD/O survive/VB/O these/DT/O decisions/NNS/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O in/IN/O time/NN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O correct/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O writing/VBG/O history/NN/O is/VBZ/O tough/JJ/O enough/RB/O without/IN/O judges/NNS/O gratuitously/RB/O throwing/VBG/O obstacles/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O scholar/NN/O 's/POS/O path/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Schlesinger/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O Albert/NNP/B-PERSON Schweitzer/NNP/I-PERSON professor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O humanities/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O a/DT/O winner/NN/O of/IN/O Pulitzer/NNP/O Prizes/NNPS/O in/IN/O history/NN/O and/CC/O biography/NN/O ././O
