WASHINGTON/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O
United/NNP/B-ORG Technologies/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG won/VBD/O an/DT/O $/$/O 18/CD/O million/CD/O Army/NNP/B-ORG contract/NN/O for/IN/O helicopter/NN/O modifications/NNS/O and/CC/O spare/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ././O
Ingalls/NNP/B-ORG Shipbuilding/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O division/NN/O of/IN/O Litton/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O given/VBN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 15.5/CD/O million/CD/O extension/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O contract/NN/O for/IN/O shipyard/NN/O services/NNS/O ././O
