Duriron/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Automax/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Cincinnati/NNP/B-GPE maker/NN/O of/IN/O control/NN/O accessories/NNS/O for/IN/O industrial/JJ/O valves/NNS/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Duriron/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O through/IN/O an/DT/O exchange/NN/O of/IN/O stock/NN/O ././O
Duriron/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O pumps/NNS/O ,/,/O valves/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O controls/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O impact/VB/O its/PRP$/O 1989/CD/O profit/NN/O ././O
