Western/JJ/O European/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O who/WP/O favor/VBP/O speedy/JJ/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O monetary/JJ/O union/NN/O are/VBP/O adding/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O argument/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O arsenal/NN/O :/:/O the/DT/O dizzying/VBG/O political/JJ/O changes/NNS/O under/IN/O way/NN/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ././O
French/NNP/O President/NNP/O Francois/NNP/B-PERSON Mitterrand/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Jacques/NNP/B-PERSON Delors/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Spanish/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Felipe/NNP/B-PERSON Gonzalez/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O have/VBP/O begun/VBN/O linking/VBG/O the/DT/O rapid/JJ/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O speed/VB/O up/IN/O changes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O stressing/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O way/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC to/TO/O help/VB/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC is/VBZ/O to/TO/O move/VB/O faster/RBR/O towards/IN/O Western/NNP/O European/NNP/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O monetary/JJ/O unity/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mitterrand/NNP/B-PERSON proposed/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O conference/NN/O be/VB/O convened/VBN/O next/JJ/O fall/NN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O treaty/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG allowing/VBG/O a/DT/O European/JJ/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O treaty/NN/O be/VB/O ratified/VBN/O by/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Mitterrand/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O proposed/VBD/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O ``/``/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG ''/''/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O channel/VB/O development/NN/O money/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ././O
One/CD/O basis/NN/O for/IN/O linking/VBG/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC is/VBZ/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O that/IN/O integrating/VBG/O 110/CD/O million/CD/O Eastern/JJ/O Europeans/NNPS/O with/IN/O 320/CD/O million/CD/O Western/JJ/O Europeans/NNPS/O is/VBZ/O primarily/RB/O the/DT/O task/NN/O of/IN/O Europeans/NNPS/O ,/,/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O obvious/JJ/O strategic/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O interest/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O natural/JJ/O division/NN/O of/IN/O labor/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Francois/NNP/B-PERSON Heisbourg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Strategic/NNP/I-ORG Studies/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE more/RBR/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O strategic/JJ/O issues/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Western/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC more/RBR/O involved/VBN/O with/IN/O specific/JJ/O aid/NN/O measures/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/O designation/NN/O at/IN/O July/NNP/O 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O summit/NN/O of/IN/O major/JJ/O industrialized/VBN/O nations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG EC/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O coordinator/NN/O of/IN/O Western/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O a/DT/O first/JJ/O step/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O French/JJ/O analysis/NN/O goes/VBZ/O further/RB/O ././O
Managing/VBG/O change/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O require/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O more/JJR/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O prominent/JJ/O role/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O especially/RB/O in/IN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O German/JJ/O reunification/NN/O ././O
Thierry/NNP/B-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON Montbrial/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG French/NNP/I-ORG Institutue/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O clear/JJ/O what/WP/O ,/,/O exactly/RB/O ,/,/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE wants/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O Once/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O feel/VBP/O comfortable/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O that/RB/O much/RB/O easier/JJR/O to/TO/O make/VB/O more/JJR/O progress/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O social/JJ/O reforms/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O now/RB/O starting/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC ././O
