Securities/NNS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Breeden/NNP/I-PERSON told/VBD/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O subcommittee/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O consider/VB/O imposing/VBG/O ``/``/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O halt/VB/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O at/IN/O volatile/JJ/O times/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O first/JJ/O testimony/NN/O to/TO/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG since/IN/O taking/VBG/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG post/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O is/VBZ/O studying/VBG/O the/DT/O Friday/NNP/O the/DT/O 13th/JJ/O market/NN/O plunge/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O how/WRB/O current/JJ/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O affected/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O that/DT/O day/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O following/VBG/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
Circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O ,/,/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O a/DT/O breather/NN/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O sharp/JJ/O price/NN/O movements/NNS/O ,/,/O curb/NN/O trading/NN/O of/IN/O futures/NNS/O or/CC/O stocks/NNS/O at/IN/O various/JJ/O trigger/NN/O points/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O circuit/NN/O breaker/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O closed/VBN/O down/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O n't/RB/O tripped/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O reject/VB/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O move/VB/O through/IN/O this/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON contended/VBD/O that/IN/O uncertainty/NN/O over/IN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG might/MD/O act/VB/O could/MD/O worsen/VB/O volatility/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Breeden/NNP/B-PERSON offered/VBD/O strong/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O would/MD/O force/VB/O brokerage/NN/O houses/NNS/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG detailed/VBN/O information/NN/O about/IN/O loans/NNS/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O holding/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O backed/VBD/O a/DT/O rule/NN/O to/TO/O require/VB/O large/JJ/O traders/NNS/O to/TO/O report/VB/O transactions/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O systematic/JJ/O basis/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O information/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O argued/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O critical/JJ/O to/TO/O reconstructing/VBG/O sharp/JJ/O market/NN/O moves/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O one/CD/O nearly/RB/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
