Among/IN/O other/JJ/O concerns/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O says/VBZ/O researchers/NNS/O with/IN/O business/NN/O ties/NNS/O are/VBP/O more/RBR/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O falsify/VB/O findings/NNS/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O tout/VB/O new/JJ/O drugs/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O ties/NNS/O between/IN/O academia/NN/O and/CC/O venture/NN/O capital/NN/O have/VBP/O blossomed/VBN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O governmental/JJ/O fear/NN/O of/IN/O abuse/NN/O has/VBZ/O risen/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O guidelines/NNS/O could/MD/O ``/``/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O impossible/JJ/O to/TO/O commercialize/VB/O research/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O associate/JJ/O provost/NN/O and/CC/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O research/NN/O at/IN/O Massachusetts/NNP/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O asking/VBG/O grant/NN/O recipients/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O for/IN/O comments/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O until/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 15/CD/O ././O
After/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O make/VB/O a/DT/O final/JJ/O decision/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O $/$/O 2.3/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O investors/NNS/O launched/VBD/O Lithox/NNP/B-ORG last/JJ/O year/NN/O to/TO/O market/NN/O a/DT/O gallstone/NN/O cure/NN/O being/NN/O developed/VBN/O by/IN/O researchers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/I-ORG San/NNP/I-ORG Diego/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O researchers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Lithox/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O receive/VB/O a/DT/O royalty/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O if/IN/O their/PRP$/O research/NN/O yields/VBZ/O a/DT/O commercial/JJ/O product/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O because/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O like/IN/O many/JJ/O other/JJ/O universities/NNS/O ,/,/O shares/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O royalties/NNS/O with/IN/O researchers/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O disqualify/VB/O itself/PRP/O from/IN/O federal/JJ/O funds/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Daly/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
While/IN/O universities/NNS/O develop/VBP/O the/DT/O basic/JJ/O research/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O venture/NN/O capitalists/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O ones/NNS/O best/RB/O positioned/VBD/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O its/PRP$/O commercialization/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Gloria/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Doubleday/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Commonwealth/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O way/NN/O to/TO/O transfer/VB/O technology/NN/O straight/RB/O off/IN/O the/DT/O campuses/NNS/O of/IN/O universities/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O if/IN/O that/DT/O happens/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O process/NN/O of/IN/O transferring/VBG/O technology/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O marketplace/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O harmed/VBN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O say/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O stakes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O controversy/NN/O are/VBP/O large/JJ/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O deals/NNS/O involved/VBD/O transactions/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O scientific/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O or/CC/O researchers/NNS/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O commercialize/VB/O their/PRP$/O work/NN/O in/IN/O return/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O equity/NN/O stake/NN/O or/CC/O royalties/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O many/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O deals/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O venture/NN/O capitalists/NNS/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O inside/NN/O track/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Lawrence/NNP/B-PERSON Bock/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Avalon/NNP/B-ORG Ventures/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O La/NNP/B-GPE Jolla/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Investors/NNS/O were/VBD/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O gamble/VB/O on/IN/O new/JJ/O technologies/NNS/O because/IN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O exclusive/JJ/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O those/DT/O technologies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O under/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O ,/,/O all/DT/O federally/RB/O funded/VBN/O research/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O reported/VBN/O publicly/RB/O so/IN/O that/IN/O anyone/NN/O can/MD/O capitalize/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O work/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Without/IN/O the/DT/O exclusivity/NN/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O venture/NN/O capitalists/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O incentive/NN/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O deals/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Bock/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Avalon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O invested/VBD/O $/$/O 14/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O Athena/NNP/B-ORG Neurosciences/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE San/NNP/I-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O license/VB/O and/CC/O develop/VB/O technology/NN/O for/IN/O delivery/NN/O of/IN/O drugs/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O brain/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O before/IN/O Athena/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O an/DT/O exclusive/JJ/O license/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Register/NNP/I-ORG published/VBD/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O details/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O giving/VBG/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O potential/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O exploit/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Bock/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Athena/NNP/B-ORG eventually/RB/O acquired/VBD/O exclusive/JJ/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O currently/RB/O is/VBZ/O developing/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Bock/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O close/JJ/O call/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O proposed/VBN/O guidelines/NNS/O could/MD/O also/RB/O delay/VB/O commercialization/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O force/VB/O small/JJ/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O waste/VB/O scarce/JJ/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O entrepreneurs/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
For/IN/O its/PRP$/O part/NN/O ,/,/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG insists/VBZ/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O guidelines/NNS/O ``/``/O should/MD/O not/RB/O stifle/VB/O research/NN/O creativity/NN/O or/CC/O technology/NN/O transfer/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O research/NN/O laboratory/NN/O to/TO/O commercial/JJ/O use/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Universities/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O MIT/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O a/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O act/VB/O as/IN/O brokers/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O individual/JJ/O scientists/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Katherine/NNP/B-PERSON Bick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O oversees/VBZ/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG grants/NNS/O program/NN/O as/IN/O its/PRP$/O deputy/NN/O director/NN/O for/IN/O extramural/JJ/O research/NN/O ././O
NIH/NNP/B-ORG staff/NN/O members/NNS/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O guidelines/NNS/O are/VBP/O essential/JJ/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O the/DT/O escalation/NN/O of/IN/O problems/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O already/RB/O begun/VBN/O to/TO/O surface/VB/O in/IN/O scientific/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
Not/RB/O long/RB/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O scientists/NNS/O holding/VBG/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O Spectra/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceutical/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG were/VBD/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O falsifying/VBG/O research/NN/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O congressional/JJ/O subcommitee/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O investigating/VBG/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O abuse/NN/O from/IN/O researchers/NNS/O holding/VBG/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O companies/NNS/O exploiting/VBG/O their/PRP$/O research/NN/O ././O
Among/IN/O other/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG guidelines/NNS/O would/MD/O prohibit/VB/O researchers/NNS/O and/CC/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O immediate/JJ/O families/NNS/O from/IN/O holding/VBG/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O company/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O affected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O outcome/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O research/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Bick/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG administrator/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O business/NN/O and/CC/O scientific/JJ/O community/NN/O is/VBZ/O overreacting/VBG/O to/TO/O what/WP/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O merely/RB/O meant/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ``/``/O ideas/NNS/O for/IN/O discussion/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O predictions/NNS/O of/IN/O doom/NN/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O premature/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O agencies/NNS/O like/IN/O the/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG circulate/VBP/O guidelines/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O often/RB/O already/RB/O formulated/VBN/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O veteran/NN/O scientists/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O institutions/NNS/O already/RB/O are/VBP/O taking/VBG/O note/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/I-ORG San/NNP/I-ORG Francisco/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O also/RB/O circulating/VBG/O a/DT/O memo/NN/O among/IN/O its/PRP$/O scientific/JJ/O faculty/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O restrict/VB/O contact/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O many/JJ/O other/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O ,/,/O scientists/NNS/O are/VBP/O shunning/VBG/O contacts/NNS/O with/IN/O venture/NN/O investors/NNS/O until/IN/O the/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG policy/NN/O is/VBZ/O settled/VBN/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Daly/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O capitalist/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O matter/VB/O whether/IN/O they/PRP/O call/VBP/O it/PRP/O guidelines/NNS/O or/CC/O policy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O damage/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O done/VBN/O ././O
