Brooks/NNP/B-ORG Armored/NNP/I-ORG Car/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG never/RB/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O get/VB/O into/IN/O money/NN/O laundering/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O July/NNP/O 5/CD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O thunderstorm/NN/O in/IN/O Wilmington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Del./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O caused/VBD/O Shellpot/NNP/B-LOC Creek/NNP/I-LOC to/TO/O rise/VB/O 15/CD/O feet/NNS/O ,/,/O pouring/VBG/O 1.3/CD/O million/CD/O gallons/NNS/O of/IN/O water/NN/O into/IN/O basement/NN/O vaults/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O water/NN/O destroyed/VBD/O about/IN/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O currency/NN/O and/CC/O caked/VBD/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O coins/NNS/O with/IN/O mud/NN/O ,/,/O rendering/VBG/O them/PRP/O dangerous/JJ/O to/TO/O counting/VBG/O machines/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O paper/NN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O moldy/JJ/O ,/,/O mildewy/JJ/O and/CC/O smelly/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O exchanged/VBN/O through/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Philadelphia/NNP/I-ORG without/IN/O incident/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O got/VBD/O caught/VBN/O between/IN/O bureaucracies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O President/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON F./NNP/I-PERSON Brooks/NNP/I-PERSON Jr/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Mint/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O take/VB/O the/DT/O coin/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O mutilated/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG accepts/VBZ/O only/JJ/O clean/JJ/O coins/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Philadelphia/NNP/I-ORG Fed/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O merely/RB/O an/DT/O ``/``/O agent/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O coins/NNS/O ,/,/O responsible/JJ/O only/RB/O for/IN/O storage/NN/O and/CC/O distribution/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O issue/VBP/O paper/NN/O money/NN/O ;/:/O we/PRP/O destroy/VBP/O paper/NN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Jane/NNP/B-PERSON Hinkle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-ORG Fed/NNP/I-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O coin/NN/O is/VBZ/O their/PRP$/O problem/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Brooks/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O ,/,/O figuring/VBG/O that/IN/O transporting/VBG/O the/DT/O mucked/VBN/O up/IN/O money/NN/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O cost/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O thousands/NNS/O more/RBR/O ././O
So/IN/O Brooks/NNP/B-PERSON gave/VBD/O the/DT/O dirty/JJ/O work/NN/O to/TO/O Coin/NNP/B-ORG Wrap/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O came/VBD/O up/RP/O with/IN/O an/DT/O unusual/JJ/O solution/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O giant/JJ/O heater/NN/O ,/,/O working/VBG/O like/IN/O a/DT/O blowtorch/NN/O ,/,/O causes/VBZ/O the/DT/O mud/NN/O to/TO/O crust/NN/O and/CC/O burns/NNS/O off/RP/O any/DT/O wrappers/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O clanging/VBG/O around/RB/O for/IN/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O or/CC/O so/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O shiny/JJ/O ,/,/O hot/JJ/O money/NN/O pours/VBZ/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cement/NN/O chute/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O a/DT/O giant/JJ/O vacuum/NN/O sucks/VBZ/O away/RB/O the/DT/O dried/VBN/O mud/NN/O and/CC/O burnt/JJ/O wrappers/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O cooling/VBG/O ,/,/O the/DT/O coins/NNS/O are/VBP/O then/RB/O rewrapped/NN/O ././O
Brooks/NNP/B-ORG expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O Coin/NNP/B-ORG Wrap/NNP/I-ORG a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O --/:/O a/DT/O cost/NN/O that/DT/O insurance/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O cover/VB/O ././O
And/CC/O while/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O is/VBZ/O half/RB/O done/VBN/O ,/,/O Brooks/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O still/RB/O bitter/JJ/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O did/VBD/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O find/VB/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O worth/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O approach/NN/O was/VBD/O suggested/VBN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O String/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O Brooks/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O ``/``/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O laugh/NN/O at/IN/O me/PRP/O or/CC/O anything/NN/O ././O
