Howell/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Port/NNP/B-GPE Washington/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O construction/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O established/VBN/O in/IN/O 1891/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O three/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE branches/NNS/O ././O
Ohbayashi/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O was/VBD/O undertaken/VBN/O to/TO/O participate/VB/O in/IN/O ventures/NNS/O in/IN/O and/CC/O around/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
They/PRP/O said/VBD/O Howell/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O particularly/RB/O successful/JJ/O there/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O membership/NN/O cooperation/NN/O with/IN/O local/JJ/O unions/NNS/O ././O
Ohbayashi/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O second/JJ/O largest/JJS/O construction/NN/O company/NN/O ././O
Until/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O inability/NN/O to/TO/O form/VB/O membership/NN/O ties/NNS/O with/IN/O organized/VBN/O labor/NN/O has/VBZ/O kept/VBN/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O penetrating/VBG/O the/DT/O lucrative/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE metropolitan/JJ/O area/NN/O construction/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O hopes/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O acquisition/NN/O will/MD/O help/VB/O secure/VB/O large/JJ/O construction/NN/O orders/NNS/O from/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O concerns/NNS/O with/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE operations/NNS/O ././O
Ohbayashi/NNP/B-ORG cited/VBD/O industry/NN/O publications/NNS/O crediting/VBG/O Howell/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O currently/RB/O capitalized/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 2.2/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O with/IN/O receiving/VBG/O orders/NNS/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 225/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O company/NN/O received/VBD/O orders/NNS/O totaling/VBG/O 12.44/CD/O billion/CD/O yen/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 87.9/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE business/NN/O activities/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ended/VBD/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O ././O
