A/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O panel/NN/O of/IN/O journalists/NNS/O that/WDT/O discussed/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O image/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O intercollegiate/JJ/O athletics/NNS/O for/IN/O an/DT/O audience/NN/O of/IN/O campus/NN/O information/NN/O directors/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
Competition/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O maintained/VBN/O --/:/O and/CC/O stadiums/NNS/O probably/RB/O would/MD/O remain/VB/O full/JJ/O --/:/O if/IN/O schedules/NNS/O were/VBD/O reduced/VBN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O games/NNS/O returned/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O students/NNS/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Comments/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O audience/NN/O reflected/VBD/O widespread/JJ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O wistful/JJ/O ,/,/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O those/DT/O conclusions/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O session/NN/O broke/VBD/O up/IN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O approached/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O identified/VBD/O himself/PRP/O as/IN/O the/DT/O alumni/NNS/O director/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Big/NNP/O Ten/CD/O university/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O love/VB/O to/TO/O see/VB/O sports/NNS/O cut/VB/O back/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O so/RB/O would/MD/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O counterparts/NNS/O at/IN/O other/JJ/O schools/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O everybody/NN/O 's/VBZ/O afraid/JJ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O move/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O confided/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O like/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O Russians/NNPS/O :/:/O Nobody/NN/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O disarm/VB/O first/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O so/RB/O our/PRP$/O institutions/NNS/O of/IN/O higher/JJR/O learning/NN/O lurch/VBP/O from/IN/O scandal/NN/O to/TO/O scandal/NN/O on/IN/O gridiron/NN/O and/CC/O basketball/NN/O court/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O casualties/NNS/O mount/VBP/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O :/:/O ``/``/O A/NNP/O Payroll/NNP/O to/TO/O Meet/VB/O :/:/O A/NNP/O Story/NNP/O of/IN/O Greed/NNP/O ,/,/O Corruption/NNP/O and/CC/O Football/NNP/O at/IN/O SMU/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Macmillan/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 221/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 18.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O by/IN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Whitford/NNP/I-PERSON ;/:/O ``/``/O Big/NNP/O Red/NNP/O Confidential/NNP/O :/:/O Inside/NNP/O Nebraska/NNP/O Football/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Contemporary/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 231/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 17.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O by/IN/O Armen/NNP/B-PERSON Keteyian/NNP/I-PERSON ;/:/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Never/NNP/O Too/NNP/O Young/NNP/O to/TO/O Die/VB/O :/:/O The/NNP/O Death/NNP/O of/IN/O Len/NNP/O Bias/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Pantheon/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 252/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 18.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O by/IN/O Lewis/NNP/B-PERSON Cole/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O pick/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O Payroll/NNP/O ''/''/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O reading/NN/O for/IN/O every/DT/O college/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O school/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O ,/,/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O the/DT/O NCAA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ``/``/O death/NN/O penalty/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O without/IN/O football/NN/O --/:/O for/IN/O repeated/VBN/O rules/NNS/O violations/NNS/O ././O
Given/VBN/O current/JJ/O headlines/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Florida/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O brought/VBD/O the/DT/O bribe/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE school/NN/O was/VBD/O Ron/NNP/B-PERSON Meyer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O flashy/JJ/O sort/NN/O who/WP/O came/VBD/O in/IN/O 1975/CD/O to/TO/O rescue/VB/O a/DT/O woebegone/JJ/O program/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Whitford/NNP/B-PERSON writes/VBZ/O ././O
One/CD/O recruiter/NN/O working/VBG/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Meyer/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O so/RB/O generous/JJ/O with/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 20/CD/O bills/NNS/O that/IN/O prospects/NNS/O sang/VBD/O ``/``/O Here/RB/O Comes/VBZ/O Santa/NNP/O Claus/NNP/O ''/''/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O approached/VBD/O ././O
Paying/VBG/O players/NNS/O at/IN/O SMU/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O no/DT/O casual/JJ/O operation/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O involved/VBD/O the/DT/O athletics/NNS/O director/NN/O ,/,/O two/CD/O different/JJ/O football/NN/O coaching/NN/O staffs/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O school/NN/O trustees/NNS/O and/CC/O governors/NNS/O --/:/O just/RB/O about/IN/O everybody/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seemed/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Shields/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O university/NN/O 's/POS/O president/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O memorable/JJ/O passage/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Mr./NNP/O Shields/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O having/VBG/O finally/RB/O learned/VBN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O practice/NN/O ,/,/O expresses/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O outrage/NN/O to/TO/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Clements/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O then/RB/O a/DT/O university/NN/O governor/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O now/RB/O the/DT/O governor/NN/O of/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE !/./O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O oil/NN/O man/NN/O Edwin/NNP/B-PERSON Cox/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O of/IN/O trustees/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O stay/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O author/NN/O Whitford/NNP/B-PERSON quotes/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Clements/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O saying/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O Go/VB/O run/VB/O the/DT/O university/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Which/WDT/O was/VBD/O about/IN/O what/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Shields/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O quietly/RB/O ,/,/O until/IN/O he/PRP/O resigned/VBD/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O pleading/VBG/O ill/JJ/O health/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O stuff/NN/O hit/VBD/O the/DT/O fan/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Whitford/NNP/B-PERSON drew/VBD/O on/IN/O voluminous/JJ/O news/NN/O media/NNS/O coverage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O SMU/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O on/IN/O a/DT/O university/NN/O internal/JJ/O investigation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Keteyian/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O digging/NN/O on/IN/O University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Nebraska/NNP/I-ORG football/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O to/TO/O date/NN/O ,/,/O high/JJ/O and/CC/O dry/JJ/O as/RB/O far/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O NCAA/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O concerned/VBN/O ././O
Unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O low/JJ/O grades/NNS/O as/IN/O an/DT/O investigative/JJ/O reporter/NN/O ,/,/O relying/VBG/O heavily/RB/O on/IN/O what/WP/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O late/JJ/O mayor/NN/O ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Daley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O called/VBD/O ``/``/O insinuendo/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Discrepancies/NNS/O go/VBP/O unexplained/JJ/O in/IN/O ``/``/O Confidential/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O one/CD/O ex-player/NN/O claims/VBZ/O he/PRP/O received/VBD/O $/$/O 4,000/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 5,000/CD/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O season/NN/O football/NN/O tickets/NNS/O while/IN/O others/NNS/O said/VBD/O theirs/PRP/O brought/VBD/O only/RB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O hundred/CD/O dollars/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Keteyian/NNP/B-PERSON ca/MD/O n't/RB/O nail/VB/O down/RP/O something/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O who/WP/O really/RB/O owned/VBD/O a/DT/O car/NN/O driven/VBN/O by/IN/O Husker/NNP/O tailback/NN/O Doug/NNP/B-PERSON Dubose/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O he/PRP/O simply/RB/O reprints/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O notes/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O serious/JJ/O charge/NN/O --/:/O that/IN/O star/NN/O flanker/NN/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON Fryar/NNP/I-PERSON ``/``/O threw/VBD/O ''/''/O the/DT/O 1984/CD/O Orange/NNP/O Bowl/NNP/O game/NN/O by/IN/O intentionally/RB/O dropping/VBG/O a/DT/O pass/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O zone/NN/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O included/VBN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O the/DT/O Nebraska/NNP/B-ORG assistant/NN/O coach/NN/O quoted/VBN/O denied/VBD/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O book/NN/O produces/VBZ/O more/JJR/O smoke/NN/O than/IN/O a/DT/O smoldering/VBG/O sofa/NN/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O flames/NNS/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O concerning/VBG/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O steroids/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O mystery/NN/O how/WRB/O this/DT/O could/MD/O have/VB/O escaped/VBN/O the/DT/O notice/NN/O of/IN/O Nebraska/NNP/B-ORG coaches/NNS/O ././O
Probably/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Never/NNP/O Too/NNP/O Young/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O ,/,/O focusing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O 1986/CD/O death/NN/O from/IN/O cocaine/NN/O ingestion/NN/O of/IN/O Bias/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Maryland/NNP/I-ORG basketball/NN/O star/NN/O ticketed/VBN/O for/IN/O sure/JJ/O pro/JJ/O stardom/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O university/NN/O was/VBD/O no/RB/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O blame/VB/O for/IN/O that/DT/O than/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O similar/JJ/O fate/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O student/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O must/MD/O bear/VB/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O conduct/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O aftermath/NN/O ././O
Bias/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O coach/NN/O ,/,/O Lefty/NNP/B-PERSON Driesell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ordered/VBD/O the/DT/O room/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Bias/NNP/B-PERSON died/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O cleaned/VBN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O police/NN/O could/MD/O arrive/VB/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O order/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O carried/VBN/O out/IN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O school/NN/O 's/POS/O athletics/NNS/O director/NN/O issued/VBD/O false/JJ/O information/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O academic/JJ/O standing/NN/O of/IN/O Bias/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O players/NNS/O ././O
Those/DT/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O the/DT/O responses/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O with/IN/O something/NN/O to/TO/O hide/VB/O ././O
One/NN/O wonders/VBZ/O how/WRB/O other/JJ/O college/NN/O athletic/JJ/O officials/NNS/O would/MD/O behave/VB/O under/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O circumstances/NNS/O ././O
Tomorrow/NN/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O On/NNP/O Sports/NNPS/O ''/''/O column/NN/O will/MD/O look/VB/O at/IN/O another/DT/O aspect/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O college/NN/O sports/NNS/O mess/NN/O ././O
