Robert/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Hodson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 65/CD/O ,/,/O retired/VBD/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O but/CC/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O ././O
Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Crane/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 44/CD/O ,/,/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O financial/JJ/O and/CC/O planning/VBG/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O brokerage/NN/O group/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Taylor/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O appointments/NNS/O are/VBP/O effective/JJ/O Nov./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
Corroon/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O announce/VB/O a/DT/O successor/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Crane/NNP/B-PERSON at/IN/O a/DT/O later/JJ/O date/NN/O ././O
