In/IN/O a/DT/O rare/JJ/O package/NN/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O ,/,/O K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Troy/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O 17/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O strip/NN/O shopping/NN/O centers/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O limited/VBN/O partnership/NN/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE developer/NN/O Philip/NNP/B-PERSON Pilevsky/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O sources/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O estimate/VBP/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O at/IN/O close/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Pilevsky/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ././O
K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG previously/RB/O had/VBD/O announced/VBN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O report/VB/O its/PRP$/O third/JJ/O consecutive/JJ/O decline/NN/O in/IN/O quarterly/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O period/NN/O ended/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O day/NN/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O deal/NN/O was/VBD/O completed/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O unclear/JJ/O what/WDT/O effect/NN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shopping/NN/O centers/NNS/O will/MD/O have/VB/O on/IN/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG developed/VBD/O the/DT/O centers/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O range/VBP/O in/IN/O size/NN/O from/IN/O about/IN/O 150,000/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O to/TO/O just/RB/O over/IN/O 250,000/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O ././O
Most/JJS/O are/VBP/O anchored/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG store/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O retailer/NN/O reportedly/RB/O will/MD/O lease/VB/O its/PRP$/O stores/NNS/O back/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O developer/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O the/DT/O small/JJ/O centers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O centers/NNS/O comprise/VBP/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 1.6/CD/O million/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O retail/JJ/O space/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O spread/VBN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O and/CC/O include/VBP/O locations/NNS/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O active/JJ/O in/IN/O office/NN/O and/CC/O residential/JJ/O development/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O nationally/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Pilevsky/NNP/B-PERSON controls/VBZ/O through/IN/O limited/VBN/O partnerships/NNS/O about/IN/O 85/CD/O shopping/NN/O centers/NNS/O with/IN/O about/IN/O 17/CD/O million/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O ././O
K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG runs/VBZ/O 2,200/CD/O K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG stores/NNS/O ,/,/O primarily/RB/O in/IN/O leased/VBN/O facilities/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O typically/RB/O sells/VBZ/O the/DT/O centers/NNS/O it/PRP/O develops/VBZ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O has/VBZ/O usually/RB/O sold/VBN/O only/RB/O one/CD/O or/CC/O several/JJ/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
