Office/NN/O Market/NN/O Weakens/VBZ/O In/IN/O Overbuilt/JJ/O Northeast/NN/B-LOC
THE/DT/O NORTHEAST/NN/B-LOC office/NN/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O feeling/VBG/O serious/JJ/O aftereffects/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O giddy/JJ/O overbuilding/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1980s/CD/O ././O
Foreclosures/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O financial/JJ/O distress/NN/O ,/,/O most/RBS/O often/RB/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O market/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Southwest/NN/B-LOC ,/,/O are/VBP/O surfacing/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O suburban/JJ/O office/NN/O market/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O once/RB/O thriving/JJ/O Northeast/NN/B-LOC ././O
Rising/VBG/O office/NN/O vacancy/NN/O rates/NNS/O in/IN/O Fairfield/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O have/VBP/O builders/NNS/O and/CC/O bankers/NNS/O scrambling/VBG/O to/TO/O restructure/VB/O loans/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O in/IN/O suburban/JJ/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O developers/NNS/O are/VBP/O bracing/VBG/O for/IN/O cutbacks/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O user/NN/O of/IN/O office/NN/O space/NN/O ././O
Owners/NNS/O are/VBP/O voluntarily/RB/O --/:/O and/CC/O quietly/RB/O --/:/O turning/VBG/O over/RP/O properties/NNS/O to/TO/O lenders/NNS/O through/IN/O ``/``/O deeds/NNS/O in/IN/O lieu/NN/O of/IN/O foreclosure/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Often/RB/O ,/,/O developers/NNS/O stay/VBP/O on/RP/O as/IN/O property/NN/O manager/NN/O ././O
Real/JJ/O estate/NN/O analyst/NN/O Lloyd/NNP/B-PERSON Lynford/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Northeast/NN/B-LOC 's/POS/O distress/NN/O is/VBZ/O masked/VBN/O by/IN/O relatively/RB/O low/JJ/O vacancy/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O overbuilt/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O tenants/NNS/O have/VBP/O many/JJ/O choices/NNS/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O negotiating/VBG/O low/JJ/O rents/NNS/O that/WDT/O squeeze/VBP/O building/NN/O owners/NNS/O ././O
Beverly/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNP/I-GPE Comes/VBZ/O To/TO/O Suburban/JJ/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE
WHY/WRB/O SHOULD/MD/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O cross/VB/O the/DT/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC to/TO/O buy/VB/O American/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O simply/RB/O recreate/VB/O it/PRP/O at/IN/O home/NN/O ?/./O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O company/NN/O hired/VBD/O Richardson/NNP/B-PERSON Nagy/NNP/I-PERSON Martin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Newport/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O architectural/JJ/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O design/VB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O press/NN/O has/VBZ/O dubbed/VBN/O ``/``/O the/DT/B-GPE Beverly/NNP/I-GPE Hills/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O usual/JJ/O housing/NN/O site/NN/O size/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O spacious/JJ/O living/NN/O rooms/NNS/O and/CC/O baths/NNS/O ,/,/O plus/CC/O a/DT/O master/NN/O grandparents/NNS/O suite/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O foyer/NN/O for/IN/O removing/VBG/O shoes/NNS/O to/TO/O suit/VB/O Japanese/JJ/O life/NN/O styles/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O were/VBD/O disappointed/VBN/O we/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O use/VB/O wood/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O architect/NN/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Richardson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O only/RB/O want/VBP/O stronger/JJR/O materials/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
At/IN/O $/$/O 1,000/CD/O per/IN/O square/JJ/O foot/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O want/VBP/O the/DT/O feeling/NN/O of/IN/O indestructibility/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O explains/VBZ/O ,/,/O not/RB/O to/TO/O mention/VB/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O possible/JJ/O earthquake/NN/O damage/NN/O ././O
``/``/O One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O difficulties/NNS/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O have/VBP/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O each/DT/O product/NN/O is/VBZ/O like/IN/O starting/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O starting/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fashion/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O L./NNP/B-PERSON Robert/NNP/I-PERSON Lieb/NNP/I-PERSON president/NN/O of/IN/O Mountain/NNP/B-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Paterson/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.J/NNP/B-GPE ././O
So/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O using/VBG/O ``/``/O river/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O project/NN/O names/NNS/O ././O
Caspi/NNP/B-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Armonk/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O developed/VBN/O two/CD/O apartment/NN/O buildings/NNS/O called/VBN/O Classic/JJ/B-FAC and/CC/O plans/VBZ/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O ././O
Developer/NNP/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON Caspi/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O brand/NN/O name/NN/O indicates/VBZ/O consistent/JJ/O quality/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O regardless/RB/O of/IN/O location/NN/O ,/,/O design/NN/O or/CC/O amenities/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O brand/NN/O names/NNS/O is/VBZ/O developer/NN/O Ara/NNP/B-PERSON Hovnanian/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Because/IN/O of/IN/O standardized/JJ/O designs/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hovnanian/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O a/DT/O buyer/NN/O can/MD/O visualize/VB/O Society/NNP/B-FAC Hill/NNP/I-FAC regardless/RB/O of/IN/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ././O ''/''/O
Quake/NN/O Not/RB/O Likely/RB/O to/TO/O Jolt/VB/O The/DT/O Commercial/NN/O Market/NN/O
THE/DT/O EARTHQUAKE/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O sent/VBN/O few/JJ/O tremors/NNS/O through/IN/O the/DT/O hearts/NNS/O of/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O investors/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O I/PRP/O were/VBD/O buying/VBG/O a/DT/O building/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE now/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O thing/NN/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O do/VB/O is/VBZ/O insist/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O structural/JJ/O inspection/NN/O ,/,/O then/RB/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O delay/VB/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O ,/,/O stall/VB/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O local/JJ/O builders/NNS/O are/VBP/O eager/JJ/O to/TO/O tell/VB/O the/DT/O world/NN/O that/IN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O look/VB/O like/IN/O the/DT/O TV/NN/O images/NNS/O of/IN/O destruction/NN/O ././O
Planners/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Urban/NNP/B-ORG Land/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG real/JJ/O estate/NN/O conference/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O hastily/RB/O added/VBD/O a/DT/O panel/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O 's/POS/O effects/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O message/NN/O is/VBZ/O we/PRP/O build/VBP/O 'em/PRP/O right/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Bedford/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE developer/NN/O and/CC/O officer/NN/O at/IN/O Urban/NNP/B-ORG Land/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/POS/O seven/CD/O million/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O space/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O doing/VBG/O great/JJ/O ././O
