The/DT/O filing/NN/O ,/,/O made/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Bankruptcy/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG here/RB/O ,/,/O follows/VBZ/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O by/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG owner/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O to/TO/O management/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O undisclosed/JJ/O price/NN/O ././O
GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O subsidiary/JJ/O of/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O providing/VBG/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O with/IN/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O financing/NN/O ././O
L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG planned/VBN/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Tina/NNP/B-PERSON Brozman/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Bankruptcy/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Rumors/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O effect/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Merksamer/NNP/B-ORG chain/NN/O would/MD/O file/VB/O for/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O arose/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O jewelry/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O executive/NN/O said/VBD/O an/DT/O accord/NN/O signed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O unsecured/JJ/O creditors/NNS/O of/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O frozen/VBN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG assets/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Merksamer/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Sanford/NNP/B-PERSON Sigoloff/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O were/VBD/O unavailable/JJ/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O jewelry/NN/O chain/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Sacramento/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 62/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O operating/VBG/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBD/O June/NNP/O 30/CD/O ././O
