-LRB-/-LRB-/O During/IN/O its/PRP$/O centennial/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O The/NNP/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O report/VB/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O century/NN/O that/WDT/O stand/VBP/O as/IN/O milestones/NNS/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O business/NN/O history/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
TAX/NN/O SHELTERS/NNS/O CALLED/VBN/O Individual/NNP/O Retirement/NNP/O Accounts/NNPS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O ``/``/O IRAs/NNPS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O were/VBD/O created/VBN/O without/IN/O fanfare/NN/O on/IN/O Sept./NNP/O 2/CD/O ,/,/O 1974/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O grew/VBD/O beyond/IN/O expectations/NNS/O as/IN/O an/DT/O inducement/NN/O to/TO/O personal/JJ/O saving/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O Labor/NNP/O Day/NNP/O ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O first/JJ/O major/JJ/O act/NN/O after/IN/O succeeding/VBG/O the/DT/O resigned/JJ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Nixon/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O Gerald/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Ford/NNP/I-PERSON signed/VBD/O the/DT/O Employee/NNP/O Retirement/NNP/O Income/NNP/O Security/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
Pension/NN/O reform/NN/O was/VBD/O its/PRP$/O main/JJ/O thrust/NN/O ././O
Labor/NNP/O and/CC/O business/NN/O leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Rose/NNP/B-LOC Garden/NNP/I-LOC rites/NNS/O ,/,/O hailed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O provisions/NNS/O for/IN/O insuring/VBG/O corporate/JJ/O pension/NN/O benefits/NNS/O ././O
IRAs/NNPS/O were/VBD/O like/JJ/O stepchildren/NN/O there/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O IRA/NNP/O 's/POS/O conception/NN/O is/VBZ/O murky/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O 1972/CD/O ,/,/O then/RB/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Shultz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O support/NN/O of/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Carl/NNP/B-PERSON Curtis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O sought/VBD/O some/DT/O form/NN/O of/IN/O pensions/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O uncovered/JJ/O ././O
This/DT/O team/NN/O initially/RB/O called/VBD/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O model/NN/O Personal/NNP/O Retirement/NNP/O Account/NNP/O ,/,/O or/CC/O ``/``/O PRA/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O sing/VB/O ././O
So/IN/O they/PRP/O opted/VBD/O for/IN/O IRA/NNP/O ,/,/O naming/VBG/O it/PRP/O after/IN/O Ira/NNP/B-PERSON Cohen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O brilliant/JJ/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG actuary/NN/O who/WP/O helped/VBD/O them/PRP/O ././O
Ira/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O himself/PRP/O ,/,/O confirms/VBZ/O this/DT/O account/NN/O ././O
IRA/NNP/O rules/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O changed/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O caused/VBD/O an/DT/O explosion/NN/O of/IN/O IRA/NNP/O promotions/NNS/O by/IN/O brokers/NNS/O ,/,/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O mutual/JJ/O funds/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
IRA/NNP/O account/NN/O assets/NNS/O have/VBP/O grown/VBN/O to/TO/O about/IN/O $/$/O 400/CD/O billion/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 393/CD/O billion/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O and/CC/O just/RB/O $/$/O 26/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O 1981/CD/O ././O
