Medical/JJ/O researchers/NNS/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O transplantation/NN/O of/IN/O small/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O fetal/JJ/O tissue/NN/O into/IN/O humans/NNS/O could/MD/O help/VB/O treat/VB/O juvenile/JJ/O diabetes/NN/O and/CC/O such/JJ/O degenerative/JJ/O diseases/NNS/O as/IN/O Alzheimer/NNP/O 's/POS/O ,/,/O Parkinson/NNP/O 's/POS/O and/CC/O Huntington/NNP/O 's/POS/O ././O
Department/NN/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O HHS/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Louis/NNP/B-PERSON Sullivan/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O support/VB/O Dr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ruling/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O issued/VBN/O soon/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O form/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O acting/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Institutes/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Both/DT/O Dr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Dr./NNP/O Sullivan/NNP/B-PERSON oppose/VBP/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O for/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O does/VBZ/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O except/IN/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O where/WRB/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O life/NN/O is/VBZ/O threatened/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O controversy/NN/O began/VBD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O when/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Institutes/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O implications/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O research/NN/O ,/,/O asked/VBD/O for/IN/O an/DT/O HHS/NNP/B-ORG review/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O implant/VB/O fetal/JJ/O tissue/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O brain/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O patient/NN/O suffering/NN/O from/IN/O Parkinson/NNPS/O 's/POS/O disease/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O department/NN/O placed/VBD/O a/DT/O moratorium/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O research/NN/O ,/,/O pending/VBG/O a/DT/O review/NN/O of/IN/O scientific/JJ/O ,/,/O legal/JJ/O and/CC/O ethical/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O dispute/NN/O has/VBZ/O hampered/VBN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O recruit/VB/O prominent/JJ/O doctors/NNS/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O prestigious/JJ/O posts/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O helm/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Centers/NNPS/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Disease/NNP/I-ORG Control/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Antonio/NNP/B-PERSON Novello/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whom/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON nominated/VBD/O to/TO/O serve/VB/O as/IN/O surgeon/NN/O general/NN/O ,/,/O reportedly/RB/O has/VBZ/O assured/VBN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O opposes/VBZ/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Novello/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O deputy/NN/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Child/NNP/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Human/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Some/DT/O researchers/NNS/O have/VBP/O charged/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O is/VBZ/O imposing/VBG/O new/JJ/O ideological/JJ/O tests/NNS/O for/IN/O top/JJ/O scientific/JJ/O posts/NNS/O ././O
Earlier/JJR/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Dr./NNP/O Sullivan/NNP/B-PERSON tried/VBD/O to/TO/O defuse/VB/O these/DT/O charges/NNS/O by/IN/O stressing/VBG/O that/IN/O candidates/NNS/O to/TO/O head/VB/O the/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O CDC/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O judged/VBN/O by/IN/O ``/``/O standards/NNS/O of/IN/O scientific/JJ/O and/CC/O administrative/JJ/O excellence/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O not/RB/O politics/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O scientific/JJ/O progress/NN/O moves/VBZ/O into/IN/O uncharted/JJ/O ground/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O role/NN/O for/IN/O society/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O judgments/NNS/O about/IN/O its/PRP$/O applications/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Myron/NNP/B-PERSON Genel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O associate/NN/O dean/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Yale/NNP/I-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O disturbing/JJ/O thing/NN/O about/IN/O this/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O polarized/VBN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O that/IN/O no/DT/O mechanism/NN/O exists/VBZ/O ''/''/O for/IN/O finding/VBG/O a/DT/O middle/JJ/O ground/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Dr./NNP/O Genel/NNP/B-PERSON warns/VBZ/O that/IN/O Dr./NNP/O Mason/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ruling/NN/O may/MD/O discourage/VB/O private/JJ/O funding/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O unavailability/NN/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O funds/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O climate/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O was/VBD/O made/VBN/O ,/,/O certainly/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O provide/VB/O any/DT/O incentive/NN/O for/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O visible/JJ/O foundations/NNS/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O support/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O flap/NN/O over/IN/O transplants/NNS/O ,/,/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O of/IN/O research/NN/O involving/VBG/O fetal/JJ/O tissues/NNS/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O fronts/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Such/JJ/O research/NN/O may/MD/O ultimately/RB/O result/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O regenerate/VB/O damaged/JJ/O tissues/NNS/O or/CC/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O off/RP/O genes/NNS/O that/WDT/O cause/VBP/O cancer/NN/O ''/''/O or/CC/O to/TO/O regulate/VB/O genes/NNS/O that/WDT/O cause/VBP/O Down/NNP/O 's/POS/O syndrome/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O cause/NN/O of/IN/O mental/JJ/O retardation/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O an/DT/O NIH/NNP/B-ORG summary/NN/O ././O
