Clark/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Vitulli/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sales/NNS/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O arm/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O Mazda/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O position/NN/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O oversee/VB/O Mazda/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sales/NNS/O ,/,/O service/NN/O ,/,/O parts/NNS/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Previously/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Vitulli/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 43/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O general/JJ/O marketing/NN/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG division/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O executive/NN/O with/IN/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
