Hudson/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Stearn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O resigned/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stearn/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 46/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O company/NN/O spokesman/NN/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O elaborate/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O departure/NN/O ././O
Hudson/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O provides/VBZ/O maintenance/NN/O ,/,/O fueling/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O airlines/NNS/O and/CC/O airports/NNS/O ,/,/O reported/VBD/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O most/RBS/O recent/JJ/O fiscal/NN/O year/NN/O and/CC/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O omitted/VBD/O the/DT/O semiannual/JJ/O dividend/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stearn/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O president/NN/O since/IN/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O act/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O to/TO/O Hudson/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG ././O
His/PRP$/O duties/NNS/O as/IN/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O assumed/VBN/O by/IN/O Chairman/NNP/O Jay/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Langner/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
