Judging/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Americana/NNS/O in/IN/O Haruki/NNP/B-PERSON Murakami/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O A/DT/O Wild/NNP/O Sheep/NNP/O Chase/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Kodansha/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 320/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 18.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O baby/NN/O boomers/NNS/O on/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC have/VBP/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O in/IN/O common/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O novel/NN/O 's/POS/O texture/NN/O is/VBZ/O almost/RB/O entirely/RB/O Western/JJ/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O American/JJ/O ././O
Characters/NNS/O drink/VBP/O Salty/NNP/O Dogs/NNP/O ,/,/O whistle/VBP/O ``/``/O Johnny/NNP/O B./NNP/O Goode/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O watch/VBP/O Bugs/NNP/O Bunny/NNP/O reruns/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O read/VBP/O Mickey/NNP/B-PERSON Spillane/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O talk/VBP/O about/IN/O Groucho/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Harpo/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
They/PRP/O worry/VBP/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O careers/NNS/O ,/,/O drink/VBP/O too/RB/O much/RB/O and/CC/O suffer/VBP/O through/IN/O broken/VBN/O marriages/NNS/O and/CC/O desultory/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ?/./O
If/IN/O ``/``/O A/DT/O Wild/NNP/O Sheep/NNP/O Chase/NNP/O ''/''/O carries/VBZ/O an/DT/O implicit/JJ/O message/NN/O for/IN/O international/JJ/O relations/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O are/VBP/O more/RBR/O like/IN/O us/PRP/O than/IN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O think/VBP/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O to/TO/O say/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O nutty/JJ/O plot/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O A/DT/O Wild/NNP/O Sheep/NNP/O Chase/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O rooted/VBN/O in/IN/O reality/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O imaginative/JJ/O and/CC/O often/RB/O funny/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O in/IN/O tow/NN/O his/PRP$/O prescient/JJ/O girlfriend/NN/O ,/,/O whose/WP$/O sassy/JJ/O retorts/NNS/O mark/VBP/O her/PRP/O as/IN/O anything/NN/O but/CC/O a/DT/O docile/JJ/O butterfly/NN/O ././O
Along/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O meets/VBZ/O a/DT/O solicitous/JJ/O Christian/JJ/O chauffeur/NN/O who/WP/O offers/VBZ/O the/DT/O hero/NN/O God/NNP/O 's/POS/O phone/NN/O number/NN/O ;/:/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-PERSON Sheep/NNP/I-PERSON Man/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O sweet/JJ/O ,/,/O roughhewn/JJ/O figure/NN/O who/WP/O wears/VBZ/O --/:/O what/WP/O else/RB/O --/:/O a/JJ/O sheepskin/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O more/RBR/O recent/JJ/O novel/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Norwegian/NNP/O Wood/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O every/DT/O Japanese/NN/O under/IN/O 40/CD/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fluent/JJ/O in/IN/O Beatles/NNP/O lyrics/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O four/CD/O million/CD/O copies/NNS/O since/IN/O Kodansha/NNP/B-ORG published/VBD/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O books/NNS/O are/VBP/O written/VBN/O in/IN/O idiomatic/JJ/O ,/,/O contemporary/JJ/O language/NN/O and/CC/O usually/RB/O carry/VBP/O hefty/JJ/O dashes/NNS/O of/IN/O Americana/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Whiting/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O You/PRP/O Gotta/NNP/O Have/NNP/O Wa/,/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Macmillan/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 339/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 17.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Beatles/NNP/O give/VBP/O way/NN/O to/TO/O baseball/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Nipponese/JJ/O version/NN/O we/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O hard/RB/O put/VBN/O to/TO/O call/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O game/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Whiting/NNP/B-PERSON describes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O Nipponese/JJ/O baseball/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O mirror/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O fabled/JJ/O virtues/NNS/O of/IN/O hard/JJ/O work/NN/O and/CC/O harmony/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O Wa/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O Japanese/NNP/O for/IN/O ``/``/O team/NN/O spirit/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O ballplayers/NNS/O have/VBP/O miles/NNS/O and/CC/O miles/NNS/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
A/DT/O player/NN/O 's/POS/O commitment/NN/O to/TO/O practice/NN/O and/CC/O team/NN/O image/NN/O is/VBZ/O as/RB/O important/JJ/O as/IN/O his/PRP$/O batting/NN/O average/NN/O ././O
Polls/NNS/O once/RB/O named/VBD/O Tokyo/NNP/B-ORG Giants/NNP/I-ORG star/NN/O Tatsunori/NNP/B-PERSON Hara/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O ``/``/O humble/JJ/O ,/,/O uncomplaining/JJ/O ,/,/O obedient/JJ/O soul/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O as/IN/O the/DT/O male/JJ/O symbol/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/DT/O besuboru/FW/O is/VBZ/O played/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O ball/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O bat/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O unrecognizable/JJ/O :/:/O Fans/NNS/O politely/RB/O return/VBP/O foul/JJ/O balls/NNS/O to/TO/O stadium/NN/O ushers/NNS/O ;/:/O the/DT/O strike/NN/O zone/NN/O expands/VBZ/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hitter/NN/O ;/:/O ties/NNS/O are/VBP/O permitted/VBN/O --/:/O even/JJ/O welcomed/VBN/O --/:/O since/IN/O they/PRP/O honorably/RB/O sidestep/VBP/O the/DT/O shame/NN/O of/IN/O defeat/NN/O ;/:/O players/NNS/O must/MD/O abide/VB/O by/IN/O strict/JJ/O rules/NNS/O of/IN/O conduct/NN/O even/RB/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O personal/JJ/O lives/NNS/O --/:/O players/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Tokyo/NNP/I-ORG Giants/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O must/MD/O always/RB/O wear/VB/O ties/NNS/O when/WRB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O road/NN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O Gotta/NNP/O Have/NNP/O Wa/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O often/RB/O amusing/JJ/O chronicle/NN/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O American/JJ/O ballplayers/NNS/O ,/,/O rationed/VBN/O to/TO/O two/CD/O per/IN/O team/NN/O ,/,/O fare/VBP/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O enormous/JJ/O sums/NNS/O of/IN/O money/NN/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O paid/VBN/O to/TO/O stand/VB/O up/RP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O plate/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O number/NN/O decide/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O worth/JJ/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O run/VBP/O for/IN/O home/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Funny/NNP/O Business/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Soho/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 228/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 17.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O by/IN/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Katzenstein/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O anything/NN/O but/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O petulant/JJ/O complaint/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O impudent/JJ/O American/NN/O whom/WP/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG hosted/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O while/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O Luce/NNP/O Fellowship/NNP/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O to/IN/O the/DT/O regret/NN/O of/IN/O both/DT/O parties/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O sometimes/RB/O amusing/JJ/O ,/,/O more/RBR/O often/RB/O supercilious/JJ/O ,/,/O even/RB/O vicious/JJ/O passages/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Katzenstein/NNP/B-PERSON describes/VBZ/O how/WRB/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG invades/VBZ/O even/RB/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O mundane/JJ/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O workers/NNS/O '/POS/O lives/NNS/O --/:/O at/IN/O the/DT/O regimented/JJ/O office/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O employees/NNS/O are/VBP/O assigned/VBN/O lunch/NN/O partners/NNS/O --/:/O and/JJ/O at/IN/O ``/``/O home/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O austere/JJ/O company/NN/O dormitory/NN/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O prying/JJ/O caretaker/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O observations/NNS/O about/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O management/NN/O style/NN/O are/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O ././O
All/DT/O of/IN/O this/DT/O must/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O enormously/RB/O frustrating/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Katzenstein/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O went/VBD/O to/TO/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O degrees/NNS/O in/IN/O business/NN/O and/CC/O computer/NN/O science/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O raring/JJ/O to/TO/O invent/VB/O another/DT/O Walkman/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG ultimately/RB/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O lesson/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O management/NN/O books/NNS/O and/CC/O fired/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Katzenstein/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O after/IN/O he/PRP/O committed/VBD/O the/DT/O social/JJ/O crime/NN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O an/DT/O appointment/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O the/DT/O venerable/JJ/O Akio/NNP/B-PERSON Morita/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O founder/NN/O of/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O shame/NN/O their/PRP$/O meeting/NN/O never/RB/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Katzenstein/NNP/B-PERSON certainly/RB/O would/MD/O have/VB/O learned/VBD/O something/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O even/RB/O possible/JJ/O Mr./NNP/O Morita/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O have/VB/O too/RB/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Kirkpatrick/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Journal/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O deputy/NN/O editorial/NN/O features/NNS/O editor/NN/O ,/,/O worked/VBD/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
More/JJR/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O corners/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O globe/NN/O are/VBP/O becoming/VBG/O free/JJ/O of/IN/O tobacco/NN/O smoke/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O law/NN/O requires/VBZ/O smokers/NNS/O to/TO/O put/VB/O out/RP/O their/PRP$/O cigarettes/NNS/O before/IN/O entering/VBG/O restaurants/NNS/O ,/,/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O and/CC/O sports/NNS/O centers/NNS/O or/CC/O face/VB/O a/DT/O $/$/O 250/CD/O fine/NN/O ././O
Discos/NNS/O and/CC/O private/JJ/O clubs/NNS/O are/VBP/O exempt/JJ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O ban/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O smoking/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O permitted/VBN/O in/IN/O bars/NNS/O except/IN/O during/IN/O meal/NN/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O different/JJ/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Seoul/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O officials/NNS/O began/VBD/O visiting/VBG/O about/RB/O 26,000/CD/O cigarette/NN/O stalls/NNS/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O illegal/JJ/O posters/NNS/O and/CC/O signboards/NNS/O advertising/VBG/O imported/VBN/O cigarettes/NNS/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O opened/VBN/O its/PRP$/O market/NN/O to/TO/O foreign/JJ/O cigarettes/NNS/O but/CC/O restricts/VBZ/O advertising/NN/O to/TO/O designated/VBN/O places/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O marketing/NN/O study/NN/O indicates/VBZ/O that/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE consumers/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O materialistic/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 14/CD/O major/JJ/O markets/NNS/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O survey/NN/O was/VBD/O carried/VBN/O out/RP/O ././O
The/DT/O study/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Backer/NNP/B-ORG Spielvogel/NNP/I-ORG Bates/NNP/I-ORG ad/NN/O agency/NN/O also/RB/O found/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O colony/NN/O 's/POS/O consumers/NNS/O feel/VBP/O more/RBR/O pressured/JJ/O than/IN/O those/DT/O in/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O surveyed/VBN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O include/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
More/JJR/O than/IN/O three/CD/O in/IN/O five/CD/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O under/IN/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O deal/NN/O of/IN/O stress/NN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O one/CD/O in/IN/O two/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE consumers/NNS/O and/CC/O one/CD/O in/IN/O four/CD/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Thai/NNP/O cabinet/NN/O endorsed/VBD/O Finance/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Pramual/NNP/B-PERSON Sabhavasu/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O $/$/O 19/CD/O million/CD/O conference/NN/O center/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O meeting/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O International/NNP/B-ORG Monetary/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG two/CD/O years/NNS/O from/IN/O now/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O meeting/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O draw/VB/O 20,000/CD/O to/TO/O Bangkok/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O held/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Plaza/NNP/I-ORG Hotel/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O government/NN/O balked/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O hotel/NN/O 's/POS/O conditions/NNS/O for/IN/O undertaking/VBG/O necessary/JJ/O expansion/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O major/JJ/O concern/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O plan/NN/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O center/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O short/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O
Yasser/NNP/B-PERSON Arafat/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O written/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Olympic/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG asking/VBG/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O back/VB/O a/DT/O Palestinian/JJ/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O join/VB/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Palestine/NNP/B-ORG Liberation/NNP/I-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG news/NN/O agency/NN/O WAFA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
An/DT/O official/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Palestinian/NNP/I-ORG Olympic/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O first/RB/O applied/VBD/O for/IN/O membership/NN/O in/IN/O 1979/CD/O and/CC/O renewed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O application/NN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O of/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O PLO/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O join/VB/O international/JJ/O organizations/NNS/O but/CC/O failed/VBD/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O membership/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Tourism/NNP/I-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O man/NN/O ,/,/O whom/WP/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O name/VB/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O found/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O disease/NN/O after/IN/O hospital/NN/O tests/NNS/O ././O
Once/RB/O the/DT/O disease/NN/O was/VBD/O confirmed/VBN/O ,/,/O all/DT/O the/DT/O man/NN/O 's/POS/O associates/NNS/O and/CC/O family/NN/O were/VBD/O tested/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O none/NN/O have/VBP/O so/RB/O far/RB/O been/VBN/O found/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O AIDS/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O newspaper/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O man/NN/O had/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O time/NN/O had/VBN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O chaotic/JJ/O sex/NN/O life/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O including/VBG/O relations/NNS/O with/IN/O foreign/JJ/O men/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O newspaper/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Polish/JJ/O government/NN/O increased/VBD/O home/NN/O electricity/NN/O charges/NNS/O by/IN/O 150/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O doubled/VBD/O gas/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O official/JJ/O news/NN/O agency/NN/O PAP/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O increases/NNS/O were/VBD/O intended/VBN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O unrealistically/RB/O low/JJ/O energy/NN/O charges/NNS/O into/IN/O line/NN/O with/IN/O production/NN/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O compensate/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O rise/NN/O in/IN/O coal/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O happier/JJR/O news/NN/O ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O establishing/VBG/O diplomatic/JJ/O ties/NNS/O with/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O announced/VBD/O $/$/O 450/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O financially/RB/O strapped/VBN/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Nagymaros/NNP/B-GPE dam/NN/O was/VBD/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O twinned/VBN/O with/IN/O another/DT/O dam/NN/O ,/,/O now/RB/O nearly/RB/O complete/JJ/O ,/,/O 100/CD/O miles/NNS/O upstream/RB/O in/IN/O Czechoslovakia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O ending/VBG/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O ,/,/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG authorized/VBD/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Miklos/NNP/B-PERSON Nemeth/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O modify/VB/O a/DT/O 1977/CD/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O Czechoslovakia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O still/RB/O wants/VBZ/O the/DT/O dam/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nemeth/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O parliament/NN/B-ORG that/IN/O Czechoslovakia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O suffer/VB/O environmental/JJ/O damage/NN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O twin/NN/O dams/NNS/O were/VBD/O built/VBN/O as/IN/O planned/VBN/O ././O
Czechoslovakia/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O seek/VB/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O from/IN/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE if/IN/O the/DT/O twindam/NN/O contract/NN/O were/VBD/O broken/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O Czech/JJ/O dam/NN/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O operated/VBN/O solely/RB/O at/IN/O peak/NN/O periods/NNS/O without/IN/O the/DT/O Nagymaros/NNP/B-GPE project/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O painting/NN/O by/IN/O August/NNP/B-PERSON Strindberg/NNP/I-PERSON set/VBD/O a/DT/O Scandinavian/JJ/O price/NN/O record/NN/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O sold/VBD/O at/IN/O auction/NN/O in/IN/O Stockholm/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O $/$/O 2.44/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
``/``/O Lighthouse/NNP/O II/NNP/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O painted/VBN/O in/IN/O oils/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O playwright/NN/O in/IN/O 1901/CD/O .../:/O
After/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O decline/NN/O ,/,/O weddings/NNS/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE showed/VBD/O a/DT/O 2.2/CD/O %/NN/O upturn/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O 6,000/CD/O more/JJR/O couples/NNS/O exchanging/VBG/O rings/NNS/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O than/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O national/JJ/O statistics/NNS/O office/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O weddings/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O --/:/O 271,124/CD/O --/:/O was/VBD/O still/RB/O well/RB/O below/IN/O the/DT/O 400,000/CD/O registered/VBN/O in/IN/O 1972/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O of/IN/O increasing/VBG/O marriages/NNS/O ././O
