The/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Mercantile/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O institute/VB/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O ``/``/O circuit/NN/O breaker/NN/O ''/''/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O stemming/VBG/O market/NN/O slides/NNS/O ././O
Separately/NNP/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Phelan/NNP/I-PERSON told/VBD/O a/DT/O closed/VBN/O House/NNP/B-ORG subcommittee/NN/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O support/VB/O Securities/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG halts/NNS/O of/IN/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O during/IN/O market/NN/O emergencies/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O support/VB/O reinstating/VBG/O a/DT/O ``/``/O collar/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O arguing/VBG/O that/IN/O firms/NNS/O could/MD/O get/VB/O around/IN/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O limit/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/O limit/NN/O in/IN/O effect/NN/O ,/,/O members/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O execute/VB/O trades/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O limit/NN/O price/NN/O or/CC/O at/IN/O higher/JJR/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O below/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
All/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O require/VBP/O regulatory/JJ/O approval/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O shortly/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O limit/NN/O lapses/VBZ/O under/IN/O current/JJ/O exchange/NN/O rules/NNS/O if/IN/O contracts/NNS/O trade/VBP/O above/IN/O the/DT/O limit/NN/O price/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O opening/VBG/O 10/CD/O minutes/NNS/O of/IN/O trading/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O House/NNP/B-ORG aides/NNS/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Phelan/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O congressmen/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O collar/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O banned/VBD/O program/NN/O trades/NNS/O through/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG computer/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/O Jones/NNP/O Industrial/NNP/O Average/NNP/O moved/VBD/O 50/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O work/VB/O well/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O firms/NNS/O could/MD/O get/VB/O around/IN/O the/DT/O collar/NN/O by/IN/O executing/VBG/O trades/NNS/O manually/RB/O ././O
SEC/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Breeden/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O circuit/NN/O breakers/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O preset/JJ/O trigger/NN/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O discretionary/JJ/O power/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O programs/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG aide/NN/O suggested/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Phelan/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O so/RB/O ``/``/O vague/JJ/O and/CC/O mushy/JJ/O ''/''/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O meeting/NN/O where/WRB/O people/NNS/O of/IN/O all/DT/O viewpoints/NNS/O could/MD/O ``/``/O come/VB/O out/RB/O feeling/VBG/O good/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
At/IN/O one/CD/O point/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Phelan/NNP/B-PERSON angered/VBD/O the/DT/O subcommittee/NN/O 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Edward/NNP/B-PERSON Markey/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O by/IN/O not/RB/O going/VBG/O much/RB/O beyond/IN/O what/WP/O already/RB/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O reported/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O morning/NN/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Markey/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O we/PRP/O could/MD/O have/VB/O done/VBN/O this/DT/O in/IN/O public/NN/O ''/''/O because/IN/O so/RB/O little/RB/O sensitive/JJ/O information/NN/O was/VBD/O disclosed/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O aide/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Phelan/NNP/B-PERSON then/RB/O responded/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O happy/JJ/O just/RB/O writing/VBG/O a/DT/O report/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O aide/NN/O added/VBD/O ././O
At/IN/O another/DT/O point/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O hearing/NN/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Markey/NNP/B-PERSON asked/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Phelan/NNP/B-PERSON what/WP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O discussed/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG exchange/NN/I-ORG board/NN/O meeting/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O response/NN/O annoyed/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Markey/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O House/NNP/B-ORG aides/NNS/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O congressman/NN/O snapped/VBD/O back/RP/O that/IN/O there/EX/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O enough/JJ/O studies/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O time/NN/O for/IN/O action/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O ././O
Fifteen/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 26/CD/O subcommittee/NN/O members/NNS/O attended/VBD/O the/DT/O hearing/NN/O ,/,/O most/RBS/O notably/RB/O Rep./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Dingell/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O House/NNP/B-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O let/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Markey/NNP/B-PERSON carry/VB/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dingell/NNP/B-PERSON expressed/VBD/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O about/IN/O jurisdictional/JJ/O problems/NNS/O in/IN/O regulating/VBG/O program/NN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O uses/VBZ/O futures/NNS/O to/TO/O offset/VB/O stock/NN/O trades/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O futures/NNS/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O regulated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Commodity/NNP/I-ORG Futures/NNP/I-ORG Trading/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O reports/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Agriculture/NNP/B-ORG committees/NNS/O in/IN/O both/DT/O houses/NNS/O ././O
