While/IN/O worry/NN/O grows/VBZ/O about/IN/O big/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O big/JJ/O trading/NN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O rapidly/RB/O increasing/VBG/O their/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O smaller/JJR/O business/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O controversial/JJ/O trend/NN/O improves/VBZ/O access/NN/O to/TO/O American/JJ/O markets/NNS/O and/CC/O technology/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O for/IN/O small/JJ/O American/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O provides/VBZ/O a/DT/O growing/VBG/O source/NN/O of/IN/O capital/NN/O and/CC/O even/RB/O marketing/NN/O help/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O eventually/RB/O secured/VBD/O Ministry/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG import/NN/O approval/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O Candela/NNP/B-ORG laser/NN/O products/NNS/O --/:/O one/CD/O that/WDT/O breaks/VBZ/O up/RP/O kidney/NN/O stones/NNS/O and/CC/O another/DT/O that/WDT/O treats/VBZ/O skin/NN/O lesions/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O last/JJ/O count/NN/O ,/,/O Candela/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O sold/VBN/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O medical/JJ/O devices/NNS/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O view/VBP/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O growth/NN/O area/NN/O so/IN/O they/PRP/O went/VBD/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O systematic/JJ/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Olsen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Candela/NNP/B-ORG vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O many/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O trading/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O favorite/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE small/JJ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O whose/WP$/O research/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O milked/VBN/O for/IN/O future/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O use/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O bankroll/VBP/O many/JJ/O small/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O with/IN/O promising/JJ/O products/NNS/O or/CC/O ideas/NNS/O ,/,/O frequently/RB/O putting/VBG/O their/PRP$/O money/NN/O behind/IN/O projects/NNS/O that/IN/O commercial/JJ/O banks/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O touch/VB/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O alone/RB/O ,/,/O Japanese/JJ/O corporations/NNS/O invested/VBD/O $/$/O 214/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O minority/NN/O positions/NNS/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O 61/CD/O %/NN/O rise/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O figure/NN/O for/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O reports/VBZ/O Venture/NNP/B-ORG Economics/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Needham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O concern/NN/O tracks/VBZ/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O new/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O investments/NNS/O involved/VBD/O outright/JJ/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O small/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE firms/NNS/O ././O
Heightened/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O American/JJ/O small/JJ/O business/NN/O parallels/VBZ/O an/DT/O acceleration/NN/O of/IN/O investments/NNS/O giving/VBG/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O control/NN/O of/IN/O large/JJ/O ,/,/O highly/RB/O visible/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE corporations/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Only/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O announced/VBN/O that/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O acquired/VBN/O a/DT/O 51/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE prestigious/JJ/O Rockefeller/NNP/B-FAC Center/NNP/I-FAC ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O small/JJ/O deals/NNS/O are/VBP/O far/RB/O less/RBR/O conspicuous/JJ/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O add/VBP/O to/TO/O Japanese/JJ/O penetration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O deals/NNS/O also/RB/O improve/VBP/O Japanese/JJ/O access/NN/O to/TO/O American/JJ/O technology/NN/O and/CC/O market/NN/O knowledge/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O feed/VBP/O American/JJ/O anxieties/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O area/NN/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O
Free/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Glass/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Warrenton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O fabricator/NN/O of/IN/O architectural/JJ/O glass/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O foundering/VBG/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O original/JJ/O management/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O deal/NN/O is/VBZ/O chiefly/RB/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O window/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE glass/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Ichiro/NNP/B-PERSON Wakui/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O executive/NN/O in/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O general/JJ/O merchandise/NN/O department/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O just/RB/O a/DT/O simple/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Wakui/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O see/VB/O the/DT/O glass/NN/O market/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O inside/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O the/DT/O outside/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mitsubishi/NNS/B-ORG 's/POS/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Free/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O ``/``/O very/RB/O small/JJ/O .../:/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Wakui/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bodner/NNP/B-PERSON declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O arrangement/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O vertically/RB/O integrated/VBN/O combines/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O got/VBD/O their/PRP$/O start/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O feudal/JJ/O period/NN/O ,/,/O deal/VBP/O globally/RB/O in/IN/O commodities/NNS/O ,/,/O construction/NN/O and/CC/O manufacturing/VBG/O ././O
They/PRP/O operate/VBP/O ships/NNS/O and/CC/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Adds/VBZ/O Takeshi/NNP/B-PERSON Kondo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O C./NNP/B-ORG Itoh/NNP/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O making/VBG/O investments/NNS/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O in/IN/O new/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Profit/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O short/JJ/O term/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O usually/RB/O a/DT/O secondary/JJ/O goal/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Strategic/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O financial/JJ/O return/NN/O ,/,/O drive/VBP/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O deals/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O Venture/NNP/B-ORG Economics/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O classic/JJ/O problem/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O small/JJ/O businessman/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Malcolm/NNP/B-PERSON Davies/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O managing/VBG/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Trading/NNP/B-ORG Alliance/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O are/VBP/O queuing/VBG/O at/IN/O the/DT/O door/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O his/PRP$/O product/NN/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O working/VBG/O capital/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O thing/NN/O and/CC/O commercial/JJ/O banks/NNS/O are/VBP/O very/RB/O unsympathetic/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O want/VBP/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O a/DT/O balance/NN/O sheet/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O relation/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O business/NN/O a/DT/O company/NN/O can/MD/O generate/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Adds/VBZ/O Mitsui/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Klauser/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O Unlike/IN/O corporations/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O trading/NN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O so/RB/O much/RB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O return/NN/O on/IN/O investment/NN/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O on/IN/O increasing/VBG/O trade/NN/O flows/NNS/O ././O
To/TO/O the/DT/O extent/NN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O do/VB/O this/DT/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O quite/RB/O content/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O a/DT/O return/NN/O on/IN/O investment/NN/O of/IN/O 1/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Klauser/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O Mitsui/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O 75/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE subsidiaries/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O holds/VBZ/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O the/DT/O trading/NN/O company/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O double/VB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE affiliates/NNS/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Sales/NNS/O by/IN/O these/DT/O subsidiaries/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ending/VBG/O last/JJ/O March/NNP/O were/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 17/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O 1/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O return/NN/O on/IN/O $/$/O 17/CD/O billion/CD/O ``/``/O ai/VBP/O n't/RB/O hay/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Klauser/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
