Such/JJ/O is/VBZ/O hardly/RB/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O Bell/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O patents/NNS/O went/VBD/O ././O
Western/NNP/B-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG indeed/RB/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O get/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O acquired/VBD/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Edison/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON microphone/NN/O patent/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O immediately/RB/O sued/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Bell/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG claiming/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O microphone/NN/O invented/VBN/O by/IN/O my/PRP$/O grandfather/NN/O ,/,/O Emile/NNP/B-PERSON Berliner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O Bell/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O a/DT/O princely/JJ/O $/$/O 50,000/CD/O ,/,/O infringed/VBN/O upon/IN/O Western/NNP/B-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Edison/NNP/B-PERSON patent/NN/O ././O
