The/DT/B-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Georgia/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O officially/RB/O opened/VBN/O an/DT/O office/NN/O in/IN/O Taipei/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Life/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Georgia/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Nationale/NNP/I-ORG Nederlanden/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNP/B-GPE ././O
