Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC is/VBZ/O propelling/VBG/O the/DT/O region/NN/O toward/IN/O economic/JJ/O integration/NN/O ././O
Interviews/NNS/O with/IN/O analysts/NNS/O and/CC/O business/NN/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE suggest/VBP/O that/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O capital/NN/O may/MD/O produce/VB/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O cooperation/NN/O that/IN/O Southeast/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O politicians/NNS/O have/VBP/O pursued/VBN/O in/IN/O fits/NNS/O and/CC/O starts/NNS/O for/IN/O decades/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O flow/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O funds/NNS/O has/VBZ/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O motion/NN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O process/NN/O whereby/WRB/O these/DT/O economies/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O knitted/VBN/O together/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O great/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O machine/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Hormats/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O commitment/NN/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC also/RB/O includes/VBZ/O steep/JJ/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O assistance/NN/O and/CC/O trade/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O nations/NNS/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O ``/``/O little/JJ/O tigers/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O contributing/VBG/O to/TO/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC 's/POS/I-LOC integration/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O their/PRP$/O influence/NN/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O subordinate/JJ/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O swelling/VBG/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O economic/JJ/O evolution/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O nations/NNS/O '/POS/O internal/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O ``/``/O will/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O offend/VB/O their/PRP$/O largest/JJS/O aid/NN/O donor/NN/O ,/,/O largest/JJS/O private/JJ/O investor/NN/O and/CC/O largest/JJS/O lender/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Drobnick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O international/JJ/O business/NN/O and/CC/O research/NN/O program/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Graduate/NNP/B-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Japanese/JJ/O money/NN/O will/MD/O help/VB/O turn/VB/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC into/IN/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O cohesive/JJ/O economic/JJ/O region/NN/O ././O
Rather/RB/O ,/,/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O will/MD/O spur/VB/O integration/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O sectors/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Kent/NNP/B-PERSON Calder/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O specialist/NN/O in/IN/O East/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O economies/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Woodrow/NNP/I-ORG Wilson/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Internatonal/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/O Princeton/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Countries/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O a/DT/O framework/NN/O for/IN/O closer/JJR/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O ties/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O ministers/NNS/O of/IN/O 12/CD/O Asian/JJ/O and/CC/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC nations/NNS/O will/MD/O meet/VB/O in/IN/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE next/JJ/O week/NN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O global/JJ/O trade/NN/O issues/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O regional/JJ/O matters/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O transportation/NN/O and/CC/O telecommunications/NN/O ././O
Participants/NNS/O will/MD/O include/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O six/CD/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Southeast/NNP/I-ORG Asian/NNP/I-ORG Nations/NNPS/I-ORG --/:/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE Philippines/NNPS/I-GPE and/CC/O Brunei/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON proposal/NN/O reasserts/VBZ/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O intention/NN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O playing/VBG/O a/DT/O leading/VBG/O political/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O Asian/JJ/O nations/NNS/O are/VBP/O apprehensive/JJ/O about/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O demand/NN/O that/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE step/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O military/JJ/O spending/NN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE security/NN/O burden/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O further/RBR/O complicated/JJ/O by/IN/O uncertainty/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leases/NNS/O on/IN/O military/JJ/O bases/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE and/CC/O by/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE troop/NN/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Many/JJ/O Asians/NNPS/O regard/VBP/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE presence/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O desirable/JJ/O counterweight/NN/O to/TO/O Japanese/JJ/O influence/NN/O ././O
