Criticism/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O recent/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O is/VBZ/O looming/VBG/O ever/RB/O larger/JJR/O in/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O countries/NNS/O '/POS/O relations/NNS/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O from/IN/O both/DT/O nations/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE public/NN/O 's/POS/O skittishness/NN/O about/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O could/MD/O color/VB/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O round/NN/O of/IN/O bilateral/JJ/O economic/JJ/O talks/NNS/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Not/RB/O that/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE disagree/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O ;/:/O indeed/RB/O ,/,/O each/DT/O has/VBZ/O come/VBN/O out/RP/O in/IN/O favor/NN/O of/IN/O unfettered/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
Where/WRB/O they/PRP/O disagree/VBP/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE direct/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE wants/VBZ/O the/DT/O removal/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O perceives/VBZ/O as/IN/O barriers/NNS/O to/TO/O investment/NN/O ;/:/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE denies/VBZ/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O real/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O heated/JJ/O talk/NN/O stirred/VBD/O up/RP/O by/IN/O recent/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O focusing/VBG/O attention/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O differences/NNS/O in/IN/O investment/NN/O climate/NN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O only/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O subjects/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O covered/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bilateral/JJ/O talks/NNS/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Structural/NNP/O Impediments/NNP/O Initiative/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O ``/``/O should/MD/O see/VB/O this/DT/O rhetoric/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O signal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O need/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O change/NN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Dallara/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE assistant/NN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG secretary/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE this/DT/O week/NN/O informally/RB/O discussing/VBG/O the/DT/O impending/VBG/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O government/NN/O and/CC/O business/NN/O leaders/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE investors/NNS/O should/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O greater/JJR/O opportunity/NN/O at/IN/O direct/JJ/O investment/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/NNP/O fret/NN/O openly/RB/O about/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE public/NN/O 's/POS/O rancor/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O vitally/RB/O important/JJ/O for/IN/O those/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O business/NN/O interests/NNS/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O -RCB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O emotions/NNS/O and/CC/O concerns/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O Taizo/NNP/B-PERSON Watanabe/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O chastised/VBD/O the/DT/O media/NN/O for/IN/O paying/VBG/O such/JJ/O close/JJ/O attention/NN/O to/TO/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O when/WRB/O other/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O notably/RB/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O acquiring/VBG/O more/JJR/O American/JJ/O assets/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O before/IN/O those/DT/O moves/NNS/O added/VBD/O fuel/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O fires/NNS/O of/IN/O discontent/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O well/RB/O stoked/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O highly/RB/O publicized/VBN/O experience/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O one/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE investor/NN/O ,/,/O T./NNP/B-PERSON Boone/NNP/I-PERSON Pickens/NNP/I-PERSON Jr/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O any/DT/O influence/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Koito/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O refused/VBN/O to/TO/O grant/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Pickens/NNP/B-PERSON seats/NNS/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O board/NN/O ,/,/O asserting/VBG/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O greenmailer/NN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O pressure/VB/O Koito/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O other/JJ/O shareholders/NNS/O into/IN/O buying/VBG/O him/PRP/O out/RP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O profit/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Pickens/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O considerable/JJ/O political/JJ/O hay/NN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O troubles/NNS/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O chaired/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O fellow/JJ/O Texan/NN/O ,/,/O Democratic/JJ/O Sen./NNP/O Lloyd/NNP/B-PERSON Bentsen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O urged/VBD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Trade/NNP/O Representative/NNP/O Carla/NNP/B-PERSON Hills/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O use/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Pickens/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O experience/NN/O in/IN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE ``/``/O to/TO/O highlight/VB/O this/DT/O problem/NN/O facing/VBG/O Americans/NNS/O who/WP/O seek/VBP/O access/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O capital/NN/O markets/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
While/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dallara/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Japanese/NNP/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O investors/NNS/O '/POS/O access/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O markets/NNS/O may/MD/O get/VB/O a/DT/O disproportionate/JJ/O share/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O public/NN/O 's/POS/O attention/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O important/JJ/O economic/JJ/O issues/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O table/NN/O at/IN/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O talks/NNS/O ././O
Among/IN/O them/PRP/O are/VBP/O differences/NNS/O in/IN/O savings/NNS/O and/CC/O investment/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O corporate/JJ/O structures/NNS/O and/CC/O management/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O government/NN/O spending/NN/O ././O
Each/DT/O side/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O litany/NN/O of/IN/O recommendations/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O anxious/JJ/O for/IN/O results/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O feel/VBP/O very/RB/O strongly/RB/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O really/RB/O need/VBP/O action/NN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O range/NN/O of/IN/O issues/NNS/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O identified/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O need/VBP/O it/PRP/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O spring/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Dallara/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Both/DT/O sides/NNS/O have/VBP/O agreed/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O most/RBS/O successful/JJ/O if/IN/O negotiators/NNS/O start/VBP/O by/IN/O focusing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O areas/NNS/O that/WDT/O can/MD/O be/VB/O most/RBS/O easily/RB/O changed/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O clarified/VBN/O what/WP/O those/DT/O might/MD/O be/VB/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O set/NN/O of/IN/O meetings/NNS/O two/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O complained/VBD/O that/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O n't/RB/O come/VBN/O up/RP/O with/IN/O specific/JJ/O changes/NNS/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O retort/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O round/NN/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O early/JJ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O concessions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Just/RB/O to/TO/O say/VB/O the/DT/O distribution/NN/O system/NN/O is/VBZ/O wrong/JJ/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O anything/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O Ministry/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Industry/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O clarify/VB/O what/WP/O exactly/RB/O is/VBZ/O wrong/JJ/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O sorting/VBG/O out/RP/O specifics/NNS/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O take/VB/O time/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O no/DT/O matter/NN/O how/WRB/O badly/RB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE wants/VBZ/O quick/JJ/O results/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O meeting/NN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O agree/VB/O on/IN/O basic/JJ/O data/NNS/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O price/NN/O discussions/NNS/O ././O
Since/IN/O then/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O team/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O 15/CD/O MITI/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O crossed/VBN/O the/DT/O globe/NN/O gauging/VBG/O consumer/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O sheaf/NN/O of/IN/O documents/NNS/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O can/MD/O trust/VB/O ././O
``/``/O Little/RB/O by/IN/O little/RB/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O progress/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O MITI/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Both/DT/O sides/NNS/O are/VBP/O taking/VBG/O action/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Elisabeth/NNP/B-PERSON Rubinfien/NNP/I-PERSON contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
