Pick/VB/O a/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O any/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O turf/NN/O recently/RB/O has/VBZ/O ranged/VBN/O from/IN/O Chile/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O Austria/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O Portugal/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Next/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Philippine/NNP/O Fund/NNP/O 's/POS/O launch/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O capped/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O visit/NN/O by/IN/O Philippine/JJ/O President/NNP/O Corazon/NNP/B-PERSON Aquino/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O the/NNP/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O a/DT/O head/NN/O of/IN/O state/NN/B-ORG has/VBZ/O kicked/VBN/O off/RP/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG here/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O next/JJ/O province/NN/O ?/./O
``/``/O Anything/NN/O 's/VBZ/O possible/JJ/O --/:/O how/WRB/O about/RP/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Guinea/NNP/I-GPE Fund/NNP/O ?/./O ''/''/O quips/VBZ/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Foot/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O managing/VBG/O partner/NN/O at/IN/O Newgate/NNP/B-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Associates/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Northampton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass/NNP/B-GPE ././O
They/PRP/O fell/VBD/O into/IN/O oblivion/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O 1929/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O surge/NN/O brings/VBZ/O to/TO/O nearly/RB/O 50/CD/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O country/NN/O funds/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O or/CC/O soon/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O listed/VBN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE or/CC/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
These/DT/O funds/NNS/O now/RB/O account/VBP/O for/IN/O several/JJ/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O assets/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O individual/JJ/O investors/NNS/O have/VBP/O turned/VBN/O away/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O securities/NNS/O firms/NNS/O have/VBP/O scrambled/VBN/O to/TO/O find/VB/O new/JJ/O products/NNS/O that/WDT/O brokers/NNS/O find/VBP/O easy/JJ/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O firms/NNS/O are/VBP/O stretching/VBG/O their/PRP$/O nets/NNS/O far/RB/O and/CC/O wide/RB/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Financial/JJ/O planners/NNS/O often/RB/O urge/VBP/O investors/NNS/O to/TO/O diversify/VB/O and/CC/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O a/DT/O smattering/NN/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O securities/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O many/JJ/O emerging/VBG/O markets/NNS/O have/VBP/O outpaced/VBN/O more/RBR/O mature/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Country/NN/O funds/NNS/O offer/VBP/O an/DT/O easy/JJ/O way/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O a/DT/O taste/NN/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O without/IN/O the/DT/O hard/JJ/O research/NN/O of/IN/O seeking/VBG/O out/RP/O individual/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O take/VB/O much/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O burned/VBN/O ././O
Political/JJ/O and/CC/O currency/NN/O gyrations/NNS/O can/MD/O whipsaw/VB/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O concern/NN/O :/:/O The/DT/O funds/NNS/O '/POS/O share/NN/O prices/NNS/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O swing/VB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O broader/JJR/O market/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O dropped/VBD/O nearly/RB/O 7/CD/O %/NN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE Fund/NNP/O plunged/VBD/O about/RB/O 18/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE Fund/NNP/O fell/VBD/O 16/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O most/JJS/O country/NN/O funds/NNS/O were/VBD/O clobbered/VBN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O most/JJS/O stocks/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O so/RB/O wild/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O '/POS/O frenzy/NN/O right/RB/O now/RB/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O many/JJ/O are/VBP/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O historically/RB/O fat/JJ/O premiums/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O underlying/JJ/O portfolios/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O an/DT/O average/JJ/O discount/NN/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O part/NN/O of/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O country/NN/O funds/NNS/O currently/RB/O trade/VBP/O at/IN/O an/DT/O average/JJ/O premium/NN/O of/IN/O 6/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O reason/NN/O :/:/O Share/NN/O prices/NNS/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O these/DT/O funds/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O have/VBP/O climbed/VBN/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O sharply/RB/O than/IN/O the/DT/O foreign/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O they/PRP/O hold/VBP/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O probably/RB/O worth/IN/O paying/VBG/O a/DT/O premium/NN/O for/IN/O funds/NNS/O that/WDT/O invest/VBP/O in/IN/O markets/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O partially/RB/O closed/VBN/O to/TO/O foreign/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O some/DT/O specialists/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
But/CC/O some/DT/O European/JJ/O funds/NNS/O recently/RB/O have/VBP/O skyrocketed/VBN/O ;/:/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE Fund/NNP/O has/VBZ/O surged/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O startling/JJ/O 120/CD/O %/NN/O premium/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O several/JJ/O new/JJ/O funds/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O fully/RB/O invested/VBN/O yet/RB/O have/VBP/O jumped/VBN/O to/TO/O trade/VB/O at/IN/O big/JJ/O premiums/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O very/RB/O alarmed/VBN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O these/DT/O rich/JJ/O valuations/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Smith/NNP/B-ORG Barney/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Mr./NNP/O Porter/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O newly/RB/O fattened/VBN/O premiums/NNS/O reflect/VBP/O the/DT/O increasingly/RB/O global/JJ/O marketing/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O country/NN/O funds/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Porter/NNP/B-PERSON suggests/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O may/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O viewpoint/NN/O cast/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O listed/VBN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Porter/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Nonetheless/RB/O ,/,/O plenty/JJ/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE analysts/NNS/O and/CC/O money/NN/O managers/NNS/O are/VBP/O aghast/JJ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O lofty/JJ/O trading/NN/O levels/NNS/O of/IN/O some/DT/O country/NN/O funds/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O way/NN/O investors/NNS/O can/MD/O essentially/RB/O buy/VB/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O without/IN/O paying/VBG/O the/DT/O premium/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O insist/VBP/O on/RP/O jumping/VBG/O in/RB/O now/RB/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O ,/,/O Newgate/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Foot/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O only/JJ/O advice/NN/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O for/IN/O these/DT/O folks/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O come/VBP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O party/NN/O late/RB/O had/VBD/O better/RBR/O be/VB/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O quickly/RB/O ././O
