But/CC/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O TV/NN/O stations/NNS/O that/WDT/O bought/VBD/O ``/``/O Cosby/NNP/O ''/''/O reruns/NNS/O for/IN/O record/NN/O prices/NNS/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O laughing/VBG/O much/RB/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O reruns/NNS/O have/VBP/O helped/VBN/O ratings/NNS/O at/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 187/CD/O network/NN/O affiliates/NNS/O and/CC/O independent/JJ/O TV/NN/O stations/NNS/O that/WDT/O air/VBP/O the/DT/O shows/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O ratings/NNS/O are/VBP/O considerably/RB/O below/IN/O expectations/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O some/DT/O stations/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O not/RB/O buy/VB/O new/JJ/O episodes/NNS/O when/WRB/O their/PRP$/O current/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O expire/VBP/O ././O
Viacom/NNP/B-ORG denies/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O using/VBG/O pressure/NN/O tactics/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O negotiate/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON Gillespie/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O marketing/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O offering/VBG/O this/DT/O plan/NN/O now/RB/O because/IN/O we/PRP/O feel/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O network/NN/O affiliate/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Midwest/NN/B-LOC ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O if/IN/O I/PRP/O tell/VBP/O them/PRP/O I/PRP/O need/VBP/O more/JJR/O time/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O take/VB/O `/``/O Cosby/NNP/O '/''/O across/IN/O the/DT/O street/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O
Viacom/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O move/NN/O comes/VBZ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O syndication/NN/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O flooded/VBN/O with/IN/O situation/NN/O comedies/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O running/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O networks/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O station/NN/O manager/NN/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O Viacom/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O pre-emptive/JJ/O strike/NN/O ''/''/O because/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O worried/VBN/O that/IN/O ``/``/O Cosby/NNP/O ''/''/O ratings/NNS/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O in/IN/O syndication/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gillespie/NNP/B-PERSON at/IN/O Viacom/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O the/DT/O ratings/NNS/O are/VBP/O rising/VBG/O ././O
And/CC/O executives/NNS/O at/IN/O stations/NNS/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O major/JJ/O markets/NNS/O as/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Providence/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O R.I./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Cleveland/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Raleigh/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.C./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Minneapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ky./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O very/RB/O well/RB/O not/RB/O renew/VB/O ``/``/O Cosby/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O At/IN/O the/DT/O prices/NNS/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O charged/VBN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O should/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O some/DT/O return/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Neil/NNP/B-PERSON Kuvin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O WHAS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG affiliate/NN/O in/IN/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O ``/``/O Cosby/NNP/O ''/''/O gets/VBZ/O the/DT/O station/NN/O 's/POS/O highest/JJS/O ratings/NNS/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O ``/``/O pleased/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O feel/VBP/O pressured/JJ/O ,/,/O disappointed/JJ/O ,/,/O uncomfortable/JJ/O and/CC/O ,/,/O frankly/RB/O ,/,/O quite/RB/O angry/JJ/O with/IN/O Viacom/NNP/B-ORG ././O
