Oil/NN/O production/NN/O from/IN/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Bass/NNP/B-LOC Strait/NNP/I-LOC fields/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O by/IN/O 11,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O to/TO/O about/IN/O 321,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O launch/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Whiting/NNP/B-LOC field/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O of/IN/O five/CD/O small/JJ/O fields/NNS/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O brought/VBN/O into/IN/O production/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Esso/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O Whiting/NNP/B-LOC field/NN/O started/VBD/O production/NN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
Output/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O gradually/RB/O increased/VBN/O until/IN/O it/PRP/O reaches/VBZ/O about/IN/O 11,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O field/NN/O has/VBZ/O reserves/NNS/O of/IN/O 21/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O ././O
Reserves/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O five/CD/O new/JJ/O fields/NNS/O total/VBP/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Perch/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Dolphin/NNP/B-LOC fields/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O start/VB/O producing/VBG/O early/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Seahorse/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Tarwhine/NNP/B-LOC fields/NNS/O later/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Esso/NN/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O fields/NNS/O were/VBD/O developed/VBN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Australian/JJ/O government/NN/O decided/VBD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O from/IN/O new/JJ/O fields/NNS/O free/JJ/O of/IN/O excise/JJ/O tax/NN/O ././O
