Eaton/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O sold/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Sierra/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O company/NN/O formed/VBN/O by/IN/O employees/NNS/O of/IN/O that/DT/O unit/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Sierra/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O about/RB/O 200/CD/O employees/NNS/O and/CC/O supplies/VBZ/O professional/JJ/O services/NNS/O and/CC/O advanced/JJ/O products/NNS/O to/TO/O industry/NN/O ././O
Eaton/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O an/DT/O automotive/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O controls/NNS/O and/CC/O aerospace/NN/O electronics/NNS/O concern/NN/O ././O
