PAPERS/NNS/O :/:/O
Backe/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Atlantic/NNP/B-ORG Publications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O 30/CD/O community/NN/O papers/NNS/O and/CC/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 7/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Backe/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O media/NNS/O firm/NN/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Backe/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
TV/NN/O :/:/O
Price/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG completed/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O four/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O TV/NN/O stations/NNS/O to/TO/O NTG/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 120/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O cash/NN/O and/CC/O notes/NNS/O ,/,/O retaining/VBG/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O equity/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O concern/NN/O ././O
NTG/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O formed/VBN/O by/IN/O Osborn/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Desai/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG ././O
