Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Backe/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O media/NNS/O firm/NN/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Backe/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
NTG/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O formed/VBN/O by/IN/O Osborn/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Desai/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG ././O
