It/PRP/O eventually/RB/O secured/VBD/O Ministry/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG import/NN/O approval/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O Candela/NNP/B-ORG laser/NN/O products/NNS/O --/:/O one/CD/O that/WDT/O breaks/VBZ/O up/RP/O kidney/NN/O stones/NNS/O and/CC/O another/DT/O that/WDT/O treats/VBZ/O skin/NN/O lesions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O bankroll/VBP/O many/JJ/O small/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O with/IN/O promising/JJ/O products/NNS/O or/CC/O ideas/NNS/O ,/,/O frequently/RB/O putting/VBG/O their/PRP$/O money/NN/O behind/IN/O projects/NNS/O that/IN/O commercial/JJ/O banks/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O touch/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O Needham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O concern/NN/O tracks/VBZ/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O new/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O ././O
Heightened/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O American/JJ/O small/JJ/O business/NN/O parallels/VBZ/O an/DT/O acceleration/NN/O of/IN/O investments/NNS/O giving/VBG/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O control/NN/O of/IN/O large/JJ/O ,/,/O highly/RB/O visible/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE corporations/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Free/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Glass/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Warrenton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O fabricator/NN/O of/IN/O architectural/JJ/O glass/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O foundering/VBG/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O original/JJ/O management/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O deal/NN/O is/VBZ/O chiefly/RB/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O window/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE glass/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Ichiro/NNP/B-PERSON Wakui/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O executive/NN/O in/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O general/JJ/O merchandise/NN/O department/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Mitsubishi/NNS/B-ORG 's/POS/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Free/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O ``/``/O very/RB/O small/JJ/O .../:/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Wakui/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bodner/NNP/B-PERSON declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O arrangement/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O vertically/RB/O integrated/VBN/O combines/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O got/VBD/O their/PRP$/O start/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O feudal/JJ/O period/NN/O ,/,/O deal/VBP/O globally/RB/O in/IN/O commodities/NNS/O ,/,/O construction/NN/O and/CC/O manufacturing/VBG/O ././O
They/PRP/O operate/VBP/O ships/NNS/O and/CC/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Profit/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O short/JJ/O term/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O usually/RB/O a/DT/O secondary/JJ/O goal/NN/O ././O
Adds/VBZ/O Mitsui/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Klauser/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O Unlike/IN/O corporations/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O trading/NN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O so/RB/O much/RB/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O return/NN/O on/IN/O investment/NN/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O on/IN/O increasing/VBG/O trade/NN/O flows/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Klauser/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O Mitsui/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O 75/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE subsidiaries/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O holds/VBZ/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O the/DT/O trading/NN/O company/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O double/VB/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE affiliates/NNS/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Sales/NNS/O by/IN/O these/DT/O subsidiaries/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ending/VBG/O last/JJ/O March/NNP/O were/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 17/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O 1/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O return/NN/O on/IN/O $/$/O 17/CD/O billion/CD/O ``/``/O ai/VBP/O n't/RB/O hay/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Klauser/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
