In/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O may/MD/O reflect/VB/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O `/``/O she/PRP/O speaks/VBZ/O a/DT/O more/JJR/O progressive/JJ/O language/NN/O '/''/O than/IN/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Prof/NNP/O ././O -LCB-/-LRB-/B-PERSON Ethel/NNP/I-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON Klein/NNP/I-PERSON puts/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ././O
Among/IN/O professionals/NNS/O ,/,/O 76/CD/O %/NN/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O favorable/JJ/O opinion/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O to/TO/O 62/CD/O %/NN/O who/WP/O approve/VBP/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O 's/POS/O performance/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O a/DT/O quarter/NN/O of/IN/O black/JJ/O voters/NNS/O disapprove/VBP/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O job/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O negative/JJ/O view/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O spouse/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O surprising/JJ/O that/IN/O so/RB/O few/JJ/O blacks/NNS/O find/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O and/CC/O Mrs./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON distasteful/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O positive/JJ/O view/NN/O is/VBZ/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O newsworthy/JJ/O ././O
Such/PDT/O an/DT/O editorial/NN/O point/NN/O of/IN/O view/NN/O perpetuates/VBZ/O an/DT/O insidious/JJ/O ,/,/O stereotyped/JJ/O perspective/NN/O ././O
Why/WRB/O are/VBP/O we/PRP/O blacks/NNS/O continually/RB/O defined/VBN/O by/IN/O our/PRP$/O minority/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O lowest/JJS/O common/JJ/O denominator/NN/O ././O
Preston/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Foster/NNP/I-PERSON Birmingham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ala/NNP/B-GPE ././O
