The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Soviet/NNP/B-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE are/VBP/O holding/VBG/O technical/JJ/O talks/NNS/O about/IN/O possible/JJ/O repayment/NN/O by/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O $/$/O 188/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O pre-Communist/JJ/O Russian/JJ/O debts/NNS/O owed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O debts/NNS/O are/VBP/O repaid/VBN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O clear/VB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O for/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O after/IN/O two/CD/O meetings/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O ``/``/O too/RB/O early/RB/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ''/''/O whether/IN/O that/DT/O will/MD/O happen/VB/O ././O
Coincident/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O permitted/VBN/O a/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O bank/NN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE branch/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O branch/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O approved/VBN/O last/JJ/O spring/NN/O and/CC/O opened/VBD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
Under/IN/O a/DT/O 1934/CD/O law/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Johnson/NNP/O Debt/NNP/O Default/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ,/,/O as/RB/O amended/VBN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O illegal/JJ/O for/IN/O Americans/NNS/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O credit/NN/O to/TO/O countries/NNS/O in/IN/O default/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O ,/,/O unless/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O World/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O International/NNP/B-ORG Monetary/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O U.S.S.R./NNP/B-GPE belongs/VBZ/O to/TO/O neither/DT/O organization/NN/O ././O
Moscow/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O settled/VBN/O pre-1917/JJ/O debts/NNS/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O countries/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O at/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O face/NN/O value/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG stressed/VBD/O the/DT/O pre-1933/JJ/O debts/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O key/NN/O to/TO/O satisfying/VBG/O the/DT/O Johnson/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
