Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 25/CD/O countries/NNS/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O placed/VBD/O under/IN/O varying/VBG/O degrees/NNS/O of/IN/O scrutiny/NN/O have/VBP/O made/VBN/O ``/``/O genuine/JJ/O progress/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O this/DT/O touchy/JJ/O issue/NN/O ././O
Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O improved/VBN/O its/PRP$/O standing/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O initialing/VBG/O a/DT/O bilateral/JJ/O copyright/NN/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O amending/VBG/O its/PRP$/O trademark/NN/O law/NN/O and/CC/O introducing/VBG/O legislation/NN/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O foreign/JJ/O movie/NN/O producers/NNS/O from/IN/O unauthorized/JJ/O showings/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O films/NNS/O ././O
Saudi/NNP/B-GPE Arabia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O part/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O vowed/VBN/O to/TO/O enact/VB/O a/DT/O copyright/NN/O law/NN/O compatible/JJ/O with/IN/O international/JJ/O standards/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O apply/VB/O the/DT/O law/NN/O to/TO/O computer/NN/O software/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O to/TO/O literary/JJ/O works/NNS/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
These/DT/O three/CD/O countries/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O completely/RB/O off/IN/O the/DT/O hook/NN/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O this/DT/O tells/VBZ/O us/PRP/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O law/NN/O is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE could/MD/O be/VB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O countries/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O removed/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O priority/NN/O list/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O craft/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O patent/NN/O law/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O still/RB/O concerned/VBN/O about/IN/O ``/``/O disturbing/JJ/O developments/NNS/O in/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O continuing/VBG/O slow/JJ/O progress/NN/O in/IN/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
She/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O elaborate/JJ/O ,/,/O although/IN/O earlier/JJR/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O reports/NNS/O have/VBP/O complained/VBN/O of/IN/O videocassette/NN/O piracy/NN/O in/IN/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O disregard/NN/O for/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE pharmaceutical/JJ/O patents/NNS/O in/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O 1988/CD/O trade/NN/O act/NN/O requires/VBZ/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O issue/VB/O another/DT/O review/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O performance/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O countries/NNS/O by/IN/O April/NNP/O 30/CD/O ././O
