Texas/NNP/B-ORG Instruments/NNPS/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Instruments/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O opened/VBD/O a/DT/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O manufacture/VB/O control/NN/O devices/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O plant/NN/O ,/,/O located/VBN/O in/IN/O Chinchon/NNP/B-GPE about/IN/O 60/CD/O miles/NNS/O from/IN/O Seoul/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O will/MD/O help/VB/O meet/VB/O increasing/VBG/O and/CC/O diversifying/VBG/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O control/NN/O products/NNS/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O plant/NN/O will/MD/O produce/VB/O control/NN/O devices/NNS/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O motor/NN/O vehicles/NNS/O and/CC/O household/NN/O appliances/NNS/O ././O
