The/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O suspended/VBD/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE savings/NNS/O bonds/NNS/O because/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O lifted/VBN/O the/DT/O ceiling/NN/O on/IN/O government/NN/O debt/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O borrowing/NN/O authority/NN/O dropped/VBD/O at/IN/O midnight/NN/O Tuesday/NNP/O to/TO/O $/$/O 2.80/CD/O trillion/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 2.87/CD/O trillion/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O voted/VBN/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O the/DT/O ceiling/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.1/CD/O trillion/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O act/VB/O until/IN/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O earliest/JJS/O ././O
The/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O default/VB/O on/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 9/CD/O if/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O act/VB/O by/IN/O then/RB/O ././O
