It/PRP/O was/VBD/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Nixon/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON first/JJ/O visit/NN/O to/TO/O China/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O 1972/CD/O that/WDT/O set/VBD/O in/IN/O motion/NN/O the/DT/O historic/JJ/O rapprochement/NN/O between/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O prominent/JJ/O American/NNP/O to/TO/O come/VB/O to/TO/O China/NNP/B-GPE since/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O bloody/JJ/O suppression/NN/O of/IN/O pro-democracy/JJ/O demonstrators/NNS/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O ,/,/O harped/VBD/O on/IN/O international/JJ/O outrage/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O massacre/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Chinese/NNP/O ,/,/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O ,/,/O took/VBD/O aim/NN/O at/IN/O American/JJ/O ``/``/O interference/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O domestic/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O official/JJ/O newspaper/NN/O ,/,/O Legal/NNP/B-ORG Daily/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O even/RB/O directly/RB/O criticized/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O normally/RB/O referred/VBN/O to/TO/O here/RB/O as/IN/O an/DT/O ``/``/O old/JJ/O friend/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O paper/NN/O accused/VBD/O him/PRP/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O a/DT/O leading/VBG/O proponent/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O peaceful/JJ/O evolution/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O catch/NN/O phrase/NN/O to/TO/O describe/VB/O what/WP/O China/NNP/B-GPE believes/VBZ/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O Western/JJ/O countries/NNS/O to/TO/O seduce/VB/O socialist/JJ/O nations/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O capitalist/JJ/O sphere/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O tension/NN/O was/VBD/O evident/JJ/O on/IN/O Wednesday/NNP/O evening/NN/O during/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O final/JJ/O banquet/NN/O toast/NN/O ,/,/O normally/RB/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O for/IN/O reciting/VBG/O platitudes/NNS/O about/IN/O eternal/JJ/O friendship/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Many/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE ,/,/O including/VBG/O many/JJ/O friends/NNS/O of/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O crackdown/NN/O was/VBD/O excessive/JJ/O and/CC/O unjustified/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Yang/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O directly/RB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O ordering/VBG/O the/DT/O attack/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O April/NNP/O through/IN/O June/NNP/O damaged/VBD/O the/DT/O respect/NN/O and/CC/O confidence/NN/O which/WDT/O most/JJS/O Americans/NNPS/O previously/RB/O had/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O leaders/NNS/O of/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Chinese/NNP/O responded/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O equally/RB/O undiplomatic/JJ/O fashion/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Chinese/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O expressed/VBD/O no/DT/O regret/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O killings/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O even/RB/O suggested/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O prominently/RB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O demonstrations/NNS/O this/DT/O spring/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O supreme/NN/O leader/NN/O ,/,/O Deng/NNP/B-PERSON Xiaoping/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O told/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O Frankly/RB/O speaking/VBG/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O involved/VBN/O too/RB/O deeply/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O turmoil/NN/O and/CC/O counterrevolutionary/JJ/O rebellion/NN/O which/WDT/O occurred/VBD/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE not/RB/O long/RB/O ago/RB/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O victim/NN/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O unjust/JJ/O to/TO/O reprove/VB/O China/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O his/PRP$/O return/NN/O toast/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Yang/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O relationship/NN/O had/VBD/O reached/VBN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O stalemate/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Relations/NNS/O between/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O tense/JJ/O since/IN/O June/NNP/O 7/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Chinese/JJ/O dissident/NN/O Fang/NNP/B-PERSON Lizhi/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Li/NNP/B-PERSON Shuxian/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O took/VBD/O refuge/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Embassy/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O traveling/VBG/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O citizen/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O clear/RB/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O unofficial/JJ/O envoy/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON met/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O adviser/NN/O ,/,/O Brent/NNP/B-PERSON Scowcroft/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O before/IN/O coming/VBG/O to/TO/O China/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O Saturday/NNP/O ././O
And/CC/O he/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O brief/VB/O the/DT/O president/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O China/NNP/B-GPE today/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O included/VBD/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ,/,/O human/JJ/O rights/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Fang/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE pulled/VBD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O his/PRP$/O talks/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O president/NN/O urged/VBD/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O to/TO/O acknowledge/VB/O that/DT/O their/PRP$/O nation/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O community/NN/O and/CC/O welcome/VB/O the/DT/O infusion/NN/O of/IN/O outside/JJ/O contacts/NNS/O and/CC/O ideas/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Ideas/NNS/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O over/IN/O borders/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O SDI/NNP/O ideological/JJ/O weapon/NN/O that/WDT/O can/MD/O shoot/VB/O them/PRP/O down/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Embassy/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O signs/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O of/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O yielding/NN/O on/IN/O key/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O one/CD/O minor/JJ/O matter/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O gained/VBN/O a/DT/O concession/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O with/IN/O Premier/NNP/O Li/NNP/B-PERSON Peng/NNP/I-PERSON on/IN/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O hoped/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O encounter/VB/O guards/NNS/O with/IN/O machine/NN/O guns/NNS/O during/IN/O his/PRP$/O visit/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Embassy/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O guards/NNS/O there/RB/O retained/VBN/O their/PRP$/O pistols/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O contingent/NN/O of/IN/O plainclothes/NNS/O police/NNS/O remained/VBD/O nearby/RB/O in/IN/O unmarked/JJ/O cars/NNS/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O police/NNS/O and/CC/O soldiers/NNS/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O harass/VB/O Americans/NNPS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O filed/VBN/O several/JJ/O protests/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O week/NN/O ././O
Several/JJ/O times/NNS/O ,/,/O Chinese/JJ/O guards/NNS/O have/VBP/O pointed/VBN/O their/PRP$/O automatic/JJ/O rifles/NNS/O at/IN/O young/JJ/O children/NNS/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE diplomats/NNS/O and/CC/O clicked/VBD/O the/DT/O trigger/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O rifles/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O loaded/VBN/O ././O
