Since/IN/O chalk/NN/O first/RB/O touched/VBD/O slate/NN/O ,/,/O schoolchildren/NN/O have/VBP/O wanted/VBN/O to/TO/O know/VB/O :/:/O What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O test/NN/O ?/./O
The/DT/O mathematics/NN/O section/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O widely/RB/O used/JJ/O California/NNP/O Achievement/NNP/O Test/NNP/O asks/VBZ/O fifth/JJ/O graders/NNS/O :/:/O ``/``/O What/WP/O is/VBZ/O another/DT/O name/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Roman/JJ/O numeral/NN/O IX/CD/O ?/./O ''/''/O
In/IN/O many/JJ/O other/JJ/O instances/NNS/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O almost/RB/O no/DT/O difference/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O test/NN/O and/CC/O Learning/NNP/O Materials/NNPS/O ././O
Close/JJ/O parallels/NNS/O between/IN/O tests/NNS/O and/CC/O practice/NN/O tests/NNS/O are/VBP/O common/JJ/O ,/,/O some/DT/O educators/NNS/O and/CC/O researchers/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O I/PRP/O took/VBD/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O these/DT/O preparation/NN/O booklets/NNS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O into/IN/O my/PRP$/O classroom/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O time/NN/O justifying/VBG/O to/TO/O my/PRP$/O students/NNS/O and/CC/O parents/NNS/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O cheating/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Kaminski/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Traverse/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O teacher/NN/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O studied/VBN/O test/NN/O coaching/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O critics/NNS/O say/VBP/O such/JJ/O coaching/NN/O aids/NNS/O can/MD/O defeat/VB/O the/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O standardized/JJ/O tests/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O gauge/VB/O learning/NN/O progress/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O as/IN/O if/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE decided/VBD/O to/TO/O give/VB/O only/JJ/O French/JJ/O history/NN/O questions/NNS/O to/TO/O students/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O European/JJ/O history/NN/O class/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O everybody/NN/O aces/VBZ/O the/DT/O test/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O say/VBP/O their/PRP$/O kids/NNS/O are/VBP/O good/JJ/O in/IN/O European/JJ/O history/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Cannell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O Albuquerque/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.M./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O psychiatrist/NN/O and/CC/O founder/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O educational/JJ/O research/NN/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O Friends/NNPS/B-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Education/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O studied/VBN/O standardized/JJ/O testing/NN/O ././O
Standardized/JJ/O achievement/NN/O tests/NNS/O are/VBP/O given/VBN/O about/IN/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O times/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O across/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O to/TO/O students/NNS/O generally/RB/O from/IN/O kindergarten/NN/O through/IN/O eighth/JJ/O grade/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Louisiana/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O educators/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O common/JJ/O classroom/NN/O tools/NNS/O ././O
About/IN/O 20,000/CD/O sets/NNS/O of/IN/O Learning/NNP/O Materials/NNPS/O teachers/NNS/O '/POS/O binders/NNS/O have/VBP/O also/RB/O been/VBN/O sold/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O materials/NNS/O in/IN/O each/DT/O set/NN/O reach/VBP/O about/IN/O 90/CD/O students/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O asserted/VBD/O that/IN/O exact/JJ/O questions/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O replicated/VBN/O ././O
When/WRB/O referred/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O questions/NNS/O that/WDT/O matched/VBN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O coincidental/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kaminski/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O schoolteacher/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Mehrens/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Michigan/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG education/NN/O professor/NN/O ,/,/O concluded/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O study/NN/O last/JJ/O June/NNP/O that/IN/O CAT/NNP/O test/NN/O versions/NNS/O of/IN/O Scoring/NNP/O High/NNP/O and/CC/O Learning/NNP/O Materials/NNPS/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O classroom/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O similarity/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O actual/JJ/O test/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Learning/NNP/O Materials/NNPS/O matched/VBD/O on/IN/O 66.5/CD/O of/IN/O 69/CD/O subskills/NNS/O ././O
Scoring/NNP/O High/NNP/O matched/VBD/O on/IN/O 64.5/CD/O ././O
Rick/NNP/B-PERSON Brownell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O Scoring/NNP/O High/NNP/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O Messrs./NNPS/O Kaminski/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mehrens/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O ignoring/VBG/O ``/``/O the/DT/O need/NN/O students/NNS/O have/VBP/O for/IN/O becoming/VBG/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O tests/NNS/O and/CC/O testing/NN/O format/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O authors/NNS/O of/IN/O Scoring/NNP/O High/NNP/O ``/``/O scrupulously/RB/O avoid/VBP/O ''/''/O replicating/VBG/O exact/JJ/O questions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O deny/VB/O that/IN/O some/DT/O items/NNS/O are/VBP/O similar/JJ/O ././O
When/WRB/O Scoring/NNP/O High/NNP/O first/RB/O came/VBD/O out/RB/O in/IN/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O publication/NN/O of/IN/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ././O
