Copperweld/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O specialty/NN/O steelmaker/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O 445/CD/O workers/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Shelby/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O began/VBD/O a/DT/O strike/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Steelworkers/NNP/I-ORG Local/NNP/I-ORG 3057/CD/I-ORG rejected/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O contract/NN/O on/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O previous/JJ/O contract/NN/O between/IN/O Copperweld/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Ohio/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG Tube/NNP/I-ORG division/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O union/NN/O expired/VBD/O at/IN/O midnight/NN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
Copperweld/NN/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O a/DT/O protracted/JJ/O strike/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O measures/NNS/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O shipments/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O work/NN/O stoppage/NN/O ././O
