The/DT/O vote/NN/O came/VBD/O after/IN/O a/DT/O debate/NN/O replete/JJ/O with/IN/O complaints/NNS/O from/IN/O both/DT/O proponents/NNS/O and/CC/O critics/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O substantial/JJ/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wage/NN/O floor/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O reflected/VBD/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O on/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O by/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Democratic/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O after/IN/O congressional/JJ/O Republicans/NNPS/O urged/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O bend/VB/O a/DT/O bit/NN/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O previous/JJ/O resistance/NN/O to/TO/O compromise/VB/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O passed/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O minimum/JJ/O wage/NN/O would/MD/O rise/VB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.80/CD/O next/JJ/O April/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O take/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O quickly/RB/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O smiles/NNS/O about/IN/O this/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Rep./NNP/O Pat/NNP/B-PERSON Williams/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Mont/NNP/B-GPE ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O during/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG floor/NN/O debate/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ``/``/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O all/DT/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O vote/VB/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
While/IN/O the/DT/O minimum/JJ/O wage/NN/O had/VBD/O traditionally/RB/O been/VBN/O pegged/VBN/O at/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O average/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE manufacturing/NN/O wage/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O level/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 4.25/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O in/IN/O 1991/CD/O will/MD/O still/RB/O be/VB/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O average/JJ/O factory/NN/O pay/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Williams/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O Rep./NNP/O Marge/NNP/B-PERSON Roukema/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O N.J/NNP/B-GPE ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O instead/RB/O praised/VBD/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O acceptance/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O youth/NN/O ``/``/O training/NN/O ''/''/O wage/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O subminimum/NN/O that/IN/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG administrations/NNS/O have/VBP/O sought/VBN/O for/IN/O many/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
Policy/NN/O makers/NNS/O regard/VBP/O the/DT/O youth/NN/O wage/NN/O as/IN/O helping/VBG/O to/TO/O limit/VB/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O jobs/NNS/O from/IN/O an/DT/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O minimum/JJ/O wage/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O lately/RB/O touted/VBN/O it/PRP/O as/RB/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O help/VB/O impart/VB/O job/NN/O skills/NNS/O to/TO/O entrants/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O work/NN/O force/NN/O ././O
Labor/NN/O unions/NNS/O and/CC/O Democrats/NNPS/O long/RB/O fought/VBD/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O recently/RB/O acceded/VBD/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O face/NN/O of/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O insistence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O compromise/NN/O sets/VBZ/O the/DT/O training/NN/O wage/NN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 3.35/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O next/IN/O April/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O $/$/O 3.61/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 85/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O minimum/JJ/O wage/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O 1991/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O training/NN/O wage/NN/O covers/VBZ/O only/JJ/O workers/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O 16/CD/O to/TO/O 19/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ././O
