This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O year/NN/O the/DT/O negative/JJ/O ad/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O a/DT/O secondary/JJ/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O most/JJS/O political/JJ/O campaigns/NNS/O ,/,/O became/VBD/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O event/NN/O ././O
But/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O leading/VBG/O political/JJ/O contests/NNS/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O negative/JJ/O ads/NNS/O have/VBP/O reached/VBN/O new/JJ/O levels/NNS/O of/IN/O hostility/NN/O ,/,/O raising/VBG/O fears/NNS/O that/IN/O this/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O mudslinging/NN/O ,/,/O empty/JJ/O of/IN/O significant/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ushering/VBG/O in/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O era/NN/O of/IN/O campaigns/NNS/O without/IN/O content/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Now/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON Napolitan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O pioneer/NN/O in/IN/O political/JJ/O television/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O attack/VB/O first/RB/O ,/,/O last/RB/O and/CC/O always/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O To/TO/O get/VB/O people/NNS/O 's/POS/O attention/NN/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Bailey/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O consultant/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O your/PRP$/O TV/NN/O ad/NN/O needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O bold/JJ/O and/CC/O entertaining/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ,/,/O more/RBR/O often/RB/O than/IN/O not/RB/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O means/VBZ/O confrontational/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O unlike/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O worry/VB/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O is/VBZ/O truthful/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O as/RB/O often/RB/O as/IN/O not/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O principal/JJ/O fights/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O campaigns/NNS/O are/VBP/O prompted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O ads/NNS/O themselves/PRP/O ././O
Take/VB/O a/DT/O look/NN/O ,/,/O then/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O attack/NN/O commercials/NNS/O that/WDT/O set/VBD/O the/DT/O tone/NN/O for/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O elections/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE :/:/O
New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE :/:/I-GPE
The/DT/O screen/NN/O fills/VBZ/O with/IN/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O ,/,/O tight/JJ/O facial/JJ/O shot/NN/O of/IN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Dinkins/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Democratic/JJ/O candidate/NN/O for/IN/O mayor/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Dinkins/NNP/I-PERSON failed/VBD/O to/TO/O file/VB/O his/PRP$/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O for/IN/O four/CD/O straight/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O disembodied/JJ/O male/NN/O voice/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O then/RB/O this/DT/O television/NN/O commercial/NN/O ,/,/O paid/VBN/O for/RB/O by/IN/O Republican/NNP/O Rudolph/NNP/B-PERSON Giuliani/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O campaign/NN/O and/CC/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O Roger/NNP/B-PERSON Ailes/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O master/NN/O of/IN/O negative/JJ/O TV/NN/O ads/NNS/O ,/,/O really/RB/O gets/VBZ/O down/RB/O to/TO/O business/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O charges/VBZ/O ,/,/O also/RB/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O report/VB/O his/PRP$/O campaign/NN/O contributions/NNS/O accurately/RB/O ,/,/O hid/VBD/O his/PRP$/O links/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O failing/VBG/O insurance/NN/O company/NN/O and/CC/O paid/VBD/O a/DT/O convicted/VBN/O kidnapper/NN/O ``/``/O through/IN/O a/DT/O phony/JJ/O organization/NN/O with/IN/O no/DT/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O no/DT/O receipts/NNS/O and/CC/O no/DT/O office/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Dinkins/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O kicker/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Why/WRB/O does/VBZ/O he/PRP/O always/RB/O wait/VB/O until/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O caught/VBN/O ?/./O ''/''/O
``/``/O Nasty/JJ/O innuendoes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Siegal/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O issues/NNS/O director/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O prosecute/VB/O a/DT/O case/NN/O of/IN/O political/JJ/O corruption/NN/O that/WDT/O simply/RB/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O exist/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Stung/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Giuliani/NNP/B-PERSON ads/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O TV/NN/O consultants/NNS/O ,/,/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Shrum/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Doak/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O finally/RB/O unleashed/VBD/O a/DT/O negative/JJ/O ad/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O screen/NN/O shows/VBZ/O two/CD/O distorted/JJ/O ,/,/O unrecognizable/JJ/O photos/NNS/O ,/,/O presumably/RB/O of/IN/O two/CD/O politicians/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Compare/VB/O two/CD/O candidates/NNS/O for/IN/O mayor/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O announcer/NN/O ././O
One/NN/O claims/VBZ/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O pro-choice/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O has/VBZ/O opposed/VBN/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O right/NN/O to/TO/O choose/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O Funny/JJ/O thing/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O kicker/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O both/DT/O these/DT/O candidates/NNS/O are/VBP/O named/VBN/O Rudolph/NNP/B-PERSON Giuliani/NNP/I-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
Who/WP/O 's/VBZ/O telling/VBG/O the/DT/O truth/NN/O ?/./O
Everybody/NN/O --/:/O and/IN/O nobody/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O classic/JJ/O situation/NN/O of/IN/O ads/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O true/JJ/O but/CC/O not/RB/O always/RB/O fully/RB/O accurate/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O fail/VB/O to/TO/O file/VB/O his/PRP$/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O for/IN/O four/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O insists/VBZ/O he/PRP/O voluntarily/RB/O admitted/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O oversight/NN/O ''/''/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O being/VBG/O considered/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O city/NN/O job/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O insurance/NN/O company/NN/O with/IN/O financial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O insists/VBZ/O he/PRP/O made/VBD/O no/DT/O secret/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O Campaign/NNP/B-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O refused/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON $/$/O 95,142/CD/O in/IN/O matching/JJ/O funds/NNS/O because/IN/O his/PRP$/O campaign/NN/O records/NNS/O are/VBP/O incomplete/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O campaign/NN/O has/VBZ/O blamed/VBN/O these/DT/O reporting/NN/O problems/NNS/O on/IN/O computer/NN/O errors/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O managers/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O have/VB/O an/DT/O office/NN/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O organization/NN/O did/VBD/O have/VB/O members/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Giuliani/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O campaign/NN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Powers/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Dinkins/NNP/B-PERSON ad/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O deceptive/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O side/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O argues/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O knows/VBZ/O Giuliani/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O always/RB/O been/VBN/O pro-choice/JJ/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O personal/JJ/O reservations/NNS/O ././O
Virginia/NNP/B-GPE :/:/O
Democratic/JJ/O Lt./NNP/O Gov./NNP/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Wilder/NNP/I-PERSON opened/VBD/O his/PRP$/O gubernatorial/JJ/O battle/NN/O with/IN/O Republican/JJ/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON Coleman/NNP/I-PERSON with/IN/O an/DT/O abortion/NN/O commercial/NN/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Greer/NNP/I-PERSON that/IN/O analysts/NNS/O of/IN/O every/DT/O political/JJ/O persuasion/NN/O agree/VBP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O tour/NN/O de/FW/O force/NN/O ././O
Against/IN/O a/DT/O shot/NN/O of/IN/O Monticello/NNP/B-FAC superimposed/VBN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O American/JJ/O flag/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O announcer/NN/O talks/VBZ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O strong/JJ/O tradition/NN/O of/IN/O freedom/NN/O and/CC/O individual/JJ/O liberty/NN/O ''/''/O that/IN/O Virginians/NNPS/O have/VBP/O nurtured/VBN/O for/IN/O generations/NNS/O ././O
Then/RB/O ,/,/O just/RB/O as/IN/O an/DT/O image/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O statue/NN/O of/IN/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Jefferson/NNP/I-PERSON dissolves/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O screen/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O announcer/NN/O continues/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O On/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON Coleman/NNP/I-PERSON wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O take/VB/O away/RP/O your/PRP$/O right/NN/O to/TO/O choose/VB/O and/CC/O give/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O politicians/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O commercial/JJ/O --/:/O which/WDT/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O take/VB/O away/RP/O the/DT/O right/NN/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O ``/``/O even/RB/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O charge/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON denies/VBZ/O --/:/O changed/VBD/O the/DT/O dynamics/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O transforming/VBG/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O in/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O into/IN/O a/DT/O referendum/NN/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ad/NN/O prompted/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O general/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O launch/VB/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O advertisements/NNS/O created/VBN/O by/IN/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Goodman/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O shake/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Wilder/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O support/NN/O among/IN/O the/DT/O very/JJ/O women/NNS/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O attracted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O ad/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O voice/NN/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O C'mon/VB/O ,/,/O now/RB/O ,/,/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O you/PRP/O have/VB/O boyfriends/NNS/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Then/RB/O an/DT/O announcer/NN/O interjects/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Wilder/NNP/I-PERSON who/WP/O introduced/VBD/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O force/VB/O rape/NN/O victims/NNS/O age/NN/O 13/CD/O and/CC/O younger/JJR/O to/TO/O be/VB/O interrogated/VBN/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O private/JJ/O lives/NNS/O by/IN/O lawyers/NNS/O for/IN/O accused/VBN/O rapists/NNS/O ././O
So/RB/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O time/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Wilder/NNP/B-PERSON talks/VBZ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O rights/NNS/O of/IN/O women/NNS/O ,/,/O ask/VB/O him/PRP/O about/IN/O this/DT/O law/NN/O he/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Wilder/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O introduce/VB/O such/JJ/O legislation/NN/O 17/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O so/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O request/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O constituent/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O common/JJ/O legislative/JJ/O technique/NN/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O lawmakers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O legislation/NN/O itself/PRP/O noted/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O introduced/VBN/O ``/``/O by/IN/O request/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O Mr./NNP/O Wilder/NNP/B-PERSON introduced/VBD/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O rape/NN/O victims/NNS/O from/IN/O unfounded/JJ/O interrogation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O have/VBP/O grown/VBN/O tired/JJ/O of/IN/O these/DT/O ads/NNS/O and/CC/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O gotten/VBN/O the/DT/O stigma/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O a/DT/O negative/JJ/O campaigner/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON Rozell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O scientist/NN/O at/IN/O Mary/NNP/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG College/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Wilder/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O managed/VBN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O across/RP/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O that/IN/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O say/VB/O anything/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O elected/VBN/O governor/NN/O and/CC/O --/:/O more/RBR/O important/JJ/O --/:/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O put/VB/O the/DT/O onus/NN/O for/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O negative/JJ/O campaigning/NN/O on/IN/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O this/DT/O week/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O devote/VB/O the/DT/O remainder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O season/NN/O to/TO/O positive/JJ/O campaigning/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O truce/NN/O lasted/VBD/O only/RB/O hours/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O night/NN/O ,/,/O television/NN/O stations/NNS/O were/VBD/O carrying/VBG/O new/JJ/O ads/NNS/O featuring/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O raising/VBG/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wilder/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sensitivity/NN/O to/TO/O rape/NN/O victims/NNS/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE :/:/I-GPE
The/DT/O attacks/NNS/O began/VBD/O when/WRB/O Democratic/JJ/O Rep./NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Florio/NNP/I-PERSON aired/VBD/O an/DT/O ad/NN/O featuring/VBG/O a/DT/O drawing/NN/O of/IN/O Pinocchio/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O photograph/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O rival/NN/O ,/,/O Republican/JJ/O Rep./NNP/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Courter/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O Remember/VB/O Pinocchio/NNP/B-PERSON ?/./O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O female/JJ/O voice/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Consider/VB/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Courter/NNP/I-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O then/RB/O this/DT/O commercial/NN/O ,/,/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Squier/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O gets/VBZ/O down/RB/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O mean/JJ/O and/CC/O dirty/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
Pictures/NNS/O of/IN/O rusted/VBN/O oil/NN/O drums/NNS/O swim/VBP/O into/IN/O focus/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O female/JJ/O voice/NN/O purrs/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O That/DT/O hazardous/JJ/O waste/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O property/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O neighbors/NNS/O are/VBP/O suing/VBG/O for/IN/O consumer/NN/O fraud/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O the/DT/O nose/NN/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O face/NN/O grows/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O fraud/NN/O involved/VBN/O ,/,/O cry/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O partisans/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON commercial/NN/O itself/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O so/RB/O the/DT/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON campaign/NN/O has/VBZ/O responded/VBN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O Pinocchio/NNP/B-PERSON commercial/NN/O ,/,/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ailes/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O this/DT/O one/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O screen/NN/O fills/VBZ/O with/IN/O photographs/NNS/O of/IN/O both/DT/O candidates/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Who/WP/O 's/VBZ/O really/RB/O lying/VBG/O ?/./O ''/''/O asks/VBZ/O a/DT/O female/JJ/O voice/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/VBZ/O lying/VBG/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O voice/NN/O goes/VBZ/O on/RP/O ,/,/O because/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O barrel/NN/O on/IN/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O land/NN/O .../:/O contained/VBD/O heating/NN/O oil/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O cleaned/VBN/O up/RP/O and/CC/O caused/VBD/O no/DT/O pollution/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O long/JJ/O nose/NN/O shrinks/VBZ/O while/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O grows/VBZ/O ././O
Who/WP/O 's/VBZ/O telling/VBG/O the/DT/O truth/NN/O ?/./O
Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Salmore/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O scientist/NN/O at/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE Eagleton/NNP/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O another/DT/O example/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O ad/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O true/JJ/O but/CC/O not/RB/O fully/RB/O accurate/JJ/O ././O
Barrels/NNS/O were/VBD/O dumped/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON property/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O complaint/NN/O was/VBD/O made/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O evidence/NN/O the/DT/O barrels/NNS/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O serious/JJ/O threat/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O so/RB/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Salmore/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O devastating/VBG/O ''/''/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O raised/VBD/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O credibility/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O building/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O tradition/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1966/CD/O ,/,/O on/IN/O route/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O re-election/NN/O rout/NN/O of/IN/O Democrat/NNP/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON O'Connor/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG Gov./NNP/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Rockefeller/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE appeared/VBD/O in/IN/O person/NN/O saying/VBG/O ,/,/O ``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O crime/NN/O rates/NNS/O high/JJ/O ,/,/O O'Connor/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O your/PRP$/O man/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
