He/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O report/VB/O to/TO/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Pardus/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Hatch/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 59/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O executive/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O previously/RB/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG Edison/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Carney/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 45/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Hatch/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG Edison/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Robert/NNP/B-PERSON P./NNP/I-PERSON Tassinari/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 63/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-ORG Utilities/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O previously/RB/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
