The/DT/O declaration/NN/O by/IN/O Economy/NNP/B-ORG Minister/NNP/O Nestor/NNP/B-PERSON Rapanelli/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O believed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O such/JJ/O an/DT/O action/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O called/VBN/O for/IN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O Argentine/JJ/O official/NN/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O stature/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Latin/NNP/O American/NNP/O nation/NN/O has/VBZ/O paid/VBN/O very/RB/O little/RB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O debt/NN/O since/IN/O early/JJ/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Argentina/NNP/B-GPE aspires/VBZ/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O a/DT/O reduction/NN/O of/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O external/JJ/O debt/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Rapanelli/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O through/IN/O his/PRP$/O spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O Miguel/NNP/B-PERSON Alurralde/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rapanelli/NNP/B-PERSON met/VBD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O with/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Assistant/NNP/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Mulford/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Argentine/JJ/O negotiator/NN/O Carlos/NNP/B-PERSON Carballo/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE this/DT/O week/NN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O with/IN/O banks/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rapanelli/NNP/B-PERSON recently/RB/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O government/NN/O of/IN/O President/NNP/O Carlos/NNP/B-PERSON Menem/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O took/VBD/O office/NN/O July/NNP/O 8/CD/O ,/,/O feels/VBZ/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O reduction/NN/O of/IN/O principal/NN/O and/CC/O interest/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O way/NN/O the/DT/O debt/NN/O problem/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O solved/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O said/VBD/O before/IN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O wants/VBZ/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O debt/NN/O forgiven/VBN/O ././O
