Lancaster/NNP/B-ORG Colony/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O acquired/VBD/O Reames/NNP/B-ORG Foods/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O cash/NN/O transaction/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Reames/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O maker/NN/O and/CC/O marketer/NN/O of/IN/O frozen/VBN/O noodles/NNS/O and/CC/O pre-cooked/JJ/O pasta/NN/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Clive/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O Lancaster/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
