The/DT/O dollar/NN/O posted/VBD/O gains/NNS/O against/IN/O all/DT/O major/JJ/O currencies/NNS/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O buoyed/VBN/O by/IN/O persistent/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE bond/NN/O issues/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O market/NN/O sentiment/NN/O remains/VBZ/O cautiously/RB/O bearish/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O sluggish/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE economic/JJ/O indicators/NNS/O ,/,/O dealers/NNS/O note/VBP/O that/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O demand/NN/O has/VBZ/O helped/VBN/O underpin/VB/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O kept/VBN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE currency/NN/O from/IN/O plunging/VBG/O below/IN/O key/JJ/O levels/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O dealers/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O locked/VBN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O relatively/RB/O narrow/JJ/O range/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O the/DT/O hefty/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O dollars/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O offset/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O 's/POS/O strength/NN/O ,/,/O resulting/VBG/O in/IN/O a/DT/O stalemate/NN/O ././O
Who/WP/O knows/VBZ/O what/WP/O will/MD/O happen/VB/O down/IN/O the/DT/O road/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O three/CD/O to/TO/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O if/IN/O foreign/JJ/O investment/NN/O starts/VBZ/O to/TO/O erode/VB/O ?/./O ''/''/O
In/IN/O late/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE trading/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O 1.8500/CD/O marks/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 1.8415/CD/O marks/NNS/O late/JJ/O Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O 143.80/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O 142.85/CD/O yen/NNS/O late/JJ/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
Sterling/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.5755/CD/O ,/,/O down/RB/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.5805/CD/O late/JJ/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./JJ/B-GPE currency/NN/O opened/VBD/O for/IN/O trading/NN/O at/IN/O 143.93/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O Wednesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE close/NN/O of/IN/O 143.08/CD/O yen/NNS/O ././O
Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Madison/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O corporate/JJ/O trader/NN/O with/IN/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O traced/VBD/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O solid/JJ/O performance/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O yen/NN/O to/TO/O purchases/NNS/O of/IN/O securities/NNS/O by/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O insurance/NN/O companies/NNS/O and/CC/O trust/NN/O banks/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O sense/NN/O that/IN/O another/DT/O wave/NN/O of/IN/O investment/NN/O is/VBZ/O waiting/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wings/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O contends/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O perception/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O a/DT/O vitriolic/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE response/NN/O to/TO/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG announcement/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O temporarily/RB/O mollified/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O remains/VBZ/O unclear/JJ/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O bond/NN/O issue/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O rolled/VBN/O over/RP/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O traders/NNS/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE say/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O of/IN/O lower/JJR/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O has/VBZ/O spurred/VBN/O dollar/NN/O buying/VBG/O by/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O again/RB/O showed/VBD/O little/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O further/JJ/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O slowing/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE economy/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O traders/NNS/O note/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O its/PRP$/O cues/NNS/O more/RBR/O from/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O than/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE economic/JJ/O indicators/NNS/O ././O
Dealers/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O merely/RB/O drifted/VBD/O lower/RBR/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O release/NN/O Wednesday/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE purchasing/NN/O managers/NNS/O '/POS/O report/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O managers/NNS/O '/POS/O index/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O measures/VBZ/O the/DT/O health/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O manufacturing/VBG/O sector/NN/O ,/,/O stood/VBD/O at/IN/O 47.6/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O October/NNP/O ,/,/O above/IN/O September/NNP/O 's/POS/O 46/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O also/RB/O above/IN/O average/JJ/O forecasts/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O index/NN/O of/IN/O 45.3/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O dealers/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O was/VBD/O pressured/JJ/O slightly/RB/O because/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O market/NN/O participants/NNS/O had/VBD/O boosted/VBN/O their/PRP$/O expectations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O day/NN/O and/CC/O were/VBD/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O an/DT/O index/NN/O above/IN/O 50/CD/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O indicates/VBZ/O an/DT/O expanding/VBG/O manufacturing/NN/O economy/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O most/JJS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O index/NN/O had/VBD/O no/RB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O minimal/JJ/O effect/NN/O on/IN/O trade/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Commodity/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O gold/NN/O for/IN/O current/JJ/O delivery/NN/O settled/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 374.20/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ,/,/O down/IN/O 50/CD/O cents/NNS/O ././O
Estimated/VBN/O volume/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O moderate/JJ/O 3.5/CD/O million/CD/O ounces/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O early/RB/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O gold/NN/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 374.19/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ././O
