Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC is/VBZ/O propelling/VBG/O the/DT/O region/NN/O toward/IN/O economic/JJ/O integration/NN/O ././O
Interviews/NNS/O with/IN/O analysts/NNS/O and/CC/O business/NN/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE suggest/VBP/O that/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O capital/NN/O may/MD/O produce/VB/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O cooperation/NN/O that/IN/O Southeast/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O politicians/NNS/O have/VBP/O pursued/VBN/O in/IN/O fits/NNS/O and/CC/O starts/NNS/O for/IN/O decades/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O power/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O sparking/VBG/O fears/NNS/O of/IN/O domination/NN/O and/CC/O posing/VBG/O fresh/JJ/O policy/NN/O questions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O flow/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O funds/NNS/O has/VBZ/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O motion/NN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O process/NN/O whereby/WRB/O these/DT/O economies/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O knitted/VBN/O together/RP/O by/IN/O the/DT/O great/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O machine/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Hormats/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O tripled/VBN/O their/PRP$/O commitments/NNS/O in/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC to/TO/O $/$/O 5.57/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O Board/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG approved/VBD/O $/$/O 705.6/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O 10/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE investment/NN/O figure/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O commitment/NN/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC also/RB/O includes/VBZ/O steep/JJ/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O assistance/NN/O and/CC/O trade/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O nations/NNS/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O ``/``/O little/JJ/O tigers/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O contributing/VBG/O to/TO/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC 's/POS/I-LOC integration/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O their/PRP$/O influence/NN/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O subordinate/JJ/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O ././O
For/IN/O recipient/JJ/O countries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O investment/NN/O will/MD/O provide/VB/O needed/JJ/O jobs/NNS/O and/CC/O spur/VB/O growth/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Asian/JJ/O nations/NNS/O '/POS/O harsh/JJ/O memories/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O military/JJ/O domination/NN/O by/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O century/NN/O make/VBP/O them/PRP/O fearful/JJ/O of/IN/O falling/VBG/O under/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O economic/JJ/O hegemony/NN/O now/RB/O ././O
Because/IN/O of/IN/O budget/NN/O constraints/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE encourages/VBZ/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O share/VB/O economic/JJ/O burdens/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O resists/VBZ/O yielding/VBG/O political/JJ/O ground/NN/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O swelling/VBG/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O economic/JJ/O evolution/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O Japanese/JJ/O manufacturers/NNS/O concentrated/VBD/O on/IN/O domestic/JJ/O production/NN/O for/IN/O export/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O 1990s/NNS/O ,/,/O spurred/VBN/O by/IN/O rising/VBG/O labor/NN/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O strong/JJ/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O these/DT/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O increasingly/RB/O turn/VB/O themselves/PRP/O into/IN/O multinationals/NNS/O with/IN/O plants/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O capture/VB/O the/DT/O investment/NN/O ,/,/O Southeast/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O nations/NNS/O will/MD/O move/VB/O to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O Japanese/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O nations/NNS/O '/POS/O internal/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O ``/``/O will/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O offend/VB/O their/PRP$/O largest/JJS/O aid/NN/O donor/NN/O ,/,/O largest/JJS/O private/JJ/O investor/NN/O and/CC/O largest/JJS/O lender/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Drobnick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O international/JJ/O business/NN/O and/CC/O research/NN/O program/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Graduate/NNP/B-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Japanese/JJ/O money/NN/O will/MD/O help/VB/O turn/VB/O Southeast/NNP/B-LOC Asia/NNP/I-LOC into/IN/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O cohesive/JJ/O economic/JJ/O region/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O Asian/JJ/O cooperation/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O parallel/VB/O the/DT/O European/NNP/B-ORG Common/NNP/I-ORG Market/NNP/I-ORG approach/NN/O ././O
Rather/RB/O ,/,/O Japanese/JJ/O investment/NN/O will/MD/O spur/VB/O integration/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O sectors/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Kent/NNP/B-PERSON Calder/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O specialist/NN/O in/IN/O East/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O economies/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Woodrow/NNP/I-ORG Wilson/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Internatonal/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/O Princeton/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O electronics/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O company/NN/O might/MD/O make/VB/O television/NN/O picture/NN/O tubes/NNS/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O assemble/VB/O the/DT/O sets/NNS/O in/IN/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O export/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O effect/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O pull/VB/O Asia/NN/B-LOC together/RP/O not/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O common/JJ/O market/NN/O but/CC/O as/IN/O an/DT/O integrated/JJ/O production/NN/O zone/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Mr./NNP/O Hormats/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Countries/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O a/DT/O framework/NN/O for/IN/O closer/JJR/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O ties/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O ministers/NNS/O of/IN/O 12/CD/O Asian/JJ/O and/CC/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC nations/NNS/O will/MD/O meet/VB/O in/IN/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE next/JJ/O week/NN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O global/JJ/O trade/NN/O issues/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O regional/JJ/O matters/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O transportation/NN/O and/CC/O telecommunications/NN/O ././O
Participants/NNS/O will/MD/O include/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O six/CD/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Southeast/NNP/I-ORG Asian/NNP/I-ORG Nations/NNPS/I-ORG --/:/O Thailand/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE Philippines/NNPS/I-GPE and/CC/O Brunei/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE this/DT/O year/NN/O offered/VBD/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O plan/NN/O for/IN/O cooperation/NN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O Pacific/NNP/B-LOC rim/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O speech/NN/O by/IN/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG James/NNP/B-PERSON Baker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O following/VBG/O up/RP/O a/DT/O proposal/NN/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O by/IN/O Australian/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Hawke/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON proposal/NN/O reasserts/VBZ/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O intention/NN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O playing/VBG/O a/DT/O leading/VBG/O political/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O as/IN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O order/NN/O is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O shape/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O regional/JJ/O friends/NNS/O ,/,/O must/MD/O play/VB/O a/DT/O crucial/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O designing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O architecture/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O maintaining/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE influence/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O difficult/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O face/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O dominance/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE not/RB/O only/RB/O outstrips/VBZ/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O investment/NN/O flows/NNS/O but/CC/O also/RB/O outranks/VBZ/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O trade/NN/O with/IN/O most/JJS/O Southeast/JJ/O Asian/JJ/O countries/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O although/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE remains/VBZ/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O trade/NN/O partner/NN/O for/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O government/NN/O ,/,/O now/RB/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O aid/NN/O donor/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O pumping/VBG/O far/RB/O more/JJR/O assistance/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O than/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O ././O
While/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O voice/VBP/O optimism/NN/O about/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O enlarged/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O they/PRP/O also/RB/O convey/VBP/O an/DT/O undertone/NN/O of/IN/O caution/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O understanding/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE that/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O its/PRP$/O functions/NNS/O ''/''/O in/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O says/VBZ/O J./NNP/B-PERSON Michael/NNP/I-PERSON Farren/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O undersecretary/NN/O of/IN/O commerce/NN/O for/IN/O trade/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O they/PRP/O approach/VBP/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O benevolent/JJ/O ,/,/O altruistic/JJ/O attitude/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O net/JJ/O gain/NN/O for/IN/O everyone/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O Asian/JJ/O nations/NNS/O are/VBP/O apprehensive/JJ/O about/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O demand/NN/O that/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE step/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O military/JJ/O spending/NN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE security/NN/O burden/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O further/RBR/O complicated/JJ/O by/IN/O uncertainty/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leases/NNS/O on/IN/O military/JJ/O bases/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE and/CC/O by/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE troop/NN/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Many/JJ/O Asians/NNPS/O regard/VBP/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE presence/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O desirable/JJ/O counterweight/NN/O to/TO/O Japanese/JJ/O influence/NN/O ././O
``/``/O No/DT/O one/NN/O wants/VBZ/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O pick/VB/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O marbles/NNS/O and/CC/O go/VB/O home/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Hormats/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
For/IN/O their/PRP$/O part/NN/O ,/,/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O step/VB/O up/RP/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O decade/NN/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O slow/VB/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O juggernaut/NN/O ././O
