Consolidated/NNP/B-ORG Rail/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O spend/VB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O 1,000/CD/O enclosed/VBN/O railcars/NNS/O for/IN/O transporting/VBG/O autos/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O multilevel/JJ/O railcars/NNS/O ,/,/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O delivery/NN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O Thrall/NNP/B-ORG Manufacturing/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE Heights/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Ill./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O division/NN/O of/IN/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O Duchossois/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Elmhurst/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ill/NNP/B-GPE ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O railroad/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O acquired/VBN/O 850/CD/O such/JJ/O railcars/NNS/O ././O
