Furukawa/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O acquire/VB/O two/CD/O construction/NN/O machinery/NN/O plants/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O sales/NNS/O unit/NN/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE formerly/RB/O belonging/VBG/O to/TO/O Dresser/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O made/VBD/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O locally/RB/O produce/VB/O hydraulically/RB/O operated/VBN/O shovels/NNS/O ././O
Furukawa/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O French/JJ/O and/CC/O German/JJ/O plants/NNS/O together/RB/O will/MD/O total/VB/O about/RB/O 40/CD/O billion/CD/O yen/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 280/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
