SHAREDATA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O amend/VB/O a/DT/O registration/NN/O statement/NN/O filed/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O delete/VB/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O 500,000/CD/O newly/RB/O issued/VBN/O common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Chandler/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O resubmit/VB/O the/DT/O registration/NN/O to/TO/O cover/VB/O only/RB/O the/DT/O 2.3/CD/O million/CD/O warrants/NNS/O ,/,/O each/DT/O exercisable/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O common/JJ/O share/NN/O ././O
