A/DT/O survey/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 12/CD/O district/NN/O banks/NNS/O shows/VBZ/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O sluggish/JJ/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O upward/JJ/O pressures/NNS/O on/IN/O prices/NNS/O have/VBP/O moderated/VBN/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O bring/VB/O down/RB/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O expecting/VBG/O easier/JJR/O credit/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG cut/VBD/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O federal/JJ/O funds/NNS/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O about/RB/O 0.25/CD/O percentage/NN/O point/NN/O to/TO/O 8.75/CD/O %/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O plunge/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O has/VBZ/O shown/VBN/O no/DT/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O movement/NN/O since/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O report/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG found/VBD/O that/IN/O manufacturing/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O particular/JJ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O weak/JJ/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Philadelphia/NNP/I-ORG Fed/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O manufacturing/NN/O activity/NN/O ``/``/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O decline/VB/O ''/''/O for/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O month/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O row/NN/O ././O
Several/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG governors/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O pushing/VBG/O for/IN/O easier/JJR/O credit/NN/O ;/:/O but/CC/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O regional/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG presidents/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O resisting/VBG/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O move/NN/O ././O
