A/DT/O survey/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 12/CD/O district/NN/O banks/NNS/O shows/VBZ/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O sluggish/JJ/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O upward/JJ/O pressures/NNS/O on/IN/O prices/NNS/O have/VBP/O moderated/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O economy/NN/O is/VBZ/O clearly/RB/O slowing/VBG/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Black/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Richmond/NNP/I-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O look/VBP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O as/IN/O posting/VBG/O roughly/RB/O 2.5/CD/O %/NN/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O see/VB/O some/DT/O slowing/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O agrees/VBZ/O Kansas/NNP/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG Fed/NNP/I-ORG President/NNP/O Roger/NNP/B-PERSON Guffey/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O both/DT/O Mr./NNP/O Guffey/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Black/NNP/B-PERSON say/VBP/O the/DT/O slowdown/NN/O so/RB/O far/RB/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O cause/NN/O for/IN/O concern/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O coming/VBG/O closer/RBR/O to/TO/O achieving/VBG/O the/DT/O stated/VBN/O objective/NN/O of/IN/O slowing/VBG/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O point/NN/O where/WRB/O hopefully/RB/O some/DT/O downward/JJ/O trend/NN/O in/IN/O prices/NNS/O will/MD/O occur/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Guffey/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O bring/VB/O down/RP/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O expecting/VBG/O easier/JJR/O credit/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O market/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O expecting/VBG/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O ease/VB/O sooner/RBR/O and/CC/O a/DT/O little/RB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O date/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O global/JJ/O markets/NNS/O for/IN/O Bankers/NNP/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG cut/VBD/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O federal/JJ/O funds/NNS/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O by/IN/O about/RB/O 0.25/CD/O percentage/NN/O point/NN/O to/TO/O 8.75/CD/O %/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O plunge/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O has/VBZ/O shown/VBN/O no/DT/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O movement/NN/O since/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O report/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG found/VBD/O that/IN/O manufacturing/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O particular/JJ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O weak/JJ/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Philadelphia/NNP/I-ORG Fed/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O manufacturing/NN/O activity/NN/O ``/``/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O decline/VB/O ''/''/O for/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O month/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O row/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE district/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O report/NN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O a/DT/O manufacturer/NN/O of/IN/O capital/NN/O goods/NNS/O noted/VBD/O slower/JJR/O orders/NNS/O for/IN/O some/DT/O types/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O defense/NN/O equipment/NN/O ,/,/O petroleum/NN/O equipment/NN/O ,/,/O food/NN/O packaging/NN/O machinery/NN/O and/CC/O material/NN/O handling/NN/O equipment/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O construction/NN/O also/RB/O was/VBD/O described/VBN/O as/IN/O slow/JJ/O in/IN/O most/JJS/O areas/NNS/O ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O slowdown/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O few/JJ/O clear/JJ/O signs/NNS/O that/IN/O growth/NN/O is/VBZ/O coming/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O halt/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O divided/VBN/O over/IN/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O credit/NN/O ././O
Several/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG governors/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O pushing/VBG/O for/IN/O easier/JJR/O credit/NN/O ;/:/O but/CC/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O regional/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG presidents/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O resisting/VBG/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O move/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Black/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O pleased/VBN/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O performance/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O see/VB/O ``/``/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O excesses/NNS/O out/IN/O there/RB/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O tilt/VB/O us/PRP/O into/IN/O recession/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O always/RB/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O of/IN/O recession/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O added/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Guffey/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O ask/VBP/O me/PRP/O to/TO/O put/VB/O a/DT/O percentage/NN/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O think/VB/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O well/RB/O below/IN/O a/DT/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O chance/NN/O ././O
