He/PRP/O said/VBD/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 90/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O funds/NNS/O were/VBD/O placed/VBN/O with/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O institutional/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O went/VBD/O to/TO/O investors/NNS/O from/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ././O
That/DT/O fund/NN/O was/VBD/O put/VBN/O together/RP/O by/IN/O Blackstone/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE investment/NN/O bank/NN/O ././O
Second/JJ/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O channel/VBP/O monthly/JJ/O mortgage/NN/O payments/NNS/O into/IN/O semiannual/JJ/O payments/NNS/O ,/,/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O administrative/JJ/O burden/NN/O on/IN/O investors/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O addressing/VBG/O those/DT/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Maxwell/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O funds/NNS/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O ``/``/O extremely/RB/O attractive/JJ/O to/TO/O Japanese/JJ/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O investors/NNS/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
They/PRP/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O large/JJ/O purchasers/NNS/O of/IN/O Fannie/NNP/B-ORG Mae/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG corporate/JJ/O debt/NN/O ,/,/O buying/VBG/O $/$/O 2.4/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O Fannie/NNP/B-ORG Mae/NNP/I-ORG bonds/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O nine/CD/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O almost/RB/O a/DT/O tenth/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O amount/NN/O issued/VBN/O ././O
