Cathryn/NNP/B-PERSON Rice/NNP/I-PERSON could/MD/O hardly/RB/O believe/VB/O her/PRP$/O eyes/NNS/O ././O
She/PRP/O had/VBD/O seen/VBN/O cheating/NN/O before/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O these/DT/O notes/NNS/O were/VBD/O uncanny/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O student/NN/O surrendered/VBD/O the/DT/O notes/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O without/IN/O a/DT/O protest/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O teacher/NN/O in/IN/O question/NN/O was/VBD/O Nancy/NNP/B-PERSON Yeargin/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O considered/VBN/O by/IN/O many/JJ/O students/NNS/O and/CC/O parents/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O school/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O had/VBD/O gone/VBN/O so/RB/O far/RB/O as/IN/O to/TO/O display/VB/O the/DT/O questions/NNS/O on/IN/O an/DT/O overhead/JJ/O projector/NN/O and/CC/O underline/VB/O the/DT/O answers/NNS/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O fired/VBN/O and/CC/O prosecuted/VBN/O under/IN/O an/DT/O unusual/JJ/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE law/NN/O that/WDT/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O crime/NN/O to/TO/O breach/VB/O test/NN/O security/NN/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O alternative/NN/O was/VBD/O 90/CD/O days/NNS/O in/IN/O jail/NN/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O story/NN/O is/VBZ/O partly/RB/O one/NN/O of/IN/O personal/JJ/O downfall/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O unstinting/JJ/O teacher/NN/O who/WP/O won/VBD/O laurels/NNS/O and/CC/O inspired/VBD/O students/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O she/PRP/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O never/RB/O teach/VB/O again/RB/O ././O
Prosecutors/NNS/O alleged/VBD/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O students/NNS/O '/POS/O scores/NNS/O to/TO/O win/VB/O a/DT/O bonus/NN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O 1984/CD/O Education/NNP/O Improvement/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O says/VBZ/O standardized/JJ/O achievement/NN/O test/NN/O scores/NNS/O are/VBP/O greatly/RB/O inflated/VBN/O because/IN/O teachers/NNS/O often/RB/O ``/``/O teach/VBP/O the/DT/O test/NN/O ''/''/O as/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O ,/,/O although/IN/O most/JJS/O are/VBP/O never/RB/O caught/VBN/O ././O
Evidence/NN/O of/IN/O widespread/JJ/O cheating/NN/O has/VBZ/O surfaced/VBN/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O states/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O or/CC/O so/RB/O ././O
California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O education/NN/O department/NN/O suspects/VBZ/O adult/NN/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O erasures/NNS/O at/IN/O 40/CD/O schools/NNS/O that/WDT/O changed/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O answers/NNS/O to/TO/O right/JJ/O ones/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O statewide/JJ/O test/NN/O ././O
Use/NN/O of/IN/O Scoring/NNP/O High/NNP/O is/VBZ/O widespread/JJ/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O common/JJ/O in/IN/O Greenville/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O school/NN/O district/NN/O ././O
Experts/NNS/O say/VBP/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O another/DT/O state/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O where/WRB/O tests/NNS/O mean/VBP/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE ././O
High/JJ/O test/NN/O scores/NNS/O ,/,/O on/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O hand/NN/O ,/,/O bring/VB/O recognition/NN/O and/CC/O extra/JJ/O money/NN/O --/:/O a/IN/O new/JJ/O computer/NN/O lab/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O school/NN/O ,/,/O grants/NNS/O for/IN/O special/JJ/O projects/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O bonus/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O superintendent/NN/O ././O
Critics/NNS/O say/VBP/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O paying/VBG/O a/DT/O price/NN/O by/IN/O stressing/VBG/O improved/VBN/O test/NN/O scores/NNS/O so/RB/O much/RB/O ././O
Friends/NNPS/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Education/NNP/I-ORG rates/VBZ/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O seven/CD/O states/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O study/NN/O on/IN/O academic/JJ/O cheating/NN/O ././O
Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Sandifer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O testing/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE department/NN/O of/IN/O education/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Cannell/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O allegations/NNS/O of/IN/O cheating/NN/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O purely/RB/O without/IN/O foundation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O unfair/JJ/O inferences/NNS/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE reforms/NNS/O were/VBD/O designed/VBN/O for/IN/O schools/NNS/O like/IN/O Greenville/NNP/B-ORG High/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Ward/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O over/RB/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O becoming/VBG/O the/DT/O school/NN/O 's/POS/O seventh/JJ/O principal/NN/O in/IN/O 15/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O immediate/JJ/O predecessor/NN/O suffered/VBD/O a/DT/O nervous/JJ/O breakdown/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Ward/NNP/B-PERSON resolved/VBD/O to/TO/O clean/VB/O out/RP/O ``/``/O deadwood/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O school/NN/O 's/POS/O faculty/NN/O and/CC/O restore/VB/O safety/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O she/PRP/O also/RB/O had/VBD/O some/DT/O new/JJ/O factors/NNS/O working/VBG/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O behalf/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O was/VBD/O statewide/JJ/O school/NN/O reform/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O raised/VBD/O overall/JJ/O educational/JJ/O funding/NN/O and/CC/O ushered/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O public/JJ/O spirit/NN/O for/IN/O school/NN/O betterment/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O was/VBD/O Nancy/NNP/B-PERSON Yeargin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O Greenville/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O full/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O energy/NN/O and/CC/O ambitions/NNS/O that/IN/O reformers/NNS/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O reward/VB/O ././O
I/PRP/O loved/VBD/O the/DT/O school/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O history/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON she/PRP/O gave/VBD/O up/RP/O ambitions/NNS/O in/IN/O architecture/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O studying/VBG/O to/TO/O become/VB/O a/DT/O teacher/NN/O ././O
Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Beth/NNP/I-PERSON Marchand/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Greenville/NNP/B-GPE 11th/JJ/O grader/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O says/VBZ/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON inspired/VBD/O her/PRP/O to/TO/O go/VB/O into/IN/O education/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O fellow/JJ/O teachers/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O viewed/VBD/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O cocky/JJ/O and/CC/O too/RB/O yielding/JJ/O to/TO/O students/NNS/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Ward/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O often/RB/O defended/VBD/O her/PRP/O to/TO/O colleagues/NNS/O who/WP/O called/VBD/O her/PRP/O a/DT/O grandstander/NN/O ././O
Pressures/NNS/O began/VBD/O to/TO/O build/VB/O ././O
Friends/NNS/O told/VBD/O her/PRP/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O pushing/VBG/O too/RB/O hard/RB/O ././O
Huge/JJ/O gains/NNS/O by/IN/O her/PRP$/O students/NNS/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O 1988/CD/O meant/VBD/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 5,000/CD/O in/IN/O bonuses/NNS/O over/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O --/:/O a/JJ/O meaningful/JJ/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O annual/JJ/O salary/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 23,000/CD/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON admits/VBZ/O she/PRP/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O mistake/NN/O but/CC/O insists/VBZ/O her/PRP$/O motives/NNS/O were/VBD/O correct/JJ/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O also/RB/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O lift/VB/O Greenville/NNP/B-ORG High/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG overall/JJ/O test/NN/O scores/NNS/O ,/,/O usually/RB/O near/IN/O the/DT/O bottom/NN/O of/IN/O 14/CD/O district/NN/O high/JJ/O schools/NNS/O in/IN/O rankings/NNS/O carried/VBN/O annually/RB/O by/IN/O local/JJ/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O desperately/RB/O needed/VBD/O somebody/NN/O who/WP/O showed/VBD/O they/PRP/O cared/VBD/O for/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O who/WP/O loved/VBD/O them/PRP/O ././O
School/NNP/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O prosecutors/NNS/O say/VB/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O lying/VBG/O ././O
They/PRP/O found/VBD/O students/NNS/O in/IN/O an/DT/O advanced/JJ/O class/NN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O earlier/RB/O who/WP/O said/VBD/O she/PRP/O gave/VBD/O them/PRP/O similar/JJ/O help/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O because/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O tried/VBN/O in/IN/O court/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O evidence/NN/O was/VBD/O never/RB/O presented/VBN/O publicly/RB/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON concedes/VBZ/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O went/VBD/O over/RB/O the/DT/O questions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O earlier/JJR/O class/NN/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O all/DT/O ''/''/O students/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Watson/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON never/RB/O complained/VBD/O to/TO/O school/NN/O officials/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O standardized/JJ/O test/NN/O was/VBD/O unfair/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O believe/VBP/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O use/VB/O the/DT/O system/NN/O to/TO/O change/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
She/PRP/O says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O offered/VBD/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O quiet/JJ/O resignation/NN/O and/CC/O thought/VBD/O she/PRP/O could/MD/O help/VB/O save/VB/O her/PRP/O teaching/NN/O certificate/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O ././O
I/PRP/O was/VBD/O dumbfounded/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mrs./NNP/O Ward/NNP/B-PERSON recalls/VBZ/O ././O
Supportive/JJ/O callers/NNS/O decried/VBD/O unfair/JJ/O testing/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O on/IN/O a/DT/O local/JJ/O radio/NN/O talk/NN/O show/NN/O on/IN/O which/WDT/O she/PRP/O appeared/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O show/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O give/VB/O the/DT/O particulars/NNS/O of/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O offense/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O only/RB/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O helped/VBD/O students/NNS/O do/VB/O better/RBR/O on/IN/O the/DT/O test/NN/O ././O
Editorials/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Greenville/NNP/B-GPE newspaper/NN/O allowed/VBD/O that/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O case/NN/O showed/VBD/O how/WRB/O testing/NN/O was/VBD/O being/VBG/O overused/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O radio/NN/O show/NN/O ``/``/O enraged/VBD/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mrs./NNP/O Ward/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Many/JJ/O colleagues/NNS/O are/VBP/O angry/JJ/O at/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Yeargin/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O realized/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O no/RB/O longer/RBR/O be/VB/O possible/JJ/O to/TO/O win/VB/O reinstatement/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O afraid/JJ/O of/IN/O further/JJ/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Ward/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O for/IN/O one/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O relieved/JJ/O ././O
