The/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O 's/POS/O nomination/NN/O of/IN/O Clarence/NNP/B-PERSON Thomas/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O a/DT/O seat/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O here/RB/O received/VBD/O a/DT/O blow/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Bar/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG gave/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON only/RB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O qualified/JJ/O ''/''/O rating/NN/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O ``/``/O well/RB/O qualified/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
People/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Judiciary/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O vote/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O nomination/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O some/DT/O liberal/JJ/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O question/VB/O the/DT/O ABA/NNP/B-ORG rating/NN/O in/IN/O hearings/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O currently/RB/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Equal/NNP/I-ORG Employment/NNP/I-ORG Opportunity/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O would/MD/O add/VB/O another/DT/O conservative/JJ/O voice/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O closely/RB/O divided/VBN/O court/NN/O ././O
Groups/NNS/O have/VBP/O accused/VBN/O him/PRP/O of/IN/O advocating/VBG/O policies/NNS/O that/WDT/O narrowed/VBD/O rights/NNS/O of/IN/O older/JJR/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O of/IN/O ignoring/VBG/O discrimination/NN/O by/IN/O large/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Fourteen/CD/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O jurisdiction/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O EEOC/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O said/VBN/O they/PRP/O oppose/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O nomination/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O serious/JJ/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O judgment/NN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O respect/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O senior/JJ/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O worried/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O ABA/NNP/B-ORG rating/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O pleased/VBN/O the/DT/O ABA/NNP/B-ORG rated/VBD/O him/PRP/O qualified/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Runkel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O department/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/NN/O spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ABA/NNP/B-ORG gives/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O qualified/VBN/O ''/''/O rating/VBG/O to/TO/O nominees/NNS/O it/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O would/MD/O perform/VB/O ``/``/O satisfactorily/RB/O ''/''/O on/IN/O the/DT/O bench/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O contrast/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O '/POS/O association/NN/O gives/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O well/RB/O qualified/VBN/O ''/''/O rating/NN/O to/TO/O those/DT/O ``/``/O regarded/VBN/O as/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O available/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O vacancy/NN/O ././O
