The/DT/O final/JJ/O vote/NN/O came/VBD/O after/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG rejected/VBD/O Republican/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O weaken/VB/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O and/CC/O approved/VBD/O two/CD/O amendments/NNS/O sought/VBN/O by/IN/O organized/VBN/O labor/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O broader/JJR/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG stands/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O would/MD/O apply/VB/O to/TO/O acquisitions/NNS/O involving/VBG/O any/DT/O major/JJ/O airline/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O giving/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG the/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O review/VB/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O transactions/NNS/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O large/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O debt/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O put/VB/O the/DT/O brakes/NNS/O on/IN/O airline/NN/O acquisitions/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O so/RB/O load/VB/O a/DT/O carrier/NN/O up/RP/O with/IN/O debt/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O impede/VB/O safety/NN/O or/CC/O a/DT/O carrier/NN/O 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Rep./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Paul/NNP/I-PERSON Hammerschmidt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Ark/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG Works/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O would/MD/O give/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG up/IN/O to/TO/O 50/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O review/VB/O any/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O airline/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG approved/VBD/O an/DT/O amendment/NN/O offered/VBN/O by/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON DeFazio/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ore./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O criteria/NNS/O ,/,/O also/RB/O require/VB/O the/DT/O department/NN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O airline/NN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O added/VBN/O debt/NN/O incurred/VBN/O were/VBD/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O result/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O 's/POS/O employees/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O their/PRP$/O wages/NNS/O or/CC/O benefits/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Rep./NNP/O Hammerschmidt/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O provision/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O dubbed/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O special/JJ/O interest/NN/O ''/''/O amendment/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O controversial/JJ/O ././O
