Consumer/NN/O confidence/NN/O stayed/VBD/O strong/JJ/O in/IN/O October/NNP/O ,/,/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O unsettling/JJ/O gyrations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O index/NN/O was/VBD/O 116.9/CD/O in/IN/O October/NNP/O 1988/CD/O and/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O year/NN/O has/VBZ/O ranged/VBN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O low/JJ/O of/IN/O 112.9/CD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O of/IN/O 120.7/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O uses/VBZ/O a/DT/O base/NN/O of/IN/O 100/CD/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ././O
An/DT/O equal/JJ/O number/NN/O in/IN/O each/DT/O month/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O employment/NN/O conditions/NNS/O were/VBD/O good/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O consumer/NN/O confidence/NN/O survey/NN/O ,/,/O covering/VBG/O 5,000/CD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE households/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O conducted/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O of/IN/O each/DT/O month/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Conference/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG by/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Family/NNP/I-ORG Opinion/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Toledo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O market/NN/O researcher/NN/O ././O
Home/NN/O purchase/NN/O plans/NNS/O increased/VBD/O to/TO/O 3.3/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O 3.1/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O ././O
