``/``/O Feeding/NNP/O Frenzy/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Henry/NNP/B-ORG Holt/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O 326/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 19.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O a/DT/O highly/RB/O detailed/VBN/O account/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ,/,/O begins/VBZ/O on/IN/O a/DT/O reassuring/JJ/O note/NN/O ././O
Right/RB/O up/IN/O front/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O preface/NN/O ,/,/O co-author/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Sternberg/NNP/I-PERSON gives/VBZ/O us/PRP/O an/DT/O example/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O integrity/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O offered/VBN/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O trip/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Bronx/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O home/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O by/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O principals/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O tells/VBZ/O the/DT/O reader/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O mindful/JJ/O of/IN/O accepting/VBG/O anything/NN/O of/IN/O value/NN/O from/IN/O those/DT/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O writing/VBG/O about/IN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O declined/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O book/NN/O revolves/VBZ/O around/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Mariotta/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O founder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Fred/NNP/B-PERSON Neuberger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O became/VBD/O his/PRP$/O partner/NN/O soon/RB/O after/IN/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O creation/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O started/VBN/O in/IN/O 1965/CD/O ,/,/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O really/RB/O get/VB/O rolling/VBG/O until/IN/O 1975/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Neuberger/NNP/B-PERSON discovered/VBD/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O Section/NN/O 8/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O A/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O minority/NN/O business/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Neuberger/NNP/B-PERSON realized/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O of/IN/O Italian/JJ/O ancestry/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mariotta/NNP/B-PERSON still/RB/O could/MD/O qualify/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O minority/NN/O person/NN/O since/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O born/VBN/O in/IN/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O partners/NNS/O merely/RB/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O falsify/VB/O the/DT/O true/JJ/O ownership/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O corporation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O plugged/VBD/O itself/PRP/O right/RB/O into/IN/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON campaign/NN/O rhetoric/NN/O about/IN/O rebuilding/VBG/O the/DT/B-GPE South/NNP/I-GPE Bronx/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O kept/VBD/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O minority/NN/O --/:/O South/NNP/B-GPE Bronx/NNP/I-GPE angle/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON '80s/CD/O ././O
Starting/VBG/O with/IN/O Congressman/NNP/O Mario/NNP/B-PERSON Biaggi/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O now/RB/O serving/VBG/O a/DT/O jail/NN/O sentence/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O began/VBD/O a/DT/O career/NN/O of/IN/O bribing/VBG/O federal/JJ/O ,/,/O state/NN/O and/CC/O local/JJ/O public/JJ/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O those/DT/O close/JJ/O to/TO/O public/JJ/O officials/NNS/O ,/,/O right/RB/O up/IN/O to/TO/O and/CC/O including/VBG/O E./NNP/B-PERSON Robert/NNP/I-PERSON Wallach/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O close/JJ/O friend/NN/O and/CC/O adviser/NN/O to/TO/O former/JJ/O Attorney/NNP/O General/NNP/O Ed/NNP/B-PERSON Meese/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O use/VB/O old/JJ/O fashioned/VBN/O bribery/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O made/VBD/O ample/JJ/O use/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O modern/JJ/O techniques/NNS/O of/IN/O influence/NN/O peddling/NN/O ,/,/O retaining/VBG/O politically/RB/O connected/VBN/O ``/``/O respectable/JJ/O ''/''/O law/NN/O firms/NNS/O ,/,/O investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O consultants/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON confidant/NN/O Lyn/NNP/B-PERSON Nofzinger/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
When/WRB/O necessary/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O sought/VBD/O and/CC/O received/VBD/O assistance/NN/O from/IN/O organized/VBN/O crime/NN/O ././O
Sometimes/RB/O the/DT/O bribed/VBN/O became/VBD/O partners/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O used/VBD/O the/DT/O merit/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O you/PRP/O were/VBD/O especially/RB/O helpful/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O corrupt/JJ/O scheme/NN/O you/PRP/O received/VBD/O not/RB/O just/RB/O cash/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O bag/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O equity/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O you/PRP/O were/VBD/O not/RB/O an/DT/O effective/JJ/O crook/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O found/VBD/O yourself/PRP/O out/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O cold/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O fate/NN/O that/WDT/O eventually/RB/O befell/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Mariotta/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O semiliterate/JJ/O ``/``/O minority/NN/O ''/''/O person/NN/O ././O
None/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O scams/NNS/O show/VBP/O much/JJ/O ingenuity/NN/O :/:/O Auditors/NNS/O found/VBD/O crookery/NN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O day/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O ././O
Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O scammers/NNS/O simply/RB/O bribed/VBD/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O shut/VB/O up/IN/O ././O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O not/RB/O one/CD/O is/VBZ/O wrestling/VBG/O with/IN/O good/JJ/O and/CC/O evil/JJ/O ,/,/O or/CC/O especially/RB/O intelligent/JJ/O or/CC/O even/RB/O temporarily/RB/O insane/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O one/CD/O character/NN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O somewhat/RB/O interesting/JJ/O was/VBD/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON Louis/NNP/I-PERSON Lobsenz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O pediatrician/NN/O who/WP/O changed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O name/NN/O to/TO/O Rusty/NNP/B-PERSON Kent/NNP/I-PERSON London/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O became/VBD/O a/DT/O master/NN/O gambler/NN/O and/CC/O author/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O book/NN/O on/IN/O blackjack/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O enters/VBZ/O the/DT/O story/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O in/IN/O time/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O arrested/VBN/O ././O
Absorbed/VBN/O in/IN/O doling/VBG/O out/RP/O ``/``/O Feeding/NNP/O Frenzy/NNP/O 's/POS/O ''/''/O tidbits/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O authors/NNS/O gloss/VBP/O over/IN/O the/DT/O root/NN/O causes/NNS/O of/IN/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O namely/RB/O the/DT/O Section/NN/O 8/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O A/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O federal/JJ/O program/NN/O under/IN/O whose/WP$/O auspices/NNS/O the/DT/O scandal/NN/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O do/VBP/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O come/VB/O around/RB/O to/TO/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O courts/NNS/O might/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O end/VB/O ``/``/O rigid/JJ/O affirmative/JJ/O action/NN/O programs/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Programs/NNS/O like/IN/O Section/NN/O 8/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O A/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O are/VBP/O a/DT/O little/RB/O like/IN/O leaving/VBG/O gold/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O street/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O expressing/VBG/O surprise/NN/O when/WRB/O thieves/NNS/O walk/VBP/O by/RP/O to/TO/O scoop/VB/O it/PRP/O up/IN/O ././O
Numerous/JJ/O other/JJ/O scandals/NNS/O ,/,/O among/IN/O them/PRP/O the/DT/O ones/NNS/O at/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O characteristics/NNS/O as/IN/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Why/WRB/O are/VBP/O programs/NNS/O like/IN/O this/DT/O not/RB/O eliminated/VBN/O ?/./O
``/``/O Feeding/NNP/O Frenzy/NNP/O ''/''/O does/VBZ/O provide/VB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O clues/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O and/CC/O around/IN/O all/DT/O levels/NNS/O of/IN/O government/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O groups/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O can/MD/O best/JJS/O be/VB/O described/VBN/O as/IN/O belonging/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O insider/NN/O commercial/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O know/VBP/O that/IN/O whenever/WRB/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O redistributing/VBG/O wealth/NN/O ,/,/O regulating/VBG/O commerce/NN/O or/CC/O maintaining/VBG/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O defense/NN/O establishment/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O big/JJ/O money/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O influencing/VBG/O ,/,/O brokering/VBG/O or/CC/O selling/VBG/O the/DT/O processes/NNS/O and/CC/O decisions/NNS/O of/IN/O government/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O our/PRP$/O version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC 's/POS/I-LOC Nomenklatura/NN/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O absolutely/RB/O no/DT/O wish/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O anything/NN/O change/VB/O ././O
How/WRB/O many/JJ/O government/NN/O programs/NNS/O and/CC/O policies/NNS/O exist/VBP/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O line/VBP/O the/DT/O pockets/NNS/O of/IN/O political/JJ/O insiders/NNS/O ?/./O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O issue/NN/O raised/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ././O
