The/DT/B-ORG British/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Industry/NNP/I-ORG ordered/VBD/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O competitive/JJ/O impact/NN/O of/IN/O Michelin/NNP/B-ORG Tyre/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG planned/VBN/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Tyre/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O department/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O referred/VBD/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Monopolies/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Mergers/NNPS/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O 's/POS/O possible/JJ/O effects/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O for/IN/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O replacement/NN/O tires/NNS/O ././O
Michelin/NNP/B-ORG Tyre/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Michelin/NNP/B-ORG S.A/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Michelin/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O immediately/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O referral/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O noted/VBD/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O from/IN/O BTR/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O already/RB/O been/VBN/O concluded/VBN/O ././O
National/NNP/B-ORG Tyre/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O 420/CD/O branches/NNS/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O 1988/CD/O pretax/NN/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O #/#/O 8.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
