You/PRP/O now/RB/O may/MD/O drop/VB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O read/VB/O the/DT/O text/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O broadcasting/VBG/O to/TO/O those/DT/O 130/CD/O million/CD/O people/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O who/WP/O tune/VBP/O in/RP/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O each/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O can/MD/O even/RB/O take/VB/O notes/NNS/O --/:/O extensive/JJ/O notes/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG folks/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O look/VB/O over/IN/O your/PRP$/O shoulder/NN/O --/:/O about/IN/O what/WP/O you/PRP/O read/VBP/O ././O
You/PRP/O can/MD/O do/VB/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O even/RB/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O a/DT/O reporter/NN/O or/CC/O a/DT/O researcher/NN/O or/CC/O a/DT/O scholar/NN/O or/CC/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
And/CC/O my/PRP$/O newspaper/NN/O can/MD/O print/VB/O the/DT/O text/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O broadcasts/NNS/O ././O
Until/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O as/IN/O an/DT/O ordinary/JJ/O citizen/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O democracy/NN/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O what/WP/O your/PRP$/O government/NN/O was/VBD/O telling/VBG/O your/PRP$/O cousins/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O I/PRP/O apparently/RB/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O print/VB/O hither/RB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O booming/VBG/O to/TO/O yon/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O censorship/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O outrageous/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O stupid/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O theory/NN/O was/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O propaganda/NN/O agency/NN/O and/CC/O this/DT/O government/NN/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O propagandize/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O sounds/VBZ/O neat/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O this/DT/O government/NN/O --/:/O any/DT/O government/NN/O --/:/O propagandizes/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O people/NNS/O every/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
Government/NNP/O press/NN/O releases/NNS/O ,/,/O speeches/NNS/O ,/,/O briefings/NNS/O ,/,/O tours/NNS/O of/IN/O military/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O ,/,/O publications/NNS/O are/VBP/O all/DT/O propaganda/NN/O of/IN/O sorts/NNS/O ././O
Propaganda/NN/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O information/NN/O to/TO/O support/VB/O a/DT/O viewpoint/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O beauty/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O democracy/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O enables/VBZ/O you/PRP/O to/TO/O hear/VB/O or/CC/O read/VB/O every/DT/O viewpoint/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O make/VB/O up/RP/O your/PRP$/O own/JJ/O mind/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O viewing/VBG/O and/CC/O dissemination/NN/O of/IN/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG material/NN/O were/VBD/O especially/RB/O absurd/JJ/O :/:/O An/DT/O agency/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O information/NN/O business/NN/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O being/VBG/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O inform/VB/O ././O
In/IN/O June/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O wrote/VBD/O in/IN/O this/DT/O space/NN/O about/IN/O this/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Assuming/VBG/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O those/DT/O columns/NNS/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O clipped/VBD/O and/CC/O put/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O refrigerator/NN/O door/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 'll/MD/O review/VB/O the/DT/O facts/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Voice/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O government/NN/O agency/NN/O that/WDT/O broadcasts/VBZ/O news/NN/O and/CC/O views/NNS/O --/:/O some/DT/O might/MD/O say/VB/O propaganda/NN/O --/:/O in/IN/O 43/CD/O languages/NNS/O to/TO/O 130/CD/O million/CD/O listeners/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O budget/NN/O $/$/O 184/CD/O million/CD/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O paid/VBN/O for/IN/O by/IN/O you/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O a/DT/O 1948/CD/O law/NN/O barred/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O dissemination/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O that/DT/O material/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O law/NN/O let/VBD/O scholars/NNS/O ,/,/O reporters/NNS/O and/CC/O researchers/NNS/O read/VB/O texts/NNS/O of/IN/O VOA/NNP/B-ORG material/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O at/IN/O VOA/NNP/B-ORG headquarters/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O barred/VBD/O them/PRP/O from/IN/O copying/VBG/O texts/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O that/DT/O word/NN/O ``/``/O dissemination/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
How/WRB/O 's/VBZ/O that/DT/O again/RB/O ?/./O
``/``/O You/PRP/O may/MD/O come/VB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O to/TO/O read/VB/O but/CC/O not/RB/O copy/VB/O either/DT/O manually/RB/O or/CC/O by/IN/O photocopying/VBG/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O explained/VBD/O when/WRB/O I/PRP/O asked/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Nor/CC/O are/VBP/O you/PRP/O free/JJ/O to/TO/O reprint/VB/O such/JJ/O material/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O advised/VBN/O ././O
That/WDT/O sounded/VBD/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O like/IN/O censorship/NN/O ,/,/O so/RB/O after/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O letters/NNS/O and/CC/O conversations/NNS/O that/WDT/O went/VBD/O nowhere/RB/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O sued/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O weeks/NNS/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O lost/VBD/O the/DT/O case/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O district/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Des/NNP/B-GPE Moines/NNP/I-GPE ././O
At/IN/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O way/NN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O reported/VBN/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O indeed/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O was/VBD/O dismissed/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O I/PRP/O --/:/O I/PRP/O like/VBP/O to/TO/O think/VB/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O we/PRP/O ,/,/O all/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O --/:/O won/VBD/O the/DT/O point/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O a/DT/O funny/JJ/O thing/NN/O happened/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O :/:/O The/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG States/NNPS/I-ORG Information/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O runs/VBZ/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O changed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O position/NN/O on/IN/O three/CD/O key/JJ/O points/NNS/O ././O
--/:/O The/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O on/IN/O reflection/NN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O print/VB/O anything/NN/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O get/VB/O my/PRP$/O hands/NNS/O on/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O word/NN/O dissemination/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O decided/VBD/O ,/,/O referred/VBD/O only/RB/O to/TO/O itself/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG officially/RB/O and/CC/O publicly/RB/O declared/VBD/O the/DT/O absolute/JJ/O right/NN/O of/IN/O everyone/NN/O except/IN/O the/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O disseminate/VB/O agency/NN/O program/NN/O materials/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O my/PRP$/O lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O scholarly/JJ/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON McCormick/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Des/NNP/B-GPE Moines/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O memo/NN/O pointing/VBG/O out/RP/O the/DT/O facts/NNS/O and/CC/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O make/VB/O me/PRP/O feel/VB/O good/JJ/O after/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O I/PRP/O had/VBD/O lost/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O court/NN/O noted/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG position/NN/O but/CC/O ,/,/O just/RB/O in/IN/O case/NN/O ,/,/O officially/RB/O found/VBN/O ``/``/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O not/RB/O intend/VB/O to/TO/O preclude/VB/O plaintiffs/NNS/O from/IN/O disseminating/VBG/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG information/NN/O domestically/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
--/:/O The/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O on/IN/O reflection/NN/O ,/,/O anyone/NN/O could/MD/O view/VB/O the/DT/O VOA/NNP/B-ORG materials/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O just/RB/O the/DT/O reporters/NNS/O ,/,/O scholars/NNS/O ,/,/O researchers/NNS/O and/CC/O congressmen/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O mentioned/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O statute/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG publicly/RB/O and/CC/O officially/RB/O stated/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O litigation/NN/O that/IN/O all/DT/O persons/NNS/O are/VBP/O allowed/VBN/O access/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O materials/NNS/O ,/,/O notwithstanding/IN/O the/DT/O statutory/JJ/O designations/NNS/O ,/,/O because/IN/O the/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O determined/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O not/RB/O check/VB/O the/DT/O credentials/NNS/O of/IN/O any/DT/O person/NN/O appearing/VBG/O and/CC/O requesting/VBG/O to/TO/O see/VB/O the/DT/O materials/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O McCormick/NNP/B-PERSON noted/VBD/O ././O
--/:/O And/CC/O the/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O could/MD/O take/VB/O extensive/JJ/O notes/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O agency/NN/O publicly/RB/O and/CC/O officially/RB/O declared/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O that/IN/O persons/NNS/O who/WP/O examine/VBP/O the/DT/O materials/NNS/O may/MD/O make/VB/O notes/NNS/O and/CC/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O position/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O persons/NNS/O may/MD/O not/RB/O take/VB/O verbatim/JJ/O notes/NNS/O ,/,/O no/DT/O one/NN/O will/MD/O check/VB/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O what/WDT/O notes/NNS/O a/DT/O person/NN/O has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O McCormick/NNP/B-PERSON reported/VBD/O ././O
I/PRP/O had/VBD/O sought/VBN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O print/VB/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG material/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O denied/VBN/O me/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O had/VBD/O sought/VBN/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O the/DT/O information/NN/O ,/,/O arguing/VBG/O in/IN/O effect/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O print/VB/O government/NN/O information/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O very/RB/O helpful/JJ/O if/IN/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O information/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O court/NN/O disagreed/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O proscribes/VBZ/O the/DT/O government/NN/O from/IN/O passing/VBG/O laws/NNS/O abridging/VBG/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O free/JJ/O speech/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Judge/NNP/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON O'Brien/NNP/I-PERSON ruled/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O First/NNP/O Amendment/NNP/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O prescribe/VB/O a/DT/O duty/NN/O upon/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O assure/VB/O easy/JJ/O access/NN/O to/TO/O information/NN/O for/IN/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
So/IN/O now/RB/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O is/VBZ/O this/DT/O :/:/O
You/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O read/VB/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG scripts/NNS/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O mind/VB/O traveling/VBG/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE every/DT/O week/NN/O or/CC/O so/RB/O and/CC/O visiting/VBG/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG office/NN/O during/IN/O business/NN/O hours/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O print/VB/O those/DT/O scripts/NNS/O if/IN/O I/PRP/O go/VBP/O there/RB/O and/CC/O laboriously/RB/O --/:/O but/CC/O no/RB/O longer/JJR/O surreptitiously/RB/O --/:/O copy/VBP/O them/PRP/O out/RP/O in/IN/O long/JJ/O hand/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O neither/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O can/MD/O copy/VB/O the/DT/O material/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O Xerox/NNP/B-ORG machine/NN/O or/CC/O have/VB/O it/PRP/O sent/VBN/O to/TO/O us/PRP/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O O'Brien/NNP/B-PERSON ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O easy/JJ/O to/TO/O conclude/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O position/NN/O is/VBZ/O `/``/O inappropriate/JJ/O or/CC/O even/RB/O stupid/JJ/O ,/,/O '/''/O ''/''/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O step/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O suspect/VBP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O try/VB/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O law/NN/O changed/VBD/O ././O
We/PRP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O I/PRP/O assume/VBP/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O in/IN/O this/DT/O with/IN/O me/PRP/O at/IN/O this/DT/O point/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O get/VB/O three/CD/O words/NNS/O --/:/O ``/``/O for/IN/O examination/NN/O only/RB/O ''/''/O --/:/O eliminated/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
Section/NN/O 501/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O United/NNP/O States/NNPS/O Information/NNP/O and/CC/O Educational/NNP/O Exchange/NNP/O Act/NNP/O of/IN/O 1948/CD/O says/VBZ/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG material/NN/O shall/MD/O be/VB/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O certain/JJ/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O but/CC/O now/RB/O ,/,/O thanks/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O new/JJ/O position/NN/O ,/,/O all/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ``/``/O for/IN/O examination/NN/O only/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O those/DT/O words/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O there/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O nice/JJ/O people/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Voice/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O send/VB/O you/PRP/O the/DT/O information/NN/O or/CC/O ,/,/O at/IN/O the/DT/O very/RB/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O let/VB/O you/PRP/O photocopy/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O trivial/JJ/O issue/NN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBD/O .../:/O raised/VBN/O important/JJ/O questions/NNS/O which/WDT/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O answered/VBN/O :/:/O What/WP/O does/VBZ/O USIA/NNP/B-ORG say/VB/O about/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE abroad/RB/O ;/:/O how/WRB/O do/VBP/O we/PRP/O say/VB/O it/PRP/O ;/:/O and/CC/O how/WRB/O can/MD/O American/JJ/O taxpayers/NNS/O get/VB/O the/DT/O answers/NNS/O to/TO/O these/DT/O questions/NNS/O ?/./O ''/''/O a/DT/O man/NN/O wrote/VBD/O me/PRP/O a/DT/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O man/NN/O was/VBD/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Z./NNP/I-PERSON Wick/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O
He/PRP/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O answers/NNS/O then/RB/O ././O
Now/RB/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O some/DT/O ././O
This/DT/O democracy/NN/O is/VBZ/O suddenly/RB/O a/DT/O little/RB/O more/RBR/O democratic/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O feel/VBP/O pretty/RB/O good/JJ/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gartner/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O editor/NN/O and/CC/O co-owner/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Daily/NNP/I-ORG Tribune/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Ames/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O president/NN/O of/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
