The/DT/B-ORG Labor/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG cited/VBD/O USX/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O numerous/JJ/O health/NN/O and/CC/O safety/NN/O violations/NNS/O at/IN/O two/CD/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE plants/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O proposed/VBD/O $/$/O 7.3/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O fines/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O penalty/NN/O ever/RB/O proposed/VBN/O for/IN/O alleged/VBN/O workplace/NN/O violations/NNS/O by/IN/O an/DT/O employer/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O department/NN/O 's/POS/O Occupational/NNP/B-ORG Safety/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG proposed/VBD/O fines/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 6.1/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O alleged/VBN/O violations/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O Fairless/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O steel/NN/O mill/NN/O ;/:/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O record/NN/O for/IN/O proposed/VBN/O penalties/NNS/O at/IN/O any/DT/O single/JJ/O facility/NN/O ././O
Labor/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON Dole/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O The/DT/O magnitude/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O penalties/NNS/O and/CC/O citations/NNS/O is/VBZ/O matched/VBN/O only/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O magnitude/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hazards/NNS/O to/TO/O workers/NNS/O which/WDT/O resulted/VBD/O from/IN/O corporate/JJ/O indifference/NN/O to/TO/O worker/NN/O safety/NN/O and/CC/O health/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O severe/JJ/O cutbacks/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O maintenance/NN/O and/CC/O repair/NN/O programs/NNS/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O those/DT/O hazards/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
OSHA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O there/EX/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O three/CD/O worker/NN/O fatalities/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O 17/CD/O deaths/NNS/O since/IN/O 1972/CD/O ././O
Gerard/NNP/B-PERSON Scannell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O head/NN/O of/IN/O OSHA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O USX/NNP/B-ORG managers/NNS/O have/VBP/O known/VBN/O about/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O safety/NN/O and/CC/O health/NN/O deficiencies/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O plants/NNS/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O yet/RB/O have/VBP/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O necessary/JJ/O action/NN/O to/TO/O counteract/VB/O the/DT/O hazards/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O settlement/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O USX/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O received/VBN/O any/DT/O documents/NNS/O from/IN/O OSHA/NNP/B-ORG regarding/VBG/O the/DT/O penalty/NN/O or/CC/O fine/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Once/IN/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O receive/VB/O very/RB/O serious/JJ/O evaluation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O No/DT/O consideration/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O important/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O health/NN/O and/CC/O safety/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O employees/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
USX/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O cooperating/VBG/O with/IN/O OSHA/NNP/B-ORG since/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O began/VBD/O investigating/VBG/O the/DT/O Clairton/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Fairless/NNP/B-GPE works/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O safety/NN/O problems/NNS/O were/VBD/O identified/VBN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O corrected/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O USX/NNP/B-ORG citations/NNS/O represented/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O sizable/JJ/O enforcement/NN/O action/NN/O taken/VBN/O by/IN/O OSHA/NNP/B-ORG under/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Scannell/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O promised/VBN/O stiffer/JJR/O fines/NNS/O ,/,/O though/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O penalties/NNS/O sought/VBN/O by/IN/O OSHA/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O been/VBN/O rising/VBG/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O even/RB/O before/IN/O he/PRP/O took/VBD/O office/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O big/JJ/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O USX/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O has/VBZ/O proved/VBN/O unwilling/JJ/O to/TO/O devote/VB/O the/DT/O necessary/JJ/O resources/NNS/O and/CC/O manpower/NN/O to/TO/O removing/VBG/O hazards/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O safeguarding/VBG/O safety/NN/O and/CC/O health/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Linda/NNP/B-PERSON Anku/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O OSHA/NNP/B-ORG regional/JJ/O administrator/NN/O in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
USX/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O 15/CD/O working/NN/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O contest/VB/O the/DT/O citations/NNS/O and/CC/O proposed/VBN/O penalties/NNS/O ,/,/O before/IN/O the/DT/O independent/JJ/O Occupational/NNP/B-ORG Safety/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Review/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O contesting/VBG/O the/DT/O fine/NN/O ././O
