For/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O appropriators/NNS/O approved/VBD/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O secondary/JJ/O loan/NN/O guarantees/NNS/O under/IN/O an/DT/O expanded/VBN/O trade/NN/O credit/NN/O insurance/NN/O program/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O total/JJ/O loan/NN/O guarantees/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Overseas/NNP/I-ORG Private/NNP/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O increased/VBN/O by/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O over/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1989/CD/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE package/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O conference/NN/O approved/VBD/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 55/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O direct/JJ/O cash/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O assistance/NN/O as/IN/O well/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O though/IN/O no/DT/O decision/NN/O was/VBD/O made/VBN/O ,/,/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O are/VBP/O committed/VBN/O to/TO/O adding/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O economic/JJ/O support/NN/O funds/NNS/O and/CC/O environmental/JJ/O initiatives/NNS/O sought/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O on/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE contrasts/VBZ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O differences/NNS/O remaining/VBG/O over/IN/O the/DT/O underlying/VBG/O foreign/JJ/O aid/NN/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O provoked/VBN/O veto/NN/O threats/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O is/VBZ/O sharply/RB/O confined/VBN/O under/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O budget/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O pressures/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O a/DT/O factor/NN/O in/IN/O shaping/VBG/O the/DT/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE package/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O while/IN/O more/RBR/O ambitious/JJ/O authorizing/VBG/O legislation/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O pending/VBG/O ,/,/O the/DT/O appropriations/NNS/O bill/NN/O in/IN/O conference/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O decisive/JJ/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE aid/NN/O to/TO/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ././O
To/TO/O accommodate/VB/O the/DT/O additional/JJ/O cash/NN/O assistance/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Appropriations/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG last/JJ/O week/NN/O was/VBD/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O reallocate/VB/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 140/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG ././O
And/CC/O though/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O loan/NN/O guarantees/NNS/O approved/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O is/VBZ/O significant/JJ/O ,/,/O recent/JJ/O experience/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O program/NN/O in/IN/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC indicates/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O take/VB/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O Polish/JJ/O government/NN/O can/MD/O fully/RB/O use/VB/O the/DT/O aid/NN/O effectively/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O on/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE came/VBD/O as/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O separately/RB/O approved/VBD/O $/$/O 220/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O international/JJ/O population/NN/O planning/VBG/O activities/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O 11/CD/O %/NN/O increase/NN/O over/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1989/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O divided/VBN/O over/IN/O whether/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Nations/NNPS/I-ORG Population/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O receive/VB/O any/DT/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O appropriations/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O increase/NN/O is/VBZ/O itself/PRP/O significant/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O area/NN/O of/IN/O common/JJ/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O world/NN/O environment/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O will/MD/O be/VB/O provided/VBN/O in/IN/O development/NN/O assistance/NN/O to/TO/O fund/VB/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O initiatives/NNS/O ,/,/O related/VBN/O both/DT/O to/TO/O global/JJ/O warming/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O plight/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O African/JJ/O elephant/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O sweeping/JJ/O nature/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O draws/VBZ/O a/DT/O variety/NN/O of/IN/O special/JJ/O interest/NN/O amendments/NNS/O ,/,/O running/VBG/O from/IN/O an/DT/O import/NN/O exemption/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE airplane/NN/O museum/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O but/CC/O intriguing/JJ/O struggle/NN/O among/IN/O sugar/NN/O producing/VBG/O nations/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O fate/NN/O of/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O quota/NN/O of/IN/O exports/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O profitable/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O ././O
About/IN/O a/DT/O quarter/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O share/NN/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O been/VBN/O reallocated/VBN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O 23,403/CD/O tons/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O a/DT/O lucrative/JJ/O target/NN/O for/IN/O growers/NNS/O because/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE price/NN/O of/IN/O 18/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O pound/NN/O runs/VBZ/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O nickel/NN/O a/DT/O pound/NN/O above/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O rate/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Jerry/NNP/B-PERSON Lewis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O conservative/JJ/O Californian/NN/O ,/,/O added/VBD/O a/DT/O provision/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O intended/VBN/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O Bolivia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG then/RB/O broadened/VBD/O the/DT/O list/NN/O further/RB/O by/IN/O including/VBG/O all/DT/O countries/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-LOC Caribbean/NNP/I-LOC Basin/NNP/I-LOC initiate/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNP/B-GPE -/:/O backed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O powerful/JJ/O Hawaii/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O Sen./NNP/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Inouye/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Jamaica/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O wary/JJ/O of/IN/O upsetting/VBG/O its/PRP$/O Caribbean/NNP/B-LOC Basin/NNP/I-LOC allies/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O apparently/RB/O instructed/VBN/O its/PRP$/O lobbyist/NN/O to/TO/O abandon/VB/O the/DT/O provision/NN/O initially/RB/O drafted/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gray/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O greater/JJR/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Inouye/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O strong/JJ/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O sugar/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O insert/VB/O a/DT/O claim/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNPS/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O separate/JJ/O floor/NN/O action/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG waived/VBD/O budget/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O and/CC/O gave/VBD/O quick/JJ/O approval/NN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.18/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O supplemental/JJ/O appropriations/NNS/O for/IN/O law/NN/O enforcement/NN/O and/CC/O anti-drug/JJ/O programs/NNS/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O funding/NN/O is/VBZ/O attached/VBN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 27.1/CD/O billion/CD/O transportation/NN/O bill/NN/O that/WDT/O goes/VBZ/O next/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O carries/VBZ/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O proposed/VBN/O permanent/JJ/O smoking/NN/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O virtually/RB/O all/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE domestic/JJ/O airline/NN/O flights/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O leadership/NN/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O move/VB/O the/DT/O compromise/NN/O measure/NN/O promptly/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O as/RB/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O bounce/VB/O bills/NNS/O back/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O most/RBS/O recent/JJ/O example/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 17.3/CD/O billion/CD/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O bill/NN/O funding/VBG/O the/DT/O State/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG departments/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O after/IN/O losing/VBG/O a/DT/O battle/NN/O Tuesday/NNP/O night/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O appropriators/NNS/O from/IN/O both/DT/O houses/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O back/RB/O to/TO/O conference/NN/O ././O
