People/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Judiciary/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O vote/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O nomination/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O some/DT/O liberal/JJ/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O question/VB/O the/DT/O ABA/NNP/B-ORG rating/NN/O in/IN/O hearings/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O currently/RB/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Equal/NNP/I-ORG Employment/NNP/I-ORG Opportunity/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O would/MD/O add/VB/O another/DT/O conservative/JJ/O voice/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O closely/RB/O divided/VBN/O court/NN/O ././O
Groups/NNS/O have/VBP/O accused/VBN/O him/PRP/O of/IN/O advocating/VBG/O policies/NNS/O that/WDT/O narrowed/VBD/O rights/NNS/O of/IN/O older/JJR/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O of/IN/O ignoring/VBG/O discrimination/NN/O by/IN/O large/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O senior/JJ/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O worried/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O ABA/NNP/B-ORG rating/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ABA/NNP/B-ORG gives/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O qualified/VBN/O ''/''/O rating/VBG/O to/TO/O nominees/NNS/O it/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O would/MD/O perform/VB/O ``/``/O satisfactorily/RB/O ''/''/O on/IN/O the/DT/O bench/NN/O ././O
