For/IN/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O T./NNP/B-PERSON Marshall/NNP/I-PERSON Hahn/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O corporate/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON mode/NN/O :/:/O kind/JJ/O and/CC/O gentle/JJ/O ././O
Nekoosa/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O cold/JJ/O shoulder/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O reaction/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O faced/VBN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O 18/CD/O earlier/JJR/O acquisitions/NNS/O ,/,/O all/DT/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O were/VBD/O negotiated/VBN/O behind/IN/O the/DT/O scenes/NNS/O ././O
So/IN/O far/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O entice/VB/O Nekoosa/NNP/B-ORG into/IN/O negotiating/VBG/O a/DT/O friendly/JJ/O surrender/NN/O while/IN/O talking/VBG/O tough/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O aggressively/RB/O completion/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O transaction/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O battle/NN/O opens/VBZ/O up/RP/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O bidding/NN/O war/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O all/DT/O that/DT/O implies/VBZ/O ././O
If/IN/O a/DT/O competitor/NN/O enters/VBZ/O the/DT/O game/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O face/VB/O the/DT/O dilemma/NN/O of/IN/O paying/VBG/O a/DT/O premium/NN/O for/IN/O Nekoosa/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O seeing/VBG/O the/DT/O company/NN/O fall/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O arms/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O rival/NN/O ././O
Given/VBN/O that/DT/O choice/NN/O ,/,/O associates/NNS/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O industry/NN/O observers/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O university/NN/O president/NN/O --/:/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O developed/VBN/O a/DT/O reputation/NN/O for/IN/O not/RB/O overpaying/VBG/O for/IN/O anything/NN/O --/:/O would/MD/O fold/VB/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O consensus/NN/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O insiders/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Associates/NNS/O say/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON picked/VBD/O up/RP/O that/DT/O careful/JJ/O approach/NN/O to/TO/O management/NN/O as/IN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Virginia/NNP/B-ORG Polytechnic/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Assuming/VBG/O that/DT/O post/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O 35/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O managed/VBD/O by/IN/O consensus/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O rule/NN/O in/IN/O universities/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Strother/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O university/NN/O official/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O researching/VBG/O a/DT/O book/NN/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O also/RB/O showed/VBD/O a/DT/O willingness/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O stand/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1970/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O in/RP/O state/NN/O police/NNS/O to/TO/O arrest/VB/O student/NN/O protesters/NNS/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O occupying/VBG/O a/DT/O university/NN/O building/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON rose/VBD/O swiftly/RB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O ranks/NNS/O ,/,/O demonstrating/VBG/O a/DT/O raw/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O knew/VBD/O he/PRP/O possessed/VBD/O early/RB/O on/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O son/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O physicist/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON skipped/VBD/O first/JJ/O grade/NN/O because/IN/O his/PRP$/O reading/NN/O ability/NN/O was/VBD/O so/RB/O far/RB/O above/IN/O his/PRP$/O classmates/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O earned/VBD/O his/PRP$/O doctorate/NN/O in/IN/O nuclear/JJ/O physics/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Massachusetts/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Technology/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON agrees/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O retentive/JJ/O ''/''/O memory/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O friends/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O understatement/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O call/VBP/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O photographic/JJ/O ''/''/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON began/VBD/O selling/VBG/O non-core/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O and/CC/O chemicals/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O even/RB/O sold/VBD/O one/CD/O unit/NN/O that/WDT/O made/VBD/O vinyl/NN/O checkbook/NN/O covers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O formula/NN/O has/VBZ/O paid/VBN/O off/RP/O ,/,/O so/RB/O far/RB/O ././O
Profit/NN/O from/IN/O continuing/VBG/O operations/NNS/O has/VBZ/O soared/VBN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 467/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON attributes/VBZ/O the/DT/O gains/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O philosophy/NN/O of/IN/O concentrating/VBG/O on/IN/O what/WP/O a/DT/O company/NN/O knows/VBZ/O best/JJS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O record/NN/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O diversified/VBN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O all/DT/O that/DT/O impressive/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Nekoosa/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O a/DT/O diversification/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O can/MD/O Mr./NNP/O Hahn/NNP/B-PERSON carry/VB/O it/PRP/O off/IN/O ?/./O
In/IN/O this/DT/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O industry/NN/O observers/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O entering/VBG/O uncharted/JJ/O waters/NNS/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Kathryn/NNP/B-PERSON McAuley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Manhattan/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O greatest/JJS/O acquisition/NN/O challenge/NN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O faced/VBN/O ././O
