A/DT/O man/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O came/VBD/O before/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Agriculture/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG yesterday/NN/O to/TO/O talk/VB/O about/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O intention/NN/O to/TO/O send/VB/O some/DT/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O food/NN/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O with/IN/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O come/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O committee/NN/O 's/POS/O members/NNS/O are/VBP/O worried/VBN/O what/WP/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O free/JJ/O food/NN/O might/MD/O do/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O prospects/NNS/O of/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O own/JJ/O farmers/NNS/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Ackerman/NNP/I-PERSON noted/VBD/O that/IN/O past/JJ/O food/NN/O aid/NN/O had/VBD/O harmed/VBN/O farmers/NNS/O in/IN/O El/NNP/B-GPE Salvador/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Egypt/NNP/B-GPE ././O
However/RB/O well/RB/O intentioned/JJ/O ,/,/O food/NN/O transfers/NNS/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O habit/NN/O of/IN/O growing/VBG/O larger/JJR/O and/CC/O wrecking/VBG/O the/DT/O market/NN/O incentives/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O recipient/JJ/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O own/JJ/O farmers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O First/NNP/O World/NNP/O has/VBZ/O for/IN/O some/DT/O time/NN/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O bad/JJ/O habit/NN/O of/IN/O smothering/VBG/O other/JJ/O people/NNS/O 's/POS/O economies/NNS/O with/IN/O this/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O unfocused/JJ/O kindness/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O constantly/RB/O stressed/VBN/O that/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O farmers/NNS/O mostly/RB/O need/VBP/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O market/NN/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O products/NNS/O ././O
