Lewis/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Veraldi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O father/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O team/NN/O that/WDT/O created/VBD/O the/DT/O highly/RB/O successful/JJ/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG Taurus/NNP/O and/CC/O Mercury/NNP/B-ORG Sable/NNP/O cars/NNS/O ,/,/O retired/VBD/O early/RB/O after/IN/O experiencing/VBG/O recent/JJ/O heart/NN/O problems/NNS/O ././O
Most/RBS/O recently/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Veraldi/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 59/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O product/NN/O and/CC/O manufacturing/VBG/O engineering/NN/O at/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O concept/NN/O 's/POS/O goal/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O eliminate/VB/O bureaucracy/NN/O and/CC/O make/VB/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O product/NN/O development/NN/O more/RBR/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O consumer/NN/O demands/NNS/O ././O
