The/DT/O ruling/NN/O could/MD/O lead/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O cancellation/NN/O of/IN/O huge/JJ/O bank/NN/O debts/NNS/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE Borough/NNP/B-GPE of/IN/I-GPE Hammersmith/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/I-GPE Fulham/NNP/I-GPE ran/VBD/O up/IN/O after/IN/O losing/VBG/O heavily/RB/O on/IN/O swap/NN/O transactions/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O appeal/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O council/NN/O backed/VBD/O the/DT/O audit/NN/O commission/NN/O 's/POS/O stand/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O swap/NN/O transactions/NNS/O are/VBP/O illegal/JJ/O ././O
Other/JJ/O financial/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O involved/VBN/O include/VBP/O Barclays/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Midland/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Security/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Citicorp/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Citibank/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Banks/NNS/O could/MD/O seek/VB/O to/TO/O recover/VB/O payments/NNS/O to/TO/O local/JJ/O authorities/NNS/O in/IN/O instances/NNS/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O banks/NNS/O made/VBD/O net/JJ/O payments/NNS/O to/TO/O councils/NNS/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O various/JJ/O banks/NNS/O involved/VBN/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O during/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O other/JJ/O arrangements/NNS/O with/IN/O local/JJ/O authorities/NNS/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O be/VB/O questionable/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O banks/NNS/O have/VBP/O 28/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O file/VB/O an/DT/O appeal/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O so/RB/O shortly/RB/O ././O
