The/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG issued/VBD/O preliminary/JJ/O rulings/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE anti-dumping/JJ/O act/NN/O that/IN/O imports/NNS/O of/IN/O sweaters/NNS/O from/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Taiwan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE may/MD/O be/VB/O injuring/VBG/O a/DT/O domestic/JJ/O industry/NN/O ././O
Because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O rulings/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O investigate/VB/O complaints/NNS/O by/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sweater/NN/O makers/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O imports/NNS/O are/VBP/O reaching/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE at/IN/O unfairly/RB/O low/JJ/O prices/NNS/O in/IN/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE anti-dumping/JJ/O act/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O law/NN/O defines/VBZ/O unfairly/RB/O low/JJ/O prices/NNS/O as/IN/O ones/NNS/O below/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O production/NN/O or/CC/O below/IN/O prices/NNS/O in/IN/O an/DT/O exporter/NN/O 's/POS/O home/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
ITC/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O final/JJ/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O ITC/NNP/B-ORG rulings/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O come/VB/O until/IN/O next/JJ/O March/NNP/O or/CC/O later/JJ/O ././O
If/IN/O both/DT/O agencies/NNS/O find/VBP/O violations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O law/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O assess/VB/O penalty/NN/O duties/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O imports/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O already/RB/O are/VBP/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O import/NN/O quotas/NNS/O under/IN/O bilateral/JJ/O textile/NN/O and/CC/O apparel/NN/O trade/NN/O agreements/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O another/DT/O action/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O ITC/NNP/B-ORG dismissed/VBD/O anti-dumping/JJ/O act/NN/O complaints/NNS/O filed/VBN/O by/IN/O Du/NNP/B-ORG Pont/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Wilmington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Del./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O against/IN/O imports/NNS/O of/IN/O neoprene/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O type/NN/O of/IN/O synthetic/JJ/O rubber/NN/O ,/,/O from/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
These/DT/O imports/NNS/O totaled/VBD/O about/IN/O $/$/O 17/CD/O million/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
