Carnival/NNP/B-ORG Cruise/NNP/I-ORG Lines/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O potential/JJ/O problems/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O construction/NN/O of/IN/O two/CD/O big/JJ/O cruise/NN/O ships/NNS/O from/IN/O Finland/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O averted/VBN/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Carnival/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O formed/VBN/O in/IN/O Finland/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O will/MD/O carry/VB/O on/IN/O Waertsilae/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O shipbuilding/NN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Carnival/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O 11/CD/O %/NN/O shareholder/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O second/JJ/O ship/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O delivered/VBN/O late/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O or/CC/O early/RB/O in/IN/O 1991/CD/O ././O
Carnival/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O expected/VBN/O that/DT/O ship/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O delivered/VBN/O next/JJ/O fall/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O planned/VBN/O third/JJ/O ship/NN/O still/RB/O may/MD/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Finnish/JJ/O shipyard/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O may/MD/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O elsewhere/RB/O ,/,/O Carnival/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
