Robert/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Bernstein/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O announced/VBD/O his/PRP$/O resignation/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O publishing/NN/O house/NN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O run/VBN/O for/IN/O 23/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O successor/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O named/VBN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O fueled/VBD/O speculation/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bernstein/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O have/VB/O clashed/VBN/O with/IN/O S.I./NNP/B-PERSON Newhouse/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O family/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Advance/NNP/B-ORG Publications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O owns/VBZ/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Abrupt/JJ/O departures/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O unheard/JJ/O of/IN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O Newhouse/NNP/B-PERSON empire/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bernstein/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O departure/NN/O ``/``/O evolved/VBD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O discussions/NNS/O with/IN/O Si/NNP/B-PERSON Newhouse/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O I/PRP/O reached/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O elaborate/VB/O ,/,/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O just/RB/O seemed/VBD/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O thing/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O at/IN/O this/DT/O minute/NN/O ././O
Sometimes/RB/O you/PRP/O just/RB/O go/VBP/O with/IN/O your/PRP$/O gut/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Bernstein/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O stay/VB/O until/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 31/CD/O and/CC/O work/VB/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O successor/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O named/VBN/O soon/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Newhouse/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O insisted/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O unhappy/JJ/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bernstein/NNP/B-PERSON or/CC/O the/DT/O performance/NN/O of/IN/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O trade/NN/O publishing/VBG/O house/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O publisher/NN/O 's/POS/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O volume/NN/O increased/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O during/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bernstein/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O tenure/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O handled/VBN/O the/DT/O extraordinary/JJ/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O quite/RB/O brilliantly/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Newhouse/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O doing/VBG/O well/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O stable/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O got/VBN/O good/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O
Bob/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O an/DT/O agenda/NN/O and/CC/O this/DT/O seemed/VBD/O like/IN/O the/DT/O natural/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Publishing/NN/O officials/NNS/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O while/IN/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O enjoyed/VBN/O spectacular/JJ/O growth/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O smoothly/RB/O integrated/VBN/O many/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bigger/JJR/O ones/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O absorbed/VBN/O so/RB/O easily/RB/O ././O
Crown/NNP/B-ORG Publishing/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O acquired/VBN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O said/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O turning/VBG/O in/RP/O disappointing/JJ/O results/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O report/VB/O its/PRP$/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bernstein/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O succeeded/VBD/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON Cerf/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O only/RB/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG since/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O founded/VBN/O in/IN/O 1925/CD/O ././O
Speculation/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O successor/NN/O centers/VBZ/O on/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O division/NN/O heads/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O house/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O say/VBP/O Anthony/NNP/B-PERSON Cheetham/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O recently/RB/O acquired/VBN/O British/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Century/NNP/B-ORG Hutchinson/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O could/MD/O be/VB/O chosen/VBN/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O speculation/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Newhouse/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O bring/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O powerhouse/NN/O businessman/NN/O or/CC/O another/DT/O Newhouse/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O member/NN/O to/TO/O run/VB/O the/DT/O business/NN/O side/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O combination/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O publishing/NN/O executive/NN/O like/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Gottlieb/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O left/VBD/O Random/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Alfred/NNP/B-ORG A./NNP/I-ORG Knopf/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O run/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Yorker/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O also/RB/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Newhouse/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bernstein/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O tall/JJ/O ,/,/O energetic/JJ/O man/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O widely/RB/O respected/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O publishing/NN/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O spent/VBN/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O time/NN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O on/IN/O human/JJ/O rights/NNS/O issues/NNS/O ././O
