Odyssey/NNP/B-ORG Partners/NNPS/I-ORG Limited/NNP/I-ORG Partnership/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O May/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG Stores/NNPS/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Caldor/NNP/B-ORG discount/NN/O chain/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O plus/CC/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 52/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O debt/NN/O ././O
Caldor/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Norwalk/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O operates/VBZ/O 118/CD/O stores/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Northeast/NN/B-LOC ;/:/O it/PRP/O reported/VBD/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.6/CD/O billion/CD/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
