Some/DT/O Democrats/NNPS/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O warning/VBG/O that/IN/O a/DT/O complicated/JJ/O new/JJ/O funding/NN/O device/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O federal/JJ/O antitrust/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O could/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O further/JJR/O cutbacks/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O regulatory/JJ/O area/NN/O already/RB/O reduced/VBN/O sharply/RB/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O funding/NN/O mechanism/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O received/VBN/O congressional/JJ/O approval/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O signed/VBN/O by/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O would/MD/O affect/VB/O the/DT/O antitrust/JJ/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O overall/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O spending/NN/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG cut/VBD/O by/IN/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O 's/POS/O request/NN/O for/IN/O antitrust/JJ/O enforcement/NN/O for/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O began/VBD/O Oct./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
To/TO/O offset/VB/O the/DT/O reduction/NN/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG approved/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O fee/NN/O that/IN/O investors/NNS/O and/CC/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O each/DT/O time/NN/O they/PRP/O make/VBP/O required/VBN/O filings/NNS/O to/TO/O antitrust/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O about/IN/O mergers/NNS/O ,/,/O acquisitions/NNS/O and/CC/O certain/JJ/O other/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O ././O
Some/RB/O Democrats/NNPS/O ,/,/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Brooks/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O unsuccessfully/RB/O opposed/VBD/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O fear/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O fees/NNS/O may/MD/O not/RB/O fully/RB/O make/VB/O up/RP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O cuts/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expect/VBP/O the/DT/O filing/NN/O fees/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O up/RP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O reductions/NNS/O and/CC/O possibly/RB/O exceed/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O could/MD/O operate/VB/O to/TO/O augment/VB/O our/PRP$/O budget/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Rill/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG antitrust/JJ/O chief/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O measures/NNS/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O both/DT/O houses/NNS/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O request/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 47/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Antitrust/NNP/I-ORG Division/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG budget/NN/O request/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 70/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O about/IN/O $/$/O 34/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O go/VB/O for/IN/O antitrust/JJ/O enforcement/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O by/IN/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O had/VBD/O requested/VBN/O roughly/RB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O amount/NN/O for/IN/O antitrust/JJ/O enforcement/NN/O for/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O as/IN/O was/VBD/O appropriated/VBN/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1989/CD/O ././O
Under/IN/O that/DT/O law/NN/O ,/,/O parties/NNS/O proposing/VBG/O mergers/NNS/O or/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O or/CC/O more/RBR/O must/MD/O notify/VB/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG antitrust/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O before/IN/O completing/VBG/O the/DT/O transactions/NNS/O ././O
Currently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O charges/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O filings/NNS/O ././O
Proponents/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O funding/NN/O arrangement/NN/O predict/VBP/O that/IN/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O recent/JJ/O filing/NN/O levels/NNS/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 2,000/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O fees/NNS/O will/MD/O yield/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O this/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O cuts/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O that/DT/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O cut/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O a/DT/O program/NN/O increase/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 5/CD/O million/CD/O ''/''/O each/DT/O for/IN/O the/DT/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Neal/NNP/B-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O during/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG debate/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Rep./NNP/O Don/NNP/B-PERSON Edwards/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O responded/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O could/MD/O stifle/VB/O merger/NN/O activity/NN/O ,/,/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O fees/NNS/O collected/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O antitrust/JJ/O staffs/NNS/O of/IN/O both/PDT/O the/DT/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG were/VBD/O cut/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O enforcement/NN/O of/IN/O major/JJ/O merger/NN/O cases/NNS/O fell/VBD/O off/RP/O drastically/RB/O during/IN/O that/DT/O period/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Today/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O time/NN/O to/TO/O signal/VB/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O any/DT/O way/NN/O sanctions/VBZ/O the/DT/O dismal/JJ/O state/NN/O into/IN/O which/WDT/O antitrust/JJ/O enforcement/NN/O has/VBZ/O fallen/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Edwards/NNP/B-PERSON argued/VBD/O ././O
Any/DT/O money/NN/O in/IN/O excess/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O collected/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O fees/NNS/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O would/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG at/IN/O large/JJ/O ././O
Corporate/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O fees/NNS/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O inhibit/VB/O many/JJ/O mergers/NNS/O or/CC/O other/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O ././O
Though/IN/O some/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O prospective/JJ/O acquirers/NNS/O were/VBD/O scrambling/VBG/O to/TO/O make/VB/O filings/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O fees/NNS/O take/VBP/O effect/NN/O ,/,/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O noticed/VBN/O any/DT/O surge/NN/O in/IN/O filings/NNS/O ././O
