American/NNP/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Journals/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O president/NN/O ,/,/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON K./NNP/I-PERSON Russell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O will/MD/O resign/VB/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O relocate/NN/O to/TO/O new/JJ/O headquarters/NNS/O in/IN/O Charlotte/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.C/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Ray/NNP/B-PERSON Shaw/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O assume/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Russell/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O responsibilities/NNS/O if/IN/O a/DT/O successor/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O found/VBN/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
