Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O 's/POS/O big/JJ/O securities/NNS/O firms/NNS/O face/VBP/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O their/PRP$/O credit/NN/O ratings/NNS/O lowered/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O reason/NN/O :/:/O Risks/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O firms/NNS/O '/POS/O new/JJ/O ``/``/O merchant/NN/O banking/NN/O ''/''/O activities/NNS/O are/VBP/O rising/VBG/O as/IN/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O traditional/JJ/O business/NN/O erodes/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O downgrading/NN/O of/IN/O debt/NN/O issued/VBN/O by/IN/O CS/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O by/IN/O Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Investors/NNPS/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O coupled/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG announcement/NN/O that/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O under/IN/O review/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O downgrade/NN/O ,/,/O sent/VBD/O shivers/NNS/O through/IN/O the/DT/O brokerage/NN/O community/NN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O biggest/JJS/O firms/NNS/O still/RB/O retain/VB/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O ratings/NNS/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O commercial/JJ/O paper/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O departure/NN/O from/IN/O their/PRP$/O traditional/JJ/O practice/NN/O of/IN/O transferring/VBG/O almost/RB/O all/DT/O financing/VBG/O risks/NNS/O to/TO/O investors/NNS/O ././O
CS/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O benefits/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O backing/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O largest/JJS/O shareholder/NN/O ,/,/O Credit/NNP/B-ORG Suisse/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O third/JJ/O largest/JJS/O bank/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O worried/VBN/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O already/RB/O competes/VBZ/O at/IN/O a/DT/O disadvantage/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O big/JJ/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O rivals/NNS/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O slightly/RB/O lower/JJR/O commercial/JJ/O paper/NN/O rating/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O collapse/NN/O of/IN/O junk/NN/O bond/NN/O prices/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O cancellation/NN/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O junk/NN/O bond/NN/O financings/NNS/O apparently/RB/O have/VBP/O taken/VBN/O their/PRP$/O toll/NN/O on/IN/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O underwriter/NN/O in/IN/O that/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG this/DT/O year/NN/O eliminated/VBD/O its/PRP$/O retail/NN/O or/CC/O individual/JJ/O customer/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O cutting/VBG/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O workforce/NN/O almost/RB/O in/IN/O half/NN/O to/TO/O just/RB/O over/IN/O 5,000/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O moreover/RB/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O grown/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O rate/NN/O as/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O at/IN/O these/DT/O firms/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Drexel/NNP/B-ORG remains/VBZ/O confident/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O future/JJ/O creditworthiness/NN/O ././O
