Metallgesellschaft/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O 51/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Lentjes/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ferdinand/NNP/I-ORG Lentjes/NNP/I-ORG Foundation/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Lentjes/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O product/NN/O mix/NN/O of/IN/O specialized/VBN/O boilers/NNS/O and/CC/O pipes/NNS/O provides/VBZ/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O fit/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O Lurgi/NNP/B-ORG G.m.b/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG H./NN/I-ORG plant/NN/O engineering/VBG/O unit/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O strategy/NN/O to/TO/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O core/NN/O metals/NNS/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O processing/NN/O and/CC/O plant/NN/O engineering/NN/O activities/NNS/O while/IN/O shedding/VBG/O peripheral/JJ/O units/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Lentjes/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O 1988/CD/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O marks/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 434.4/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O current/JJ/O order/NN/O backlog/NN/O of/IN/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O marks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O sale/NN/O comes/VBZ/O in/IN/O place/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O planned/VBN/O initial/JJ/O public/JJ/O offering/NN/O of/IN/O Lentjes/NNP/B-ORG stock/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O to/TO/O market/NN/O before/IN/O year/NN/O end/NN/O apparently/RB/O was/VBD/O upset/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O weakness/NN/O of/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE share/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
