The/DT/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O Younkers/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O after/IN/O failing/VBG/O to/TO/O find/VB/O a/DT/O buyer/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O of/IN/O Midwestern/JJ/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O sell/VB/O a/DT/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O to/TO/O management/NN/O and/CC/O take/VB/O other/JJ/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O retailing/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Equitable/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O a/DT/O buyer/NN/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O considers/VBZ/O ``/``/O fair/JJ/O value/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O Younkers/NNP/B-ORG because/IN/O of/IN/O recent/JJ/O turmoil/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bond/NN/O and/CC/O stock/NN/O markets/NNS/O and/CC/O in/IN/O retailing/NN/O ././O
Younkers/NNS/B-ORG rang/VBD/O up/RP/O sales/NNS/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O of/IN/O $/$/O 313/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O operates/VBZ/O stores/NNS/O mostly/RB/O in/IN/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Nebraska/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Younkers/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O chain/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Fred/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Hubbell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Equitable/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Equitable/NNP/B-ORG hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O eventually/RB/O reduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Younkers/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
