But/CC/O the/DT/O 1989/CD/O fall/NN/O total/NN/O of/IN/O 80/CD/O ,/,/O while/IN/O well/RB/O below/IN/O 1988/CD/O activity/NN/O ,/,/O shows/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O steady/JJ/O ratcheting/VBG/O up/IN/O in/IN/O citizen/NN/O referenda/NN/O and/CC/O initiatives/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Patrick/NNP/B-PERSON McGuigan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O Family/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/I-ORG Law/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Democracy/NNP/I-ORG Report/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Ballot/NN/O questions/NNS/O range/VBP/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Maine/NNP/B-GPE initiative/NN/O on/IN/O banning/VBG/O Cruise/NN/O missiles/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O referendum/NN/O on/IN/O increasing/VBG/O the/DT/O North/NNP/B-GPE Dakota/NNP/I-GPE income/NN/O tax/NN/O ././O
Ballot/NN/O watchers/NNS/O say/VBP/O attention/NN/O already/RB/O is/VBZ/O focused/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O 1990/CD/O elections/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O two/CD/O petition/NN/O drives/NNS/O for/IN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O election/NN/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O essentially/RB/O finished/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Schmidt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O author/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Citizen/NNP/O Lawmakers/NNPS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O McGuigan/NNP/B-PERSON cites/VBZ/O three/CD/O completed/VBN/O efforts/NNS/O in/IN/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Hot/JJ/O ballot/NN/O topics/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O and/CC/O insurance/NN/O reform/NN/O ././O
Taking/VBG/O a/DT/O cue/NN/O from/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O more/JJR/O politicians/NNS/O will/MD/O launch/VB/O their/PRP$/O campaigns/NNS/O by/IN/O backing/VBG/O initiatives/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Magleby/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Brigham/NNP/B-ORG Young/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ././O
PHOTOGRAPH/NN/O COLLECTING/NN/O gains/VBZ/O new/JJ/O stature/NN/O as/IN/O prices/NNS/O rise/VBP/O ././O
Price/NN/O records/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O set/NN/O at/IN/O auctions/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O works/NNS/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O exceeding/VBG/O price/NN/O estimates/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O prices/NNS/O reflect/VBP/O development/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O market/NN/O structure/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O such/JJ/O variables/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O prints/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O finally/RB/O some/DT/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O sense/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Corporations/NNS/O and/CC/O museums/NNS/O are/VBP/O among/IN/O the/DT/O serious/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O ,/,/O giving/VBG/O greater/JJR/O market/NN/O stability/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Persky/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Photograph/NNP/I-ORG Collector/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O I/PRP/O see/VBP/O prints/NNS/O going/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O institutions/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O know/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O come/VB/O back/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Most/JJS/O in/IN/O demand/NN/O :/:/O classic/JJ/O photographs/NNS/O by/IN/O masters/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Stieglitz/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Man/NNP/B-PERSON Ray/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O much/RB/O contemporary/JJ/O work/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O fetching/VBG/O ``/``/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O deal/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Miles/NNP/B-PERSON Barth/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Photography/NNP/I-ORG ././O
DIALING/VBG/O 900/CD/O brings/VBZ/O callers/NNS/O a/DT/O growing/VBG/O number/NN/O of/IN/O services/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O service/NN/O --/:/O which/WDT/O costs/VBZ/O the/DT/O caller/NN/O from/IN/O 30/CD/O cents/NNS/O to/TO/O $/$/O 25/CD/O a/DT/O minute/NN/O --/:/O currently/RB/O is/VBZ/O dominated/VBN/O by/IN/O celebrity/NN/O chatter/NN/O ,/,/O horoscopes/NNS/O and/CC/O romance/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O more/RBR/O serious/JJ/O applications/NNS/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wings/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O future/JJ/O growth/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O ././O
Colleges/NNS/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O eyeing/VBG/O registration/NN/O through/IN/O 900/CD/O service/NN/O ././O
Charities/NNS/O test/VBP/O the/DT/O waters/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O face/VBP/O legal/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O to/TO/O electronic/JJ/O fund/NN/O raising/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O thing/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O really/RB/O break/VB/O this/DT/O market/NN/O right/RB/O open/JJ/O is/VBZ/O merchandising/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Ms./NNP/O West/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 800/CD/O service/NN/O will/MD/O ``/``/O migrate/VB/O to/TO/O 900/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O predicts/VBZ/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Lawless/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O US/NNP/B-ORG Sprint/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 900/CD/O product/NN/O ././O
FAMILY/NN/O PETS/NNS/O are/VBP/O improving/VBG/O recovery/NN/O rates/NNS/O of/IN/O patients/NNS/O at/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Hospital/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Milwaukee/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Patients/NNS/O who/WP/O receive/VBP/O canine/JJ/O or/CC/O feline/JJ/O visitors/NNS/O are/VBP/O found/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O lower/JJR/O blood/NN/O pressure/NN/O and/CC/O improved/VBN/O appetite/NN/O and/CC/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O receptive/JJ/O to/TO/O therapy/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Ann/NNP/I-PERSON O'Loughlin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O program/NN/O coordinator/NN/O ././O
TIRED/JJ/O OF/IN/O TRIMMING/VBG/O ?/./O
MEDICINE/NNP/O TRANSPLANT/NNP/O :/:/O Growth/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O trade/NN/O and/CC/O travel/NN/O prompts/VBZ/O Beth/NNP/B-ORG Israel/NNP/I-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O bilingual/JJ/O medical/JJ/O practice/NN/O ././O
DIAPER/NN/O SERVICES/NNS/O make/VBP/O a/DT/O comeback/NN/O amid/IN/O growing/VBG/O environmental/JJ/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
Concerned/VBN/O about/IN/O shrinking/VBG/O landfills/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O safety/NN/O of/IN/O chemicals/NNS/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O super-absorbent/JJ/O disposables/NNS/O ,/,/O parents/NNS/O are/VBP/O returning/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O cloth/NN/O diaper/NN/O ././O
Tiny/NNP/B-ORG Tots/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Campbell/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O up/IN/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O gaining/VBG/O 1,200/CD/O new/JJ/O customers/NNS/O each/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Mogavero/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Care/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Piscataway/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O Syracuse/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O DyDee/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG new/JJ/O marketing/NN/O push/NN/O stresses/VBZ/O environmental/JJ/O awareness/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Diaper/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O since/IN/O January/NNP/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O gotten/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 672/CD/O inquiries/NNS/O from/IN/O people/NNS/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O starting/VBG/O diaper/NN/O services/NNS/O ././O
Elisa/NNP/B-PERSON Hollis/NNP/I-PERSON launched/VBD/O a/DT/O diaper/NN/O service/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O because/IN/O State/NNP/B-GPE College/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O she/PRP/O lives/VBZ/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O one/CD/O ././O
Diaper/NN/O shortages/NNS/O this/DT/O summer/NN/O limited/VBD/O growth/NN/O at/IN/O Stork/NNP/B-ORG Diaper/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Springfield/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O up/IN/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O
Also/RB/O spurring/VBG/O the/DT/O move/NN/O to/TO/O cloth/NN/O :/:/O diaper/NN/O covers/NNS/O with/IN/O Velcro/NN/O fasteners/NNS/O that/WDT/O eliminate/VBP/O the/DT/O need/NN/O for/IN/O safety/NN/O pins/NNS/O ././O
BRIEFS/NNPS/O :/:/O
Only/RB/O 57.6/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/O Yorkers/NNPS/O watch/VBP/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O news/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lowest/JJS/O viewership/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O study/NN/O by/IN/O Impact/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Columbus/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE .../:/O ././O
