Millicom/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O a/DT/O license/NN/O to/TO/O introduce/VB/O and/CC/O operate/VB/O a/DT/O cellular/JJ/O mobile/JJ/O telephone/NN/O system/NN/O in/IN/O Pakistan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
A/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O for/IN/O Millicom/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O telecommunications/NNS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O she/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O ././O
Millicom/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O build/VB/O and/CC/O operate/VB/O the/DT/O system/NN/O in/IN/O Pakistan/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O Comvik/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG AB/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Kinnevik/NNP/B-ORG group/NN/O of/IN/O Sweden/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Arfeen/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Pakistan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
