What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O name/NN/O ?/./O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Bullock/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O senior/JJ/O partner/NN/O of/IN/O Deloitte/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O ``/``/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O start/VB/O these/DT/O proceedings/NNS/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O taken/VBN/O lightly/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Bullock/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O firm/NN/O has/VBZ/O used/VBN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O ``/``/O Deloitte/NNP/B-ORG ''/''/O since/IN/O 1845/CD/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Burton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O accounting/NN/O professor/NN/O at/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Graduate/NNP/B-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O ``/``/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O emotion/NN/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O accounting/NN/O firm/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O history/NN/O and/CC/O with/IN/O roots/NNS/O in/IN/O England/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O accounting/NN/O predates/VBZ/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
Although/IN/O accountants/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O noted/VBN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O being/VBG/O deeply/RB/O emotional/JJ/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O really/RB/O hold/VBP/O it/PRP/O all/DT/O in/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Burton/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O chief/JJ/O accountant/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O merger/NN/O is/VBZ/O proceeding/VBG/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O except/IN/O as/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O withdrawal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Deloitte/NNP/B-ORG U.K./NNP/B-GPE firm/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
In/IN/O England/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O this/DT/O would/MD/O mean/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O Deloitte/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O lose/VB/O revenue/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O audit/NN/O of/IN/O GM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Vauxhill/NNP/B-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Harris/NNP/B-PERSON Amhowitz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O of/IN/O Coopers/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O Coopers/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O was/VBD/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O litigation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O declined/VBD/O further/JJ/O comment/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O that/IN/O Coopers/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O use/VB/O in/IN/O England/NNP/B-GPE if/IN/O Deloitte/NNP/B-ORG UK/NNP/B-GPE won/VBD/O its/PRP$/O litigation/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O its/PRP$/O name/NN/O ././O
