Just/RB/O because/IN/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O High/NNP/O School/NNP/O did/VBD/O nothing/NN/O when/WRB/O its/PRP$/O valuable/JJ/O 1930s/NNS/O mural/NN/O was/VBD/O thrown/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O trash/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O the/DT/O city/NN/O no/RB/O longer/RBR/O owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O work/NN/O of/IN/O art/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O ruled/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O mural/NN/O ,/,/O now/RB/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O million/CD/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O appraisers/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O tossed/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O trash/NN/O heap/NN/O in/IN/O 1971/CD/O by/IN/O workers/NNS/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O renovating/VBG/O the/DT/O building/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O discarded/VBN/O mural/NN/O was/VBD/O found/VBN/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O school/NN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O concerned/JJ/O Stamford/NNP/B-ORG graduate/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O eventually/RB/O was/VBD/O turned/VBN/O over/RP/O to/TO/O Hiram/NNP/B-PERSON Hoelzer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O professional/JJ/O art/NN/O restorer/NN/O ././O
Throughout/IN/O the/DT/O 1970s/NNS/O ,/,/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE school/NN/O and/CC/O city/NN/O officials/NNS/O made/VBD/O no/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O locate/VB/O the/DT/O mural/NN/O ././O
Apparently/RB/O the/DT/O officials/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O know/VB/O the/DT/O mural/NN/O was/VBD/O missing/VBG/O until/IN/O 1980/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O researcher/NN/O found/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O painting/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hoelzer/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O studio/NN/O and/CC/O questioned/VBD/O school/NN/O officials/NNS/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
In/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O thanked/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Hoelzer/NNP/B-PERSON for/IN/O taking/VBG/O care/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mural/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O demanded/VBD/O he/PRP/O return/VB/O it/PRP/O as/RB/O soon/RB/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hoelzer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O sued/VBD/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O claiming/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O had/VBD/O abandoned/VBN/O the/DT/O artwork/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O waited/VBN/O too/RB/O long/JJ/O to/TO/O reclaim/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O Judge/NNP/O Louis/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Stanton/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O faulted/VBN/O for/IN/O waiting/VBG/O too/RB/O long/RB/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O realize/VB/O until/IN/O 1986/CD/O that/DT/O its/PRP$/O ownership/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O painting/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O dispute/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O also/RB/O ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O painting/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O abandoned/VBN/O because/IN/O officials/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O intend/VB/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O thrown/VBN/O away/RP/O and/CC/O were/VBD/O unaware/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O workmen/NNS/O had/VBD/O discarded/VBN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hoelzer/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O return/VB/O phone/NN/O calls/NNS/O seeking/VBG/O comment/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O 's/POS/O decision/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O ordered/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O hearing/NN/O be/VB/O held/VBN/O Nov./NNP/O 17/CD/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O the/DT/O city/NN/O should/MD/O pay/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Hoelzer/NNP/B-PERSON for/IN/O his/PRP$/O services/NNS/O ././O
Mary/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Sommer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O corporate/JJ/O counsel/NN/O for/IN/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O city/NN/O has/VBZ/O discussed/VBN/O several/JJ/O possible/JJ/O plans/NNS/O for/IN/O displaying/VBG/O the/DT/O mural/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O portrays/VBZ/O various/JJ/O scenes/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Great/NNP/O Depression/NNP/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O mural/NN/O ``/``/O preserves/VBZ/O an/DT/O era/NN/O in/IN/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O country/NN/O when/WRB/O this/DT/O type/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O was/VBD/O being/VBG/O done/VBN/O ././O
