The/DT/O Members/NNS/O know/VBP/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O doing/VBG/O wrong/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O need/MD/O help/NN/O to/TO/O restrain/VB/O their/PRP$/O darker/JJR/O compulsions/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O turning/VBG/O himself/PRP/O in/RP/O ././O
We/PRP/O can/MD/O applaud/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Pryor/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O moment/NN/O of/IN/O epiphany/NN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O understand/VBP/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O confreres/FW/O need/VBP/O restraint/NN/O lest/IN/O they/PRP/O kill/VBP/O again/RB/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O have/VB/O 20/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O reject/VB/O the/DT/O package/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O majority/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O then/RB/O a/DT/O President/NNP/O could/MD/O veto/VB/O that/DT/O rejection/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O proposal/NN/O would/MD/O restore/VB/O some/DT/O discipline/NN/O erased/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O process/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O 1974/CD/O Budget/NNP/O ``/``/O Reform/NNP/O ''/''/O Act/NNP/O ././O
Presidents/NNP/B-PERSON Kennedy/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON were/VBD/O both/DT/O big/JJ/O users/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O impoundment/NN/O power/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG saw/VBD/O its/PRP$/O chance/NN/O against/IN/O a/DT/O weakened/VBN/O President/NNP/O Nixon/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O stripped/VBD/O it/PRP/O away/RB/O ././O
Today/NN/O a/DT/O President/NNP/O can/MD/O still/RB/O send/VB/O up/RP/O spending/NN/O rescissions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O meaningless/JJ/O unless/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O guilty/JJ/O conscience/NN/O and/CC/O changes/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O mind/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O like/IN/O asking/VBG/O foxes/NNS/O to/TO/O feel/VB/O remorse/NN/O about/IN/O chickens/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O naturally/RB/O rescissions/NNS/O are/VBP/O almost/RB/O never/RB/O approved/VBN/O ././O
Senator/NNP/O Coats/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O would/MD/O let/VB/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O spending/NN/O cuts/NNS/O take/VB/O place/NN/O automatically/RB/O unless/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG acts/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Coats/NNP/B-PERSON plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O his/PRP$/O proposal/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O amendment/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O debt/NN/O limit/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O endorsed/VBN/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 50/CD/O sitting/VBG/O Senators/NNS/O have/VBP/O voted/VBN/O to/TO/O support/VB/O enhanced/JJ/O rescission/NN/O authority/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O told/VBN/O Senator/NNP/O Pryor/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O a/DT/O co-sponsor/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O are/VBP/O serious/JJ/O about/IN/O kicking/VBG/O their/PRP$/O compulsions/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O sign/VB/O up/RP/O ././O
