Until/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O BNL/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O top/JJ/O managers/NNS/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O directors/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O appointed/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG decree/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O under/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O proposed/VBN/O statutes/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O assembly/NN/O of/IN/O shareholders/NNS/O must/MD/O approve/VB/O board/NN/O members/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O director/NN/O general/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O also/RB/O sit/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ,/,/O still/RB/O would/MD/O be/VB/O appointed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG ././O
BNL/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Italian/NNP/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O rocked/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O disclosure/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE branch/NN/O extended/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O unauthorized/JJ/O credits/NNS/O to/TO/O Iraq/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O related/VBN/O move/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O also/RB/O proposed/VBD/O that/IN/O board/NN/O representation/NN/O be/VB/O linked/VBN/O more/RBR/O closely/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O shareholding/NN/O structure/NN/O ././O
BNL/NNP/B-ORG called/VBD/O a/DT/O shareholders/NNS/O '/POS/O assembly/NN/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O December/NNP/O to/TO/O vote/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O proposals/NNS/O ././O
BNL/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O about/RB/O 75,000/CD/O nonvoting/JJ/O shares/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O listed/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Milan/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O shares/NNS/O were/VBD/O suspended/VBN/O from/IN/O trading/NN/O following/VBG/O disclosure/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE scandal/NN/O ;/:/O Consob/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O exchange/NN/O regulatory/JJ/O body/NN/O ,/,/O reportedly/RB/O will/MD/O decide/VB/O soon/RB/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O end/VB/O the/DT/O trading/NN/O suspension/NN/O ././O
