The/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O investment/NN/O trust/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O leased/VBD/O the/DT/O three/CD/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE facilities/NNS/O to/TO/O National/NNP/B-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Care/NNP/I-ORG Affiliates/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Buffalo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Health/NNP/B-ORG Care/NNP/I-ORG Property/NNP/I-ORG holds/VBZ/O an/DT/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O 139/CD/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O 30/CD/O states/NNS/O ././O
