``/``/O Politics/NNS/O has/VBZ/O essentially/RB/O put/VBN/O up/RP/O a/DT/O roadblock/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O finding/VBG/O sites/NNS/O for/IN/O new/JJ/O federal/JJ/O prisons/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O at/IN/O a/DT/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O called/VBN/O to/TO/O report/VB/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O ``/``/O emergency/NN/O assistance/NN/O program/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O the/DT/O capital/NN/O ././O
Without/IN/O more/JJR/O space/NN/O to/TO/O incarcerate/VB/O convicted/VBN/O criminals/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O will/MD/O not/RB/O win/VB/O the/DT/O war/NN/O on/IN/O drugs/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON declared/VBD/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O make/VB/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE a/DT/O ``/``/O test/NN/O case/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O how/WRB/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O would/MD/O aid/VB/O cities/NNS/O afflicted/VBN/O by/IN/O heavy/JJ/O drug/NN/O trafficking/NN/O and/CC/O violence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O drug/NN/O czar/NN/O claimed/VBD/O that/IN/O enforcement/NN/O efforts/NNS/O are/VBP/O working/VBG/O here/RB/O ,/,/O ``/``/O albeit/IN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O slower/JJR/O and/CC/O more/RBR/O halting/JJ/O pace/NN/O than/IN/O we/PRP/O would/MD/O like/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O prisons/NNS/O are/VBP/O too/RB/O crowded/JJ/O ././O
Drugs/NNS/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O openly/RB/O around/IN/O schools/NNS/O ,/,/O parks/NNS/O and/CC/O housing/NN/O projects/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O name/VB/O the/DT/O area/NN/O officials/NNS/O who/WP/O he/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O have/VBP/O impeded/VBN/O plans/NNS/O for/IN/O building/VBG/O more/JJR/O federal/JJ/O prisons/NNS/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O problem/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O other/JJ/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O criticized/VBN/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE Gov./NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Schaefer/NNP/I-PERSON for/IN/O blocking/VBG/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O possible/JJ/O sites/NNS/O in/IN/O that/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE Mayor/NNP/O Marion/NNP/B-PERSON Barry/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O delayed/VBN/O consideration/NN/O of/IN/O sites/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O ././O
Referring/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O claim/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O would/MD/O provide/VB/O $/$/O 97/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O emergency/NN/O federal/JJ/O support/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Thompson/NNP/B-PERSON wrote/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Our/PRP$/O analysis/NN/O was/VBD/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O even/RB/O come/VB/O close/JJ/O to/TO/O documenting/VBG/O that/DT/O figure/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Of/IN/O his/PRP$/O successes/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON stressed/VBD/O that/IN/O existing/VBG/O federal/JJ/O prisons/NNS/O have/VBP/O taken/VBN/O custody/NN/O of/IN/O 375/CD/O local/JJ/O inmates/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O lent/VBN/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O 10/CD/O prosecutors/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Investigation/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O provided/VBN/O crime/NN/O laboratory/NN/O facilities/NNS/O and/CC/O training/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ././O
