Mr./NNP/O Gaubert/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O majority/NN/O stockholder/NN/O of/IN/O Independent/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O relinquished/VBN/O his/PRP$/O control/NN/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O '/POS/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O their/PRP$/O inquiry/NN/O into/IN/O his/PRP$/O activities/NNS/O at/IN/O another/DT/O savings/NN/O and/CC/O loan/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gaubert/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O suit/NN/O to/TO/O recover/VB/O his/PRP$/O damages/NNS/O was/VBD/O dismissed/VBN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O by/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/O Judge/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Maloney/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE under/IN/O the/DT/O Federal/NNP/O Tort/NNP/O Claims/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O offers/VBZ/O broad/JJ/O protection/NN/O for/IN/O actions/NNS/O by/IN/O federal/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O and/CC/O employees/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gaubert/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O Abbe/NNP/B-PERSON David/NNP/I-PERSON Lowell/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O impact/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O on/IN/O other/JJ/O cases/NNS/O involving/VBG/O thrift/NN/O takeovers/NNS/O will/MD/O depend/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O degree/NN/O of/IN/O similarity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O facts/NNS/O ././O
MAITRE'D/NNP/O CLAIMS/VBZ/O in/IN/O suit/NN/O that/IN/O restaurant/NN/O fired/VBD/O her/PRP/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O pregnant/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O suit/NN/O alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Levine/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O fired/VBN/O after/IN/O she/PRP/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O a/DT/O lower/JJR/O paying/VBG/O ,/,/O less/RBR/O visible/JJ/O job/NN/O upon/IN/O reaching/VBG/O her/PRP/O sixth/JJ/O month/NN/O of/IN/O pregnancy/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Levine/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O her/PRP$/O employer/NN/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O pregnant/JJ/O in/IN/O February/NNP/O ;/:/O a/DT/O month/NN/O later/RBR/O ,/,/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O restaurant/NN/O manager/NN/O told/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Levine/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O she/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O demoted/VBN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O assistant/NN/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O felt/VBD/O customers/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O uncomfortable/JJ/O with/IN/O a/DT/O pregnant/JJ/O maitre/NNP/O 'd/NNP/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Moss/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Levine/NNP/B-PERSON secretly/RB/O taped/VBD/O many/JJ/O conversations/NNS/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O bosses/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Odeon/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O which/WDT/O they/PRP/O told/VBD/O her/PRP/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O being/VBG/O fired/VBD/O as/IN/O maitre/NNP/O 'd/NNP/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O pregnant/JJ/O ././O
Paul/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Aloe/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O for/IN/O Odeon/NNP/B-ORG owner/NN/O Keith/NNP/B-PERSON McNally/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O denied/VBD/O the/DT/O allegations/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Levine/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O never/RB/O been/VBN/O fired/VBN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O she/PRP/O had/VBD/O stopped/VBN/O working/VBG/O at/IN/O the/DT/O restaurant/NN/O ././O
Lawyers/NNS/O representing/VBG/O five/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O seven/CD/O defendants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O say/VBP/O their/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O can/MD/O no/RB/O longer/RBR/O afford/VB/O their/PRP$/O services/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O trial/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O lasted/VBD/O seven/CD/O months/NNS/O and/CC/O ended/VBD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O hung/VBN/O jury/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O defendants/NNS/O were/VBD/O indicted/VBN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O conspired/VBD/O to/TO/O defraud/VB/O five/CD/O thrifts/NNS/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 130/CD/O million/CD/O through/IN/O a/DT/O complicated/VBN/O scheme/NN/O to/TO/O inflate/VB/O the/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O land/NN/O and/CC/O condominium/NN/O construction/NN/O along/IN/O Interstate/NNP/B-FAC 30/CD/I-FAC ,/,/O east/JJ/O of/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Assistant/NNP/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O Terry/NNP/B-PERSON Hart/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE says/VBZ/O the/DT/O government/NN/O will/MD/O oppose/VB/O any/DT/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O defense/NN/O team/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O delay/VB/O a/DT/O retrial/NN/O ././O
FEDERAL/JJ/O JUDGE/NN/O ALCEE/NNP/B-PERSON HASTINGS/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O facing/VBG/O impeachment/NN/O ,/,/O received/VBD/O an/DT/O unanticipated/JJ/O boost/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Specter/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O impeachment/NN/O trial/NN/O committee/NN/O that/WDT/O heard/VBD/O evidence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O last/JJ/O summer/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O former/JJ/O prosecutor/NN/O and/CC/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Judiciary/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Specter/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O exercise/VB/O influence/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG votes/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O impeachment/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
Five/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O partners/NNS/O --/:/O James/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Morris/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Philip/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Morris/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON White/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Ann/NNP/B-PERSON Adams/NNP/I-PERSON Webster/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Jacqueline/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Epps/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O are/VBP/O opening/VBG/O a/DT/O boutique/NN/O in/IN/O Richmond/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O concentrate/VB/O on/IN/O corporate/JJ/O defense/NN/O litigation/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O in/IN/O product/NN/O liability/NN/O cases/NNS/O ././O
