When/WRB/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON arrives/VBZ/O here/RB/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O hemispheric/JJ/O summit/NN/O organized/VBN/O to/TO/O commemorate/VB/O a/DT/O century/NN/O of/IN/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O democracy/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O he/PRP/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O deliver/VB/O a/DT/O credible/JJ/O message/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Panamanian/JJ/O fiasco/NN/O ?/./O
Undoubtedly/NNP/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O be/VB/O praised/VBN/O by/IN/O some/DT/O Latin/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O prone/JJ/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O lip/JJ/O service/NN/O to/TO/O nonintervention/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O they/PRP/O privately/RB/O encourage/VBP/O more/RBR/O assertive/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE action/NN/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O Gen./NNP/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Noriega/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O safeguard/VB/O their/PRP$/O countries/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Sandinista/NNP/O onslaught/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Panamanian/JJ/O affair/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O the/DT/O tip/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O alarming/JJ/O iceberg/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O originates/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O decision/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O antagonize/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O avoid/VB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O all/DT/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O being/VBG/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O meddling/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O dangerous/JJ/O vacuum/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE leadership/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O leaves/VBZ/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC open/JJ/O to/TO/O Soviet/JJ/O adventurism/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O influence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O not/RB/O being/VBG/O felt/VBD/O in/IN/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ;/:/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O decisions/NNS/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O respond/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O divorced/VBN/O from/IN/O reality/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Fernando/NNP/B-PERSON Volio/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O congressman/NN/O and/CC/O former/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O minister/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O disarray/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O 's/POS/O Latin/NNP/O diplomacy/NN/O was/VBD/O evident/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O failure/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG States/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O condemn/VB/O categorically/RB/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Faced/VBN/O with/IN/O this/DT/O embarrassment/NN/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE diplomats/NNS/O expressed/VBD/O confidence/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O influential/JJ/O Rio/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O South/JJ/O American/JJ/O nations/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O gathered/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O Peru/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O would/MD/O take/VB/O a/DT/O stronger/JJR/O posture/NN/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O Panamanian/JJ/O dictator/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O slaps/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O wrist/NN/O ,/,/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON went/VBD/O unpunished/JJ/O by/IN/O that/DT/O body/NN/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ;/:/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O even/RB/O singled/VBD/O out/RP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O closing/VBG/O statement/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O come/VB/O to/TO/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O encounter/VB/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O strongman/NN/O Daniel/NNP/B-PERSON Ortega/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O eager/JJ/O for/IN/O photo/JJ/O opportunities/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE president/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O host/NN/O ,/,/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O President/NNP/O Oscar/NNP/B-PERSON Arias/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O invite/VB/O Chile/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Cuba/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Haiti/NNP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O summit/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O restricted/VBN/O to/TO/O democracies/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O included/VBN/O ././O
Formally/RB/O upgrading/VBG/O the/DT/O Sandinistas/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O democratic/JJ/O status/NN/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O initiative/NN/O harshly/RB/O criticized/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Costa/JJ/O Rican/JJ/O press/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O Carlos/NNP/B-PERSON Manuel/NNP/I-PERSON Castillo/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O the/DT/O presidential/JJ/O candidate/NN/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Arias/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O National/NNP/B-ORG Liberation/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O made/VBD/O public/JJ/O his/PRP$/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O presence/NN/O of/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ``/``/O in/IN/O a/DT/O democratic/JJ/O festivity/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O dubious/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O Central/JJ/O American/JJ/O presidents/NNS/O met/VBD/O in/IN/O Tela/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Honduras/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O a/DT/O timetable/NN/O for/IN/O disbanding/VBG/O the/DT/O anti-Sandinista/JJ/O rebels/NNS/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O officials/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG hoped/VBD/O that/IN/O by/IN/O pleasing/VBG/O President/NNP/O Arias/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O gain/VB/O his/PRP$/O support/NN/O to/TO/O postpone/VB/O any/DT/O decision/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Contras/NNP/O until/IN/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O promises/NNS/O of/IN/O democratic/JJ/O elections/NNS/O were/VBD/O tested/VBN/O next/IN/O February/NNP/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O relying/VBG/O on/IN/O an/DT/O ardent/JJ/O critic/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Contra/NNP/O movement/NN/O for/IN/O help/NN/O in/IN/O delaying/VBG/O the/DT/O disarming/VBG/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Contras/NNS/O was/VBD/O risky/JJ/O business/NN/O ././O
Prior/RB/O to/TO/O this/DT/O episode/NN/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Dodd/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O sensing/VBG/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O field/NN/O ,/,/O undertook/VBD/O a/DT/O personal/JJ/O diplomatic/JJ/O mission/NN/O through/IN/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC to/TO/O promote/VB/O an/DT/O early/JJ/O disbanding/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O rebels/NNS/O ././O
Visiting/VBG/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O praised/VBD/O the/DT/O Sandinistas/NNS/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O electoral/JJ/O system/NN/O and/CC/O chided/VBD/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O for/IN/O not/RB/O rewarding/VBG/O the/DT/O Sandinistas/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Honduras/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O Contras/NNP/O are/VBP/O a/DT/O hot/JJ/O political/JJ/O issue/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O promised/VBD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O unblock/VB/O some/DT/O $/$/O 70/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O assistance/NN/O withheld/VBN/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O failure/NN/O of/IN/O local/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O to/TO/O comply/VB/O with/IN/O conditions/NNS/O agreed/VBD/O upon/RP/O with/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Aid/NN/O was/VBD/O also/RB/O the/DT/O gist/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O Sen./NNP/O Dodd/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O with/IN/O Salvadoran/JJ/O President/NNP/O Alfredo/NNP/B-PERSON Cristiani/NNP/I-PERSON ;/:/O Mr./NNP/O Cristiani/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O much/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O mercy/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE largess/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O listen/VB/O very/RB/O carefully/RB/O to/TO/O Sen./NNP/O Dodd/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O likes/NN/O and/CC/O dislikes/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O therefore/RB/O not/RB/O surprising/JJ/O that/IN/O close/JJ/O allies/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O virtually/RB/O neglected/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O ordered/VBD/O the/DT/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O insurgents/NNS/O dismantled/VBN/O by/IN/O December/NNP/O ,/,/O long/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O elections/NNS/O ././O
Fittingly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Tela/NNP/O Accords/NNP/O were/VBD/O nicknamed/VBN/O by/IN/O Hondurans/NNS/O ``/``/O the/DT/O Dodd/NNP/B-PERSON plan/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O individual/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O carried/VBD/O out/RP/O by/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE legislators/NNS/O adds/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O confusing/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE performance/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O emboldened/VBN/O Soviet/JJ/O initiatives/NNS/O in/IN/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
On/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 3/CD/O ,/,/O following/VBG/O conversations/NNS/O with/IN/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG James/NNP/B-PERSON Baker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Soviet/NNP/O Foreign/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Eduard/NNP/B-PERSON Shevardnadze/NNP/I-PERSON arrived/VBD/O in/IN/O Managua/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O acclaim/VB/O ``/``/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O great/JJ/O peace/NN/O efforts/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
There/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Shevardnadze/NNP/B-PERSON felt/VBD/O legitimized/VBN/O to/TO/O unveil/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O peace/NN/O plan/NN/O :/:/O The/DT/O U.S.S.R./NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O prolong/VB/O a/DT/O suspension/NN/O of/IN/O arms/NNS/O shipments/NNS/O to/TO/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE after/IN/O the/DT/O February/NNP/O election/NN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE did/VBD/O likewise/RB/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O allies/NNS/O in/IN/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O called/VBD/O on/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/O 's/POS/O neighbors/NNS/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O military/JJ/O equilibrium/NN/O ''/''/O guaranteed/VBN/O by/IN/O both/DT/O superpowers/NNS/O ././O
Since/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Shevardnadze/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O proposals/NNS/O followed/VBD/O discussions/NNS/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O speculations/NNS/O arose/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O was/VBD/O seeking/VBG/O an/DT/O accommodation/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Soviets/NNS/O in/IN/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
This/DT/O scheme/NN/O would/MD/O fit/VB/O the/DT/O Arias/NNP/O Plan/NNP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O declared/VBD/O a/DT/O false/JJ/O symmetry/NN/O between/IN/O Soviet/NNP/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Sandinista/JJ/O dictatorship/NN/O and/CC/O that/DT/O provided/VBN/O by/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O freely/RB/O elected/VBN/O governments/NNS/O ././O
Furthermore/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O encourage/VB/O those/DT/O on/IN/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG Hill/NNP/I-ORG asking/VBG/O for/IN/O cuts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O assistance/NN/O to/TO/O El/NNP/B-GPE Salvador/NNP/I-GPE if/IN/O President/NNP/O Cristiani/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O not/RB/O bend/VB/O to/TO/O demands/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Marxist/JJ/O guerrillas/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O sad/JJ/O condition/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE policy/NN/O in/IN/O Central/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC is/VBZ/O best/RB/O depicted/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O end/NN/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sponsorship/NN/O of/IN/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Costa/NNP/I-ORG Rica/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Costa/NNP/O Rican/NNP/O government/NN/O requested/VBD/O help/NN/O to/TO/O establish/VB/O a/DT/O radio/NN/O station/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O northern/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O flooded/VBN/O by/IN/O airwaves/NNS/O of/IN/O Sandinista/JJ/O propaganda/NN/O ././O
Recovering/VBG/O radiophonic/JJ/O sovereignty/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Costa/NNP/I-ORG Rica/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O funded/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O affiliated/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Voice/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O VOA/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
A/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O this/DT/O cooperation/NN/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Costa/NNP/I-ORG Rica/NNP/I-ORG operating/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O shoestring/NN/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O news/NN/O reports/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O abrupt/JJ/O termination/NN/O was/VBD/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O fears/NNS/O that/IN/O VOA/NNP/B-ORG transmissions/NNS/O could/MD/O interfere/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O peace/NN/O process/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O meantime/NN/O ,/,/O Russia/NNP/B-GPE gave/VBD/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE another/DT/O powerful/JJ/O radio/NN/O transmitter/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O installed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O of/IN/O Esteli/NNP/B-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O capable/JJ/O of/IN/O reaching/VBG/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O Caribbean/JJ/B-LOC area/NN/O and/CC/O deep/JJ/O into/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Perhaps/RB/O its/PRP$/O loud/JJ/O signal/NN/O may/MD/O generate/VB/O some/DT/O awareness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O condominium/NN/O being/VBG/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O isthmus/NN/O thanks/NNS/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE default/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O entrenchment/NN/O in/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O alarming/JJ/O for/IN/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O peaceful/JJ/O democracy/NN/O without/IN/O an/DT/O army/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O poll/NN/O conducted/VBN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O by/IN/O a/DT/O Gallup/NN/B-ORG affiliate/NN/O showed/VBD/O that/IN/O 64/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Costa/NNS/O Ricans/NNS/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O if/IN/O their/PRP$/O country/NN/O is/VBZ/O militarily/RB/O attacked/VBN/O by/IN/O either/DT/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O come/VB/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O defense/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O light/NN/O of/IN/O events/NNS/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O such/JJ/O clear/JJ/O strategic/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ,/,/O waiting/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Delta/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O prove/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O dangerous/JJ/O gambit/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Daremblum/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O columnist/NN/O for/IN/O La/NNP/B-ORG Nacion/NNP/I-ORG newspaper/NN/O ././O
