For/IN/O retailers/NNS/O ,/,/O Christmas/NNP/O ,/,/O not/RB/O Halloween/NNP/O ,/,/O promises/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O spookiest/JJS/O season/NN/O ././O
Concerns/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O doubts/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O in/IN/O general/JJ/O and/CC/O rising/VBG/O competition/NN/O from/IN/O catalog/NN/O companies/NNS/O also/RB/O haunt/VBP/O store/NN/O operators/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O widespread/JJ/O discounting/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O outlook/NN/O for/IN/O industry/NN/O profits/NNS/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O good/JJ/O ././O
Management/NNP/B-ORG Horizons/NNP/I-ORG forecasts/VBZ/O a/DT/O 1.4/CD/O %/NN/O profit/NN/O decline/NN/O for/IN/O non-auto/JJ/O retailers/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O annual/JJ/O drops/NNS/O that/WDT/O averaged/VBD/O 4.5/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O and/CC/O 1987/CD/O ././O
``/``/O For/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O two/CD/O and/CC/O a/DT/O half/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O retailing/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O mild/JJ/O recession/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Carl/NNP/B-PERSON Steidtmann/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O economist/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Columbus/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O consulting/VBG/O firm/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O stores/NNS/O are/VBP/O entering/VBG/O the/DT/O Christmas/NNP/O season/NN/O in/IN/O turmoil/NN/O :/:/O Bonwit/NNP/B-ORG Teller/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O B./NNP/B-ORG Altman/NNP/I-ORG parent/NN/O L.J./NNP/B-ORG Hooker/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O operating/VBG/O under/IN/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O ;/:/O B.A.T/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG healthy/JJ/O Saks/NNP/B-ORG Fifth/NNP/I-ORG Avenue/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Marshall/NNP/B-ORG Field/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG chains/NNS/O are/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O auction/NN/O block/NN/O ;/:/O Campeau/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Bloomingdale/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O block/NN/O ././O
Industry/NN/O observers/NNS/O expect/VBP/O a/DT/O wide/JJ/O divergence/NN/O in/IN/O performance/NN/O ././O
Stores/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O confusion/NN/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O fare/VB/O poorly/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O lose/VB/O customers/NNS/O to/TO/O stable/JJ/O chains/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Limited/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O May/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG Stores/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Dillard/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG Stores/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O should/MD/O do/VB/O well/RB/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Steidtmann/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O a/DT/O bi-polar/JJ/O Christmas/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Steidtmann/NNP/B-PERSON predicts/VBZ/O that/IN/O healthy/JJ/O stores/NNS/O hawking/VBG/O mostly/RB/O apparel/NN/O could/MD/O ring/VB/O up/RP/O gains/NNS/O of/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 25/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Troubled/VBN/O chains/NNS/O could/MD/O see/VB/O their/PRP$/O sales/NNS/O drop/VB/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O ,/,/O as/IN/O managers/NNS/O distracted/VBN/O by/IN/O fears/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O allow/VBP/O their/PRP$/O stores/NNS/O to/TO/O get/VB/O sloppy/JJ/O ././O
Thin/JJ/O merchandise/NN/O selections/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O troubled/VBN/O chains/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O hurt/VB/O sales/NNS/O ././O
Catalog/NN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O pose/VB/O a/DT/O bigger/JJR/O threat/NN/O to/TO/O all/DT/O stores/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O in/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O Traditionally/RB/O ,/,/O consumers/NNS/O were/VBD/O concerned/VBN/O about/IN/O ordering/VBG/O after/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O of/IN/O December/NNP/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O get/VB/O it/PRP/O by/IN/O Christmas/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Adam/NNP/B-PERSON Strum/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Wine/NNP/I-ORG Enthusiast/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O sells/VBZ/O wine/NN/O cellars/NNS/O and/CC/O accessories/NNS/O through/IN/O the/DT/O mail/NN/O ././O
Using/VBG/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG delivery/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Strum/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O December/NNP/O was/VBD/O our/PRP$/O biggest/JJS/O month/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
K/NNP/B-ORG mart/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Antonini/NNP/I-PERSON summed/VBD/O up/RP/O his/PRP$/O outlook/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Christmas/NNP/O season/NN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O not/RB/O troublesome/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O predicting/VBG/O a/DT/O blockbuster/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O more/RBR/O optimistic/JJ/O than/IN/O three/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O ''/''/O because/IN/O employment/NN/O remains/VBZ/O strong/JJ/O and/CC/O inflation/NN/O low/JJ/O ././O
Philip/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Hawley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Carter/NNP/B-ORG Hawley/NNP/I-ORG Hale/NNP/I-ORG Stores/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O expects/VBZ/O sales/NNS/O at/IN/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O open/JJ/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O rise/VB/O a/DT/O modest/JJ/O 3/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O over/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O totals/NNS/O ,/,/O both/DT/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O in/IN/O general/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O a/DT/O runaway/JJ/O Christmas/NNP/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O real/JJ/O boom/NN/O holiday/NN/O season/NN/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O eyes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Woolworth/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Sells/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O bust/NN/O either/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O estimate/NN/O includes/VBZ/O the/DT/O results/NNS/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O stores/NNS/O ././O
Of/IN/O the/DT/O 450/CD/O survey/NN/O respondents/NNS/O ,/,/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expect/VBP/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O less/JJR/O buying/VBG/O Christmas/NNP/O gifts/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O than/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O 28/CD/O %/NN/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expect/VBP/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O 37/CD/O %/NN/O said/VBD/O their/PRP$/O gift/NN/O budget/NN/O would/MD/O stay/VB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O results/NNS/O are/VBP/O almost/RB/O identical/JJ/O to/TO/O Shapiro/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O September/NNP/O 1988/CD/O numbers/NNS/O ././O
Retailers/NNS/O could/MD/O get/VB/O a/DT/O boost/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O calendar/NN/O ././O
Most/JJS/O will/MD/O stay/VB/O open/JJ/O late/JJ/O Saturday/NNP/O night/NN/O and/CC/O open/VB/O their/PRP$/O doors/NNS/O again/RB/O Sunday/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O many/JJ/O consumers/NNS/O probably/RB/O will/MD/O use/VB/O the/DT/O extra/JJ/O time/NN/O to/TO/O put/VB/O off/RP/O some/DT/O purchasing/NN/O until/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O minute/NN/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O you/PRP/O 'll/MD/O hear/VB/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O get/VBP/O into/IN/O December/NNP/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O sales/NNS/O are/VBP/O sluggish/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O predicts/VBZ/O Woolworth/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Sells/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O week/NN/O ending/VBG/O the/DT/O 24th/JJ/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O save/VB/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O month/NN/O for/IN/O everyone/NN/O ././O
