Ko/NNP/B-PERSON Shioya/NNP/I-PERSON spent/VBD/O eight/CD/O years/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O editor/NN/O in/IN/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O edition/NN/O of/IN/O Reader/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Digest/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O importer/NN/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O information/NN/O and/CC/O news/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Shioya/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O one/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O fed/VBN/O up/RP/O with/IN/O importing/VBG/O information/NN/O and/CC/O news/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Shioya/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O turned/VBN/O the/DT/O tables/NNS/O ././O
Printed/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O carrying/VBG/O the/DT/O line/NN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Insider/NNP/O 's/POS/O Japan/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Business/NNP/B-ORG Tokyo/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG October/NNP/O cover/NN/O story/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O The/DT/O World/NNP/O 's/POS/O No./NN/O 1/CD/O Customer/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O Japanese/JJ/O women/NNS/O ././O
Keizaikai/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O but/CC/O growing/VBG/O band/NN/O of/IN/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O taking/VBG/O their/PRP$/O first/JJ/O steps/NNS/O into/IN/O American/JJ/O publishing/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O making/VBG/O major/JJ/O investments/NNS/O in/IN/O entertainment/NN/O ,/,/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O and/CC/O banking/NN/O companies/NNS/O here/RB/O ././O
And/CC/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O quietly/RB/O linking/VBG/O up/RP/O with/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE publishing/NN/O trade/NN/O groups/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Japanese/JJ/O publishers/NNS/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O introduced/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O publishing/NN/O and/CC/O information/NN/O industries/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Veronis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Veronis/NNP/B-ORG Suhler/NNP/I-ORG ././O
While/IN/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O major/JJ/O deals/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O works/NNS/O currently/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O scale/NN/O of/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG recent/JJ/O $/$/O 3.4/CD/O billion/CD/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O observers/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O rule/VB/O out/RP/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O size/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O take/VBP/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O view/NN/O ././O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Veronis/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O may/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O weeks/NNS/O or/CC/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O opportunistic/JJ/O and/CC/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O feel/VBP/O comfortable/JJ/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O move/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O involvement/NN/O in/IN/O American/JJ/O publishing/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O so/RB/O small/JJ/O to/TO/O date/NN/O that/IN/O magazines/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Business/NNP/B-ORG Tokyo/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O considered/VBN/O groundbreakers/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O Keizaikai/NNP/B-PERSON launched/VBD/O Business/NNP/B-ORG Tokyo/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O appealed/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O multinational/JJ/O audience/NN/O ././O
American/JJ/O publishers/NNS/O appear/VBP/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O do/VB/O some/DT/O selling/VBG/O ././O
Susumu/NNP/B-PERSON Ohara/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Nihon/NNP/B-ORG Keizai/NNP/I-ORG Shinbun/NNP/I-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O publisher/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O receives/VBZ/O telephone/NN/O calls/NNS/O weekly/RB/O from/IN/O media/NNS/O bankers/NNS/O on/IN/O whether/CC/O his/PRP$/O parent/NN/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O buying/VBG/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE consumer/NN/O or/CC/O business/NN/O magazine/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O Japanese/NNS/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O stage/NN/O right/RB/O now/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Kenney/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O onetime/JJ/O media/NN/O adviser/NN/O for/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG who/WP/O was/VBD/O recently/RB/O appointed/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Reader/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Digest/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG new/JJ/O Magazine/NNP/B-ORG Publishing/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Before/IN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O interested/JJ/O in/IN/O hard/JJ/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O saw/VBD/O magazines/NNS/O as/IN/O soft/JJ/O ././O
Now/RB/O they/PRP/O realize/VBP/O magazines/NNS/O are/VBP/O as/RB/O much/RB/O a/DT/O franchise/NN/O as/IN/O Nabisco/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O franchise/NN/O ././O
