Ever/RB/O since/IN/O the/DT/O hotly/RB/O contested/VBN/O America/NNP/O 's/POS/O Cup/NNP/O race/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O famous/JJ/O yachting/NN/O match/NN/O has/VBZ/O run/VBN/O into/IN/O more/JJR/O rough/JJ/O sailing/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O water/NN/O than/IN/O in/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Now/RB/O that/IN/O a/DT/O key/JJ/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-ORG Diego/NNP/I-ORG Yacht/NNP/I-ORG Club/NNP/I-ORG team/NN/O is/VBZ/O splitting/JJ/O off/RP/O to/TO/O form/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O team/NN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O more/JJR/O competition/NN/O lies/VBZ/O ahead/RB/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O crack/NN/O team/NN/O of/IN/O sailors/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Isler/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O lined/VBN/O up/RP/O some/DT/O real/JJ/O brass/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O him/PRP/O finance/VB/O the/DT/O syndicate/NN/O ././O
Isler/NNP/B-ORG Sailing/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG advisory/JJ/O board/NN/O includes/VBZ/O Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Turner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Cup/NNP/O victor/NN/O ;/:/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Diamandis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O Diamandis/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Vittoria/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Avis/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
His/PRP$/O steering/NN/O committee/NN/O includes/VBZ/O other/JJ/O notable/JJ/O businessmen/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE investor/NN/O and/CC/O old/JJ/O salt/NN/O Roy/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Disney/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O structure/NN/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O and/CC/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Isler/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O order/NN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O raising/VBG/O enough/JJ/O money/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O his/PRP$/O team/NN/O afloat/RB/O --/:/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O yacht/NN/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O about/RB/O $/$/O 3/CD/O million/CD/O alone/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O sailing/NN/O syndicate/NN/O budgets/NNS/O can/MD/O easily/RB/O run/VB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O Cup/NNP/O challenge/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/B-GPE New/NNP/I-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE appellate/JJ/O court/NN/O overturned/VBD/O a/DT/O state/NN/O judge/NN/O 's/POS/O ruling/NN/O that/WDT/O awarded/VBD/O the/DT/O Cup/NNP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE team/NN/O ././O
Pending/VBG/O an/DT/O appeal/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Zealand/NNP/I-GPE team/NN/O ,/,/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Fay/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O finals/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O Cup/NNP/O challenge/NN/O are/VBP/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O held/VBN/O in/IN/O mid-1992/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE ././O
But/CC/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O uncertainty/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O outcome/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Conner/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O team/NN/O has/VBZ/O done/VBN/O little/JJ/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O gearing/VBG/O up/RP/O to/TO/O defend/VB/O its/PRP$/O title/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Conner/NNP/B-PERSON team/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O negotiate/VB/O with/IN/O corporate/JJ/O sponsors/NNS/O until/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O is/VBZ/O resolved/VBN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O race/NN/O site/NN/O is/VBZ/O determined/VBN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O syndicate/NN/O 's/POS/O budget/NN/O could/MD/O easily/RB/O reach/VB/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O spokesmen/NNS/O for/IN/O both/DT/O Mr./NNP/O Isler/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Conner/NNP/B-PERSON say/VBP/O the/DT/O formation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O syndicate/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O do/VB/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Isler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O skipper/VB/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O team/NN/O and/CC/O begin/VB/O planning/VBG/O now/RB/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O any/DT/O falling/VBG/O out/RP/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sportsmen/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Cup/NNP/I-ORG Organizing/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG insist/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O added/VBN/O competition/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O defender/NN/O 's/POS/O spot/NN/O will/MD/O only/RB/O improve/VB/O the/DT/O race/NN/O ././O
