After/IN/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O quarreling/VBG/O over/IN/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O ``/``/O Ostpolitik/NNP/O ''/''/O ,/,/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE appear/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O shifted/VBN/O onto/IN/O a/DT/O united/VBN/O course/NN/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Bonn/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O leading/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O aid/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O reformist/NN/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O pledging/VBG/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O fresh/JJ/O credit/NN/O and/CC/O forgiving/JJ/O old/JJ/O debt/NN/O while/IN/O urging/VBG/O other/JJ/O industrial/JJ/O nations/NNS/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O suit/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O encourage/VB/O pressure/NN/O for/IN/O change/NN/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC countries/NNS/O still/RB/O ruled/VBN/O by/IN/O Stalinist/JJ/O holdouts/NNS/O by/IN/O arranging/VBG/O liberal/JJ/O financial/JJ/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O trade/NN/O benefits/NNS/O for/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O ,/,/O to/TO/O a/DT/O lesser/JJR/O extent/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
West/JJ/O German/JJ/O officials/NNS/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O special/JJ/O goal/NN/O of/IN/O holding/VBG/O out/RP/O hope/NN/O for/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE fledgling/NN/O reform/NN/O movement/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O aim/NN/O of/IN/O Western/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O East/NNP/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC reforms/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O create/VB/O ``/``/O an/DT/O equitable/JJ/O and/CC/O stable/JJ/O peaceful/JJ/O order/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC from/IN/O the/DT/O Atlantic/NNP/B-LOC to/TO/O the/DT/O Urals/NNS/B-LOC ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Genscher/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O Commerce/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Mosbacher/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O separate/JJ/O speeches/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O ,/,/O appealed/VBD/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O Western/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O to/TO/O economic/JJ/O reforms/NNS/O and/CC/O business/NN/O development/NN/O in/IN/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O want/VBP/O the/DT/O bold/JJ/O programs/NNS/O of/IN/O market/NN/O development/NN/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O freedom/NN/O in/IN/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O in/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O succeed/VB/O ././O
We/PRP/O are/VBP/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O support/VB/O those/DT/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Mosbacher/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE curbs/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O exports/NNS/O of/IN/O sensitive/JJ/O technology/NN/O to/TO/O East/NNP/B-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC countries/NNS/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O in/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Representatives/NNP/I-ORG yesterday/NN/O approved/VBD/O an/DT/O $/$/O 837.5/CD/O million/CD/O aid/NN/O package/NN/O for/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE that/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O doubles/VBZ/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O requested/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O package/NN/O was/VBD/O brought/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG just/RB/O 15/CD/O days/NNS/O after/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O introduced/VBN/O ,/,/O indicating/VBG/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O eagerness/NN/O to/TO/O reward/VB/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O their/PRP$/O moves/NNS/O toward/IN/O democracy/NN/O and/CC/O freemarket/JJ/O economic/JJ/O reforms/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Polish/JJ/O fund/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O seeded/VBN/O with/IN/O $/$/O 160/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Hungarian/JJ/O fund/NN/O with/IN/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O 24/CD/O industrialized/VBN/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O coordinated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O promised/VBN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O advice/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O line/NN/O of/IN/O credit/NN/O equivalent/JJ/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.11/CD/O billion/CD/O through/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG plans/VBZ/O $/$/O 222/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O direct/JJ/O aid/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O Chancellor/NNP/O Helmut/NNP/B-PERSON Kohl/NNP/I-PERSON travels/VBZ/O to/TO/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE Nov./NNP/O 9/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O a/DT/O promise/NN/O of/IN/O three/CD/O billion/CD/O West/NNP/O German/NNP/O marks/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 1.6/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O new/JJ/O credit/NN/O guarantees/NNS/O for/IN/O industrial/JJ/O projects/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O reschedule/VB/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O marks/NNS/O in/IN/O Polish/JJ/O debt/NN/O that/WDT/O came/VBD/O due/JJ/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O one/CD/O billion/CD/O mark/NN/O credit/NN/O dating/VBG/O from/IN/O 1974/CD/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O written/VBN/O off/RP/O ././O
A/DT/O maxim/NN/O of/IN/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE banking/NN/O holds/VBZ/O that/IN/O wherever/WRB/O Deutsche/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG goes/VBZ/O ,/,/O other/JJ/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O banks/NNS/O follow/VBP/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O four/CD/O other/JJ/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O banks/NNS/O are/VBP/O believed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O making/VBG/O inquiries/NNS/O ././O
