The/DT/O University/NNP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 21.3/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O over/IN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O on/IN/O research/NN/O at/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O universities/NNS/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O successful/JJ/O in/IN/O acquiring/VBG/O the/DT/O vaccine/NN/O maker/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O would/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Toronto/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O University/NNP/O is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O an/DT/O injunction/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O Merieux/NNP/B-ORG bid/NN/O ,/,/O arguing/VBG/O that/IN/O Connaught/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O predecessor/NN/O company/NN/O agreed/VBD/O in/IN/O 1972/CD/O that/IN/O Connaught/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ownership/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O transferred/VBN/O to/TO/O foreigners/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O agreement/NN/O would/MD/O ``/``/O replace/VB/O ''/''/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O one/CD/O that/WDT/O forms/VBZ/O the/DT/O basis/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O Merieux/NNP/B-ORG takeover/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Notwithstanding/IN/O foreign/JJ/O ownership/NN/O of/IN/O Connaught/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O this/DT/O accord/NN/O would/MD/O enhance/VB/O research/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O in/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Keffer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O university/NN/O 's/POS/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O research/NN/O ././O
