Your/PRP$/O Oct./NNP/O 12/CD/O editorial/NN/O ``/``/O Pitiful/NNP/O ,/,/O Helpless/NNP/O Presidency/NNP/O ?/./O ''/''/O correctly/RB/O states/VBZ/O that/IN/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O critical/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O 's/POS/O failure/NN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O plan/NN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O to/TO/O respond/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O timely/JJ/O fashion/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O opportunities/NNS/O to/TO/O oust/VB/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Noriega/NNP/I-PERSON presented/VBD/O by/IN/O the/DT/O attempted/VBN/O military/JJ/O coup/NN/O on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 3/CD/O ././O
My/PRP$/O position/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O founded/VBN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/O facts/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O public/NN/O made/VBD/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O mind/NN/O about/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON largely/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hearings/NNS/O I/PRP/O chaired/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Subcommittee/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG Terrorism/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Narcotics/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O Feb./NNP/O 8/CD/O ,/,/O 9/CD/O ,/,/O 10/CD/O and/CC/O 11/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O again/RB/O on/IN/O April/NNP/O 4/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O during/IN/O those/DT/O hearings/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O first/RB/O learned/VBD/O the/DT/O breadth/NN/O and/CC/O depth/NN/O of/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O criminality/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O enduring/VBG/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O variety/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
