Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O rout/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG congressional/JJ/O hopeful/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Mississippi/NNP/B-GPE district/NN/O that/DT/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O backed/VBD/O a/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O presidential/JJ/O candidate/NN/O since/IN/O Adlai/NNP/B-PERSON Stevenson/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O another/DT/O reminder/NN/O that/IN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O level/NN/O ,/,/O political/JJ/O ``/``/O ticket/NN/O splitting/NN/O ''/''/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O rise/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O half/JJ/O century/NN/O ././O
Each/DT/O legislator/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O one/CD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O 535/CD/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O comes/VBZ/O to/TO/O national/JJ/O policy/NN/O making/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O individual/JJ/O voter/NN/O 's/VBZ/O standing/NN/O consequently/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O enhanced/VBN/O through/IN/O lower/JJR/O taxes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O one/CD/O exception/NN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O recent/JJ/O trend/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O defeat/NN/O of/IN/O 13/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 52/CD/O freshman/NN/O Republicans/NNS/O brought/VBD/O into/IN/O office/NN/O in/IN/O 1980/CD/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON revolution/NN/O and/CC/O running/VBG/O for/IN/O re-election/NN/O in/IN/O 1982/CD/O ././O
Fourth/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O theory/NN/O indicates/VBZ/O why/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG Republican/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O difficult/JJ/O time/NN/O attracting/VBG/O viable/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O for/IN/O congressional/JJ/O office/NN/O ././O
Potential/JJ/O candidates/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O discouraged/VBN/O from/IN/O running/VBG/O less/RBR/O by/IN/O the/DT/O congressional/JJ/O salary/NN/O than/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O of/IN/O defeat/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O opponent/NN/O ././O
Fifth/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O theory/NN/O may/MD/O provide/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O a/DT/O partial/JJ/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O why/WRB/O ticket/NN/O splitting/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O particularly/RB/O pronounced/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O indeed/RB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O data/NNS/O indicate/VBP/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O House/NNP/B-ORG attendance/NN/O rate/NN/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O exceeded/VBN/O the/DT/O Republican/JJ/O House/NNP/B-ORG attendance/NN/O rate/NN/O since/IN/O 1959/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Zupan/NNP/B-PERSON teaches/VBZ/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG business/NN/O school/NN/O ././O
