Democracy/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O cruel/JJ/O to/TO/O politicians/NNS/O :/:/O Sometimes/RB/O it/PRP/O forces/VBZ/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O choices/NNS/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O discomfort/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O healthy/JJ/O sign/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O ././O
Republicans/NNS/O are/VBP/O squinting/VBG/O most/RBS/O painfully/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O at/IN/O first/JJS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O fair/JJ/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O been/VBN/O shielded/VBN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O after/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG passed/VBD/O it/PRP/O anyway/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O hinted/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O compromise/NN/O ././O
Pro-life/JJ/O advocates/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG never/RB/O wavered/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O veto/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O never/RB/O eager/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O fight/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O happy/JJ/O to/TO/O try/VB/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O why/WRB/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O ``/``/O flexibility/NN/O ''/''/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG doubters/NNS/O were/VBD/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O manuevering/VBG/O illustrates/VBZ/O an/DT/O emerging/VBG/O Republican/JJ/O donnybrook/NN/O ,/,/O pacified/VBD/O since/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/CD/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O a/DT/O passionate/JJ/O statement/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O platform/NN/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O talking/VBG/O to/TO/O herself/PRP/O ././O
They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O frightened/VBN/O by/IN/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O see/VBP/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O especially/RB/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O pro-life/JJ/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG candidates/NNS/O for/IN/O governor/NN/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O pummeled/VBD/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Eddie/NNP/B-PERSON Mahe/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Republican/JJ/O consultant/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O two/CD/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG candidates/NNS/O could/MD/O have/VB/O avoided/VBN/O trouble/NN/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O framed/VBN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O first/RB/O ././O
Polls/NNS/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O substitute/NN/O for/IN/O principle/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O do/VB/O for/IN/O some/DT/O politicians/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Republican/JJ/O danger/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O abortion/NN/O could/MD/O become/VB/O for/IN/O them/PRP/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O long/RB/O been/VBN/O for/IN/O Democrats/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O divisive/JJ/O litmus/NN/O test/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O already/RB/O that/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O for/IN/O any/DT/O job/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O abortion/NN/O is/VBZ/O even/RB/O remotely/RB/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Caldwell/NNP/B-PERSON Butler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O conservative/JJ/O former/JJ/O congressman/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O barred/VBN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Legal/NNP/B-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG post/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O he/PRP/O gave/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O answers/NNS/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O views/NNS/O on/IN/O health/NN/O care/NN/O and/CC/O welfare/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O much/JJ/O matter/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O HHS/NNP/B-ORG spends/VBZ/O billions/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O ././O
Though/IN/O Democrats/NNS/O can/MD/O gloat/VB/O at/IN/O all/DT/O this/DT/O for/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O contain/VB/O their/PRP$/O glee/NN/O ././O
Democracy/NN/O is/VBZ/O forcing/VBG/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O debate/NN/O toward/IN/O healthy/JJ/O compromise/NN/O ,/,/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O unpolarizing/VBG/O middle/NN/O ././O
Roe/NNP/O v./IN/O Wade/NNP/O pre-empted/VBD/O political/JJ/O debate/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O the/DT/O extremes/NNS/O blossomed/VBD/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O voters/NNS/O are/VBP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O politicians/NNS/O usually/RB/O end/VBP/O up/RP/O ././O
