The/DT/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG ordered/VBD/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O not/RB/O to/TO/O use/VB/O rating/NN/O bureaus/NN/O in/IN/O those/DT/O six/CD/O states/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG ruled/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O violated/VBD/O federal/JJ/O antitrust/JJ/O law/NN/O by/IN/O fixing/VBG/O rates/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O following/JJ/O states/NNS/O :/:/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wisconsin/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Montana/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG first/RB/O issued/VBD/O an/DT/O administrative/JJ/O complaint/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O expect/VBP/O all/DT/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O appeal/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O lawyer/NN/O for/IN/O Lawyers/NNP/B-ORG Title/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O the/DT/O named/VBN/O companies/NNS/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O use/VBP/O the/DT/O type/NN/O of/IN/O cooperative/JJ/O rating/NN/O bureaus/NN/O attacked/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O FTC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O 's/POS/O order/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O much/JJ/O practical/JJ/O impact/NN/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O named/VBN/O companies/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O return/VB/O telephone/NN/O calls/NNS/O seeking/VBG/O comment/NN/O ././O
