Heidi/NNP/B-PERSON Ehman/NNP/I-PERSON might/MD/O have/VB/O stepped/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O recruiting/NN/O poster/NN/O for/IN/O young/JJ/O Republicans/NNS/O ././O
White/JJ/B-PERSON ,/,/O 24/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O singer/NN/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O church/NN/O choir/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O symbolizes/VBZ/O a/DT/O generation/NN/O that/WDT/O gave/VBD/O its/PRP$/O heart/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O felt/VBD/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O safe/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
No/RB/O longer/RBR/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG opened/VBD/O the/DT/O door/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O new/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Ehman/NNP/B-PERSON opened/VBD/O her/PRP$/O mind/NN/O to/TO/O Democratic/JJ/O politics/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O my/PRP$/O age/NN/O thought/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O --/:/O especially/RB/O for/IN/O people/NNS/O my/PRP$/O age/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Polls/NNS/O bear/VBP/O out/RP/O this/DT/O warning/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O after/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O of/IN/O increased/VBN/O Republican/JJ/O influence/NN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O politics/NNS/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O have/VBP/O contributed/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O world/NN/O turned/VBD/O upside/RB/O down/RB/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Unless/IN/O he/PRP/O closes/VBZ/O the/DT/O gap/NN/O ,/,/O Republicans/NNS/O risk/NN/O losing/VBG/O not/RB/O only/RB/O the/DT/O governorship/NN/O but/CC/O also/RB/O the/DT/O assembly/NN/O next/IN/O month/NN/O ././O
Going/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O 1990s/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O paying/VBG/O a/DT/O price/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O conservative/JJ/O social/JJ/O agenda/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O torment/VB/O Democrats/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O change/NN/O comes/VBZ/O less/RBR/O from/IN/O a/DT/O shift/NN/O in/IN/O public/JJ/O opinion/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O changed/VBD/O much/RB/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O than/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O boundaries/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE own/JJ/O highest/JJS/O court/NN/O remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O liberal/JJ/O bulwark/NN/O against/IN/O major/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ruling/NN/O ,/,/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON vs./IN/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O engaged/VBN/O voters/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O insulated/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Before/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O pro-choice/JJ/O voters/NNS/O could/MD/O safely/RB/O make/VB/O political/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O without/IN/O focusing/VBG/O narrowly/RB/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O recent/JJ/O pro-choice/JJ/O rally/NN/O in/IN/O Trenton/NNP/B-GPE drew/VBD/O thousands/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O reversal/NN/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O defying/VBG/O a/DT/O presidential/JJ/O veto/NN/O and/CC/O demanding/VBG/O that/IN/O Medicaid/NNP/B-ORG abortions/NNS/O be/VBP/O permitted/VBN/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O n't/RB/O happened/VBN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O here/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Linda/NNP/B-PERSON Bowker/NNP/I-PERSON tells/VBZ/O a/DT/O reporter/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Trenton/NNP/B-GPE office/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Organization/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Women/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O could/MD/O have/VB/O shouted/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O rooftops/NNS/O about/IN/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON .../:/O and/CC/O no/DT/O one/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O heard/VBN/O us/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O infusion/NN/O of/IN/O activists/NNS/O can/MD/O bring/VB/O a/DT/O clash/NN/O of/IN/O cultures/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Cherry/NNP/B-GPE Hill/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Abortion/NNP/I-ORG Rights/NNP/I-ORG Action/NNP/I-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O goal/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O sign/VB/O up/RP/O 50,000/CD/O pro-choice/JJ/O voters/NNS/O ,/,/O targets/VBZ/O a/DT/O union/NN/O breakfast/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O labor/NN/O support/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O cause/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O league/NN/O organizers/NNS/O seem/VBP/O more/JJR/O a/DT/O fit/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O convention/NN/O next/JJ/O door/NN/O of/IN/O young/JJ/O aerobics/NNS/O instructors/NNS/O in/IN/O leotards/NNS/O than/IN/O the/DT/O beefy/JJ/O union/NN/O leaders/NNS/O ;/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O wish/VBP/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O go/VB/O work/VB/O out/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O slim/JJ/O activist/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O labor/NN/O chief/NN/O speaks/VBZ/O sardonically/RB/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O to/TO/O ``/``/O man/VB/O and/CC/O woman/NN/O ''/''/O Election/NNP/O Day/NNP/O phones/NNS/O ././O
No/DT/O age/NN/O group/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O sensitive/JJ/O than/IN/O younger/JJR/O voters/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Ehman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
A/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O this/DT/O fall/NN/O ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE voters/NNS/O under/IN/O 30/CD/O favored/VBN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON by/IN/O 56/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 39/CD/O %/NN/O over/IN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Dukakis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O survey/NN/O then/RB/O by/IN/O Rutgers/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Eagleton/NNP/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Voters/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O age/NN/O group/NN/B-ORG backed/VBD/O Democrat/NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 55/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 29/CD/O %/NN/O over/IN/O Republican/NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Abortion/NN/O alone/RB/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O explain/VB/O this/DT/O shift/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O model/NN/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O so/RB/O personal/JJ/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O can/MD/O become/VB/O a/DT/O baseline/NN/O of/IN/O sorts/NNS/O in/IN/O judging/VBG/O a/DT/O candidate/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O times/NNS/O are/VBP/O my/PRP$/O times/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
After/IN/O losing/VBG/O by/IN/O fewer/JJR/O than/IN/O 1,800/CD/O votes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1981/CD/O governor/NN/O 's/POS/O race/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O prepared/VBN/O himself/PRP/O methodically/RB/O for/IN/O this/DT/O moment/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O deciding/VBG/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O support/VB/O curbs/NNS/O on/IN/O federal/JJ/O funding/NN/O for/IN/O Medicaid/NNP/B-ORG abortions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O consistent/JJ/O and/CC/O say/VB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O constitutionally/RB/O protected/VBN/O right/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O asks/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O how/WRB/O are/VBP/O you/PRP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O say/VB/O an/DT/O upscale/JJ/O woman/NN/O who/WP/O can/MD/O drive/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O hospital/NN/O or/CC/O clinic/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O nice/JJ/O car/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O right/NN/O and/CC/O someone/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O in/IN/O great/JJ/O shape/NN/O financially/RB/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Looking/VBG/O back/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O erred/VBD/O by/IN/O stating/VBG/O his/PRP$/O ``/``/O personal/JJ/O ''/''/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O assuring/VBG/O voters/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O impose/VB/O his/PRP$/O views/NNS/O on/IN/O ``/``/O policy/NN/O ''/''/O as/IN/O governor/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O distinction/NN/O that/IN/O satisfies/NNS/O neither/DT/O side/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O himself/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Kathy/NNP/B-PERSON Stanwick/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Abortion/NNP/I-ORG Rights/NNP/I-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O position/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O abortion/NN/O opponents/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O angry/JJ/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O hide/VB/O their/PRP$/O frustration/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Republican/NNP/O 's/POS/O ambivalence/NN/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O lead/VB/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Traynor/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG Jersey/NNP/I-ORG Right/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O by/IN/O stepping/VBG/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O pro-choice/JJ/O tradition/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON aggravates/VBZ/O fears/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O conservative/JJ/O as/IN/O well/RB/O on/IN/O more/RBR/O pressing/VBG/O concerns/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O auto/NN/O insurance/NN/O rates/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O ././O
Like/IN/O many/VB/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O serve/VB/O in/IN/O Vietnam/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O the/DT/O 1960s/CD/O yet/CC/O embraced/VBD/O a/DT/O hawkish/JJ/O defense/NN/O and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O --/:/O even/RB/O voting/VBG/O against/IN/O a/DT/O 1984/CD/O resolution/NN/O critical/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE mining/NN/O of/IN/O Nicaraguan/NNP/O harbors/NNS/O ././O
Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Kemp/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O writers/NNS/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON Kristol/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Gilder/NNP/I-PERSON were/VBD/O influences/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O own/JJ/O conservative/JJ/O credentials/NNS/O proved/VBD/O useful/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE GOP/NNP/B-ORG governor/NN/O ,/,/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Kean/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1981/CD/O Republican/NNP/O primary/NN/O here/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O same/JJ/O partnership/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O crucial/JJ/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O fortunes/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O a/DT/O reminder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O gap/NN/O between/IN/O his/PRP$/O record/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O moderate/JJ/O ,/,/O pro-choice/JJ/O Gov./NNP/O Kean/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O Warren/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE congressman/NN/O pursued/VBD/O an/DT/O anti-government/NN/O ,/,/O anti-tax/JJ/O agenda/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Gov./NNP/O Kean/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O approving/VBG/O increased/VBN/O income/NN/O and/CC/O sales/NNS/O taxes/NNS/O at/IN/O home/NN/O and/CC/O overseeing/VBG/O a/DT/O near/JJ/O doubling/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE budget/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O eight/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O office/NN/O ././O
Kean/NNP/B-PERSON forces/NNS/O play/VB/O down/RP/O any/DT/O differences/NNS/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O this/DT/O history/NN/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O harder/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O to/TO/O run/VB/O against/IN/O government/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O further/RBR/O hobbled/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O record/NN/O of/IN/O votes/NNS/O opposed/VBN/O to/TO/O government/NN/O regulation/NN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O consumers/NNS/O ././O
Fluent/NNP/O in/IN/O Spanish/NNP/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O days/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Peace/NNP/I-ORG Corps/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON actively/RB/O courts/VBZ/O minority/NN/O voters/NNS/O but/CC/O seems/VBZ/O oddly/RB/O over/IN/O his/PRP$/O head/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O warm/JJ/O and/CC/O polished/VBN/O before/IN/O a/DT/O Puerto/NNP/O Rican/NNP/O Congress/NNP/O in/IN/O Asbury/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Yet/RB/O minutes/NNS/O after/IN/O promising/VBG/O to/TO/O appoint/VB/O Hispanics/NNS/O to/TO/O high/JJ/O posts/NNS/O in/IN/O state/NN/O government/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O whether/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O ever/RB/O employed/VBN/O any/DT/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O congressional/JJ/O office/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O we/PRP/O do/VB/O now/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VB/O we/PRP/O did/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
Asked/VBD/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O question/NN/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O appearance/NN/O ,/,/O Democrat/NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON identifies/VBZ/O a/DT/O staff/NN/O member/NN/O by/IN/O name/NN/O and/CC/O explains/VBZ/O her/PRP$/O whereabouts/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O presented/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O poster/NN/O celebrating/VBG/O the/DT/O organization/NN/O 's/POS/O 20th/JJ/O anniversary/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O recognizes/VBZ/O a/DT/O photograph/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O founders/NNS/O and/CC/O recalls/VBZ/O time/NN/O spent/VBD/O together/RB/O in/IN/O Camden/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Details/NNP/O and/CC/O Camden/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O essential/JJ/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Elected/VBN/O to/TO/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O Watergate/NNP/O baby/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O 1974/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O ran/VBD/O for/IN/O governor/NN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O later/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O opinion/NN/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O stopped/VBD/O running/VBG/O since/IN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O he/PRP/O declined/VBD/O a/DT/O rematch/NN/O with/IN/O Gov./NNP/O Kean/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ././O
More/RBR/O than/IN/O ever/RB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O pro-consumer/NN/O and/CC/O pro-environment/NN/O record/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O sync/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
Auto/NN/O insurance/NN/O rates/NNS/O are/VBP/O soaring/VBG/O ././O
In/IN/O Monmouth/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O swing/NN/O area/NN/O ,/,/O Republican/NNP/O freeholders/NNS/O now/RB/O run/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O slogan/NN/O promising/VBG/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O county/NN/O ``/``/O clean/JJ/O and/CC/O green/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON savors/NNS/O this/DT/O vindication/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O at/IN/O age/NN/O 52/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O congressman/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O product/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O times/NNS/O and/CC/O losses/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O speaks/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O death/NN/O penalty/NN/O as/IN/O if/IN/O reading/VBG/O from/IN/O Exodus/NNP/O 21/CD/O ;/:/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O state/NN/O revenue/NN/O he/PRP/O focuses/VBZ/O not/RB/O on/IN/O ``/``/O taxes/NNS/O ''/''/O but/CC/O on/IN/O ``/``/O audits/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O waste/NN/O ././O
Appealing/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O young/JJ/O audience/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O scraps/VBZ/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O reference/NN/O to/TO/O Ozzie/NNP/O and/CC/O Harriet/NNP/O and/CC/O instead/RB/O quotes/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Grateful/NNP/I-ORG Dead/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O lyric/NN/O chosen/VBN/O --/:/O ``/``/O long/JJ/O strange/JJ/O night/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O may/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O apt/JJ/O footnote/NN/O to/TO/O television/NN/O spots/NNS/O by/IN/O both/DT/O candidates/NNS/O intended/VBN/O to/TO/O portray/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O liar/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O lawmaker/NN/O fits/VBZ/O a/DT/O pattern/NN/O of/IN/O younger/JJR/O reformers/NNS/O arising/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O old/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O his/PRP$/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O Camden/NNP/B-GPE remain/VBP/O a/DT/O sore/JJ/O point/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O county/NN/O 's/POS/O past/NN/O corruption/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O campaign/NN/O hierarchy/NN/O is/VBZ/O chosen/VBN/O from/IN/O elsewhere/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O faced/VBN/O with/IN/O criticism/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O sweetheart/NN/O bank/NN/O investment/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O so/RB/O far/RB/O blunted/VBN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O by/IN/O donating/VBG/O the/DT/O bulk/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O profits/NNS/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O alma/JJ/O mater/NN/O ,/,/O Trenton/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG College/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O forcefulness/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON ruling/NN/O divides/VBZ/O some/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O old/JJ/O constituency/NN/O ././O
Pasquale/NNP/B-PERSON Pignatelli/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O unlikely/JJ/O but/CC/O enthusiastic/JJ/O pipe/NN/O major/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O Essex/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE Irish/JJ/O bagpipe/NN/O band/NN/O ,/,/O speaks/VBZ/O sadly/RB/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O support/VB/O him/PRP/O because/IN/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Wames/NNP/I-PERSON Sr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 72/CD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O Catholic/NNP/O too/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O unfazed/JJ/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O stand/NN/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O security/NN/O guard/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O cargo/NN/O terminal/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O wears/VBZ/O a/DT/O Sons/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Italy/NNP/I-ORG jacket/NN/O and/CC/O cap/NN/O celebrating/VBG/O ``/``/O The/DT/O US/NNP/O 1/CD/O Band/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O I/PRP/O still/RB/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O woman/NN/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O body/NN/O as/IN/O she/PRP/O pleases/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O want/VBP/O more/JJR/O opinions/NNS/O ask/VB/O my/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O opinions/NNS/O ././O
