Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Investors/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O lowered/VBD/O its/PRP$/O rating/NN/O on/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O this/DT/O Chatsworth/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O concern/NN/O 's/POS/O convertible/JJ/O subordinated/VBN/O debentures/NNS/O ,/,/O due/RB/O 2012/CD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O Caa/NNP/O from/IN/O B2/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O reduction/NN/O reflects/VBZ/O impaired/VBN/O business/NN/O prospects/NNS/O and/CC/O reduced/VBN/O financial/JJ/O flexibility/NN/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O continuing/VBG/O losses/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O Winchester/NNP/O disk/NN/O drives/NNS/O ././O
VALLEY/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG --/:/I-ORG
Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Investors/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O lowered/VBD/O its/PRP$/O rating/NN/O on/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O this/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O senior/JJ/O debt/NN/O to/TO/O B2/NN/O from/IN/O Ba3/NN/O ././O
