As/IN/O the/DT/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON brothers/NNS/O '/POS/O personal/JJ/O bankruptcy/NN/O cases/NNS/O sputter/VBP/O into/IN/O their/PRP$/O second/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O proposed/VBN/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O its/PRP$/O huge/JJ/O claim/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O troubled/VBN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE oil/NN/O men/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O only/RB/O threatens/VBZ/O to/TO/O heighten/VB/O the/DT/O tension/NN/O and/CC/O confusion/NN/O already/RB/O surrounding/VBG/O the/DT/O cases/NNS/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG now/RB/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O for/RP/O up/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 65.7/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O each/DT/O brother/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O the/DT/O actual/JJ/O amount/NN/O would/MD/O probably/RB/O be/VB/O much/RB/O less/JJR/O ././O
Although/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Abramson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O W./NNP/B-PERSON Herbert/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Peruvian/JJ/O mineral/NN/O concern/NN/O 's/POS/O proposal/NN/O ././O
Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Bunker/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O although/IN/O his/PRP$/O attorney/NN/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O if/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O jeopardizes/VBZ/O a/DT/O tentative/JJ/O settlement/NN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O reached/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Internal/NNP/I-ORG Revenue/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O claims/VBZ/O the/DT/O brothers/NNS/O owe/VBP/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O back/JJ/O taxes/NNS/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O by/IN/O far/RB/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O creditor/NN/O in/IN/O both/DT/O cases/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O tentative/NN/O agreement/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Bunker/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O awaiting/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG approval/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O billionaire/NN/O 's/POS/O assets/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O liquidated/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG getting/VBG/O 80/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proceeds/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O being/NN/O divided/VBN/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O creditors/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Manufacturers/NNP/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O repayment/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 36/CD/O million/CD/O loan/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O similiar/JJ/O proposal/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O W./NNP/B-PERSON Herbert/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON case/NN/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O at/IN/O odds/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O non-dischargable/JJ/O debt/NN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O government/NN/O from/IN/O future/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O both/DT/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Manufacturers/NNP/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O been/VBN/O fighting/VBG/O ferociously/RB/O over/IN/O their/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pie/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O support/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Manufacturers/NNP/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O filed/VBN/O suit/NN/O asking/VBG/O Judge/NNP/O Abramson/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O subordinate/VB/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O claim/NN/O to/TO/O those/DT/O of/IN/O Manufacturer/NNP/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O threatened/VBN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O volcano/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O litigation/NN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O Manufacturers/NNP/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O attempts/VBZ/O to/TO/O force/VB/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O ././O
Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O pursue/VB/O such/JJ/O litigation/NN/O if/IN/O its/PRP$/O settlement/NN/O plan/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O W./NNP/B-PERSON Herbert/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON case/NN/O is/VBZ/O approved/VBN/O by/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Abramson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O consider/VB/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O hearing/NN/O next/IN/O week/NN/O ././O
Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG attorney/NN/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Gorman/NNP/I-PERSON decribed/VBD/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O as/IN/O one/CD/O step/NN/O toward/IN/O an/DT/O overall/JJ/O settlement/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O W./NNP/B-PERSON Herbert/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON case/NN/O but/CC/O Hugh/NNP/B-PERSON Ray/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O attorney/NN/O for/IN/O Manufacturers/NNP/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O called/VBD/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O silly/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O fight/VB/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O court/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O thing/NN/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O fluid/JJ/O right/RB/O now/RB/O that/IN/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O really/RB/O no/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O what/WP/O will/MD/O happen/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG attorney/NN/O Grover/NNP/B-PERSON Hartt/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Developments/NNS/O like/IN/O this/DT/O are/VBP/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O predict/VB/O ././O
