Raymond/NNP/B-PERSON Chandler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O 1950/CD/O letter/NN/O defending/VBG/O a/DT/O weak/JJ/O Hemingway/NNP/B-PERSON book/NN/O ,/,/O likened/VBD/O a/DT/O champion/NN/O writer/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O baseball/NN/O pitcher/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O champ/NN/O has/VBZ/O lost/VBN/O his/PRP$/O stuff/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O great/JJ/O mystery/NN/O novelist/NN/O wrote/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O throw/VB/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O hard/JJ/O one/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O throws/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O heart/NN/O instead/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O throws/VBZ/O something/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O walk/VB/O off/IN/O the/DT/O mound/NN/O and/CC/O weep/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON might/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O predicting/VBG/O the/DT/O course/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O career/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O last/JJ/O published/VBN/O novel/NN/O featuring/VBG/O private/JJ/O detective/NN/O Philip/NNP/B-PERSON Marlowe/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O inferior/JJ/O ``/``/O Playback/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O 1958/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O at/IN/O times/NNS/O read/VBD/O almost/RB/O like/IN/O a/DT/O parody/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O previous/JJ/O work/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O he/PRP/O died/VBD/O in/IN/O 1959/CD/O ,/,/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON left/VBD/O behind/RP/O four/CD/O chapters/NNS/O of/IN/O yet/RB/O another/DT/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON book/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Poodle/NNP/O Springs/NNP/O Story/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O seemed/VBD/O to/TO/O go/VB/O beyond/IN/O parody/NN/O into/IN/O something/NN/O like/IN/O burlesque/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O Champ/NNP/O ''/''/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O last/JJ/O pitch/NN/O ,/,/O apparently/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O screwball/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Parker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O author/NN/O of/IN/O several/JJ/O best/JJS/O sellers/NNS/O featuring/VBG/O Spenser/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O contemporary/JJ/O private/JJ/O eye/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON mold/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O blessings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON estate/NN/O been/VBN/O hired/VBN/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Poodle/NNP/O Springs/NNP/O Story/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O quite/RB/O have/VB/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O special/JJ/O magic/NN/O --/:/O well/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O neither/CC/O did/VBD/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O begins/VBZ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O newly/RB/O wed/VBN/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON roars/VBZ/O into/IN/O the/DT/O desert/NN/O resort/NN/O of/IN/O Poodle/NNP/B-GPE -LRB-/-LRB-/I-GPE a.k.a/JJ/I-GPE ././I-GPE Palm/NNP/I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/I-GPE Springs/NNP/I-GPE at/IN/O the/DT/O wheel/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Cadillac/NNP/B-ORG Fleetwood/NNP/O ././O
His/PRP$/O bride/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O rich/JJ/O and/CC/O beautiful/JJ/O Linda/NNP/B-PERSON Loring/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O character/NN/O who/WP/O also/RB/O appeared/VBD/O in/IN/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Long/NNP/O Goodbye/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Playback/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O the/DT/O lovebirds/NNS/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O conflict/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O setup/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Parker/NNP/B-PERSON spins/VBZ/O it/PRP/O into/IN/O a/DT/O pretty/RB/O satisfying/JJ/O tale/NN/O involving/VBG/O Poodle/NNP/B-GPE Springs/NNP/I-GPE high/JJ/O life/NN/O ,/,/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE low/JJ/O life/NN/O and/CC/O various/JJ/O folk/NN/O who/WP/O hang/VBP/O their/PRP$/O hats/NNS/O in/IN/O both/DT/O worlds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O supporting/JJ/O lineup/NN/O is/VBZ/O solid/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O patter/NN/O is/VBZ/O amusing/JJ/O and/CC/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O even/RB/O a/DT/O cameo/NN/O by/IN/O Bernie/NNP/B-PERSON Ohls/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ``/``/O good/JJ/O cop/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O previous/JJ/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON books/NNS/O who/WP/O still/RB/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O hesitate/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON jailed/VBN/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O suits/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O style/NN/O throughout/IN/O bears/VBZ/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O resemblance/NN/O to/TO/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O prose/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O most/RBS/O pared/VBN/O down/RP/O ././O
All/DT/O told/VBD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Parker/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O a/DT/O better/JJR/O job/NN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O a/DT/O novel/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O abandoned/JJ/O fragment/NN/O than/IN/O anyone/NN/O might/MD/O have/VB/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O expect/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O grounds/NNS/O for/IN/O complaint/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O one/CD/O point/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O reader/NN/O is/VBZ/O two/CD/O steps/NNS/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O catching/VBG/O on/RP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O double/JJ/O identity/NN/O scam/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O pro/NN/O ././O
More/RBR/O bothersome/JJ/O ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O several/JJ/O apparent/JJ/O anachronisms/NNS/O ././O
Contact/NN/O lenses/NNS/O ,/,/O tank/NN/O tops/NNS/O ,/,/O prostitutes/NNS/O openly/RB/O working/VBG/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O of/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O Tequila/NNP/O Sunrise/NNP/O cocktail/NN/O all/DT/O seem/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O place/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1950s/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O little/JJ/O more/JJR/O care/NN/O in/IN/O re-creating/NN/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O universe/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O that/RB/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O enjoyable/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nolan/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O contributing/VBG/O editor/NN/O at/IN/O Los/NNP/B-ORG Angeles/NNP/I-ORG Magazine/NNP/I-ORG ././O
