The/DT/O measure/NN/O provides/VBZ/O no/DT/O money/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O promised/VBN/O payments/NNS/O until/IN/O then/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O beginning/VBG/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O committed/VBN/O to/TO/O meeting/VBG/O annual/JJ/O payments/NNS/O of/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O until/IN/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O liability/NN/O of/IN/O approximately/RB/O $/$/O 1.25/CD/O billion/CD/O is/VBZ/O paid/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O abandons/VBZ/O earlier/JJR/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O find/VB/O offsetting/VBG/O cuts/NNS/O to/TO/O fund/VB/O the/DT/O payments/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O is/VBZ/O widely/RB/O seen/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O realistic/JJ/O means/NNS/O of/IN/O expediting/VBG/O reparations/NNS/O first/RB/O authorized/VBN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O came/VBD/O as/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG sent/VBD/O to/TO/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O bill/NN/O providing/VBG/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 156.7/CD/O billion/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Departments/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Labor/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Education/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Health/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Human/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O veto/NN/O power/NN/O puts/VBZ/O him/PRP/O a/DT/O commanding/VBG/O position/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O narrowly/RB/O divided/VBN/O House/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O override/VB/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O could/MD/O well/RB/O pick/VB/O up/RP/O new/JJ/O support/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O wealth/NN/O of/IN/O health/NN/O and/CC/O education/NN/O programs/NNS/O financed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O underlying/JJ/O bill/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O yesterday/NN/O funds/VBZ/O the/DT/O Departments/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG through/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Elsewhere/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 191.2/CD/O million/CD/O is/VBZ/O preserved/VBN/O for/IN/O assistance/NN/O programs/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ././O
And/CC/O in/IN/O a/DT/O footnote/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O fall/NN/O of/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG Speaker/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O voted/VBD/O to/TO/O rescind/VB/O $/$/O 11.8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O unspent/JJ/O EDA/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O Fort/NNP/B-GPE Worth/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O stockyards/NNS/O project/NN/O that/WDT/O figured/VBD/O in/IN/O ethics/NNS/O charges/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Democratic/JJ/O leader/NN/O ././O
Fiscal/JJ/O pressures/NNS/O also/RB/O forced/VBD/O the/DT/O adoption/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O fees/NNS/O charged/VBN/O by/IN/O federal/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O an/DT/O 18/CD/O %/NN/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG budget/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O financed/VBN/O entirely/RB/O by/IN/O an/DT/O added/VBN/O $/$/O 26/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O filing/NN/O fees/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O unprecedented/JJ/O step/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O anticipates/VBZ/O another/DT/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O receipts/NNS/O by/IN/O having/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Investigation/NNP/I-ORG charge/VB/O for/IN/O fingerprint/NN/O services/NNS/O in/IN/O civil/JJ/O cases/NNS/O --/:/O a/DT/O change/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O almost/RB/O certain/JJ/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG costs/NNS/O in/IN/O processing/VBG/O personnel/NNS/O and/CC/O security/NN/O clearances/NNS/O ././O
Similarly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O adjusts/VBZ/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O funding/VBG/O formula/NN/O to/TO/O promise/VB/O smaller/JJR/O states/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Delaware/NNP/B-GPE a/DT/O minimum/NN/O allocation/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.6/CD/O million/CD/O each/DT/O in/IN/O drug/NN/O grants/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O three/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O minimum/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O odd/JJ/O mix/NN/O of/IN/O departments/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/JJR/O eclectic/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O annual/JJ/O appropriations/NNS/O measures/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O assorted/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O attached/VBN/O by/IN/O lawmakers/NNS/O run/VBP/O from/IN/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O fish/NN/O farm/NN/O in/IN/O Arkansas/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O a/DT/O music/NN/O festival/NN/O in/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE under/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG States/NNP/I-ORG Information/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Lawmakers/NNS/O scrapped/VBD/O all/DT/O of/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 7.4/CD/O million/CD/O State/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG request/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O 1992/CD/O Expo/NNP/O in/IN/O Seville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O agreed/VBD/O elsewhere/RB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 15,000/CD/O for/IN/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O portrait/NN/O of/IN/O former/JJ/O Chief/NNP/O Justice/NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON Burger/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
His/PRP$/O Republican/JJ/O counterpart/NN/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Warren/NNP/B-PERSON Rudman/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O N.H./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O used/VBN/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O to/TO/O wage/VB/O a/DT/O legislative/JJ/O war/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O board/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Legal/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
An/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 321/CD/O million/CD/O is/VBZ/O provided/VBN/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O the/DT/O program/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Rudman/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O succeeded/VBD/O in/IN/O attaching/VBG/O language/NN/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O curb/VB/O the/DT/O authority/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O board/NN/O until/IN/O new/JJ/O members/NNS/O are/VBP/O confirmed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O effective/JJ/O date/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O new/JJ/O regulations/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O board/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O delayed/VBN/O until/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 1/CD/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O seeks/VBZ/O to/TO/O reverse/VB/O efforts/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O corporation/NN/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O off/RP/O funds/NNS/O to/TO/O service/NN/O organizations/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Food/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Action/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG ././O
