Isler/NNP/B-ORG Sailing/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG advisory/JJ/O board/NN/O includes/VBZ/O Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Turner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Cup/NNP/O victor/NN/O ;/:/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Diamandis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O Diamandis/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Vittoria/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Avis/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
His/PRP$/O steering/NN/O committee/NN/O includes/VBZ/O other/JJ/O notable/JJ/O businessmen/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE investor/NN/O and/CC/O old/JJ/O salt/NN/O Roy/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Disney/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O Conner/NNP/B-PERSON team/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O negotiate/VB/O with/IN/O corporate/JJ/O sponsors/NNS/O until/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O is/VBZ/O resolved/VBN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O race/NN/O site/NN/O is/VBZ/O determined/VBN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O syndicate/NN/O 's/POS/O budget/NN/O could/MD/O easily/RB/O reach/VB/O $/$/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG America/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Cup/NNP/I-ORG Organizing/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG insist/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O added/VBN/O competition/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O defender/NN/O 's/POS/O spot/NN/O will/MD/O only/RB/O improve/VB/O the/DT/O race/NN/O ././O
