Mr./NNP/O Glazer/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O immediately/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O Harley/NNP/B-ORG last/JJ/O week/NN/O publicly/RB/O questioned/VBD/O the/DT/O legality/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O filing/NN/O procedures/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Rochester/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O investor/NN/O said/VBD/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O complied/VBD/O with/IN/O every/DT/O law/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O denied/VBD/O any/DT/O wrongdoing/NN/O ././O
Harley/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O intend/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O acquired/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Glazer/NNP/B-PERSON group/NN/O or/CC/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
