Heidi/NNP/B-PERSON Ehman/NNP/I-PERSON might/MD/O have/VB/O stepped/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O recruiting/NN/O poster/NN/O for/IN/O young/JJ/O Republicans/NNS/O ././O
White/JJ/B-PERSON ,/,/O 24/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O singer/NN/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O church/NN/O choir/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O symbolizes/VBZ/O a/DT/O generation/NN/O that/WDT/O gave/VBD/O its/PRP$/O heart/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Polls/NNS/O bear/VBP/O out/RP/O this/DT/O warning/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O after/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O of/IN/O increased/VBN/O Republican/JJ/O influence/NN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O politics/NNS/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O have/VBP/O contributed/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O world/NN/O turned/VBD/O upside/RB/O down/RB/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
This/DT/O change/NN/O comes/VBZ/O less/RBR/O from/IN/O a/DT/O shift/NN/O in/IN/O public/JJ/O opinion/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O changed/VBD/O much/RB/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O than/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O boundaries/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE own/JJ/O highest/JJS/O court/NN/O remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O liberal/JJ/O bulwark/NN/O against/IN/O major/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ruling/NN/O ,/,/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON vs./IN/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O engaged/VBN/O voters/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O insulated/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O recent/JJ/O pro-choice/JJ/O rally/NN/O in/IN/O Trenton/NNP/B-GPE drew/VBD/O thousands/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O reversal/NN/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O defying/VBG/O a/DT/O presidential/JJ/O veto/NN/O and/CC/O demanding/VBG/O that/IN/O Medicaid/NNP/B-ORG abortions/NNS/O be/VBP/O permitted/VBN/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O infusion/NN/O of/IN/O activists/NNS/O can/MD/O bring/VB/O a/DT/O clash/NN/O of/IN/O cultures/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O league/NN/O organizers/NNS/O seem/VBP/O more/JJR/O a/DT/O fit/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O convention/NN/O next/JJ/O door/NN/O of/IN/O young/JJ/O aerobics/NNS/O instructors/NNS/O in/IN/O leotards/NNS/O than/IN/O the/DT/O beefy/JJ/O union/NN/O leaders/NNS/O ;/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O wish/VBP/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O go/VB/O work/VB/O out/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O slim/JJ/O activist/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O labor/NN/O chief/NN/O speaks/VBZ/O sardonically/RB/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O to/TO/O ``/``/O man/VB/O and/CC/O woman/NN/O ''/''/O Election/NNP/O Day/NNP/O phones/NNS/O ././O
No/DT/O age/NN/O group/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O sensitive/JJ/O than/IN/O younger/JJR/O voters/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Ehman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
A/DT/O year/NN/O ago/RB/O this/DT/O fall/NN/O ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE voters/NNS/O under/IN/O 30/CD/O favored/VBN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON by/IN/O 56/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 39/CD/O %/NN/O over/IN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Dukakis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O survey/NN/O then/RB/O by/IN/O Rutgers/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Eagleton/NNP/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Voters/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O age/NN/O group/NN/B-ORG backed/VBD/O Democrat/NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 55/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 29/CD/O %/NN/O over/IN/O Republican/NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Abortion/NN/O alone/RB/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O explain/VB/O this/DT/O shift/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O model/NN/O of/IN/O how/WRB/O so/RB/O personal/JJ/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O can/MD/O become/VB/O a/DT/O baseline/NN/O of/IN/O sorts/NNS/O in/IN/O judging/VBG/O a/DT/O candidate/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O distinction/NN/O that/IN/O satisfies/NNS/O neither/DT/O side/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O ././O
Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Kemp/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O writers/NNS/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON Kristol/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Gilder/NNP/I-PERSON were/VBD/O influences/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O own/JJ/O conservative/JJ/O credentials/NNS/O proved/VBD/O useful/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE GOP/NNP/B-ORG governor/NN/O ,/,/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Kean/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1981/CD/O Republican/NNP/O primary/NN/O here/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O same/JJ/O partnership/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O crucial/JJ/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O fortunes/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O a/DT/O reminder/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O gap/NN/O between/IN/O his/PRP$/O record/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O moderate/JJ/O ,/,/O pro-choice/JJ/O Gov./NNP/O Kean/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Kean/NNP/B-PERSON forces/NNS/O play/VB/O down/IN/O any/DT/O differences/NNS/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O this/DT/O history/NN/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O harder/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O to/TO/O run/VB/O against/IN/O government/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O further/RBR/O hobbled/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O record/NN/O of/IN/O votes/NNS/O opposed/VBN/O to/TO/O government/NN/O regulation/NN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O consumers/NNS/O ././O
Fluent/NNP/O in/IN/O Spanish/NNP/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O days/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Peace/NNP/I-ORG Corps/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Courter/NNP/B-PERSON actively/RB/O courts/VBZ/O minority/NN/O voters/NNS/O but/CC/O seems/VBZ/O oddly/RB/O over/IN/O his/PRP$/O head/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O warm/JJ/O and/CC/O polished/VBN/O before/IN/O a/DT/O Puerto/NNP/O Rican/NNP/O Congress/NNP/O in/IN/O Asbury/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Details/NNP/O and/CC/O Camden/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O essential/JJ/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Auto/NN/O insurance/NN/O rates/NNS/O are/VBP/O soaring/VBG/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON savors/NNS/O this/DT/O vindication/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O at/IN/O age/NN/O 52/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O congressman/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O product/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O times/NNS/O and/CC/O losses/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O speaks/VBZ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O death/NN/O penalty/NN/O as/IN/O if/IN/O reading/VBG/O from/IN/O Exodus/NNP/O 21/CD/O ;/:/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O state/NN/O revenue/NN/O he/PRP/O focuses/VBZ/O not/RB/O on/IN/O ``/``/O taxes/NNS/O ''/''/O but/CC/O on/IN/O ``/``/O audits/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O waste/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O lyric/NN/O chosen/VBN/O --/:/O ``/``/O long/JJ/O strange/JJ/O night/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O may/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O apt/JJ/O footnote/NN/O to/TO/O television/NN/O spots/NNS/O by/IN/O both/DT/O candidates/NNS/O intended/VBN/O to/TO/O portray/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O liar/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O lawmaker/NN/O fits/VBZ/O a/DT/O pattern/NN/O of/IN/O younger/JJR/O reformers/NNS/O arising/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O old/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O his/PRP$/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O Camden/NNP/B-GPE remain/VBP/O a/DT/O sore/JJ/O point/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O county/NN/O 's/POS/O past/NN/O corruption/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O campaign/NN/O hierarchy/NN/O is/VBZ/O chosen/VBN/O from/IN/O elsewhere/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O faced/VBN/O with/IN/O criticism/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O sweetheart/NN/O bank/NN/O investment/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O so/RB/O far/RB/O blunted/VBN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O by/IN/O donating/VBG/O the/DT/O bulk/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O profits/NNS/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O alma/JJ/O mater/NN/O ,/,/O Trenton/NNP/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG College/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O forcefulness/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O issue/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON ruling/NN/O divides/VBZ/O some/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O old/JJ/O constituency/NN/O ././O
Pasquale/NNP/B-PERSON Pignatelli/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O unlikely/JJ/O but/CC/O enthusiastic/JJ/O pipe/NN/O major/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O Essex/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE Irish/JJ/O bagpipe/NN/O band/NN/O ,/,/O speaks/VBZ/O sadly/RB/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Wames/NNP/I-PERSON Sr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 72/CD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O Catholic/NNP/O too/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O unfazed/JJ/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Florio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O stand/NN/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O opinions/NNS/O ././O
