Democracy/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O cruel/JJ/O to/TO/O politicians/NNS/O :/:/O Sometimes/RB/O it/PRP/O forces/VBZ/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O choices/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG opened/VBD/O the/DT/O door/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O politicians/NNS/O are/VBP/O squinting/VBG/O under/IN/O the/DT/O glare/NN/O of/IN/O democratic/JJ/O choice/NN/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O discomfort/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O healthy/JJ/O sign/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O ././O
Republicans/NNS/O are/VBP/O squinting/VBG/O most/RBS/O painfully/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O at/IN/O first/JJS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O fair/JJ/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O been/VBN/O shielded/VBN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O ././O
So/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O abortion/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O question/NN/O for/IN/O litigation/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O legislation/NN/O ,/,/O Republicans/NNS/O could/MD/O find/VB/O political/JJ/O security/NN/O in/IN/O absolutism/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O it/PRP/O matters/VBZ/O ././O
Much/JJ/O of/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE thought/VBD/O it/PRP/O detected/VBD/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O a/DT/O characteristic/JJ/O waffle/NN/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O week/NN/O ././O
Only/RB/O a/DT/O month/NN/O ago/RB/O he/PRP/O 'd/VBD/O warned/VBN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG not/RB/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O legislation/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O abortions/NNS/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O or/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O after/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG passed/VBD/O it/PRP/O anyway/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O hinted/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O compromise/NN/O ././O
Was/VBD/O the/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O once/RB/O was/VBD/O pro-choice/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O later/RBR/O pro-life/JJ/O ,/,/O converting/VBG/O again/RB/O ?/./O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O dance/NN/O was/VBD/O more/JJR/O wiggle/NN/O than/IN/O waffle/NN/O ././O
Pro-life/JJ/O advocates/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG never/RB/O wavered/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O veto/NN/O ././O
Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O a/DT/O pro-life/JJ/O leader/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O suggested/VBD/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O adapted/VBN/O restrictive/JJ/O language/NN/O from/IN/O rape/NN/O and/CC/O incest/NN/O exceptions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O states/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O never/RB/O eager/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O fight/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O happy/JJ/O to/TO/O try/VB/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O why/WRB/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O ``/``/O flexibility/NN/O ''/''/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O Democrats/NNS/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O budge/VB/O ,/,/O pro-life/JJ/O Republicans/NNS/O met/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O Chief/NNP/O of/IN/O Staff/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Sununu/NNP/I-PERSON on/IN/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON quickly/RB/O signaled/VBD/O a/DT/O veto/NN/O ././O
Amid/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O timidity/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O elsewhere/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O about/IN/O to/TO/O offend/VB/O his/PRP$/O most/RBS/O energetic/JJ/O constituency/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG doubters/NNS/O were/VBD/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O House/NNP/B-ORG vote/NN/O ,/,/O 41/CD/O Republicans/NNS/O defected/VBD/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O ,/,/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE Rep./NNP/O Nancy/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON rounded/VBD/O up/RP/O nearly/RB/O as/IN/O many/JJ/O signatures/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON urging/VBG/O him/PRP/O not/RB/O to/TO/O veto/VB/O ././O
Even/RB/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O pro-life/JJ/O stalwart/NN/O as/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Orrin/NNP/B-PERSON Hatch/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O had/VBD/O counseled/VBN/O some/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O compromise/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O manuevering/VBG/O illustrates/VBZ/O an/DT/O emerging/VBG/O Republican/JJ/O donnybrook/NN/O ,/,/O pacified/VBD/O since/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/CD/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O 1988/CD/O GOP/NNP/O convention/NN/O ,/,/O abortion/NN/O was/VBD/O barely/RB/O discussed/VBN/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O though/IN/O delegates/NNS/O were/VBD/O evenly/RB/O divided/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O anti-abortion/JJ/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O a/DT/O passionate/JJ/O statement/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O platform/NN/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O talking/VBG/O to/TO/O herself/PRP/O ././O
Now/RB/O many/DT/O Republicans/NNS/O are/VBP/O listening/VBG/O ././O
They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O frightened/VBN/O by/IN/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O see/VBP/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O especially/RB/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O pro-life/JJ/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG candidates/NNS/O for/IN/O governor/NN/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O pummeled/VBD/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Eddie/NNP/B-PERSON Mahe/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Republican/JJ/O consultant/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O two/CD/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG candidates/NNS/O could/MD/O have/VB/O avoided/VBN/O trouble/NN/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O framed/VBN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O first/RB/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O In/IN/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON Coleman/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O running/VBG/O mate/NN/O ,/,/O Eddy/NNP/B-PERSON Dalton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O are/VBP/O both/DT/O on/IN/O the/DT/O defensive/NN/O for/IN/O opposing/VBG/O abortions/NNS/O even/RB/O in/IN/O cases/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O or/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
But/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG opening/NN/O of/IN/O debate/NN/O may/MD/O have/VB/O changed/VBN/O even/RB/O that/DT/O ././O
Polls/NNS/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O substitute/NN/O for/IN/O principle/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O do/VB/O for/IN/O some/DT/O politicians/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Republican/JJ/O danger/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O abortion/NN/O could/MD/O become/VB/O for/IN/O them/PRP/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O long/RB/O been/VBN/O for/IN/O Democrats/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O divisive/JJ/O litmus/NN/O test/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O already/RB/O that/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O for/IN/O any/DT/O job/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O abortion/NN/O is/VBZ/O even/RB/O remotely/RB/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Caldwell/NNP/B-PERSON Butler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O conservative/JJ/O former/JJ/O congressman/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O barred/VBN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O Legal/NNP/B-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG post/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O he/PRP/O gave/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O answers/NNS/O on/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O the/DT/O president/NN/O 's/POS/O doctor/NN/O ,/,/O Burton/NNP/B-PERSON Lee/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O record/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O 'd/MD/O love/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O surgeon/NN/O general/JJ/O but/CC/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O pass/VB/O the/DT/O pro-life/JJ/O test/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O of/IN/O HHS/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Louis/NNP/B-PERSON Sullivan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O litmus/NN/O test/NN/O could/MD/O yet/RB/O damage/VB/O issues/NNS/O important/JJ/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Republican/JJ/O coalition/NN/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O views/NNS/O on/IN/O health/NN/O care/NN/O and/CC/O welfare/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O much/JJ/O matter/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O HHS/NNP/B-ORG spends/VBZ/O billions/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O ././O
Though/IN/O Democrats/NNS/O can/MD/O gloat/VB/O at/IN/O all/DT/O this/DT/O for/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O contain/VB/O their/PRP$/O glee/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O day/NN/O will/MD/O come/VB/O ././O
Eventually/RB/O even/RB/O Republicans/NNS/O will/MD/O find/VB/O a/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O frame/VB/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O in/IN/O ways/NNS/O that/WDT/O expose/VBP/O pro-choice/JJ/O absolutism/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O The/DT/O pro-choice/JJ/O lobby/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O ././O
-RRB-/-RRB-/O What/WP/O about/IN/O banning/VBG/O abortions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O and/CC/O third/JJ/O trimesters/NNS/O ?/./O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O The/DT/O lobby/NN/O says/VBZ/O no/RB/O again/RB/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Democracy/NN/O is/VBZ/O forcing/VBG/O the/DT/O abortion/NN/O debate/NN/O toward/IN/O healthy/JJ/O compromise/NN/O ,/,/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O unpolarizing/VBG/O middle/NN/O ././O
Roe/NNP/O v./IN/O Wade/NNP/O pre-empted/VBD/O political/JJ/O debate/NN/O ,/,/O so/IN/O the/DT/O extremes/NNS/O blossomed/VBD/O ././O
Now/RB/O the/DT/O ambivalent/JJ/O middle/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O moral/JJ/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O sorts/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O reasserting/VBG/O itself/PRP/O ././O
Within/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O outcome/NN/O in/IN/O most/JJS/O states/NNS/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O that/DT/O abortion/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O restricted/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O completely/RB/O banned/VBN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O voters/NNS/O are/VBP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O politicians/NNS/O usually/RB/O end/VBP/O up/RP/O ././O
