The/DT/O government/NN/O will/MD/O try/VB/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O all/DT/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O managed/VBD/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Asset/NNP/I-ORG Disposition/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O one/CD/O fell/JJ/O swoop/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Seidman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Deposit/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O includes/VBZ/O apartments/NNS/O ,/,/O shopping/NN/O centers/NNS/O ,/,/O office/NN/O buildings/NNS/O and/CC/O undeveloped/JJ/O land/NN/O ././O
FADA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O holds/VBZ/O problem/NN/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O thrifts/NNS/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O closed/VBN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O bailout/NN/O legislation/NN/O was/VBD/O enacted/VBN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O liquidated/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O properties/NNS/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O FADA/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O piecemeal/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O speech/NN/O before/IN/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Methodist/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
