Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O in/IN/O principle/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O five/CD/O branch/NN/O offices/NNS/O from/IN/O Trustcorp/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Toledo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O planned/VBN/O merger/NN/O of/IN/O Trustcorp/NNP/B-ORG into/IN/O Society/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Cleveland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O five/CD/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Erie/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Ottawa/NNP/B-GPE counties/NNS/O in/IN/O northern/JJ/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O total/JJ/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 88/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O purchase/NN/O price/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O established/VBN/O after/IN/O Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG has/VBZ/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O study/VB/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O Banc/NNP/B-ORG One/CD/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Society/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O branches/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O selling/VBG/O the/DT/O Trustcorp/NNP/B-ORG offices/NNS/O could/MD/O avoid/VB/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O with/IN/O regulators/NNS/O over/IN/O excessive/JJ/O concentration/NN/O of/IN/O banking/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O counties/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O merger/NN/O of/IN/O Trustcorp/NNP/B-ORG into/IN/O Society/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O industry/NN/O sources/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O merger/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O place/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1990/CD/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
