Short/JJ/O interest/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O consecutive/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O time/NN/O 4.2/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O its/PRP$/O third/JJ/O consecutive/JJ/O record/NN/O month/NN/O of/IN/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O that/DT/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O dropped/VBD/O to/TO/O 523,920,214/CD/O shares/NNS/O as/IN/O of/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O from/IN/O 547,347,585/CD/O shares/NNS/O in/IN/O mid-September/NN/O ././O
Amex/NNP/B-ORG short/JJ/O interest/NN/O climbed/VBD/O 3/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 53,496,665/CD/O shares/NNS/O from/IN/O 51,911,566/CD/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Amex/NNP/B-ORG short/JJ/O interest/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O heading/VBG/O upward/RB/O since/IN/O mid-December/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O increases/NNS/O in/IN/O each/DT/O month/NN/O since/IN/O then/RB/O except/IN/O at/IN/O mid-July/NN/O ././O
Traders/NNS/O who/WP/O sell/VBP/O short/JJ/O borrow/VBP/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O sell/VBP/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O betting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O 's/POS/O price/NN/O will/MD/O decline/VB/O and/CC/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O buy/VB/O the/DT/O shares/NNS/O back/RB/O later/RBR/O at/IN/O a/DT/O lower/JJR/O price/NN/O for/IN/O return/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O lender/NN/O ././O
Short/JJ/O interest/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O shares/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O been/VBN/O purchased/VBN/O for/IN/O return/NN/O to/TO/O lenders/NNS/O ././O
Fluctuation/NN/O in/IN/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O also/RB/O may/MD/O be/VB/O caused/VBN/O partly/RB/O by/IN/O arbitraging/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O figures/NNS/O occasionally/RB/O include/VBP/O incomplete/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O in/IN/O restricted/JJ/O stock/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O level/NN/O of/IN/O negative/JJ/O sentiment/NN/O measured/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG short/JJ/O interest/NN/O ratio/NN/O slipped/VBD/O to/TO/O 3.36/CD/O from/IN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O 's/POS/O 3.38/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O ratio/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O trading/NN/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O 's/POS/O average/JJ/O trading/NN/O volume/NN/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O convert/VB/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O position/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O suggest/VBP/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ratio/NN/O has/VBZ/O weakened/VBN/O in/IN/O value/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O indicator/NN/O because/IN/O options/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O products/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O hedge/VB/O short/JJ/O positions/NNS/O ././O
Varity/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG led/VBD/O the/DT/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG list/NN/O of/IN/O largest/JJS/O short/JJ/O volumes/NNS/O with/IN/O 12,822,563/CD/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Waste/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG posted/VBD/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O short/JJ/O volume/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE exchange/NN/O ,/,/O up/RB/O 3,383,477/CD/O shares/NNS/O to/TO/O 5,267,238/CD/O ././O
Short/JJ/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG plunged/VBD/O to/TO/O 1,425,035/CD/O shares/NNS/O from/IN/O 2,387,226/CD/O shares/NNS/O a/DT/O month/NN/O earlier/RBR/O ././O
TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG PipeLines/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG led/VBD/O the/DT/O percentage/NN/O decliners/NNS/O ,/,/O dropping/VBG/O to/TO/O 59/CD/O shares/NNS/O from/IN/O 183,467/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG short/JJ/O interest/NN/O volume/NN/O leader/NN/O again/RB/O was/VBD/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O rising/VBG/O to/TO/O 3,820,634/CD/O shares/NNS/O from/IN/O 3,363,949/CD/O ././O
Bolar/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceutical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG posted/VBD/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O volume/NN/O increase/NN/O ,/,/O 552,302/CD/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 2,157,656/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O under/IN/O an/DT/O investigation/NN/O concerning/VBG/O procedures/NNS/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O Food/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG approval/NN/O of/IN/O generic/JJ/O drugs/NNS/O ././O
Bolar/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O denied/VBN/O any/DT/O wrongdoing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O largest/JJS/O volume/NN/O drop/NN/O --/:/O down/RB/O 445,645/CD/O shares/NNS/O to/TO/O 141,903/CD/O --/:/O came/VBD/O in/IN/O shares/NNS/O represented/VBN/O by/IN/O B.A.T/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG American/JJ/O depositary/NN/O receipts/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O facing/VBG/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O proposal/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O financier/NN/O Sir/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Goldsmith/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
First/NNP/B-ORG Iberian/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG led/VBD/O the/DT/O percentage/NN/O increases/NNS/O ,/,/O rising/VBG/O to/TO/O 73,100/CD/O shares/NNS/O from/IN/O 184/CD/O ././O
Nelson/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG dropped/VBD/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O percentage/NN/O basis/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O 1,000/CD/O shares/NNS/O from/IN/O 255,923/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O adjacent/JJ/O tables/NNS/O show/VBP/O the/DT/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG issues/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O a/DT/O short/JJ/O interest/NN/O position/NN/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 100,000/CD/O shares/NNS/O existed/VBD/O as/IN/O of/IN/O mid-October/NN/O or/CC/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O short/JJ/O position/NN/O change/NN/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 50,000/CD/O shares/NNS/O since/IN/O mid-September/NN/O ././O
