Although/IN/O such/JJ/O a/DT/O venture/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O match/VB/O the/DT/O ``/``/O fourth/JJ/O network/NN/O ''/''/O created/VBN/O by/IN/O News/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Fox/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Paramount/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O have/VB/O similar/JJ/O ambitions/NNS/O ././O
Fox/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O also/RB/O owns/VBZ/O six/CD/O TV/NN/O stations/NNS/O ,/,/O provides/VBZ/O programs/NNS/O three/CD/O nights/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O to/TO/O those/DT/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O affiliates/NNS/B-ORG ././O
Paramount/NNP/B-ORG Domestic/NNP/I-ORG TV/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG TV/NNP/I-ORG formed/VBD/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O named/VBN/O Premier/NNP/B-ORG Advertiser/NNP/I-ORG Sales/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O advertising/NN/O in/IN/O programs/NNS/O syndicated/VBN/O by/IN/O both/DT/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O ``/``/O Star/NNP/O Trek/NNP/O :/:/O the/DT/O Next/JJ/O Generation/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O ``/``/O Charles/NNP/O in/IN/O Charge/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Friday/NNP/O the/DT/O 13th/NNP/O :/:/O the/DT/O Series/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O for/IN/O Paramount/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O speculation/NN/O ././O
Calls/NNS/O to/TO/O Shelly/NNP/B-PERSON Schwab/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG TV/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O returned/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O already/RB/O have/VBP/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O TV/NN/O stations/NNS/O ././O
MCA/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O WWOR/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Paramount/NNP/B-ORG last/JJ/O month/NN/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O a/DT/O 79/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG TVX/NNP/I-ORG Broadcast/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG from/IN/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O deal/NN/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 140/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
TVX/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O five/CD/O stations/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O WTXF/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG affiliate/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
One/CD/O broadcasting/NN/O executive/NN/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O co-venture/NN/O would/MD/O target/VB/O stations/NNS/O affiliated/VBN/O with/IN/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG because/IN/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O the/DT/O desirable/JJ/O independent/JJ/O stations/NNS/O in/IN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O cities/NNS/O ././O
Currently/NNP/O ,/,/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG supplies/VBZ/O programs/NNS/O on/IN/O Saturdays/NNP/O ,/,/O Sundays/NNP/O and/CC/O Mondays/NNP/O ,/,/O although/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O weeknights/NNS/O ././O
Jamie/NNP/B-PERSON Kellner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O believe/VBP/O the/DT/O partnership/NN/O of/IN/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O its/PRP$/O affiliates/NNS/O and/CC/O advertisers/NNS/O is/VBZ/O succeeding/VBG/O and/CC/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O To/TO/O make/VB/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O work/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O need/VB/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG affiliates/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O spent/VBD/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O and/CC/O money/NN/O in/IN/O building/VBG/O our/PRP$/O group/NN/O of/IN/O stations/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O ``/``/O appreciate/VB/O ''/''/O another/DT/O company/NN/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O usurp/VB/O its/PRP$/O station/NN/O lineup/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O planning/VBG/O another/DT/O night/NN/O of/IN/O original/JJ/O series/NN/O ././O
Paramount/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O broadcasting/NN/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O plan/VBP/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O theatrical/JJ/O movies/NNS/O produced/VBN/O separately/RB/O by/IN/O Paramount/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O Wednesdays/NNS/O and/CC/O perhaps/RB/O a/DT/O block/NN/O of/IN/O original/JJ/O shows/NNS/O Fridays/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O .../:/O ././O
Why/WRB/O would/MD/O I/PRP/O consider/VB/O giving/VBG/O up/RP/O Fox/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O proven/VBN/O commodity/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O for/IN/O an/DT/O unknown/JJ/O venture/NN/O ?/./O
Fox/NNP/B-ORG attracts/VBZ/O a/DT/O young/JJ/O audience/NN/O with/IN/O shows/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O ``/``/O Married/NNP/O .../:/O With/IN/O Children/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O its/PRP$/O most/RBS/O successful/JJ/O series/NN/O ././O
