Your/PRP$/O Oct./NNP/O 12/CD/O editorial/NN/O ``/``/O Pitiful/NNP/O ,/,/O Helpless/NNP/O Presidency/NNP/O ?/./O ''/''/O correctly/RB/O states/VBZ/O that/IN/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O critical/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O 's/POS/O failure/NN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O plan/NN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O to/TO/O respond/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O timely/JJ/O fashion/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O opportunities/NNS/O to/TO/O oust/VB/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Noriega/NNP/I-PERSON presented/VBD/O by/IN/O the/DT/O attempted/VBN/O military/JJ/O coup/NN/O on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 3/CD/O ././O
My/PRP$/O position/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O founded/VBN/O on/IN/O both/DT/O the/DT/O facts/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O you/PRP/O may/MD/O have/VB/O forgotten/VBN/O ,/,/O public/JJ/O opinion/NN/O about/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O large/JJ/O measure/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O my/PRP$/O investigation/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O involvement/NN/O in/IN/O narcotics/NNS/O smuggling/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O simultaneous/JJ/O work/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE operative/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
The/DT/O public/NN/O made/VBD/O up/RP/O its/PRP$/O mind/NN/O about/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON largely/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hearings/NNS/O I/PRP/O chaired/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Subcommittee/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/I-ORG Terrorism/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Narcotics/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Relations/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O Feb./NNP/O 8/CD/O ,/,/O 9/CD/O ,/,/O 10/CD/O and/CC/O 11/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O again/RB/O on/IN/O April/NNP/O 4/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O during/IN/O those/DT/O hearings/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O first/RB/O learned/VBD/O the/DT/O breadth/NN/O and/CC/O depth/NN/O of/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O criminality/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O enduring/VBG/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O variety/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O former/JJ/O Ambassador/NNP/O to/TO/O Costa/NNP/B-GPE Rica/NNP/I-GPE Francis/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON McNeil/NNP/I-PERSON testified/VBD/O before/IN/O the/DT/O subcommittee/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O knew/VBD/O that/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O involved/VBN/O with/IN/O narcotics/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O decision/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O of/IN/O 1986/CD/O ``/``/O to/TO/O put/VB/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O the/DT/O shelf/NN/O until/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O settled/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O the/DT/O report/NN/O issued/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O subcommittee/NN/O concluded/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Our/PRP$/O government/NN/O did/VBD/O nothing/NN/O regarding/VBG/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O drug/NN/O business/NN/O and/CC/O substantial/JJ/O criminal/JJ/O involvement/NN/O because/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O priority/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O Contra/NNP/O war/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O decision/NN/O resulted/VBD/O in/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O some/DT/O drugs/NNS/O entering/VBG/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNP/I-GPE as/IN/O a/DT/O hidden/JJ/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O war/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O this/DT/O problem/NN/O continued/VBD/O even/RB/O after/RB/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O indictment/NN/O ././O
Throughout/IN/O 1988/CD/O and/CC/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O pressed/VBN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O develop/VB/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O for/IN/O pushing/VBG/O this/DT/O ``/``/O narcokleptocrat/NN/O ''/''/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Regrettably/RB/O ,/,/O two/CD/O administrations/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O row/NN/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O unwilling/JJ/O and/CC/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O any/DT/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O military/JJ/O or/CC/O economic/JJ/O ,/,/O for/IN/O supporting/VBG/O the/DT/O Panamanian/JJ/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O attempts/NNS/O to/TO/O restore/VB/O democracy/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Kerry/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Mass/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O
