Chase/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O purchased/VBN/O an/DT/O option/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O the/DT/O building/NN/O at/IN/O One/CD/O New/NNP/O York/NNP/O Plaza/NNP/O for/IN/O an/DT/O undisclosed/JJ/O sum/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O Sol/NNP/B-PERSON Atlas/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O original/JJ/O lease/NN/O in/IN/O 1970/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O current/JJ/O transaction/NN/O cost/VBD/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O approximately/RB/O $/$/O 140/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Of/IN/O that/DT/O amount/NN/O ,/,/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O was/VBD/O payment/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O land/NN/O underneath/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O was/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O itself/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O building/NN/O houses/VBZ/O about/RB/O 4,500/CD/O Chase/NNP/B-ORG workers/NNS/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O moved/VBN/O to/TO/O downtown/NN/O Brooklyn/NNP/B-GPE after/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O back/JJ/O office/NN/O center/NN/O is/VBZ/O completed/VBN/O in/IN/O 1993/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Chase/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strategy/NN/O to/TO/O consolidate/VB/O its/PRP$/O back/JJ/O offices/NNS/O under/IN/O one/CD/O roof/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O headquarters/NN/O is/VBZ/O located/VBN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O blocks/NNS/O away/RB/O at/IN/O 1/CD/O Chase/NNP/O Manhattan/NNP/O Plaza/NNP/O ././O
As/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O the/DT/O building/NN/O ,/,/O Chase/NNP/B-ORG tried/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Atlas/NNP/B-PERSON estate/NN/O 's/POS/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O shortly/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O October/NNP/O 1987/CD/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O crash/NN/O ././O
Chase/NNP/B-ORG Senior/NNP/O Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Scandalios/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O exercise/VB/O its/PRP$/O option/NN/O after/IN/O bids/NNS/O fell/VBD/O short/RB/O of/IN/O expectations/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Chase/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Atlas/NNP/B-PERSON estate/NN/O were/VBD/O looking/VBG/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O building/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 475/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 375/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O owner/NN/O ,/,/O Chase/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O have/VB/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O cut/VBD/O out/RP/O for/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Chase/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O vacating/VBG/O 1.1/CD/O million/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O space/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O headquarters/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O move/VB/O shortly/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O another/DT/O major/JJ/O building/NN/O tenant/NN/O ,/,/O Thomson/NNP/B-ORG McKinnon/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Thomson/NNP/B-ORG McKinnon/NNP/I-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O likely/RB/O will/MD/O vacate/VB/O the/DT/O premises/NNS/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O liquidation/NN/O ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE real/JJ/O estate/NN/O brokerage/NN/O Edward/NNP/B-ORG S./NNP/I-ORG Gordon/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O have/VB/O the/DT/O difficult/JJ/O task/NN/O of/IN/O finding/VBG/O new/JJ/O tenants/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O striking/JJ/O views/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE harbor/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O building/NN/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O antiquated/JJ/O by/IN/O modern/JJ/O office/NN/O standards/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O Chase/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O approximately/RB/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O asbestos/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O premises/NNS/O ././O
