Others/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O feel/VBP/O confident/JJ/O that/IN/O steps/NNS/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O already/RB/O taken/VBN/O would/MD/O see/VB/O them/PRP/O through/IN/O a/DT/O disaster/NN/O ././O
Preparedness/NN/O involves/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O flashlights/NNS/O and/CC/O fire/NN/O alarms/NNS/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O path/NN/O of/IN/O potential/JJ/O disaster/NN/O have/VBP/O set/VBN/O up/RP/O contingency/NN/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O safe/JJ/O regions/NNS/O ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O transport/VB/O employees/NNS/O there/RB/O and/CC/O resume/VB/O operations/NNS/O quickly/RB/O ././O
That/DT/O means/VBZ/O making/VBG/O sure/RB/O that/IN/O copies/NNS/O of/IN/O vital/JJ/O computer/NN/O software/NN/O and/CC/O company/NN/O records/NNS/O are/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O harm/NN/O 's/POS/O way/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O businesses/NNS/O --/:/O like/IN/O Disneyland/NNP/B-FAC --/:/O claim/VBP/O that/IN/O even/RB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O became/VBD/O isolated/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O crisis/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O feed/VB/O and/CC/O care/VB/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O people/NNS/O for/IN/O as/RB/O long/JJ/O as/IN/O five/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O recommends/VBZ/O that/IN/O employees/NNS/O be/VB/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O everyday/JJ/O office/NN/O items/NNS/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O for/IN/O emergency/NN/O care/NN/O or/CC/O shelter/NN/O ././O
ARCO/NNP/B-ORG maintains/VBZ/O an/DT/O office/NN/O in/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O would/MD/O take/VB/O over/IN/O if/IN/O payroll/NN/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O Pasadena/NNP/B-GPE were/VBD/O disrupted/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O ARCO/NNP/B-ORG plan/NN/O takes/VBZ/O into/IN/O account/NN/O such/JJ/O details/NNS/O as/IN/O which/WDT/O aspects/NNS/O of/IN/O business/NN/O are/VBP/O busier/JJR/O at/IN/O certain/JJ/O times/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O quake/NN/O might/MD/O strike/VB/O ,/,/O priorities/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O assigned/VBN/O to/TO/O departments/NNS/O that/WDT/O should/MD/O be/VB/O brought/VBN/O back/RB/O on/IN/O line/NN/O first/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O computer/NN/O maker/NN/O scrambled/VBD/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O phone/NN/O line/NN/O to/TO/O tell/VB/O manufacturing/NN/O and/CC/O support/NN/O staff/NN/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O home/NN/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
Sales/NNS/O and/CC/O service/NN/O employees/NNS/O were/VBD/O asked/VBN/O to/TO/O report/VB/O to/TO/O work/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O Bay/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/I-LOC clients/NNS/O who/WP/O called/VBD/O with/IN/O computer/NN/O problems/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O confident/JJ/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O prepared/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O maintains/VBZ/O rechargeable/JJ/O flashlights/NNS/O in/IN/O offices/NNS/O and/CC/O changes/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O standby/JJ/O supply/NN/O of/IN/O drinking/NN/O water/NN/O every/DT/O three/CD/O months/NNS/O ././O
Walt/NNP/B-ORG Disney/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Disneyland/NNP/B-FAC in/IN/O Anaheim/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O stocks/VBZ/O rescue/NN/O equipment/NN/O ,/,/O medical/JJ/O supplies/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O enough/JJ/O food/NN/O and/CC/O water/NN/O to/TO/O feed/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 10,000/CD/O visitors/NNS/O for/IN/O as/RB/O long/JJ/O as/IN/O five/CD/O days/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O event/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O calamity/NN/O isolates/VBZ/O the/DT/O theme/NN/O park/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O centers/NNS/O are/VBP/O complete/JJ/O with/IN/O maps/NNS/O detailing/VBG/O utility/NN/O lines/NNS/O beneath/IN/O rides/NNS/O and/CC/O ``/``/O safe/JJ/O havens/NNS/O ''/''/O where/WRB/O people/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O assembled/VBN/O away/RB/O from/IN/O major/JJ/O structures/NNS/O ././O
Vista/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O three/CD/O chemical/NN/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O and/CC/O near/IN/O Lake/NNP/B-GPE Charles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O La./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ``/``/O prepares/VBZ/O for/IN/O every/DT/O hurricane/NN/O that/WDT/O enters/VBZ/O the/DT/B-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC of/IN/I-LOC Mexico/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Keith/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Fogg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O company/NN/O safety/NN/O director/NN/O ././O
Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O ,/,/O an/DT/O Atlantic/NNP/B-LOC storm/NN/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O affect/VB/O Vista/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O wait/VB/O until/IN/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O hours/NNS/O to/TO/O get/VB/O ready/JJ/O for/IN/O hurricanes/NNS/O ././O
You/PRP/O have/VBP/O time/NN/O to/TO/O put/VB/O precautionary/JJ/O mechanisms/NNS/O in/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O notes/VBZ/O a/DT/O Vista/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O ././O
