Raymond/NNP/B-PERSON Chandler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O 1950/CD/O letter/NN/O defending/VBG/O a/DT/O weak/JJ/O Hemingway/NNP/B-PERSON book/NN/O ,/,/O likened/VBD/O a/DT/O champion/NN/O writer/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O baseball/NN/O pitcher/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O throws/VBZ/O something/NN/O ././O
Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON might/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O predicting/VBG/O the/DT/O course/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O career/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O setup/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Parker/NNP/B-PERSON spins/VBZ/O it/PRP/O into/IN/O a/DT/O pretty/RB/O satisfying/JJ/O tale/NN/O involving/VBG/O Poodle/NNP/B-GPE Springs/NNP/I-GPE high/JJ/O life/NN/O ,/,/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE low/JJ/O life/NN/O and/CC/O various/JJ/O folk/NN/O who/WP/O hang/VBP/O their/PRP$/O hats/NNS/O in/IN/O both/DT/O worlds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O supporting/JJ/O lineup/NN/O is/VBZ/O solid/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O patter/NN/O is/VBZ/O amusing/JJ/O and/CC/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O even/RB/O a/DT/O cameo/NN/O by/IN/O Bernie/NNP/B-PERSON Ohls/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ``/``/O good/JJ/O cop/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O previous/JJ/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON books/NNS/O who/WP/O still/RB/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O hesitate/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON jailed/VBN/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O suits/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O style/NN/O throughout/IN/O bears/VBZ/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O resemblance/NN/O to/TO/O Chandler/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O prose/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O most/RBS/O pared/VBN/O down/RP/O ././O
All/DT/O told/VBD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Parker/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O a/DT/O better/JJR/O job/NN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O a/DT/O novel/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O abandoned/JJ/O fragment/NN/O than/IN/O anyone/NN/O might/MD/O have/VB/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O expect/VB/O ././O
Contact/NN/O lenses/NNS/O ,/,/O tank/NN/O tops/NNS/O ,/,/O prostitutes/NNS/O openly/RB/O working/VBG/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O of/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O Tequila/NNP/O Sunrise/NNP/O cocktail/NN/O all/DT/O seem/VBP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O place/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1950s/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O little/JJ/O more/JJR/O care/NN/O in/IN/O re-creating/NN/O Marlowe/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O universe/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O that/RB/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O enjoyable/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Nolan/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O contributing/VBG/O editor/NN/O at/IN/O Los/NNP/B-ORG Angeles/NNP/I-ORG Magazine/NNP/I-ORG ././O
