A/DT/O group/NN/O including/VBG/O Gene/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Phillips/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Southmark/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O William/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Friedman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O former/JJ/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Southmark/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O lowered/VBD/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE real/JJ/O estate/NN/O concern/NN/O to/TO/O 7.7/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O filing/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O sold/VBD/O 455,410/CD/O Southmark/NNP/B-ORG common/JJ/O shares/NNS/O from/IN/O Sept./NNP/O 5/CD/O to/TO/O Oct./NNP/O 5/CD/O for/IN/O 18.75/CD/O cents/NNS/O to/TO/O 25/CD/O cents/NNS/O a/DT/O share/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O filing/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O group/NN/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O 3,481,887/CD/O remaining/VBG/O shares/NNS/O ././O
