Just/RB/O five/CD/O months/NNS/O after/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O swallowed/VBN/O up/RP/O in/IN/O an/DT/O unsolicited/JJ/O takeover/NN/O ,/,/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON Roman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O leaving/VBG/O to/TO/O take/VB/O a/DT/O top/JJ/O post/NN/O at/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 59/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O abruptly/RB/O announced/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O leave/VB/O the/DT/O venerable/JJ/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O whose/WP$/O largest/JJS/O client/NN/O is/VBZ/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O become/VB/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O corporate/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O and/CC/O communications/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O succeed/VB/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Freeman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 57/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O retire/VB/O in/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Freeman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O retire/VB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O ``/``/O executive/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O an/DT/O embarrassing/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O discredit/VB/O banker/NN/O Edmond/NNP/B-PERSON Safra/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG representatives/NNS/O apparently/RB/O influenced/VBD/O the/DT/O publication/NN/O of/IN/O unfavorable/JJ/O articles/NNS/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Safra/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O later/RB/O apologized/VBD/O and/CC/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O contributions/NNS/O to/TO/O charities/NNS/O chosen/VBN/O by/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
Although/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Freeman/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O retiring/VBG/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O work/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O for/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O a/DT/O project/NN/O basis/NN/O ././O
Ad/NN/O industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O surprised/JJ/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O under/IN/O his/PRP$/O direction/NN/O ,/,/O bitterly/RB/O fought/VBD/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O attempt/NN/O by/IN/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE before/IN/O succumbing/VBG/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O ././O
And/CC/O although/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Sorrell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O have/VBP/O gone/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O way/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O publicly/RB/O supportive/JJ/O of/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O close/RB/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON say/VBP/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O unhappy/JJ/O giving/VBG/O up/RP/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O executives/NNS/O also/RB/O cite/VBP/O tension/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O efforts/NNS/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O man/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O costs/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O international/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O had/VBD/O overseen/VBN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG two/CD/O other/JJ/O units/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Scali/NNP/B-ORG McCabe/NNP/I-ORG Sloves/NNP/I-ORG advertising/NN/O agency/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O research/NN/O division/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O those/DT/O units/NNS/O will/MD/O now/RB/O report/VB/O directly/RB/O to/TO/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Known/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O traditional/JJ/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O much/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG mold/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O close/RB/O to/TO/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Robinson/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Aside/RB/O from/IN/O working/VBG/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Robinson/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O the/DT/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG advertising/NN/O account/NN/O for/IN/O about/RB/O 11/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON serves/VBZ/O on/IN/O several/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O charities/NNS/O and/CC/O boards/NNS/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Robinson/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O abrupt/JJ/O management/NN/O change/NN/O sparked/VBD/O widespread/JJ/O speculation/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O pushed/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O top/JJ/O spot/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON flatly/RB/O denied/VBD/O the/DT/O speculation/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O tried/VBN/O several/JJ/O times/NNS/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O ,/,/O offering/VBG/O various/JJ/O incentives/NNS/O and/CC/O in/IN/O one/CD/O instance/NN/O sending/VBG/O a/DT/O note/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O case/NN/O of/IN/O wine/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O The/DT/O wine/NN/O ,/,/O naturally/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O brand/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG client/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O asked/VBD/O me/PRP/O not/RB/O to/TO/O resign/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O implication/NN/O that/IN/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O pushed/VBN/O aside/RB/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O accurate/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O traveling/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Far/NNP/I-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Mr./NNP/O Robinson/NNP/B-PERSON first/RB/O approached/VBD/O him/PRP/O about/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O September/NNP/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O ,/,/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Sutherland/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG commissioner/NN/O from/IN/O Ireland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O also/RB/O a/DT/O serious/JJ/O contender/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG job/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O it/PRP/O ultimately/RB/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O offered/VBD/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O on/IN/O retainer/NN/O to/TO/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O an/DT/O adviser/NN/O on/IN/O international/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O talking/VBG/O on/RB/O and/CC/O off/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O four/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O job/NN/O because/IN/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O terrific/JJ/O opportunity/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O I/PRP/O leave/VBP/O the/DT/O company/NN/O in/IN/O very/RB/O strong/JJ/O hands/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O my/PRP$/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O anyone/NN/O else/RB/O 's/POS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O brushed/VBD/O aside/RP/O reports/NNS/O about/IN/O infighting/NN/O between/IN/O him/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O successor/NN/O at/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O executives/NNS/O could/MD/O hardly/RB/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O different/JJ/O ././O
During/IN/O time/NN/O off/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON tends/VBZ/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O garden/NN/O ;/:/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON confesses/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O fondness/NN/O for/IN/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O fast/JJ/O cars/NNS/O and/CC/O planes/NNS/O ././O
Industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O although/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O executives/NNS/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O clash/VB/O more/RBR/O frequently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG takeover/NN/O brought/VBD/O them/PRP/O closer/RB/O together/RB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O the/DT/O guy/NN/O who/WP/O made/VBD/O him/PRP/O head/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O and/CC/O recommended/VBD/O him/PRP/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/O as/IN/O my/PRP$/O successor/NN/O ././O
Would/MD/O I/PRP/O have/VB/O done/VBN/O all/PDT/O those/DT/O things/NNS/O successively/RB/O if/IN/O I/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O guy/NN/O ?/./O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON asked/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O labeled/VBD/O reports/NNS/O of/IN/O friction/NN/O ``/``/O ridiculous/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O spent/VBD/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O boat/NN/O in/IN/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O oversee/VB/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG public/JJ/O relations/NNS/O and/CC/O government/NN/O affairs/NNS/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O advertising/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O handled/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O operating/NN/O units/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O consider/VBP/O this/DT/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O career/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O will/MD/O sit/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O corporate/JJ/O planning/NN/O and/CC/O policy/NN/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O made/VBD/O up/RP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O and/CC/O operating/NN/O executives/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O departure/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O enormous/JJ/O repercussions/NNS/O at/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Kraft/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Foods/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Mattel/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O move/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O affect/VB/O their/PRP$/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O ././O
``/``/O General/NNP/B-ORG Foods/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O agencies/NNS/O are/VBP/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O agencies/NNS/O '/POS/O work/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Hurwitt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Kraft/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Foods/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Ken/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O my/PRP$/O key/JJ/O contact/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O J./NNP/B-PERSON Nicholas/NNP/I-PERSON Hahn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Cotton/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O represents/VBZ/O cotton/NN/O producers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/O all/RB/O that/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
I/PRP/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O seen/VBN/O or/CC/O talked/VBN/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O some/DT/O analysts/NNS/O questioned/VBD/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O have/VB/O the/DT/O skills/NNS/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O around/RP/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O has/VBZ/O done/VBN/O well/RB/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O flagship/NN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE office/NN/O has/VBZ/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O dismal/JJ/O track/NN/O record/NN/O recently/RB/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O won/VBN/O few/JJ/O new/JJ/O accounts/NNS/O while/IN/O losing/VBG/O big/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Maxwell/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O need/VB/O some/DT/O help/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Norm/NNP/B-PERSON Berry/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O a/DT/O creative/JJ/O inspiration/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O nobody/NN/O has/VBZ/O filled/VBN/O that/DT/O void/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Hill/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O other/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O having/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON succeed/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O make/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O smooth/JJ/O transition/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Graham/NNP/B-PERSON Phillips/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O there/RB/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O knows/VBZ/O the/DT/O culture/NN/O well/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O aggressive/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O apparently/RB/O gets/VBZ/O along/RP/O well/RB/O with/IN/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O Andrew/NNP/B-PERSON Wallach/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O with/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O probably/RB/O a/DT/O reasonable/JJ/O transition/NN/O ././O
Hopefully/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O answer/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O had/VBD/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O ''/''/O
Sale/NN/O of/IN/O Saatchi/NNP/B-ORG Unit/NNP/O Close/RB/O
Computer/NNP/B-ORG Sciences/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O proposed/JJ/O purchase/NN/O price/NN/O for/IN/O Cleveland/NNP/B-ORG Consulting/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O counsels/VBZ/O companies/NNS/O on/IN/O logistics/NNS/O and/CC/O supply/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Lord/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O managing/NN/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O Consultants/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O publication/NN/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Fitzwilliam/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.H./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O an/DT/O industry/NN/O standard/NN/O would/MD/O suggest/VB/O a/DT/O purchase/NN/O price/NN/O of/IN/O between/IN/O one/CD/O and/CC/O two/CD/O times/NNS/O Cleveland/NNP/B-ORG Consulting/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG approximately/RB/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O ././O
Ad/NN/O Notes/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
NEW/JJ/O ACCOUNT/NN/O :/:/O
Billings/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O .../:/O ././O
DIET/NNP/O COKE/NNP/O :/:/O
Details/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O commercial/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O brand/NN/O 's/POS/O 1990/CD/O advertising/NN/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON becomes/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O music/NN/O stars/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Michael/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Whitney/NNP/B-PERSON Houston/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O to/TO/O appear/VB/O in/IN/O ads/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O diet/NN/O drink/NN/O ././O
