It/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O snubbing/NN/O rarely/RB/O seen/VBN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O let/VBD/O alone/RB/O within/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Cranston/NNP/I-PERSON trekked/VBD/O over/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG side/NN/O of/IN/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG Hill/NNP/I-ORG a/DT/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O ago/RB/O and/CC/O volunteered/VBD/O his/PRP$/O testimony/NN/O to/TO/O fellow/JJ/O Democrat/NNP/O Rep./NNP/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Gonzalez/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON arranged/VBD/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O donations/NNS/O to/TO/O Sen./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O various/JJ/O political/JJ/O causes/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O thousands/NNS/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O lawmakers/NNS/O ././O
Lawmakers/NNS/O often/RB/O are/VBP/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O embarrass/VB/O colleagues/NNS/O ,/,/O even/RB/O those/DT/O of/IN/O opposing/JJ/O political/JJ/O parties/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O stickler/NN/O for/IN/O ethical/JJ/O standards/NNS/O who/WP/O refuses/VBZ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O honorariums/NNS/O and/CC/O who/WP/O believes/VBZ/O in/IN/O conducting/VBG/O official/JJ/O business/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O open/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O immediate/JJ/O target/NN/O of/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O inquiry/NN/O is/VBZ/O Danny/NNP/B-PERSON Wall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Thrift/NNP/I-ORG Supervision/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O primed/VBN/O to/TO/O lash/VB/O out/RP/O at/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON when/WRB/O hearings/NNS/O resume/VBP/O Thursday/NNP/O with/IN/O testimony/NN/O by/IN/O two/CD/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O from/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Black/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Mike/NNP/B-PERSON Patriarca/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON relieved/VBD/O them/PRP/O of/IN/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O supervising/VBG/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON expressed/VBD/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O report/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O summoned/VBN/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON last/JJ/O week/NN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O their/PRP$/O testimony/NN/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O raising/VBG/O eyebrows/NNS/O ././O
All/PDT/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O merely/RB/O were/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O fairness/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O constituent/NN/O ././O
Chairman/NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON expresses/VBZ/O sympathy/NN/O for/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Riegle/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O counterpart/NN/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG negotiators/NNS/O included/VBD/O Sens./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Riegle/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O principal/JJ/O sponsor/NN/O ,/,/O Republican/NNP/O Sen./NNP/O Jake/NNP/B-PERSON Garn/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON raised/VBD/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O for/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Doug/NNP/B-PERSON Barnard/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O 1986/CD/O re-election/NN/O campaign/NN/O while/IN/O the/DT/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O was/VBD/O taking/VBG/O his/PRP$/O side/NN/O against/IN/O regulators/NNS/O who/WP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O curb/VB/O risky/JJ/O investments/NNS/O and/CC/O wholesale/JJ/O deposit/NN/O brokering/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O recently/RB/O voted/VBD/O ``/``/O present/RB/O ''/''/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O authorized/VBD/O a/DT/O subpoena/NN/O to/TO/O compel/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O testify/VB/O ,/,/O then/RB/O changed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O yes/UH/O ././O
A/DT/O witness/NN/O set/VBN/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O on/IN/O Thursday/NNP/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O news/NN/O report/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O laundered/VBD/O ''/''/O campaign/NN/O contributions/NNS/O illegally/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O committee/NN/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O summoned/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O predecessor/NN/O ,/,/O Edwin/NNP/B-PERSON Gray/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O characterized/VBN/O the/DT/O five/CD/O senators/NNS/O '/POS/O roles/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O tantamount/JJ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O subvert/VB/O the/DT/O .../:/O regulatory/JJ/O process/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O back/VB/O down/RP/O even/RB/O though/IN/O the/DT/O five/CD/O senators/NNS/O have/VBP/O disputed/VBN/O his/PRP$/O account/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O 1987/CD/O meeting/NN/O ././O
