The/DT/O chips/NNS/O use/VBP/O materials/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O lead/NN/O zirconate/NN/O titanate/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O form/VB/O microscopic/JJ/O switches/NNS/O that/WDT/O retain/VBP/O their/PRP$/O data/NNS/O without/IN/O electricity/NN/O ././O
Developers/NNS/O caution/VBP/O that/IN/O broad/JJ/O applications/NNS/O are/VBP/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O away/RB/O because/IN/O the/DT/O technology/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O fully/RB/O refined/VBN/O ././O
National/NNP/B-ORG Semiconductor/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O ferroelectric/JJ/O technology/NN/O from/IN/O Krysalis/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Albuquerque/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.M/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Military/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O shown/VBN/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O National/JJ/B-ORG says/VBZ/O ,/,/O because/IN/O ferroelectric/JJ/O chips/NNS/O resist/VBP/O atomic/JJ/O radiation/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O means/VBZ/O huge/JJ/O travel/NN/O bills/NNS/O ././O
Video/NNP/B-ORG Telecom/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O markets/VBZ/O videoconferencing/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O with/IN/O court/NN/O reporters/NNS/O to/TO/O wire/VB/O a/DT/O nationwide/JJ/O network/NN/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O depositions/NNS/O by/IN/O live/JJ/O television/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O installed/VBD/O a/DT/O prototype/NN/O system/NN/O that/WDT/O connects/VBZ/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O digital/JJ/O phone/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O attorney/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O use/VB/O the/DT/O network/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O hourly/JJ/O fee/NN/O of/IN/O between/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 400/CD/O ,/,/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O take/VB/O depositions/NNS/O from/IN/O witnesses/NNS/O in/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O connected/JJ/O cities/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O recent/JJ/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG suit/NN/O accuses/VBZ/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O reverse/RB/O engineering/VBG/O a/DT/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG technology/NN/O --/:/O a/DT/O turnabout/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O nation/NN/O of/IN/O champion/JJ/O reverse/JJ/O engineers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O moves/NNS/O illustrate/VBP/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O aggressive/JJ/O attitude/NN/O toward/IN/O patent/NN/O protection/NN/O that/IN/O patent/JJ/O experts/NNS/O say/VBP/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O starting/VBG/O to/TO/O take/VB/O ././O
Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG charges/VBZ/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O has/VBZ/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O fraudulent/JJ/O and/CC/O inequitable/JJ/O conduct/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O procurement/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG patents/NNS/O ''/''/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O MC68030/NNP/O microprocessor/NN/O chip/NN/O ././O
Motorola/NNP/B-ORG either/CC/O denied/VBN/O or/CC/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O various/JJ/O charges/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O mimic/VBP/O the/DT/O brain/NN/O by/IN/O ``/``/O looking/VBG/O ''/''/O at/IN/O an/DT/O image/NN/O ,/,/O extracting/VBG/O the/DT/O fundamentals/NNS/O --/:/O boundaries/NNS/O ,/,/O corners/NNS/O and/CC/O lines/NNS/O --/:/O and/CC/O translating/VBG/O them/PRP/O into/IN/O computer/NN/O data/NNS/O ././O
Sharp/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O the/DT/O set/NN/O of/IN/O chips/NNS/O could/MD/O improve/VB/O fax/NN/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O graphics/NNS/O computers/NNS/O or/CC/O identification/NN/O systems/NNS/O that/WDT/O recognize/VBP/O facial/JJ/O features/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
