The/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Appropriations/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG approved/VBD/O an/DT/O estimated/JJ/O $/$/O 2.85/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O emergency/NN/O funding/NN/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O recovery/NN/O from/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O earthquake/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O further/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O East/NNP/B-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC victims/NNS/O of/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O package/NN/O was/VBD/O termed/VBN/O excessive/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O provoked/VBD/O a/DT/O struggle/NN/O with/IN/O influential/JJ/O California/NNP/B-GPE lawmakers/NNS/O who/WP/O sought/VBD/O unsuccessfully/RB/O to/TO/O add/VB/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O waive/VB/O current/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O to/TO/O expedite/VB/O the/DT/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O funds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O funding/VBG/O is/VBZ/O attached/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O stopgap/JJ/O bill/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O operating/VBG/O through/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 15/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O come/VB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG today/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O under/IN/O pressure/NN/O to/TO/O complete/VB/O action/NN/O before/IN/O midnight/NN/O EDT/NNP/O tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O current/NN/O continuing/JJ/O resolution/NN/O expires/VBZ/O ././O
A/DT/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG budget/NN/O office/NN/O analysis/NN/O estimates/VBZ/O that/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O --/:/O or/CC/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O level/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O bill/NN/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O needed/VBN/O for/IN/O highway/NN/O assistance/NN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O needs/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O rejects/VBZ/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O that/IN/O new/JJ/O appropriations/NNS/O are/VBP/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O disaster/NN/O loans/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Small/NNP/I-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Whitten/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O package/NN/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O accomplish/VB/O this/DT/O purpose/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O state/NN/O faces/VBZ/O more/JJR/O resistance/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O extended/JJ/O waiver/NN/O on/IN/O having/VBG/O to/TO/O put/VB/O up/RP/O any/DT/O matching/JJ/O funds/NNS/O on/IN/O repairs/NNS/O completed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O member/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG leadership/NN/O and/CC/O skilled/JJ/O legislator/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Fazio/NNP/B-PERSON nonetheless/RB/O found/VBD/O himself/PRP/O burdened/VBN/O not/RB/O only/RB/O by/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O needs/NNS/O but/CC/O by/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O amendments/NNS/O he/PRP/O accepted/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O vain/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O support/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O appeared/VBD/O embarrassed/JJ/O by/IN/O provisions/NNS/O inserted/VBN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O owners/NNS/O of/IN/O private/JJ/O beaches/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Virgin/NNP/I-GPE Islands/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O lumber/NN/O interests/NNS/O sought/VBD/O to/TO/O add/VB/O another/DT/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O plant/NN/O timber/NN/O on/IN/O private/JJ/O land/NN/O in/IN/O North/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/I-GPE South/NNP/I-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE ././O
One/CD/O provision/NN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O raised/VBN/O the/DT/O cap/NN/O on/IN/O disaster/NN/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O from/IN/O $/$/O 100,000/CD/O per/IN/O household/NN/O to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE losses/NNS/O ././O
