Detrex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O say/VB/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O post/VB/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
Detrex/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O setting/VBG/O aside/RP/O $/$/O 3.1/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O cleanup/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O reserve/NN/O reduced/VBD/O its/PRP$/O quarterly/JJ/O income/NN/O by/IN/O only/RB/O $/$/O 1.9/CD/O million/CD/O because/IN/O of/IN/O tax/NN/O considerations/NNS/O ././O
Detrex/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 17/CD/O companies/NNS/O notified/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Environmental/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG that/IN/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O potentially/RB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O cleaning/VBG/O up/RP/O the/DT/O Fields/NNP/B-LOC Brook/NNP/I-LOC watershed/NN/O near/IN/O Detrex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Ashtabula/NN/B-GPE plant/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O cost/NN/O the/DT/O EPA/NNP/B-ORG estimates/NNS/O at/IN/O $/$/O 48/CD/O million/CD/O --/:/O a/DT/O figure/NN/O Detrex/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O dispute/VBP/O ././O
