Mr./NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O case/NN/O was/VBD/O particularly/RB/O nettlesome/JJ/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O marked/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O official/NN/O was/VBD/O impeached/VBN/O and/CC/O removed/VBN/O from/IN/O office/NN/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O a/DT/O jury/NN/O had/VBD/O acquitted/VBN/O him/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O only/RB/O the/DT/O sixth/JJ/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O ever/RB/O ousted/VBN/O from/IN/O office/NN/O after/IN/O an/DT/O impeachment/NN/O trial/NN/O ././O
Conviction/NN/O on/IN/O any/DT/O single/JJ/O impeachment/NN/O article/NN/O was/VBD/O enough/JJ/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O Judge/NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON from/IN/O office/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O found/VBN/O not/RB/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O three/CD/O charges/NNS/O ,/,/O involving/VBG/O accusations/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBN/O improperly/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O information/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O sensitive/JJ/O ,/,/O government/NN/O investigation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O vote/VB/O on/IN/O six/CD/O lesser/JJR/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O appointed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O bench/NN/O by/IN/O President/NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O 1979/CD/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O few/JJ/O black/JJ/O federal/JJ/O judges/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
