Kurzweil/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Waltham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O makes/VBZ/O digital/JJ/O electronic/JJ/O keyboard/NN/O instruments/NNS/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O professional/JJ/O recording/VBG/O musicians/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O recently/RB/O introduced/VBD/O a/DT/O line/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O home/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O Raymond/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Kurzweil/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O ``/``/O The/DT/O company/NN/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O require/VB/O additional/JJ/O funding/NN/O to/TO/O realize/VB/O the/DT/O potential/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O technology/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O Kurzweil/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 6.9/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 11.2/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O its/PRP$/O president/NN/O ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Donnelly/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O resigned/VBD/O citing/VBG/O ``/``/O management/NN/O differences/NNS/O ''/''/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Kurzweil/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
