Young/JJ/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O first/JJ/O violin/NN/O teacher/NN/O was/VBD/O Henrik/NNP/B-PERSON Schwarzenberger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Hungarian/JJ/O refugee/NN/O who/WP/O taught/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Macon/NNP/B-GPE public/JJ/O school/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O only/RB/O put/VBD/O her/PRP$/O foot/NN/O down/RP/O twice/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O continues/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O second/JJ/O incident/NN/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON gave/VBD/O an/DT/O ambitious/JJ/O student/NN/O recital/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O feeling/VBG/O rather/RB/O pleased/JJ/O with/IN/O himself/PRP/O ././O
Miss/NNP/O DeLay/NNP/B-PERSON requested/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O come/VB/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O studio/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O tape/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O recital/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O why/WRB/O Barber/NNP/B-PERSON never/RB/O told/VBD/O anybody/NN/O else/RB/O ././O
His/PRP$/O guest/JJ/O appearance/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG soap/NN/O opera/NN/O ``/``/O Another/DT/O World/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O scandalized/VBD/O musical/JJ/O elitists/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sweet/JJ/O tone/NN/O ,/,/O heartfelt/JJ/O lyricism/NN/O and/CC/O rhythmic/JJ/O punch/NN/O make/VBP/O him/PRP/O an/DT/O ideal/JJ/O interpreter/NN/O of/IN/O both/DT/O works/NNS/O ././O
His/PRP$/O performance/NN/O was/VBD/O so/RB/O effusive/JJ/O and/CC/O driven/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O phrases/NNS/O rarely/RB/O breathed/VBD/O ././O
Whatever/WDT/O he/PRP/O plays/VBZ/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON finds/VBZ/O satisfaction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O music/NN/O itself/PRP/O --/:/O ``/``/O something/NN/O greater/JJR/O out/RB/O there/RB/O than/IN/O me/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O puts/VBZ/O it/PRP/O during/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE apartment/NN/O he/PRP/O shares/VBZ/O with/IN/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Camille/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O literary/JJ/O publicist/NN/O ././O
