I/PRP/O knew/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O someone/NN/O important/JJ/O ,/,/O so/IN/O I/PRP/O followed/VBD/O her/PRP/O into/IN/O the/DT/O ladies/NNS/O room/NN/O and/CC/O sure/RB/O enough/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O Liza/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Some/DT/O people/NNS/O must/MD/O drop/VB/O names/NNS/O --/:/O call/VB/O it/PRP/O an/DT/O irresistible/JJ/O impulse/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Revson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O gossip/NN/O columnist/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O actually/RB/O plan/VBP/O whose/WP$/O names/NNS/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O before/IN/O attending/VBG/O a/DT/O party/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O droppers/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O flaunt/VB/O only/RB/O their/PRP$/O friendships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Trumps/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O Brooke/NNP/B-PERSON Astor/NNP/I-PERSON or/CC/O Georgette/NNP/B-PERSON Mosbacher/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Some/DT/O people/NNS/O call/VBP/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O The/NNP/B-GPE Mistake/NNP/I-GPE on/IN/I-GPE the/NNP/I-GPE Lake/NNP/I-GPE ''/''/O --/:/O Lake/NNP/B-LOC Erie/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O ././O
Len/NNP/B-PERSON Kessler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O publicist/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O sometimes/RB/O uses/VBZ/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O attention/NN/O of/IN/O journalists/NNS/O who/WP/O try/VBP/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O him/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Dorfman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O columnist/NN/O with/IN/O USA/NNP/B-ORG Today/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O returned/VBD/O his/PRP$/O phone/NN/O calls/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O leaves/VBZ/O messages/NNS/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dorfman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O office/NN/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O story/NN/O on/IN/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Trump/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Meshulam/NNP/B-PERSON Riklis/NNP/I-PERSON or/CC/O Marvin/NNP/B-PERSON Davis/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O admits/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O story/NN/O on/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O on/IN/O these/DT/O occasions/NNS/O ././O
Jeffry/NNP/B-PERSON Thal/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O publicity/NN/O agent/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Lantz/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O warns/VBZ/O that/IN/O dropping/VBG/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O name/NN/O labels/VBZ/O the/DT/O dropper/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O fake/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O fraud/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O only/RB/O drop/VBP/O ``/``/O mere/JJ/O names/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Churchill/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
