Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG loves/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O intimate/JJ/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O customers/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O public/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O a/DT/O vanishing/VBG/O breed/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O muses/NNS/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/B-PERSON Coleman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 73/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O interviewed/VBN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG strategist/NN/O ././O
Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O profitable/JJ/O but/CC/O declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O specifics/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O sells/VBZ/O image/NN/O ././O
Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG generated/VBD/O such/JJ/O memorable/JJ/O campaigns/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O dreamed/VBD/O I/PRP/O .../:/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG bra/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG woman/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O never/RB/O know/VBP/O where/WRB/O she/PRP/O 'll/MD/O turn/VB/O up/RP/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O Capitalizing/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O brand/NN/O is/VBZ/O key/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O immediate/JJ/O plans/NNS/O include/VBP/O further/JJ/O international/JJ/O expansion/NN/O and/CC/O getting/VBG/O better/JJR/O control/NN/O of/IN/O distribution/NN/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O industry/NN/O is/VBZ/O perceived/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O growth/NN/O industry/NN/O and/CC/O clearly/RB/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG -RCB-/-RRB-/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O force/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O reckoned/VBN/O with/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Leibowitz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O situations/NNS/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Although/IN/O working/VBG/O women/NNS/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O wear/VB/O the/DT/O uniform/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O retain/VB/O their/PRP$/O femininity/NN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O buying/VBG/O better/JJR/O quality/NN/O ,/,/O more/RBR/O upscale/JJ/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Although/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O appointment/NN/O as/IN/O president/NN/O was/VBD/O long/RB/O expected/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O move/NN/O on/IN/O Sept./NNP/O 25/CD/O precipitated/VBD/O the/DT/O resignation/NN/O of/IN/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Lesk/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O merchandising/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O days/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Olga/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O competing/VBG/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O division/NN/O of/IN/O Warnaco/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Warnaco/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O owns/VBZ/O Warners/NNS/B-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O major/JJ/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O maker/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O after/IN/O spending/VBG/O 24/CD/O years/NNS/O at/IN/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 48/CD/O ,/,/O made/VBD/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O he/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O job/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O want/VBP/O the/DT/O presidency/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O to/TO/O work/VB/O for/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Mogan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 45/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O assuming/VBG/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O responsibilities/NNS/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O downplayed/VBD/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O split/VBD/O his/PRP$/O merchandising/NN/O responsibilities/NNS/O among/IN/O a/DT/O committee/NN/O of/IN/O four/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O My/PRP$/O style/NN/O is/VBZ/O less/RBR/O informal/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Top/JJ/O officers/NNS/O insist/VBP/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O greatest/JJS/O strength/NN/O is/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O family/NN/O ownership/NN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O go/VB/O anywhere/RB/O in/IN/O this/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O find/VB/O an/DT/O organizational/JJ/O chart/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O one/PRP/O delights/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O fun/NN/O competing/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O can/MD/O think/VB/O long/JJ/O range/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Other/JJ/O major/JJ/O players/NNS/O in/IN/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O apparently/RB/O feel/VBP/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O way/NN/O ././O
Warnaco/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O taken/VBN/O private/JJ/O by/IN/O Spectrum/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1986/CD/O for/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 487/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
And/CC/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Playtex/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG went/VBD/O private/JJ/O for/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 680/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Publicly/RB/O traded/VBN/O VF/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O Vanity/NNP/B-ORG Fair/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Sara/NNP/B-ORG Lee/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O Bali/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O strong/JJ/O forces/NNS/O in/IN/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O he/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O calls/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O consult/VB/O ''/''/O with/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Masket/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O could/MD/O command/VB/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O price/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O along/RB/O with/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP/O daughter/NN/O ,/,/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O vice/RB/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O family/NN/O members/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O employs/VBZ/O about/RB/O 5,000/CD/O ././O
Each/DT/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O equal/JJ/O vote/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O monthly/JJ/O meetings/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O all/RB/O very/RB/O amiable/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1960s/NNS/O she/PRP/O designed/VBD/O a/DT/O lightweight/JJ/O stretch/JJ/O bra/NN/O that/WDT/O boosted/VBD/O sales/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Rosenthal/NNP/B-PERSON introduced/VBD/O new/JJ/O undergarment/NN/O designs/NNS/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Ida/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O concentrated/VBD/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O financial/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O name/NN/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O coined/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O business/NN/O partner/NN/O ,/,/O Enid/NNP/B-PERSON Bissett/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O 14/CD/O plants/NNS/O and/CC/O distribution/NN/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O other/JJ/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Caribbean/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Ireland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG products/NNS/O are/VBP/O mainly/RB/O sold/VBN/O at/IN/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O quietly/RB/O opened/VBN/O a/DT/O retail/JJ/O store/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O in/IN/O Omaha/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Neb./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O 24/CD/O factory/NN/O outlets/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O add/VB/O more/JJR/O ././O
Before/IN/O joining/VBG/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O 1972/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O holds/VBZ/O a/DT/O doctoral/JJ/O degree/NN/O in/IN/O English/NNP/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O taught/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Wisconsin/NNP/I-ORG ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O headed/VBN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O designer/NN/O lingerie/NN/O division/NN/O ,/,/O Oscar/NNP/B-ORG de/IN/I-ORG la/DT/I-ORG Renta/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O since/IN/O its/PRP$/O inception/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
To/TO/O maintain/VB/O exclusivity/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O designer/NN/O line/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O labeled/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG name/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O husband/NN/O ,/,/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O physician/NN/O ,/,/O succeeded/VBD/O Mrs./NNP/O Rosenthal/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O served/VBD/O in/IN/O that/DT/O post/NN/O until/IN/O his/PRP$/O death/NN/O in/IN/O 1968/CD/O ././O
