Exxon/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG filed/VBD/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O charging/VBG/O state/NN/O officials/NNS/O interfered/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O initial/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O treat/VB/O last/JJ/O spring/NN/O 's/POS/O giant/JJ/O oil/NN/O spill/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O counterclaim/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O suit/NN/O filed/VBN/O by/IN/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O August/NNP/O against/IN/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O six/CD/O other/JJ/O oil/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O suit/NN/O alleges/VBZ/O that/IN/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O response/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O spill/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O contamination/NN/O of/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O miles/NNS/O of/IN/O shoreline/NN/O along/IN/O Prince/NNP/B-LOC William/NNP/I-LOC Sound/NNP/I-LOC ././O
That/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O countersuit/NN/O were/VBD/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O state/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Anchorage/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Neither/DT/O suit/NN/O lists/VBZ/O specific/JJ/O dollar/NN/O claims/NNS/O ,/,/O largely/RB/O because/IN/O damage/NN/O assessment/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O been/VBN/O completed/VBN/O ././O
Legal/JJ/O strategists/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O damage/NN/O claims/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O giant/NN/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O could/MD/O well/RB/O exceed/VB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Litigation/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O not/RB/O settled/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O court/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O drag/VB/O on/RP/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O ././O
Exxon/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O suit/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O seek/VB/O reimbursement/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O for/IN/O that/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cleanup/NN/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O damage/NN/O claims/NNS/O it/PRP/O says/VBZ/O resulted/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O conduct/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O oil/NN/O company/NN/O claims/VBZ/O that/IN/O Alaskan/JJ/O officials/NNS/O prevented/VBD/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG from/IN/O spraying/VBG/O dispersant/NN/O onto/IN/O the/DT/O almost/RB/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O gallons/NNS/O of/IN/O oil/NN/O dumped/VBN/O when/WRB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O tankers/NNS/O ran/VBD/O into/IN/O an/DT/O underwater/JJ/O reef/NN/O ././O
Craig/NNP/B-PERSON Tillery/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O Alaska/NNP/B-GPE assistant/JJ/O attorney/NN/O general/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O that/IN/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O accusations/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O new/JJ/O ././O
Exxon/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O them/PRP/O before/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O which/WDT/O point/NN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O demonstrated/VBD/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O untrue/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O will/MD/O vigorously/RB/O defend/VB/O against/IN/O any/DT/O counterclaim/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Since/IN/O the/DT/O spill/NN/O last/JJ/O March/NNP/O ,/,/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O state/NN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O wrangling/VBG/O over/IN/O whether/IN/O spraying/VBG/O dispersant/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O hours/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O spill/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O weather/NN/O was/VBD/O clear/JJ/O and/CC/O calm/JJ/O ,/,/O would/MD/O have/VB/O helped/VBN/O limit/VB/O the/DT/O environmental/JJ/O damage/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O oil/NN/O company/NN/O claims/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O permission/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Environmental/NNP/I-ORG Protection/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG prior/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O spill/NN/O to/TO/O use/VB/O dispersant/NN/O during/IN/O such/PDT/O an/DT/O incident/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O discretion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Coast/NNP/I-ORG Guard/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O dispersants/NNS/O ,/,/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O ,/,/O caused/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Coast/NNP/I-ORG Guard/NNP/I-ORG ``/``/O to/TO/O delay/VB/O granting/VBG/O permission/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Alaskan/JJ/O and/CC/O Coast/NNP/B-ORG Guard/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O charges/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O relevant/JJ/O because/IN/O tests/NNS/O conducted/VBN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O two/CD/O days/NNS/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O spill/NN/O showed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O dispersant/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O working/VBG/O anyway/RB/O ././O
Use/NN/O of/IN/O dispersants/NNS/O was/VBD/O approved/VBN/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O test/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O day/NN/O showed/VBD/O some/DT/O positive/JJ/O results/NNS/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
