GAF/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Part/NNP/O III/NNP/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O two/CD/O mistrials/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O stakes/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O manipulation/NN/O trial/NN/O of/IN/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON T./NNP/I-PERSON Sherwin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O have/VBP/O changed/VBN/O considerably/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O credibility/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG case/NN/O depended/VBD/O heavily/RB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O star/JJ/O witness/NN/O ,/,/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Jefferies/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE brokerage/NN/O chief/NN/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O implicated/VBN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O arbitrager/NN/O Ivan/NNP/B-PERSON Boesky/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O then/RB/O pointed/VBD/O the/DT/O finger/NN/O at/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sherwin/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O takeover/NN/O speculator/NN/O Salim/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Lewis/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O corporate/JJ/O raider/NN/O Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Bilzerian/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG trials/NNS/O were/VBD/O viewed/VBN/O as/IN/O previews/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O strength/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O cases/NNS/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lewis/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Bilzerian/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Jefferies/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O performance/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O witness/NN/O was/VBD/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O affect/VB/O his/PRP$/O sentencing/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG trial/NN/O ended/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O mistrial/NN/O after/IN/O four/CD/O weeks/NNS/O when/WRB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/O Judge/NNP/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON Lowe/NNP/I-PERSON found/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O prosecutor/NN/O improperly/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O unintentionally/RB/O ,/,/O withheld/VBD/O a/DT/O document/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O 93/CD/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O deliberation/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O jurors/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O trial/NN/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O hopelessly/RB/O deadlocked/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O another/DT/O mistrial/NN/O was/VBD/O declared/VBN/O on/IN/O March/NNP/O 22/CD/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O jury/NN/O found/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bilzerian/NNP/B-PERSON guilty/JJ/O on/IN/O securities/NNS/O fraud/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O charges/NNS/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O ././O
A/DT/O month/NN/O later/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Jefferies/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O spared/VBN/O a/DT/O jail/NN/O term/NN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O who/WP/O praised/VBD/O him/PRP/O for/IN/O helping/VBG/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lewis/NNP/B-PERSON pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O three/CD/O felony/NN/O counts/NNS/O ././O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O stakes/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O high/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O players/NNS/O directly/RB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG case/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O mistrials/NNS/O have/VBP/O left/VBN/O the/DT/O reputations/NNS/O of/IN/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sherwin/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Samuel/NNP/B-PERSON Heyman/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O limbo/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sherwin/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O conviction/NN/O could/MD/O carry/VB/O penalties/NNS/O of/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O fine/JJ/O on/IN/O each/DT/O count/NN/O ././O
GAF/NNP/B-ORG faces/VBZ/O potential/JJ/O fines/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O for/IN/O each/DT/O count/NN/O ././O
Individuals/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O throughout/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O defense/NN/O attorneys/NNS/O were/VBD/O talking/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O a/DT/O trial/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O month/NN/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O had/VBD/O ended/VBN/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O much/JJ/O speculation/NN/O among/IN/O attorneys/NNS/O not/RB/O involved/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O strategy/NN/O of/IN/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON Liman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Sherwin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O counsel/NN/O ,/,/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Kaufman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O will/MD/O include/VB/O testimony/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sherwin/NNP/B-PERSON or/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Heyman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Neither/DT/O testified/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O trials/NNS/O ././O
Max/NNP/B-PERSON Gitter/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O another/DT/O GAF/NNP/B-ORG defense/NN/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O As/IN/O we/PRP/O go/VBP/O in/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Yogi/NNP/B-PERSON Berra/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON famous/JJ/O line/NN/O is/VBZ/O apt/JJ/O :/:/O `/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O deja/NN/O vu/NN/O all/RB/O over/RB/O again/RB/O ././O '/''/O ''/''/O
The/DT/O dispute/NN/O pits/VBZ/O two/CD/O groups/NNS/O of/IN/O claimants/NNS/O against/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
Baltimore/NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Pretl/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O 17/CD/O other/JJ/O attorneys/NNS/O representing/VBG/O 18,136/CD/O claimants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O abroad/RB/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O appeal/NN/O would/MD/O delay/VB/O --/:/O and/CC/O perhaps/RB/O even/RB/O destroy/VB/O --/:/O a/DT/O $/$/O 2.38/CD/O billion/CD/O settlement/NN/O fund/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O centerpiece/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O latter/JJ/O provision/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O legally/RB/O unprecedented/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Morrison/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O interest/NN/O lawyer/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O D.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O challenging/VBG/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O 900/CD/O claimants/NNS/O ././O
More/JJR/O than/IN/O 100,000/CD/O claims/NNS/O against/IN/O Robins/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O pending/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O made/VBD/O and/CC/O marketed/VBD/O the/DT/O Dalkon/NNP/O Shield/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1970s/NNS/O amid/IN/O mounting/VBG/O evidence/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O cause/VB/O serious/JJ/O injuries/NNS/O ././O
Robins/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O proceedings/NNS/O under/IN/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O since/IN/O August/NNP/O 1985/CD/O ;/:/O such/JJ/O proceedings/NNS/O give/VBP/O it/PRP/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditor/NN/O lawsuits/NNS/O while/IN/O it/PRP/O works/VBZ/O out/RP/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O for/IN/O paying/VBG/O its/PRP$/O debts/NNS/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Robins/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O only/RB/O if/IN/O all/DT/O legal/JJ/O challenges/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O are/VBP/O exhausted/VBN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O brief/NN/O filed/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Pretl/NNP/B-PERSON criticizes/VBZ/O the/DT/O appeal/NN/O for/IN/O raising/VBG/O ``/``/O abstract/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O theoretical/JJ/O ''/''/O legal/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O jeopardizing/VBG/O the/DT/O proposed/JJ/O reorganization/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O payments/NNS/O to/TO/O claimants/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O the/DT/O case/NN/O Nov./NNP/O 3/CD/O and/CC/O may/MD/O issue/VB/O a/DT/O decision/NN/O as/RB/O early/RB/O as/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 6/CD/O ././O
JURY/NN/O 'S/POS/O CRIMINAL/JJ/O CONVICTION/NN/O under/IN/O Superfund/NNP/O law/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O first/JJ/O ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Donohoo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O sole/JJ/O proprieter/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ky./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O demolition/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O found/VBN/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O violating/VBG/O the/DT/O Superfund/NNP/O law/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Clean/NNP/O Air/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
Criminal/JJ/O convictions/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Superfund/NNP/O law/NN/O are/VBP/O rare/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O jury/NN/O verdict/NN/O in/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O Superfund/NNP/O ,/,/O those/DT/O who/WP/O owned/VBD/O ,/,/O generated/VBD/O or/CC/O transported/VBD/O hazardous/JJ/O waste/NN/O are/VBP/O liable/JJ/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O cleanup/NN/O ,/,/O regardless/RB/O of/IN/O whether/IN/O their/PRP$/O actions/NNS/O were/VBD/O legal/JJ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Environmental/JJ/O lawyers/NNS/O say/VBP/O virtually/RB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Superfund/NNP/O cases/NNS/O to/TO/O date/NN/O have/VBP/O involved/VBN/O civil/JJ/O penalties/NNS/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O insure/VB/O cleanup/NN/O of/IN/O past/JJ/O polluting/VBG/O activities/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Superfund/NNP/O also/RB/O contains/VBZ/O a/DT/O criminal/JJ/O provision/NN/O concerning/VBG/O the/DT/O release/NN/O of/IN/O toxic/JJ/O substances/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1986/CD/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG strengthened/VBD/O the/DT/O penalty/NN/O by/IN/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O felony/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Donohoo/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O convicted/VBN/O in/IN/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE late/RB/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O of/IN/O violating/VBG/O Superfund/NNP/O by/IN/O failing/VBG/O to/TO/O report/VB/O the/DT/O release/NN/O of/IN/O asbestos/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O building/NN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O demolishing/VBG/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O also/RB/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O failing/VBG/O to/TO/O properly/RB/O remove/VB/O asbestos/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Clean/NNP/O Air/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O sought/VBD/O a/DT/O criminal/JJ/O penalty/NN/O because/IN/O ``/``/O no/DT/O cleanup/NN/O is/VBZ/O possible/JJ/O here/RB/O ././O
Once/RB/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O asbestos/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O is/VBZ/O released/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O environment/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O lodge/VB/O anywhere/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Dennis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O assistant/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O who/WP/O prosecuted/VBD/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Donohoo/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sentenced/VBN/O Dec./NNP/O 11/CD/O ././O
His/PRP$/O lawyer/NN/O could/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Donohoo/NNP/B-PERSON faces/NNS/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O fine/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Superfund/NNP/O conviction/NN/O and/CC/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O one/CD/O year/NN/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O $/$/O 100,000/CD/O fine/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Clean/NNP/O Air/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O key/JJ/O issue/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O law/NN/O firm/NN/O is/VBZ/O handling/VBG/O without/IN/O a/DT/O fee/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O pro/FW/O bono/FW/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O a/DT/O person/NN/O sentenced/VBN/O to/TO/O death/NN/O can/MD/O voluntarily/RB/O waive/VB/O his/PRP$/O rights/NNS/O of/IN/O appellate/JJ/O review/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O murderer/NN/O ,/,/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Gene/NNP/I-PERSON Simmons/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O killing/VBG/O 14/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O murderer/NN/O on/IN/O death/NN/O row/NN/O has/VBZ/O appealed/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Simmons/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O death/NN/O sentence/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O next/JJ/O friend/NN/O ''/''/O capacity/NN/O ././O
Wilmer/NNP/B-ORG Cutler/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG brief/NN/O argues/VBZ/O that/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O mandatory/JJ/O appellate/JJ/O review/NN/O of/IN/O capital/NN/O sentences/NNS/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O inmate/NN/O who/WP/O filed/VBD/O the/DT/O appeal/NN/O lacks/VBZ/O proper/JJ/O standing/NN/O ././O
P.J./NNP/B-PERSON Mode/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Wilmer/NNP/B-ORG Cutler/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG managing/NN/O partner/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O trial/NN/O team/NN/O that/WDT/O represented/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bundy/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O asked/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O pro/FW/O bono/FW/O committee/NN/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O case/NN/O posed/VBD/O a/DT/O conflict/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O no/DT/O objections/NNS/O were/VBD/O raised/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O coupling/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O firm/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG Legal/NNP/I-ORG Foundation/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O odd/JJ/O also/RB/O ,/,/O because/IN/O Wilmer/NNP/B-ORG Cutler/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O firms/NNS/O singled/VBN/O out/RP/O for/IN/O criticism/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O legal/JJ/O group/NN/O for/IN/O displaying/VBG/O a/DT/O liberal/JJ/O bias/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O pro/FW/O bono/FW/O work/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O give/VBP/O them/PRP/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O credit/NN/O for/IN/O taking/VBG/O this/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O WLF/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Slobodin/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
THE/DT/O CASE/NN/O OF/IN/O THE/DT/O FAKE/JJ/O DALIS/NNPS/B-PERSON :/:/O
In/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O three/CD/O defendants/NNS/O pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O in/IN/O connection/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O fake/JJ/O Salvador/NNP/B-PERSON Dali/NNP/I-PERSON lithographs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O posters/NNS/O were/VBD/O sold/VBN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 1,300/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 6,000/CD/O ,/,/O although/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O says/VBZ/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O only/RB/O $/$/O 53/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 200/CD/O apiece/RB/O ././O
Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Pitman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O assistant/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O handling/VBG/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O about/RB/O 1,000/CD/O customers/NNS/O were/VBD/O defrauded/VBN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Barclay/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O total/JJ/O proceeds/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O sales/NNS/O were/VBD/O $/$/O 3.4/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Attorneys/NNP/O for/IN/O Messrs./NNP/O Burke/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Evans/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Ms./NNP/O Clarke/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/IN/O although/IN/O their/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O admitted/VBD/O to/TO/O making/VBG/O some/DT/O misrepresentations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O believed/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O works/NNS/O were/VBD/O authorized/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dali/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O died/VBD/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O posters/NNS/O were/VBD/O printed/VBN/O on/IN/O paper/NN/O pre-signed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dali/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O attorneys/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
