When/WRB/O Anne/NNP/B-PERSON Volokh/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP$/O family/NN/O immigrated/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 14/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O started/VBD/O life/NN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE with/IN/O only/RB/O $/$/O 400/CD/O ././O
They/PRP/O 'd/MD/O actually/RB/O left/VBD/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE with/IN/O $/$/O 480/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O during/IN/O a/DT/O stop/NN/O in/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON dropped/VBD/O $/$/O 80/CD/O on/IN/O a/DT/O black/JJ/O velvet/NN/O suit/NN/O ././O
Not/RB/O surprisingly/RB/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O quickly/RB/O adapted/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O way/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O months/NNS/O after/IN/O she/PRP/O arrived/VBD/O in/IN/O L.A./NNP/B-GPE she/PRP/O spent/VBD/O $/$/O 120/CD/O she/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O hat/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O A/DT/O turban/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O specifies/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O time/NN/O for/IN/O that/DT/O 14/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O I/PRP/O loved/VBD/O turbans/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Since/IN/O then/RB/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O wealthy/JJ/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O and/CC/O older/JJR/O son/NN/O --/:/O a/DT/O computer/NN/O prodigy/NN/O profiled/VBN/O in/IN/O The/NNP/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1981/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O 13/CD/O --/:/O run/VBP/O a/DT/O software/NN/O company/NN/O with/IN/O expected/JJ/O sales/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O being/VBG/O sold/VBN/O through/IN/O bookstores/NNS/O ,/,/O newsstands/NNS/O and/CC/O some/DT/O video/JJ/O stores/NNS/O ././O
Though/NNP/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O woman/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O outsized/JJ/O personality/NN/O and/CC/O dramatic/JJ/O flair/NN/O that/WDT/O seem/VBP/O perfectly/RB/O suited/VBN/O to/TO/O capitalism/NN/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O practiced/VBN/O in/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O owns/VBZ/O 48/CD/O hats/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O remembers/VBZ/O the/DT/O lean/JJ/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O recalls/VBZ/O with/IN/O relish/NN/O wearing/VBG/O her/PRP/O first/JJ/O major/JJ/O American/JJ/O purchase/NN/O --/:/O that/DT/O turban/NN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O later/RB/O and/CC/O having/VBG/O a/DT/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE boutique/NN/O owner/NN/O ask/VB/O her/PRP/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O Chanel/NNP/B-ORG ././O
With/IN/O obvious/JJ/O satisfaction/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O told/VBD/O him/PRP/O :/:/O ``/``/O No/UH/O darling/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O just/RB/O give/VB/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O Chanel/NNP/B-ORG look/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
She/PRP/O keeps/VBZ/O track/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O hats/NNS/O by/IN/O stapling/VBG/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG snapshots/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O outside/NN/O of/IN/O each/DT/O hatbox/NN/O ././O
Are/VBP/O the/DT/O hats/NNS/O merely/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O new/JJ/O L.A./NNP/B-GPE persona/NN/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O many/JJ/O ultra-thin/JJ/O Capri/NNP/B-ORG cigarettes/NNS/O she/PRP/O smokes/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O parties/NNS/O she/PRP/O throws/VBZ/O for/IN/O 500/CD/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Chekovian/JJ/O feasts/NNS/O she/PRP/O offers/VBZ/O guests/NNS/O at/IN/O her/PRP$/O weekend/NN/O place/NN/O in/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Barbara/NNP/I-GPE ?/./O
``/``/O No/UH/O ,/,/O darling/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O recently/RB/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O fluent/JJ/O ,/,/O slightly/RB/O affected/JJ/O English/NNP/O ,/,/O during/IN/O a/DT/O trip/NN/O East/RB/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O Movieline/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O national/JJ/O expansion/NN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O born/VBN/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
I/PRP/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O wear/VB/O hats/NNS/O in/IN/O Russia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O I/PRP/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O them/PRP/O and/CC/O my/PRP$/O dresses/NNS/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/O hat/NN/O side/NN/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O getting/VBG/O what/WP/O I/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
Now/RB/O 48/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O definite/JJ/O ideas/NNS/O about/IN/O what/WP/O she/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O ././O
In/IN/O restaurants/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O in/IN/O this/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Russian/NNP/I-ORG Samovar/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE restaurant/NN/O operated/VBN/O by/IN/O and/CC/O for/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O emigres/NNS/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O the/DT/O chirpy/JJ/O ,/,/O folkish/JJ/O music/NN/O bouncing/VBG/O through/IN/O the/DT/O room/NN/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O people/NNS/O here/RB/O think/VBP/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O Russian/JJ/O music/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O with/IN/O disdain/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O called/VBD/O over/RP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O waitress/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O Could/MD/O you/PRP/O turn/VB/O it/PRP/O off/RP/O ?/./O ''/''/O
That/DT/O done/VBN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON spoke/VBD/O with/IN/O rampant/JJ/O eloquence/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O many/JJ/O attributes/NNS/O she/PRP/O feels/VBZ/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O born/VBN/O with/IN/O :/:/O an/DT/O understanding/NN/O of/IN/O food/NN/O ,/,/O business/NN/O ,/,/O Russian/JJ/O culture/NN/O ,/,/O human/JJ/O nature/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O parties/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Parties/NNS/O are/VBP/O rather/RB/O a/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O mind/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O pausing/VBG/O only/RB/O to/TO/O taste/VB/O and/CC/O pass/VB/O judgment/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Georgian/JJ/O shashlik/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O a/DT/O little/RB/O well/RB/O done/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O very/RB/O good/JJ/O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O are/VBP/O born/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O parties/NNS/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O give/VBP/O parties/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O in/IN/O Russia/NNP/B-GPE we/PRP/O managed/VBD/O to/TO/O give/VB/O parties/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O lean/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O gave/VBD/O parties/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O thrown/VBN/O extravagant/JJ/O soirees/NNS/O for/IN/O crowds/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O prefers/VBZ/O more/RBR/O intimate/JJ/O gatherings/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O At/IN/O American/JJ/O cocktail/NN/O parties/VBZ/O everyone/NN/O 's/VBZ/O always/RB/O looking/VBG/O over/IN/O your/PRP$/O shoulder/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O who/WP/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O talk/VB/O to/TO/O next/RB/O ././O
I/PRP/O like/VBP/O rather/RB/O tea/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
She/PRP/O serves/VBZ/O high/JJ/O Russian/JJ/O tea/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O 5/CD/O p.m/RB/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O later/RB/O but/CC/O I/PRP/O just/RB/O moved/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O
In/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O important/JJ/O to/TO/O catch/VB/O people/NNS/O just/RB/O after/IN/O work/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
She/PRP/O also/RB/O frequently/RB/O invites/VBZ/O directors/NNS/O ,/,/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O actors/NNS/O ,/,/O writers/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O show/NN/O business/NN/O people/NNS/O for/IN/O ``/``/O coffee/NN/O and/CC/O clips/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pleasure/NN/O dome/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
They/PRP/O eat/VBP/O ``/``/O sinful/JJ/O and/CC/O sensual/JJ/O things/NNS/O ''/''/O --/:/O and/CC/O explain/VBP/O their/PRP$/O clips/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O revealing/JJ/O and/CC/O soul/NN/O baring/VBG/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O idea/NN/O for/IN/O Movieline/NNP/B-ORG actually/RB/O was/VBD/O dreamed/VBN/O up/RP/O by/IN/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O friend/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Volokhs/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O Boris/NNP/B-PERSON Krutchensky/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O title/NN/O of/IN/O co-publisher/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Laurie/NNP/B-PERSON Halpern/NNP/I-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O now/RB/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O 's/POS/O co-editor/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Krutchensky/NNP/B-PERSON approached/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON five/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O about/IN/O backing/VBG/O the/DT/O publication/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O started/VBD/O out/RP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O listing/NN/O guide/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O was/VBD/O interested/JJ/O only/RB/O if/IN/O she/PRP/O could/MD/O guide/VB/O it/PRP/O editorially/RB/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Anne/VB/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O in/IN/O blandness/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O She/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O things/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O exciting/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O this/DT/O inexhaustible/JJ/O energy/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O 'll/MD/O think/VB/O of/IN/O an/DT/O idea/NN/O the/DT/O editorial/JJ/O people/NNS/O think/VBP/O is/VBZ/O impossible/JJ/O ,/,/O then/RB/O she/PRP/O 'll/MD/O have/VB/O us/PRP/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O work/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O a/DT/O rich/JJ/O lady/NN/O who/WP/O needed/VBD/O a/DT/O hobby/NN/O ././O
Back/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE she/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O respected/JJ/O journalist/NN/O ,/,/O writing/VBG/O a/DT/O weekly/JJ/O column/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O national/JJ/O cuisine/NN/O for/IN/O Sunday/NNP/B-ORG Izvestia/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Those/DT/O columns/NNS/O --/:/O vivid/JJ/O discussions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cultural/JJ/O and/CC/O literary/JJ/O reverberations/NNS/O of/IN/O food/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O practical/JJ/O advice/NN/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O glamorize/VB/O dreary/JJ/O Sovietized/JJ/O meals/NNS/O --/:/O became/VBD/O the/DT/O basis/NN/O for/IN/O her/PRP$/O erudite/JJ/O and/CC/O entertaining/JJ/O cookbook/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Art/NNP/O of/IN/O Russian/NNP/O Cuisine/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O brought/VBN/O out/RP/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O by/IN/O Macmillan/NNP/B-ORG Publishing/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O trust/VB/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O eat/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O though/IN/O she/PRP/O herself/PRP/O stopped/VBD/O eating/VBG/O lunch/NN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O 25/CD/O pounds/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Look/VB/O at/IN/O Dostoevski/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Kafka/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
No/DT/O one/NN/O ever/RB/O eats/VBZ/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O books/NNS/O and/CC/O look/VB/O at/IN/O them/PRP/O .../:/O ././O
Tolstoy/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O characters/NNS/O eat/VBP/O ,/,/O Pushkin/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ,/,/O Gogol/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O her/PRP$/O cookbook/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O Macmillan/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O bringing/VBG/O out/RP/O in/IN/O soft/JJ/O cover/NN/O this/DT/O month/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O with/IN/O the/DT/O blini/NNS/O recipe/NN/O revised/VBN/O so/IN/O it/PRP/O works/VBZ/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O introduces/VBZ/O each/DT/O chapter/NN/O with/IN/O appropriate/JJ/O quotations/NNS/O from/IN/O Russian/JJ/O literature/NN/O :/:/O Pushkin/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O blini/NNS/O ,/,/O Goncharov/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O piroghi/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O life/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O offers/VBZ/O practical/JJ/O dieting/NN/O advice/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O Divide/VB/O your/PRP$/O meals/NNS/O into/IN/O important/JJ/O and/CC/O unimportant/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O restaurant/NN/O ,/,/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O deprive/VB/O yourself/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O meals/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O matter/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Amusing/JJ/O as/IN/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O frivolous/JJ/O as/IN/O she/PRP/O can/MD/O seem/VB/O ,/,/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O serious/JJ/O person/NN/O with/IN/O some/DT/O difficult/JJ/O memories/NNS/O ././O
She/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O child/NN/O of/IN/O relative/JJ/O privilege/NN/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O mother/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O translator/NN/O ;/:/O her/PRP$/O father/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O the/DT/O eternal/JJ/O vice/NN/O director/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O I/PRP/O emigrated/VBD/O to/TO/O wear/VB/O better/JJR/O hats/NNS/O ,/,/O do/VB/O better/JJR/O parties/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O with/IN/O a/DT/O giggle/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O leave/VB/O out/RP/O political/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O ,/,/O number/NN/O one/CD/O ././O
You/PRP/O try/VBP/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O your/PRP$/O dignity/NN/O under/IN/O difficult/JJ/O circumstances/NNS/O ././O
One/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O imagine/VB/O how/WRB/O you/PRP/O live/VBP/O when/WRB/O you/PRP/O live/VBP/O those/DT/O double/JJ/O and/CC/O triple/JJ/O lives/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
By/IN/O 1973/CD/O ,/,/O after/IN/O their/PRP$/O second/JJ/O child/NN/O was/VBD/O born/VBN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O become/VBN/O clear/JJ/O to/TO/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O Vladimir/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O computer/NN/O scientist/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O the/DT/O U.S.S.R/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON quit/VBD/O her/PRP/O job/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O herself/PRP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O eye/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O wait/NN/O was/VBD/O miserable/JJ/O ././O
Before/IN/O granting/VBG/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O parents/NNS/O a/DT/O visa/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O required/VBD/O her/PRP$/O mother/NN/O to/TO/O obtain/VB/O permission/NN/O from/IN/O her/PRP$/O first/JJ/O husband/NN/O ,/,/O whom/WP/O she/PRP/O had/VBD/O divorced/VBN/O 38/CD/O years/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O fired/VBN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O job/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O endure/VB/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O organized/JJ/O verbal/JJ/O abuse/NN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O co-workers/NNS/O ,/,/O accusations/NNS/O of/IN/O sabotage/NN/O and/CC/O counterrevolutionary/JJ/O activities/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Volokhs/NNPS/B-PERSON were/VBD/O afraid/JJ/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O 'd/MD/O end/VB/O up/RP/O like/IN/O a/DT/O friend/NN/O of/IN/O theirs/PRP/O who/WP/O 'd/VBD/O applied/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O visa/NN/O and/CC/O waited/VBN/O for/IN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O having/VBG/O been/VBN/O demoted/VBN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O profession/NN/O of/IN/O theoretical/JJ/O mathematician/NN/O to/TO/O shipping/NN/O clerk/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O visa/NN/O came/VBD/O in/IN/O relatively/RB/O short/JJ/O order/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O moved/VBD/O to/TO/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON soon/RB/O found/VBD/O work/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O field/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON refused/VBD/O the/DT/O obvious/JJ/O and/CC/O available/JJ/O occupation/NN/O -/:/O as/IN/O translator/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O Russian/NNP/O who/WP/O spoke/VBD/O fluent/JJ/O English/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O always/RB/O looking/VBG/O back/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O in/IN/O business/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Soon/RB/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O running/VBG/O the/DT/O office/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O and/CC/O son/NN/O founded/VBD/O their/PRP$/O computer/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Vesoft/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O she/PRP/O worked/VBD/O as/IN/O business/NN/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O bookkeeper/NN/O and/CC/O publicist/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O Movieline/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O located/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O building/NN/O as/IN/O Vesoft/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O Things/NNS/O work/VBP/O out/RP/O unexpectedly/RB/O in/IN/O life/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Volokh/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O never/RB/O know/VBP/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O chosen/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O scapegoat/NN/O or/CC/O the/DT/O lucky/JJ/O one/CD/O ././O
We/PRP/O were/VBD/O lucky/JJ/O ././O
