``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O extremely/RB/O complex/JJ/O market/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O commitment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Forrester/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O encourage/VB/O everyone/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Undeterred/JJ/O by/IN/O such/JJ/O words/NNS/O of/IN/O caution/NN/O ,/,/O corporate/JJ/O America/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O flocking/VBG/O to/TO/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O lured/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O untapped/JJ/O market/NN/O and/CC/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON attempt/NN/O to/TO/O overhaul/VB/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O while/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE interest/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O big/JJ/O and/CC/O growing/VBG/O ,/,/O the/DT/O difficulties/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O stymied/VBN/O deals/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O show/VBP/O no/DT/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O abating/VBG/O ././O
Alongside/IN/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O problems/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O non-convertible/JJ/O currency/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O inpenetrable/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O ,/,/O Western/JJ/O business/NN/O executives/NNS/O must/MD/O now/RB/O grapple/VB/O with/IN/O new/JJ/O complexities/NNS/O linked/VBN/O to/TO/O perestroika/FW/O ,/,/O the/DT/O restructuring/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
Executives/NNS/O say/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O moves/NNS/O to/TO/O break/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O foreign/JJ/O trade/NN/O monopoly/NN/O have/VBP/O created/VBN/O uncertainties/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O opportunities/NNS/O ././O
Changing/VBG/O legislation/NN/O has/VBZ/O opened/VBN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O to/TO/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O inexperienced/JJ/O Soviet/JJ/O players/NNS/O ,/,/O many/DT/O who/WP/O promise/VBP/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O deliver/VB/O ././O
And/CC/O some/DT/O foreign/JJ/O firms/NNS/O are/VBP/O finding/VBG/O that/IN/O even/RB/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O manage/VBP/O to/TO/O overcome/VB/O such/JJ/O hurdles/NNS/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O ventures/NNS/O now/RB/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O endorsed/VBN/O by/IN/O such/JJ/O unpredictable/JJ/O bodies/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O parliament/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O governments/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O republics/NNS/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O go/VB/O out/IN/O to/TO/O all/PDT/O your/PRP$/O constituents/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O James/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Giffen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O spearheading/VBG/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O ambitious/JJ/O attempt/NN/O by/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE firms/NNS/O to/TO/O break/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O market/NN/O ,/,/O involving/VBG/O investment/NN/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 5/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O some/RB/O two/CD/O dozen/NN/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O attempt/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG Consortium/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Giffen/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O spends/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O lobbying/VBG/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Soviet/JJ/O ministries/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O talking/VBG/O to/TO/O international/JJ/O firms/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Occidental/NNP/B-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Combustion/NNP/B-ORG Engineering/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Montedison/NNP/B-ORG S.p.A./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O several/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O groups/NNS/O ,/,/O about/IN/O jointly/RB/O building/VBG/O and/CC/O operating/VBG/O several/JJ/O big/JJ/O petrochemical/NN/O plants/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O plans/NNS/O have/VBP/O come/VBN/O under/IN/O fire/NN/O from/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O environmentalists/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O many/JJ/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O scaled/VBN/O back/RP/O or/CC/O dropped/VBN/O ././O
Whatever/WDT/O the/DT/O difficulties/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O committed/JJ/O to/TO/O increasing/VBG/O foreign/JJ/O trade/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O political/JJ/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O economic/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O top/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O priorities/NNS/O --/:/O a/DT/O point/NN/O he/PRP/O underscored/VBD/O by/IN/O spending/VBG/O two/CD/O hours/NNS/O walking/VBG/O around/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O show/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ranks/VBZ/O fourth/JJ/O of/IN/O countries/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O concluded/VBN/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O ,/,/O behind/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Finland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O several/JJ/O people/NNS/O present/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O supported/VBD/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O of/IN/O concluding/VBG/O several/JJ/O commercial/JJ/O accords/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O possibly/RB/O at/IN/O his/PRP$/O next/JJ/O summit/NN/O meeting/NN/O with/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Judging/VBG/O by/IN/O the/DT/O crush/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O exhibition/NN/O ,/,/O deprived/VBN/O Soviet/JJ/O consumers/NNS/O are/VBP/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O ready/JJ/O for/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE products/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O unruly/JJ/O crowds/NNS/O at/IN/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG Nabisco/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG booth/NN/O almost/RB/O knocked/VBD/O over/RP/O a/DT/O glass/NN/O showcase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O rush/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O Camel/NNP/B-ORG cigarette/NN/O sticker/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE products/NNS/O are/VBP/O filtering/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O market/NN/O under/IN/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O import/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG Consortium/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O planning/VBG/O to/TO/O ship/VB/O some/RB/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O consumer/NN/O goods/NNS/O ,/,/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O bank/NN/O credits/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O goal/NN/O of/IN/O most/JJS/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE firms/NNS/O --/:/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O --/:/O remains/VBZ/O elusive/JJ/O ././O
Because/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O ruble/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O convertible/JJ/O into/IN/O dollars/NNS/O ,/,/O marks/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O Western/JJ/O currencies/NNS/O ,/,/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O hope/VBP/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O production/NN/O facilities/NNS/O here/RB/O must/MD/O either/RB/O export/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O goods/NNS/O to/TO/O earn/VB/O hard/JJ/O currency/NN/O or/CC/O find/VB/O Soviet/JJ/O goods/NNS/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O take/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O counter-trade/JJ/O transaction/NN/O ././O
International/JJ/O competition/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O few/JJ/O Soviet/JJ/O goods/NNS/O that/WDT/O can/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O on/IN/O world/NN/O markets/NNS/O is/VBZ/O heating/VBG/O up/RP/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Shelley/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Zeiger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O entrepreneur/NN/O from/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE who/WP/O buys/VBZ/O Soviet/JJ/O porcelain/NN/O and/CC/O ``/``/O matryoshka/FW/O ''/''/O nesting/JJ/O dolls/NNS/O for/IN/O export/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O companies/NNS/O already/RB/O have/VBP/O snapped/VBN/O up/RP/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O production/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O items/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O capital/NN/O here/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O basis/NN/O as/IN/O investing/VBG/O in/IN/O other/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Sokol/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Medical/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Partners/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O putting/VBG/O the/DT/O medical/JJ/O consortium/NN/O together/RB/O ././O
Some/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE entrepreneurs/NNS/O operate/VBP/O on/IN/O a/DT/O smaller/JJR/O scale/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O found/VBD/O a/DT/O market/NN/O niche/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Mills/NNP/B-PERSON boasts/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O truly/RB/O entrepreneurial/JJ/O ././O
