When/WRB/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON McDuffie/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O 14/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O got/VBD/O a/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O play/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O starting/JJ/O lineup/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O high/JJ/O school/NN/O basketball/NN/O team/NN/O in/IN/O Macon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ga/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O mother/NN/O had/VBD/O tickets/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O recital/NN/O by/IN/O Itzhak/NNP/B-PERSON Perlman/NNP/I-PERSON the/DT/O same/JJ/O night/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O adamant/JJ/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O attending/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O threw/VBD/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O fit/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O begun/VBN/O violin/NN/O studies/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O six/CD/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O once/IN/O Perlman/NNP/B-PERSON started/VBD/O playing/VBG/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O give/VB/O a/DT/O damn/NN/O about/IN/O basketball/NN/O .../:/O ././O
Afterwards/RB/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O went/VBD/O home/NN/O and/CC/O practiced/VBD/O for/IN/O three/CD/O hours/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Later/RB/O this/DT/O season/NN/O he/PRP/O gives/VBZ/O a/DT/O recital/NN/O at/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Kennedy/NNP/B-FAC Center/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O and/CC/O appears/VBZ/O as/IN/O soloist/NN/O with/IN/O several/JJ/O major/JJ/O orchestras/NNS/O ././O
Yet/CC/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O career/NN/O has/VBZ/O developed/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O slower/JJR/O pace/NN/O than/IN/O those/DT/O of/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O better/RBR/O known/VBN/O contemporaries/NNS/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1970s/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O musical/JJ/O ``/``/O brat/NN/O pack/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O budding/JJ/O virtuosos/NNS/O who/WP/O studied/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Juilliard/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O the/DT/O noted/JJ/O pedagogue/NN/O Dorothy/NNP/B-PERSON DeLay/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O thought/VBD/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O hill/NN/O at/IN/O 22/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O recalls/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O outgoing/JJ/O man/NN/O with/IN/O pale/JJ/O blue/JJ/O eyes/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O light/JJ/O Southern/JJ/O drawl/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O ready/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O career/NN/O at/IN/O that/DT/O time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Young/JJ/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O first/JJ/O violin/NN/O teacher/NN/O was/VBD/O Henrik/NNP/B-PERSON Schwarzenberger/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Hungarian/JJ/O refugee/NN/O who/WP/O taught/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Macon/NNP/B-GPE public/JJ/O school/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O taught/VBD/O me/PRP/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O play/VB/O like/IN/O a/DT/O gypsy/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O jokes/VBZ/O the/DT/O musician/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O learn/VB/O to/TO/O count/VB/O until/IN/O I/PRP/O got/VBD/O to/TO/O Juilliard/NN/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
After/IN/O studies/NNS/O at/IN/O that/DT/O conservatory/NN/O 's/POS/O Pre-College/NNP/B-ORG Division/NNP/I-ORG with/IN/O an/DT/O assistant/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O legendary/JJ/O instructor/NN/O Ivan/NNP/B-PERSON Galamian/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O he/PRP/O switched/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O college/NN/O level/NN/O to/TO/O Miss/NNP/O DeLay/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Galamian/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O longtime/JJ/O assistant/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O ultimately/RB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O rival/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O I/PRP/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O prove/VB/O myself/PRP/O to/TO/O her/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O always/RB/O encouraging/JJ/O ././O
She/PRP/O only/RB/O put/VBD/O her/PRP$/O foot/NN/O down/RP/O twice/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O continues/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O my/PRP$/O freshman/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O my/PRP$/O roommate/NN/O was/VBD/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O party/NN/O animal/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O thought/VBD/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O getting/VBG/O my/PRP$/O practicing/NN/O done/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O the/DT/O violinist/NN/O tells/VBZ/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O grandmotherly/JJ/O looking/VBG/O teacher/NN/O ``/``/O put/VBD/O her/PRP$/O hands/NNS/O on/IN/O her/PRP$/O hips/NNS/O ,/,/O stomped/VBD/O her/PRP$/O foot/NN/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O `/``/O You/PRP/O 've/VBP/O just/RB/O got/VBN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O expletive/NN/O deleted/VBN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O out/IN/O of/IN/O there/RB/O ././O '/''/O ''/''/O
The/DT/O second/JJ/O incident/NN/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O after/IN/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON gave/VBD/O an/DT/O ambitious/JJ/O student/NN/O recital/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O feeling/VBG/O rather/RB/O pleased/JJ/O with/IN/O himself/PRP/O ././O
Miss/NNP/O DeLay/NNP/B-PERSON requested/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O come/VB/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O studio/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O tape/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O recital/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O note/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O truly/RB/O in/IN/O tune/NN/O .../:/O '/''/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O important/JJ/O experience/NN/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O had/VBD/O with/IN/O any/DT/O teacher/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O taught/VBD/O me/PRP/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O listen/VB/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O I/PRP/O play/VBP/O with/IN/O orchestras/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O musicians/NNS/O often/RB/O compliment/VBP/O me/PRP/O on/IN/O my/PRP$/O intonation/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
After/IN/O winning/VBG/O a/DT/O school/NN/O competition/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O performance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O latter/NN/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O Violin/NNP/O Concerto/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O invited/VBN/O to/TO/O play/VB/O the/DT/O work/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O composer/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O dying/VBG/O of/IN/O cancer/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Barber/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O seated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O fireplace/NN/O looking/VBG/O very/RB/O pale/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O recalls/VBZ/O the/DT/O violinist/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O performed/VBD/O the/DT/O work/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O piano/NN/O accompanist/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O composer/NN/O 's/POS/O apartment/NN/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O much/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O was/VBD/O important/JJ/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O score/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O beautiful/JJ/O ,/,/O Coplandesque/JJ/O motif/NN/O --/:/O he/PRP/O 'd/MD/O kill/VB/O me/PRP/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O heard/VBD/O me/PRP/O say/VB/O that/DT/O --/:/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O movement/NN/O .../:/O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O time/NN/O the/DT/O violin/NN/O has/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O right/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O he/PRP/O yelled/VBD/O out/RP/O `/``/O dolce/FW/O !/./O dolce/FW/O !/./O '/''/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O `/``/O sweet/JJ/O !/./O sweet/JJ/O !/./O '/''/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O So/IN/O we/PRP/O did/VBD/O it/PRP/O over/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O adds/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O played/VBD/O very/RB/O transparently/RB/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O tip/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bow/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O a/DT/O conductor/NN/O is/VBZ/O sensitive/JJ/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O down/RP/O the/DT/O orchestra/NN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O volume/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O at/IN/O that/DT/O point/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O makes/VBZ/O the/DT/O piece/NN/O magical/JJ/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O why/WRB/O Barber/NNP/B-PERSON never/RB/O told/VBD/O anybody/NN/O else/RB/O ././O
On/IN/O Isaac/NNP/B-PERSON Stern/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON recording/NN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O biting/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Since/IN/O leaving/VBG/O Juilliard/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O some/DT/O smart/JJ/O moves/NNS/O and/CC/O some/DT/O controversial/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ././O
His/PRP$/O guest/JJ/O appearance/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG soap/NN/O opera/NN/O ``/``/O Another/DT/O World/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O scandalized/VBD/O musical/JJ/O elitists/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sweet/JJ/O tone/NN/O ,/,/O heartfelt/JJ/O lyricism/NN/O and/CC/O rhythmic/JJ/O punch/NN/O make/VBP/O him/PRP/O an/DT/O ideal/JJ/O interpreter/NN/O of/IN/O both/DT/O works/NNS/O ././O
Aided/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O fluid/JJ/O playing/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG St./NNP/I-ORG Louis/NNP/I-ORG Symphony/NNP/I-ORG under/IN/O Leonard/NNP/B-PERSON Slatkin/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON direction/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O ``/``/O Serenade/NNP/O ''/''/O really/RB/O swings/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Schuman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Violin/NNP/O Concerto/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O sounds/VBZ/O more/RBR/O like/IN/O a/DT/O mildly/RB/O atonal/JJ/O rhapsody/NN/O for/IN/O solo/JJ/O violin/NN/O with/IN/O orchestral/JJ/O accompaniment/NN/O ,/,/O meanders/VBZ/O until/IN/O the/DT/O propulsive/JJ/O ``/``/O Agitato/NNP/O ,/,/O fervente/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O ample/JJ/O rewards/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O plaintive/JJ/O slow/JJ/O sections/NNS/O and/CC/O virtuoso/JJ/O fireworks/NNS/O for/IN/O soloist/NN/O ,/,/O brass/NN/O and/CC/O timpani/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O Avery/NNP/B-FAC Fisher/NNP/I-FAC Hall/NNP/I-FAC here/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O heard/VBN/O recently/RB/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Menuhin/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Warsaw/NNP/I-ORG Sinfonia/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O more/JJR/O conventional/JJ/O fare/NN/O --/:/O Bruch/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O overwrought/JJ/O ``/``/O Violin/NNP/O Concerto/NNP/O in/IN/O G/NNP/O Minor/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
His/PRP$/O performance/NN/O was/VBD/O so/RB/O effusive/JJ/O and/CC/O driven/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O phrases/NNS/O rarely/RB/O breathed/VBD/O ././O
Whatever/WDT/O he/PRP/O plays/VBZ/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O McDuffie/NNP/B-PERSON finds/VBZ/O satisfaction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O music/NN/O itself/PRP/O --/:/O ``/``/O something/NN/O greater/JJR/O out/RB/O there/RB/O than/IN/O me/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O puts/VBZ/O it/PRP/O during/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE apartment/NN/O he/PRP/O shares/VBZ/O with/IN/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Camille/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O literary/JJ/O publicist/NN/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O normal/JJ/O person/NN/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O write/VB/O the/DT/O Beethoven/NNP/B-PERSON `/``/O Violin/NNP/O Concerto/NNP/O ,/,/O '/''/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O declares/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Even/RB/O when/WRB/O I/PRP/O hear/VBP/O it/PRP/O played/VBN/O badly/RB/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O still/RB/O humbled/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O piece/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O ever/RB/O feel/VB/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O contributed/VBN/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O some/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O then/RB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O hard/JJ/O work/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O worth/JJ/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
