It/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O snubbing/NN/O rarely/RB/O seen/VBN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O let/VBD/O alone/RB/O within/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Cranston/NNP/I-PERSON trekked/VBD/O over/RP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG side/NN/O of/IN/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG Hill/NNP/I-ORG a/DT/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O ago/RB/O and/CC/O volunteered/VBD/O his/PRP$/O testimony/NN/O to/TO/O fellow/JJ/O Democrat/NNP/O Rep./NNP/O Henry/NNP/B-PERSON Gonzalez/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
But/CC/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O thanks/NNS/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O treated/VBN/O with/IN/O cool/JJ/O formality/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Every/DT/O witness/NN/O receives/VBZ/O a/DT/O formal/JJ/O subpoena/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O him/PRP/O ././O
Seldom/RB/O have/VBP/O House/NNP/B-ORG hearings/NNS/O caused/VBN/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O apprehension/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O where/WRB/O California/NNP/B-GPE Sen./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O four/CD/O other/JJ/O senators/NNS/O were/VBD/O already/RB/O writhing/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O glare/NN/O of/IN/O unfavorable/JJ/O publicity/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O alleged/JJ/O looting/NN/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG by/IN/O their/PRP$/O friend/NN/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O benefactor/NN/O ,/,/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Keating/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O principal/JJ/O stockholder/NN/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Phoenix/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz/NNP/B-GPE ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O day/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG hearings/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Seidman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Resolution/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O agency/NN/O created/VBN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O sick/JJ/O thrifts/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O is/VBZ/O investigating/VBG/O whether/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG made/VBD/O illegal/JJ/O political/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON arranged/VBD/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O donations/NNS/O to/TO/O Sen./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O various/JJ/O political/JJ/O causes/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O thousands/NNS/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O lawmakers/NNS/O ././O
Unlike/IN/O many/JJ/O lawmakers/NNS/O ,/,/O Chairman/NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O considers/VBZ/O intervening/VBG/O with/IN/O regulators/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O improper/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O attached/VBN/O himself/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG story/NN/O tenaciously/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Unless/IN/O the/DT/O questions/NNS/O are/VBP/O answered/VBN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O will/MD/O keep/VB/O on/RP/O going/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
Lawmakers/NNS/O often/RB/O are/VBP/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O embarrass/VB/O colleagues/NNS/O ,/,/O even/RB/O those/DT/O of/IN/O opposing/JJ/O political/JJ/O parties/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O Housing/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Urban/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG scandal/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Rep./NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Lantos/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O who/WP/O led/VBD/O the/DT/O hearings/NNS/O ,/,/O tiptoed/VBD/O through/IN/O embarrassing/JJ/O disclosures/NNS/O about/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG grants/NNS/O secured/VBN/O by/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Alfonse/NNP/B-PERSON D'Amato/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE Republican/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O Chairman/NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O genuine/JJ/O maverick/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O stickler/NN/O for/IN/O ethical/JJ/O standards/NNS/O who/WP/O refuses/VBZ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O honorariums/NNS/O and/CC/O who/WP/O believes/VBZ/O in/IN/O conducting/VBG/O official/JJ/O business/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O open/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O immediate/JJ/O target/NN/O of/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O inquiry/NN/O is/VBZ/O Danny/NNP/B-PERSON Wall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Thrift/NNP/I-ORG Supervision/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Rep./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O primed/VBN/O to/TO/O lash/VB/O out/RP/O at/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON when/WRB/O hearings/NNS/O resume/VBP/O Thursday/NNP/O with/IN/O testimony/NN/O by/IN/O two/CD/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O from/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Black/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Mike/NNP/B-PERSON Patriarca/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON relieved/VBD/O them/PRP/O of/IN/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O supervising/VBG/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON expressed/VBD/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O a/DT/O report/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O summoned/VBN/O to/TO/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON last/JJ/O week/NN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O their/PRP$/O testimony/NN/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O improperly/RB/O influence/VB/O a/DT/O witness/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O by/IN/O God/NNP/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O tolerate/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O certain/JJ/O that/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O course/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hearings/NNS/O the/DT/O names/NNS/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O of/IN/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O will/MD/O be/VB/O brought/VBN/O out/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O raising/VBG/O eyebrows/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O I/PRP/O first/RB/O got/VBD/O a/DT/O glimpse/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O witness/NN/O list/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O go/VB/O ahead/RB/O and/CC/O do/VB/O this/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Waldman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG Watch/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O consumer/NN/O group/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O are/VBP/O some/DT/O witnesses/NNS/O who/WP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O meetings/NNS/O with/IN/O senators/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O a/DT/O Democratic/JJ/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Banking/NNP/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG member/NN/O remarks/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O too/RB/O am/VBP/O astounded/JJ/O by/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O because/IN/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O certainly/RB/O placed/VBN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O senators/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O very/RB/O bad/JJ/O position/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
All/PDT/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O merely/RB/O were/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O fairness/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O constituent/NN/O ././O
Chairman/NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON expresses/VBZ/O sympathy/NN/O for/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Riegle/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O counterpart/NN/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O wise/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O good/JJ/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O know/VBP/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O honest/JJ/O man/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O Texan/NNP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG negotiators/NNS/O included/VBD/O Sens./NNP/O Cranston/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Riegle/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O principal/JJ/O sponsor/NN/O ,/,/O Republican/NNP/O Sen./NNP/O Jake/NNP/B-PERSON Garn/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Utah/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Most/RBS/O importantly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG traded/VBD/O away/RP/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O 's/POS/O controversial/JJ/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O the/DT/O bailout/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O partly/RB/O reinstated/VBN/O later/RB/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O several/JJ/O senators/NNS/O told/VBD/O him/PRP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O ``/``/O could/MD/O get/VB/O some/DT/O roadblocks/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O if/IN/O there/EX/O could/MD/O be/VB/O some/DT/O understanding/NN/O on/IN/O Garn/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O insistence/NN/O on/IN/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
Now/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O holding/VBG/O the/DT/O equivalent/NN/O of/IN/O reconfirmation/NN/O hearings/NNS/O anyway/RB/O ,/,/O under/IN/O the/DT/O guise/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG investigation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O ,/,/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O what/WP/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON concedes/VBZ/O ././O
Even/RB/O some/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG members/NNS/O could/MD/O suffer/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O fallout/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON raised/VBD/O $/$/O 20,000/CD/O for/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Doug/NNP/B-PERSON Barnard/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O 1986/CD/O re-election/NN/O campaign/NN/O while/IN/O the/DT/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O was/VBD/O taking/VBG/O his/PRP$/O side/NN/O against/IN/O regulators/NNS/O who/WP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O curb/VB/O risky/JJ/O investments/NNS/O and/CC/O wholesale/JJ/O deposit/NN/O brokering/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O recently/RB/O voted/VBD/O ``/``/O present/RB/O ''/''/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O authorized/VBD/O a/DT/O subpoena/NN/O to/TO/O compel/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O testify/VB/O ,/,/O then/RB/O changed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O yes/UH/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O 's/POS/O supporters/NNS/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O upper/JJ/O hand/NN/O as/IN/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O press/VBP/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O billion/CD/O fraud/NN/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Keating/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O witness/NN/O set/VBN/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O on/IN/O Thursday/NNP/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O news/NN/O report/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O laundered/VBD/O ''/''/O campaign/NN/O contributions/NNS/O illegally/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O witness/NN/O ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Crawford/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O state/NN/O thrift/NN/O regulator/NN/O ,/,/O denies/VBZ/O saying/VBG/O that/DT/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O whether/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O done/VBN/O properly/RB/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ,/,/O because/IN/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O telephone/NN/O interview/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O that/IN/O executives/NNS/O of/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O its/PRP$/O parent/NN/O corporation/NN/O got/VBD/O unusually/RB/O high/JJ/O salaries/NNS/O and/CC/O frequent/JJ/O calls/NNS/O directing/VBG/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O specific/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O committee/NN/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O summoned/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Wall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O predecessor/NN/O ,/,/O Edwin/NNP/B-PERSON Gray/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O characterized/VBN/O the/DT/O five/CD/O senators/NNS/O '/POS/O roles/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O tantamount/JJ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O subvert/VB/O the/DT/O .../:/O regulatory/JJ/O process/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O back/VB/O down/RP/O even/RB/O though/IN/O the/DT/O five/CD/O senators/NNS/O have/VBP/O disputed/VBN/O his/PRP$/O account/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O 1987/CD/O meeting/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O must/MD/O brace/VB/O themselves/PRP/O ././O
