At/IN/O age/NN/O eight/CD/O ,/,/O Josephine/NNP/B-PERSON Baker/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O sent/VBN/O by/IN/O her/PRP$/O mother/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O white/JJ/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O house/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O chores/NNS/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O meals/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O place/NN/O to/TO/O sleep/VB/O --/:/O a/DT/O place/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O basement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O coal/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O age/NN/O 19/CD/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE sensation/NN/O ,/,/O transformed/VBN/O from/IN/O unwanted/JJ/O child/NN/O to/TO/O international/JJ/O sex/NN/O symbol/NN/O in/IN/O just/RB/O over/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O stuff/NN/O of/IN/O dreams/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O also/RB/O of/IN/O traumas/NNS/O ././O
Only/RB/O the/DT/O bravest/JJS/O spirits/NNS/O survive/VBP/O such/JJ/O roller/NN/O coasters/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O for/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ride/NN/O was/VBD/O far/RB/O from/IN/O over/RB/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O bare/JJ/O breasts/NNS/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O dancing/NN/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O voice/NN/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O beauty/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O most/RBS/O famously/RB/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O derriere/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O prominent/JJ/O attractions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O courage/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O rare/JJ/O sort/NN/O made/VBD/O her/PRP$/O remarkable/JJ/O life/NN/O possible/JJ/O ././O
Bricktop/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O another/DT/O American/JJ/O black/JJ/O woman/NN/O who/WP/O found/VBD/O a/DT/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O fame/NN/O in/IN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O I/PRP/O 've/VBP/O ever/RB/O known/VBN/O anyone/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O less/RBR/O complicated/JJ/O view/NN/O of/IN/O life/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O whose/WP$/O life/NN/O was/VBD/O more/RBR/O complicated/JJ/O than/IN/O Josephine/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ././O ''/''/O
Men/NNS/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O constant/JJ/O complication/NN/O ././O
Baker/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O she/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O trust/VB/O them/PRP/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O reward/VB/O trust/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O she/PRP/O saw/VBD/O one/CD/O key/JJ/O love/NN/O affair/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O her/PRP$/O infidelity/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O his/PRP$/O jealousy/NN/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O appetite/NN/O for/IN/O children/NNS/O also/RB/O was/VBD/O large/JJ/O ././O
She/PRP/O adopted/VBD/O 12/CD/O of/IN/O assorted/JJ/O races/NNS/O ,/,/O naming/VBG/O them/PRP/O the/DT/O Rainbow/NNP/O Tribe/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O driving/VBG/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O first/RB/O to/TO/O despair/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O to/TO/O Argentina/NNP/B-GPE ././O
She/PRP/O made/VBD/O money/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O spent/VBD/O more/JJR/O ././O
Friends/NNS/O pitched/VBD/O in/RP/O ././O
Finally/RB/O ,/,/O Prince/NNP/O Rainier/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Princess/NNP/O Grace/NNP/B-PERSON saved/VBD/O her/PRP/O with/IN/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O house/NN/O in/IN/O Monaco/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Another/DT/O lifelong/JJ/O complication/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Phyllis/NNP/B-PERSON Rose/NNP/I-PERSON makes/VBZ/O clear/JJ/O in/IN/O ``/``/O Jazz/NN/O Cleopatra/NNP/O :/:/O Josephine/NNP/O Baker/NNP/O in/IN/O Her/PRP$/O Time/NN/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Doubleday/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 321/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 22.50/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O racism/NN/O ././O
Baker/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O the/DT/O good/JJ/O luck/NN/O to/TO/O arrive/VB/O in/IN/O 1925/CD/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O blacks/NNS/O had/VBD/O become/VBN/O exotic/JJ/O ././O
African/JJ/O art/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O vogue/NN/O and/CC/O some/DT/O intellectuals/NNS/O were/VBD/O writing/VBG/O breathlessly/RB/O of/IN/O a/DT/O dawning/VBG/O age/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O inspired/VBN/O by/IN/O blacks/NNS/O ././O
To/TO/O be/VB/O exotic/JJ/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O patronized/VBN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O prized/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O for/IN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O part/NN/O Paris/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O a/DT/O friendly/JJ/O island/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O racist/JJ/O world/NN/O ././O
Paris/NNP/B-GPE loved/VBD/O her/PRP/O at/IN/O first/JJ/O sight/NN/O ././O
``/``/O She/PRP/O just/RB/O wiggled/VBD/O her/PRP$/O fanny/NN/O and/CC/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O French/NNP/O fell/VBD/O in/IN/O love/NN/O with/IN/O her/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O sniffed/VBD/O the/DT/O literary/JJ/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O Maria/NNP/B-PERSON Jolas/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O not/RB/O entirely/RB/O inaccurately/RB/O ././O
``/``/O One/PRP/O can/MD/O hardly/RB/O overemphasize/VB/O the/DT/O importance/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O rear/JJ/O end/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Ms./NNP/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON writes/VBZ/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O teaches/VBZ/O literature/NN/O at/IN/O Wesleyan/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O quickly/RB/O proceeds/VBZ/O to/TO/O overemphasize/VB/O ,/,/O claiming/VBG/O that/IN/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O dancing/NN/O ``/``/O had/VBD/O uncovered/VBN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O region/NN/O for/IN/O desire/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O thereby/RB/O ignoring/VBG/O centuries/NNS/O of/IN/O tributes/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O callipygous/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Jazz/NN/O Cleopatra/NNP/O ''/''/O contains/VBZ/O other/JJ/O ,/,/O more/RBR/O important/JJ/O ,/,/O false/JJ/O notes/NNS/O that/WDT/O undermine/VBP/O what/WP/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O part/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O lively/JJ/O account/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O life/NN/O already/RB/O familiar/JJ/O from/IN/O earlier/JJR/O works/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O easy/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O why/WRB/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O spirit/NN/O who/WP/O broke/VBD/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O restraints/NNS/O convention/NN/O places/VBZ/O on/IN/O women/NNS/O ,/,/O attracts/VBZ/O Ms./NNP/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O author/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Parallel/JJ/O Lives/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O wonderful/JJ/O study/NN/O of/IN/O Victorian/JJ/O marriage/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O even/RB/O the/DT/O title/NN/O raises/VBZ/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O author/NN/O 's/POS/O vision/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O subject/NN/O ././O
Baker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O art/NN/O was/VBD/O jazz/NN/O only/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O widest/JJS/O stretch/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O term/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O find/VB/O parallels/NNS/O ,/,/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O sexual/JJ/O appeal/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O Cleopatra/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O requires/VBZ/O an/DT/O equal/JJ/O stretch/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON played/VBD/O scenes/NNS/O in/IN/O Casablanca/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O could/MD/O have/VB/O made/VBN/O it/PRP/O into/IN/O ``/``/O Casablanca/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
During/IN/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O ,/,/O her/PRP$/O uncomplicated/JJ/O view/NN/O of/IN/O life/NN/O led/VBD/O her/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O conclusion/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Nazis/NNPS/O were/VBD/O evil/JJ/O and/CC/O must/MD/O be/VB/O resisted/VBN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O decision/NN/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O only/RB/O about/RB/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O French/JJ/O citizens/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Humphrey/NNP/B-PERSON Bogart/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON nightclub/NN/O ,/,/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON Laszlo/NNP/I-PERSON leads/VBZ/O Free/NNP/O French/NNP/O sympathizers/NNS/O in/IN/O ``/``/O La/NNP/O Marseillaise/NNP/O ''/''/O to/TO/O drown/VB/O out/RP/O the/DT/O Nazis/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O night/NN/O the/DT/O Germans/NNPS/O occupied/VBD/O all/DT/O of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON performed/VBD/O in/IN/O Casablanca/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Free/NNP/O French/NNP/O wore/VBD/O black/JJ/O arm/NN/O bands/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O she/PRP/O sang/VBD/O ``/``/O J'ai/FW/O deux/FW/O amours/FW/O ''/''/O they/PRP/O wept/VBD/O ././O
Ms./NNP/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O best/JJS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O her/PRP$/O introduction/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON writes/VBZ/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O feels/VBZ/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O much/JJ/O in/IN/O common/NN/O with/IN/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O as/IN/O ``/``/O Jazz/NN/O Cleopatra/NNP/O ''/''/O goes/VBZ/O on/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O more/RBR/O rushed/VBN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O though/IN/O the/DT/O author/NN/O were/VBD/O growing/VBG/O less/RBR/O interested/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O help/VB/O that/IN/O sometimes/RB/O Ms./NNP/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O language/NN/O fails/VBZ/O to/TO/O deliver/VB/O the/DT/O effect/NN/O she/PRP/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O want/VB/O ././O
One/CD/O chapter/NN/O opens/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O glorious/JJ/O moments/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Elsewhere/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O explain/VB/O without/IN/O stating/VBG/O it/PRP/O plainly/RB/O that/IN/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O gay/JJ/O following/NN/O later/RB/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O career/NN/O when/WRB/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O overdressed/JJ/O singer/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O underdressed/JJ/O dancer/NN/O ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Rose/NNP/B-PERSON writes/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O She/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O female/JJ/O impersonator/NN/O who/WP/O happened/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
One/CD/O devoted/JJ/O fan/NN/O who/WP/O fell/VBD/O under/IN/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O spell/NN/O in/IN/O 1963/CD/O and/CC/O began/VBD/O collecting/VBG/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON memorabilia/NNS/O was/VBD/O Bryan/NNP/B-PERSON Hammond/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O ``/``/O Josephine/NNP/O Baker/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Jonathan/NNP/B-PERSON Cape/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 304/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 35/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O published/VBN/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O year/NN/O and/CC/O distributed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hammond/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O used/VBN/O his/PRP$/O collection/NN/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O an/DT/O album/NN/O of/IN/O photographs/NNS/O and/CC/O drawings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O star/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O text/NN/O by/IN/O Patrick/NNP/B-PERSON O'Connor/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O read/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O pictures/NNS/O make/VBP/O her/PRP$/O magnetism/NN/O clear/JJ/O and/CC/O help/VB/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O Ernest/NNP/B-PERSON Hemingway/NNP/I-PERSON called/VBD/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O The/DT/O most/RBS/O sensational/JJ/O woman/NN/O anybody/NN/O ever/RB/O saw/VBD/O ././O
Or/CC/O ever/RB/O will/MD/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lescaze/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O foreign/JJ/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Journal/NNP/B-ORG ././O
