Mr./NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O case/NN/O was/VBD/O particularly/RB/O nettlesome/JJ/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O marked/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O official/NN/O was/VBD/O impeached/VBN/O and/CC/O removed/VBN/O from/IN/O office/NN/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O a/DT/O jury/NN/O had/VBD/O acquitted/VBN/O him/PRP/O ././O
In/IN/O 1983/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O found/VBN/O not/RB/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O accepting/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 150,000/CD/O bribe/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O case/NN/O before/IN/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O charge/NN/O on/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG convicted/VBD/O him/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O only/RB/O the/DT/O sixth/JJ/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O ever/RB/O ousted/VBN/O from/IN/O office/NN/O after/IN/O an/DT/O impeachment/NN/O trial/NN/O ././O
Conviction/NN/O on/IN/O any/DT/O single/JJ/O impeachment/NN/O article/NN/O was/VBD/O enough/JJ/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O Judge/NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON from/IN/O office/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O found/VBN/O not/RB/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O three/CD/O charges/NNS/O ,/,/O involving/VBG/O accusations/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBN/O improperly/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O information/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O sensitive/JJ/O ,/,/O government/NN/O investigation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O vote/VB/O on/IN/O six/CD/O lesser/JJR/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Although/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O acquitted/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O jury/NN/O ,/,/O lawmakers/NNS/O handling/VBG/O the/DT/O prosecution/NN/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O argued/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O purpose/NN/O of/IN/O impeachment/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O to/TO/O punish/VB/O an/DT/O individual/NN/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O argued/VBD/O that/IN/O impeachment/NN/O aims/VBZ/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O public/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O from/IN/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O abused/VBN/O their/PRP$/O positions/NNS/O of/IN/O trust/NN/O ,/,/O irrespective/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O outcome/NN/O of/IN/O prior/JJ/O criminal/JJ/O or/CC/O civil/JJ/O cases/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O impromptu/JJ/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Capitol/NNP/B-ORG steps/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O denounced/VBD/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O '/POS/O action/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Their/PRP$/O opinion/NN/O is/VBZ/O devoid/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O wisdom/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O forefathers/NNS/O '/POS/O teaching/NN/O regarding/VBG/O impeachment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O run/VB/O for/IN/O governor/NN/O of/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O appointed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O bench/NN/O by/IN/O President/NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O 1979/CD/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O few/JJ/O black/JJ/O federal/JJ/O judges/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O he/PRP/O packed/VBD/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG gallery/NN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O supporters/NNS/O during/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O impeachment/NN/O trial/NN/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O civil/JJ/O rights/NNS/O groups/NNS/O kept/VBD/O their/PRP$/O distance/NN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O case/NN/O ././O
Following/VBG/O the/DT/O impeachment/NN/O conviction/NN/O ,/,/O Dr./NNP/O Benjamin/NNP/B-PERSON Hooks/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Advancement/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Colored/NNP/I-ORG People/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O issued/VBD/O a/DT/O restrained/JJ/O statement/NN/O ,/,/O warning/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Hastings/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O could/MD/O set/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O dangerous/JJ/O precedent/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O adding/VBG/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O must/MD/O respect/VB/O the/DT/O considered/JJ/O judgment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ././O
