David/NNP/B-PERSON Boren/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Intelligence/NNP/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O upset/JJ/O that/IN/O someone/NN/O leaked/VBD/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O suggesting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O undertake/VB/O to/TO/O warn/VB/O Panamanian/JJ/O thug/NN/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Noriega/NNP/I-PERSON if/IN/O it/PRP/O got/VBD/O wind/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O impending/JJ/O coup/NN/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O assassination/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O went/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O fitting/JJ/O subject/NN/O for/IN/O public/JJ/O and/CC/O congressional/JJ/O inquiry/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O President/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNP/I-GPE urged/VBD/O the/DT/O Panamanian/JJ/O armed/JJ/O forces/NNS/O to/TO/O move/VB/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O executive/JJ/O branch/NN/O bears/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O timidity/NN/O ././O
CIA/NNP/B-ORG chief/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Webster/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O hardly/RB/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE malcontent/NN/O ,/,/O got/VBD/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O started/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O by/IN/O noting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O order/NN/O banning/VBG/O assassinations/NNS/O had/VBD/O contributed/VBN/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE paralysis/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O coup/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Deputy/NNP/O Director/NNP/O of/IN/O Operations/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Stoltz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O smooth/VB/O things/NNS/O over/RP/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O instead/RB/O simply/RB/O underlined/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O point/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O pay/NN/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O duty/NN/O 's/POS/O lighter/JJR/O ././O
Witness/VB/O the/DT/O Walsh/NNP/B-PERSON prosecution/NN/O of/IN/O Ollie/NNP/B-PERSON North/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
No/DT/O doubt/NN/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O read/VBN/O it/PRP/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O do/VB/O himself/PRP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O country/NN/O a/DT/O favor/NN/O by/IN/O rescinding/VBG/O the/DT/O order/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O ambiguous/JJ/O intrusion/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O defend/VB/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O of/IN/O course/NN/O good/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE should/MD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O rescinding/VBG/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O order/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O thing/NN/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE should/MD/O start/VB/O passing/VBG/O out/RP/O exploding/VBG/O cigars/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O world/NN/O being/VBG/O the/DT/O nasty/JJ/O place/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O want/VBP/O Presidents/NNS/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O freedom/NN/O to/TO/O order/VB/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O someone/NN/O might/MD/O get/VB/O killed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O executive/JJ/O order/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O reported/JJ/O agreements/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O neither/DT/O sensible/JJ/O nor/CC/O moral/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O can/MD/O send/VB/O a/DT/O fighter/NN/O squadron/NN/O to/TO/O strafe/VB/O terrorist/JJ/O hideouts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bekaa/NNP/I-LOC Valley/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O but/CC/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O shoot/VB/O Abu/NNP/B-PERSON Nidal/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Both/PDT/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O order/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O debate/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O telling/VBG/O the/DT/O world/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O way/NN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O kill/VB/O a/DT/O madman/NN/O is/VBZ/O by/IN/O making/VBG/O sure/JJ/O we/PRP/O take/VBP/O some/DT/O innocent/JJ/O civilians/NNS/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
