Norimasa/NNP/B-PERSON Furuta/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Mazda/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O car/NN/O maker/NN/O is/VBZ/O planning/VBG/O joint/JJ/O production/NN/O with/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ahead/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 1992/CD/O integration/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Furuta/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O further/JJ/O details/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O arrangement/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O news/NN/O conference/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O project/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O undertaken/VBN/O with/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O European/JJ/O subsidiary/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O confirmed/VBD/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE motor/NN/O vehicle/NN/O maker/NN/O is/VBZ/O studying/VBG/O such/PDT/O an/DT/O arrangement/NN/O ././O
