AEG/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Siemens/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O launch/VB/O their/PRP$/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O for/IN/O power/NN/O semiconductors/NNS/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O electronics/NN/O concerns/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O set/VBN/O up/RP/O European/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG Semiconductor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O merge/VB/O their/PRP$/O activities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O ././O
AEG/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Siemens/NNP/B-ORG each/DT/O will/MD/O hold/VB/O a/DT/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O nominal/JJ/O capital/NN/O of/IN/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O marks/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 26.9/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O 700/CD/O employees/NNS/O ././O
Siemens/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE largest/JJS/O electronics/NN/O group/NN/O ././O
