Mr./NNP/O McElroy/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 54/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ././O
Sovran/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O named/VBD/O John/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Werner/NNP/I-PERSON a/DT/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O parent/JJ/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O and/CC/O elected/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O newly/RB/O created/VBN/O position/NN/O of/IN/O chief/JJ/O credit/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Sovran/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O increasing/VBG/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O corporate/JJ/O board/NN/O members/NNS/O to/TO/O 35/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Werner/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 58/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O formerly/RB/O senior/JJ/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O parent/JJ/O company/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ././O
