Tandy/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O join/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O group/NN/O that/WDT/O seeks/VBZ/O to/TO/O battle/VB/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O computer/NN/O memory/NN/O chips/NNS/O ././O
Tandy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O decision/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O setback/NN/O for/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O invest/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O ././O
Apple/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/DT/O its/PRP$/O money/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O better/RBR/O spent/VBN/O in/IN/O areas/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O research/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O major/JJ/O investors/NNS/O to/TO/O back/VB/O its/PRP$/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O crack/VB/O the/DT/O $/$/O 10/CD/O billion/CD/O market/NN/O for/IN/O dynamic/JJ/O random/JJ/O access/NN/O memory/NN/O chips/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O market/NN/O dominated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O ././O
Tandy/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O experience/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O shortage/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O merit/NN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 5/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O investment/NN/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O from/IN/O each/DT/O investor/NN/O ././O
Sanford/NNP/B-PERSON Kane/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG president/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O disappointing/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O presage/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG failure/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kane/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O two/CD/O or/CC/O three/CD/O major/JJ/O corporations/NNS/O to/TO/O announce/VB/O their/PRP$/O participation/NN/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG soon/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O finishes/VBZ/O a/DT/O business/NN/O plan/NN/O ,/,/O probably/RB/O late/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG needs/VBZ/O a/DT/O catalyst/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O to/TO/O inspire/VB/O others/NNS/O to/TO/O join/VB/O ././O
Sun/NNP/B-ORG Microsystems/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O still/RB/O actively/RB/O evaluating/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O with/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-ORG Memories/NNP/I-ORG representatives/NNS/O later/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Compaq/NNP/B-ORG Computer/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O made/VBN/O a/DT/O decision/NN/O yet/RB/O ,/,/O although/IN/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O under/IN/O active/JJ/O consideration/NN/O ././O
