The/DT/O regulations/NNS/O ,/,/O required/VBN/O under/IN/O legislation/NN/O enacted/VBN/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O apply/VB/O to/TO/O imports/NNS/O of/IN/O vehicles/NNS/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O built/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O auto/NN/O safety/NN/O standards/NNS/O and/CC/O were/VBD/O intended/VBN/O for/IN/O use/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC or/CC/O elsewhere/RB/O abroad/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O registered/JJ/O importer/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O such/JJ/O vehicles/NNS/O into/IN/O compliance/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE safety/NN/O standards/NNS/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O situation/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O anyone/NN/O can/MD/O bring/VB/O in/IN/O such/JJ/O vehicles/NNS/O and/CC/O modify/VB/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE standards/NNS/O ././O
