Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG loves/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O intimate/JJ/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O customers/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O public/NN/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/B-PERSON Coleman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 73/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O interviewed/VBN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG strategist/NN/O ././O
Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O profitable/JJ/O but/CC/O declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O specifics/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O sells/VBZ/O image/NN/O ././O
Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG generated/VBD/O such/JJ/O memorable/JJ/O campaigns/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O dreamed/VBD/O I/PRP/O .../:/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG bra/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG woman/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O days/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Olga/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O competing/VBG/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O division/NN/O of/IN/O Warnaco/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Warnaco/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O owns/VBZ/O Warners/NNS/B-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O major/JJ/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O maker/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O downplayed/VBD/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lesk/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O split/VBD/O his/PRP$/O merchandising/NN/O responsibilities/NNS/O among/IN/O a/DT/O committee/NN/O of/IN/O four/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
Top/JJ/O officers/NNS/O insist/VBP/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O greatest/JJS/O strength/NN/O is/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O family/NN/O ownership/NN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O major/JJ/O players/NNS/O in/IN/O intimate/JJ/O apparel/NN/O apparently/RB/O feel/VBP/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O way/NN/O ././O
Warnaco/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O taken/VBN/O private/JJ/O by/IN/O Spectrum/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1986/CD/O for/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 487/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O could/MD/O command/VB/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O price/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Brawer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O along/RB/O with/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP/O daughter/NN/O ,/,/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O vice/RB/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O family/NN/O members/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O employs/VBZ/O about/RB/O 5,000/CD/O ././O
Each/DT/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O equal/JJ/O vote/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O monthly/JJ/O meetings/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O name/NN/O Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O coined/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O third/JJ/O business/NN/O partner/NN/O ,/,/O Enid/NNP/B-PERSON Bissett/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O 14/CD/O plants/NNS/O and/CC/O distribution/NN/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O other/JJ/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Caribbean/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Ireland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Maidenform/NNP/B-ORG products/NNS/O are/VBP/O mainly/RB/O sold/VBN/O at/IN/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O quietly/RB/O opened/VBN/O a/DT/O retail/JJ/O store/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O in/IN/O Omaha/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Neb./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O 24/CD/O factory/NN/O outlets/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O add/VB/O more/JJR/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Coleman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O husband/NN/O ,/,/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O physician/NN/O ,/,/O succeeded/VBD/O Mrs./NNP/O Rosenthal/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O served/VBD/O in/IN/O that/DT/O post/NN/O until/IN/O his/PRP$/O death/NN/O in/IN/O 1968/CD/O ././O
