A/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O entered/VBN/O a/DT/O judgment/NN/O requiring/VBG/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE organized/JJ/O crime/NN/O figure/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O ,/,/O representing/VBG/O alleged/JJ/O profits/NNS/O he/PRP/O gained/VBD/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O involvement/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Brotherhood/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Teamsters/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE U.S./NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O Otto/NNP/B-PERSON Obermaier/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O ever/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O had/VBD/O obtained/VBN/O any/DT/O disgorgement/NN/O from/IN/O an/DT/O organized/JJ/O crime/NN/O figure/NN/O indicted/VBN/O under/IN/O the/DT/O civil/JJ/O racketeering/NN/O law/NN/O ././O
Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON Lombardo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O the/DT/O government/NN/O alleged/VBD/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O captain/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O organized/JJ/O crime/NN/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O numerous/JJ/O defendants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O sweeping/JJ/O racketeering/NN/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O Teamsters/NNPS/B-ORG ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE District/NNP/O Judge/NNP/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Edelstein/NNP/I-PERSON also/RB/O permanently/RB/O enjoined/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Lombardo/NNP/B-PERSON from/IN/O any/DT/O future/JJ/O dealings/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Teamsters/NNPS/B-ORG or/CC/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O labor/NN/O union/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lombardo/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O defendants/NNS/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O within/IN/O one/CD/O week/NN/O ././O
