In/IN/O a/DT/O startling/JJ/O turnabout/NN/O ,/,/O Members/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O complaining/VBG/O that/IN/O someone/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O branch/NN/O is/VBZ/O leaking/VBG/O on/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Boren/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Intelligence/NNP/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O upset/JJ/O that/IN/O someone/NN/O leaked/VBD/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O suggesting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O undertake/VB/O to/TO/O warn/VB/O Panamanian/JJ/O thug/NN/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Noriega/NNP/I-PERSON if/IN/O it/PRP/O got/VBD/O wind/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O impending/JJ/O coup/NN/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O assassination/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O due/JJ/O respect/NN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O highly/RB/O classified/JJ/O correspondence/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O buzzwords/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O leakers/NNS/O are/VBP/O performing/VBG/O a/DT/O public/JJ/O service/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O a/DT/O protection/NN/O service/NN/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O know/VB/O ././O
What/WP/O went/VBD/O wrong/JJ/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O fitting/JJ/O subject/NN/O for/IN/O public/JJ/O and/CC/O congressional/JJ/O inquiry/NN/O ././O
Naturally/RB/O ,/,/O Senator/NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O committee/NN/O would/MD/O like/VB/O free/JJ/O rein/NN/O to/TO/O blame/VB/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O branch/NN/O while/IN/O stamping/VBG/O ``/``/O top/JJ/O secret/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O complicity/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O no/DT/O danger/NN/O of/IN/O exposing/VBG/O sources/NNS/O and/CC/O methods/NNS/O in/IN/O disclosing/VBG/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O running/VBG/O up/IN/O and/CC/O down/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-FAC Avenue/NNP/I-FAC ././O
And/CC/O if/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O assume/VB/O authority/NN/O to/TO/O micromanage/NN/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O have/VB/O to/TO/O take/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O responsibility/NN/O too/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O President/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNP/I-GPE urged/VBD/O the/DT/O Panamanian/JJ/O armed/JJ/O forces/NNS/O to/TO/O move/VB/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
When/WRB/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O commanders/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O initiative/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O block/VB/O a/DT/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O roads/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O executive/JJ/O branch/NN/O bears/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O timidity/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O what/WP/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O initiative/NN/O can/MD/O you/PRP/O expect/VB/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O climate/NN/O set/VBN/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ?/./O
For/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O what/WP/O exactly/RB/O did/VBD/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG tell/VB/O Major/NNP/O Giroldi/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O fellow/NN/O coup/NN/O plotters/NNS/O about/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE laws/NNS/O and/CC/O executive/JJ/O orders/NNS/O on/IN/O assassinations/NNS/O ?/./O
What/WP/O part/NN/O did/VBD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE warnings/NNS/O play/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O major/NN/O 's/POS/O unwillingness/NN/O to/TO/O pull/VB/O the/DT/O trigger/NN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O General/NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O custody/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O was/VBD/O under/IN/O attack/NN/O by/IN/O pro-Noriega/JJ/B-PERSON troops/NNS/O ?/./O
Mr./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O suffer/VB/O from/IN/O any/DT/O hesitation/NN/O once/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O pistol/NN/O ././O
Maybe/RB/O we/PRP/O need/VBP/O a/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Miranda/NNP/O warning/NN/O :/:/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O conceal/VB/O your/PRP$/O coup/NN/O intentions/NNS/O ,/,/O because/IN/O we/PRP/O may/MD/O rat/VB/O on/IN/O you/PRP/O ././O
Or/CC/O maybe/RB/O a/DT/O Surgeon/NNP/O General/NNP/O 's/POS/O warning/NN/O :/:/O Confiding/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE may/MD/O be/VB/O fatal/JJ/O ././O
CIA/NNP/B-ORG chief/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Webster/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O hardly/RB/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE malcontent/NN/O ,/,/O got/VBD/O the/DT/O debate/NN/O started/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O by/IN/O noting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O order/NN/O banning/VBG/O assassinations/NNS/O had/VBD/O contributed/VBN/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE paralysis/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O coup/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Deputy/NNP/O Director/NNP/O of/IN/O Operations/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Stoltz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O smooth/VB/O things/NNS/O over/RP/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O days/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O instead/RB/O simply/RB/O underlined/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O point/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O interpretation/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O order/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Stoltz/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O and/CC/O the/DT/O way/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O various/JJ/O committees/NNS/O have/VBP/O over/IN/O time/NN/O interpreted/VBD/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O led/VBN/O in/IN/O my/PRP$/O view/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O proper/JJ/O caution/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O operators/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O me/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O other/JJ/O words/NNS/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O let/VB/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG do/VB/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O anything/NN/O anymore/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O fine/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O pay/NN/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O duty/NN/O 's/POS/O lighter/JJR/O ././O
Witness/VB/O the/DT/O Walsh/NNP/B-PERSON prosecution/NN/O of/IN/O Ollie/NNP/B-PERSON North/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
No/DT/O doubt/NN/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O read/VBN/O it/PRP/O ././O
What/WP/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O initiative/NN/O should/MD/O anyone/NN/O expect/VB/O from/IN/O people/NNS/O out/IN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O who/WP/O 've/VBP/O read/VBN/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O and/CC/O know/VBP/O what/WP/O can/MD/O happen/VB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O fail/VBP/O ?/./O
Who/WP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O end/VB/O up/RP/O as/IN/O the/DT/O protagonist/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Cohen/NNP/I-PERSON morality/NN/O play/NN/O ?/./O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O do/VB/O himself/PRP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O country/NN/O a/DT/O favor/NN/O by/IN/O rescinding/VBG/O the/DT/O order/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O ambiguous/JJ/O intrusion/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O defend/VB/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O of/IN/O course/NN/O good/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE should/MD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O rescinding/VBG/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O order/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O thing/NN/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE should/MD/O start/VB/O passing/VBG/O out/RP/O exploding/VBG/O cigars/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O world/NN/O being/VBG/O the/DT/O nasty/JJ/O place/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O want/VBP/O Presidents/NNS/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O freedom/NN/O to/TO/O order/VB/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O someone/NN/O might/MD/O get/VB/O killed/VBN/O ././O
In/IN/O such/JJ/O situations/NNS/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O write/VB/O rules/NNS/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O only/RB/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O the/DT/O President/NNP/O takes/VBZ/O the/DT/O responsibility/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O executive/JJ/O order/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O reported/JJ/O agreements/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O neither/DT/O sensible/JJ/O nor/CC/O moral/JJ/O ././O
As/IN/O it/PRP/O now/RB/O stands/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE can/MD/O bomb/VB/O Tripoli/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O ``/``/O assassinate/VB/O ''/''/O Colonel/NNP/O Gadhafi/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
It/PRP/O can/MD/O send/VB/O a/DT/O fighter/NN/O squadron/NN/O to/TO/O strafe/VB/O terrorist/JJ/O hideouts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bekaa/NNP/I-LOC Valley/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O but/CC/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O shoot/VB/O Abu/NNP/B-PERSON Nidal/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Both/PDT/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O order/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O debate/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O telling/VBG/O the/DT/O world/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O way/NN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O kill/VB/O a/DT/O madman/NN/O is/VBZ/O by/IN/O making/VBG/O sure/JJ/O we/PRP/O take/VBP/O some/DT/O innocent/JJ/O civilians/NNS/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
