Turner/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O formed/VBD/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O and/CC/O distribute/VB/O movies/NNS/O to/TO/O theaters/NNS/O overseas/RB/O and/CC/O ,/,/O eventually/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE theaters/NNS/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O unit/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O two/CD/O offerings/NNS/O are/VBP/O slated/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Secret/JJ/O Life/NN/O of/IN/O Ian/NNP/O Fleming/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O dramatization/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O British/JJ/O spy/NN/O who/WP/O wrote/VBD/O the/DT/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Bond/NNP/I-PERSON novels/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Treasure/NNP/O Island/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O Charlton/NNP/B-PERSON Heston/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O also/RB/O stars/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O movie/NN/O ././O
Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Turner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG chairman/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Gerry/NNP/B-PERSON Hogan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Networks/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Hogan/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O 's/POS/O primary/JJ/O mission/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O movies/NNS/O for/IN/O TNT/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O to/TO/O distribute/VB/O them/PRP/O internationally/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O found/VBN/O some/DT/O ideas/NNS/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O work/VB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O films/NNS/O for/IN/O theatrical/NN/O release/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O that/DT/O occurs/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O time/NN/O is/VBZ/O right/JJ/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O release/VB/O the/DT/O films/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG may/MD/O develop/VB/O such/JJ/O movies/NNS/O next/IN/O year/NN/O for/IN/O domestic/JJ/O release/NN/O in/IN/O 1991/CD/O ././O
