Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG Publications/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Haven/NNP/I-ORG Register/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 275/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG Newspaper/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Goodson/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O accused/VBN/O Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O paying/VBG/O less/JJR/O attention/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O properties/NNS/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O such/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O launch/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG St./NNP/I-ORG Louis/NNP/I-ORG Sun/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Goodson/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O settlement/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O management/NN/O contract/NN/O ././O
Goodson/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O announced/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O hired/VBD/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O president/NN/O and/CC/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O run/VB/O the/DT/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG papers/NNS/O ././O
Both/DT/O executives/NNS/O left/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O after/IN/O clashes/NNS/O with/IN/O Chairman/NNP/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Ingersoll/NNP/I-PERSON Jr/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Goodson/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O will/MD/O use/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O proceeds/NNS/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O down/RP/O debt/NN/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Morristown/NNP/I-ORG Daily/NNP/I-ORG Record/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 155/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE paper/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE Haven/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O paper/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O purchased/VBN/O by/IN/O Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O behalf/NN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O management/NN/O contract/NN/O ././O
Industry/NN/O analysts/NNS/O have/VBP/O said/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O price/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O paper/NN/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O high/JJ/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O a/DT/O strain/NN/O on/IN/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O finances/NNS/O ././O
Investment/NN/O bankers/NNS/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O bank/NN/O credit/NN/O line/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 190/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O may/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O additional/JJ/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON N./NNP/I-PERSON Hurwitz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O operating/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O telephone/NN/O interview/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O currently/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O additional/JJ/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O association/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O stretches/VBZ/O back/RB/O thirty/CD/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O friendship/NN/O between/IN/O television/NN/O producer/NN/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON Goodson/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG founder/NN/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Ingersoll/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O latter/NN/O 's/POS/O son/NN/O ,/,/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Ingersoll/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O took/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O managing/VBG/O the/DT/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG properties/NNS/O and/CC/O acting/VBG/O as/IN/O an/DT/O agent/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O newspapers/NNS/O for/IN/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O 28/CD/O dailies/NNS/O and/CC/O 200/CD/O other/JJ/O non-daily/JJ/O papers/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O revenue/NN/O will/MD/O exceed/VB/O $/$/O 750/CD/O million/CD/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG President/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Jelenic/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O delighted/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O conclusion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG relationship/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O ``/``/O concentrate/VB/O all/PDT/O our/PRP$/O energies/NNS/O ''/''/O on/IN/O Ingersoll/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O own/JJ/O papers/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Goodson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O statement/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O less/RBR/O upbeat/JJ/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O ``/``/O unfortunately/RB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O increasingly/RB/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O different/JJ/O agendas/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O feels/VBZ/O ``/``/O more/RBR/O comfortable/JJ/O with/IN/O a/DT/O management/NN/O team/NN/O whose/WP$/O sole/JJ/O interest/NN/O and/CC/O responsibility/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Goodson/NNP/B-ORG papers/NNS/O ././O
