Chip/NN/O 's/POS/O Memory/NN/O Is/VBZ/O Here/RB/O Today/NN/O ,/,/O Here/RB/O Tomorrow/NN/O
TWO/CD/O COMPANIES/NNS/O plan/VBP/O to/TO/O market/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O chip/NN/O with/IN/O ceramic/JJ/O circuits/NNS/O that/IN/O store/VBP/O data/NNS/O even/RB/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O power/NN/O is/VBZ/O off/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O chips/NNS/O use/VBP/O materials/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O lead/NN/O zirconate/NN/O titanate/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O form/VB/O microscopic/JJ/O switches/NNS/O that/WDT/O retain/VBP/O their/PRP$/O data/NNS/O without/IN/O electricity/NN/O ././O
Developers/NNS/O caution/VBP/O that/IN/O broad/JJ/O applications/NNS/O are/VBP/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O away/RB/O because/IN/O the/DT/O technology/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O fully/RB/O refined/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O Ramtron/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE Springs/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Colo./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O start/VB/O shipping/VBG/O commercial/JJ/O quantities/NNS/O of/IN/O simple/JJ/O ferroelectric/JJ/O chips/NNS/O in/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
National/NNP/B-ORG Semiconductor/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O ferroelectric/JJ/O technology/NN/O from/IN/O Krysalis/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Albuquerque/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.M/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Once/IN/O production/NN/O hurdles/NNS/O are/VBP/O overcome/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O chips/NNS/O could/MD/O take/VB/O over/RP/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O not/RB/O needing/VBG/O an/DT/O outside/JJ/O power/NN/O source/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O potentially/RB/O cheaper/JJR/O to/TO/O make/VB/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O require/VBP/O fewer/JJR/O manufacturing/NN/O steps/NNS/O than/IN/O conventional/JJ/O chips/NNS/O ././O
Military/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O shown/VBN/O interest/NN/O ,/,/O National/JJ/B-ORG says/VBZ/O ,/,/O because/IN/O ferroelectric/JJ/O chips/NNS/O resist/VBP/O atomic/JJ/O radiation/NN/O ././O
Showing/VBG/O Up/RP/O in/IN/O Court/NN/O Without/IN/O Being/VBG/O There/RB/O
AN/DT/O AUSTIN/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O company/NN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O easy/JJ/O for/IN/O you/PRP/O show/VB/O up/RP/O in/IN/O court/NN/O a/DT/O thousand/CD/O miles/NNS/O away/RB/O without/IN/O leaving/VBG/O town/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O means/VBZ/O huge/JJ/O travel/NN/O bills/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O telephone/NN/O or/CC/O videotape/NN/O depositions/NNS/O just/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O match/VB/O physical/JJ/O encounters/NNS/O ././O
Video/NNP/B-ORG Telecom/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O markets/VBZ/O videoconferencing/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O with/IN/O court/NN/O reporters/NNS/O to/TO/O wire/VB/O a/DT/O nationwide/JJ/O network/NN/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O depositions/NNS/O by/IN/O live/JJ/O television/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O installed/VBD/O a/DT/O prototype/NN/O system/NN/O that/WDT/O connects/VBZ/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O digital/JJ/O phone/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O attorney/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O use/VB/O the/DT/O network/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O hourly/JJ/O fee/NN/O of/IN/O between/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 400/CD/O ,/,/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O quality/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O take/VB/O depositions/NNS/O from/IN/O witnesses/NNS/O in/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O connected/JJ/O cities/NNS/O ././O
Japanese/NNPS/O Reverse/VBP/O Tack/NN/O On/IN/O Patent/NN/O Protection/NN/O
JAPAN/NNP/B-GPE 'S/POS/O MISUSE/NNP/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE patents/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O sore/JJ/O point/NN/O for/IN/O American/JJ/O chip/NN/O makers/NNS/O ././O
Now/RB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O one/CD/O Japanese/JJ/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O turning/VBG/O the/DT/O courtroom/NN/O tables/NNS/O ././O
Until/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O Japanese/JJ/O charges/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O responses/NNS/O to/TO/O suits/NNS/O against/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O A/DT/O settlement/NN/O was/VBD/O reached/VBN/O but/CC/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O made/VBN/O public/JJ/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
And/CC/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG went/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O offensive/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O suit/NN/O charging/VBG/O that/IN/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O new/JJ/O MC88200/NNP/O chip/NN/O infringes/VBZ/O on/IN/O a/DT/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG patent/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O recent/JJ/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG suit/NN/O accuses/VBZ/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O reverse/RB/O engineering/VBG/O a/DT/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG technology/NN/O --/:/O a/DT/O turnabout/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O nation/NN/O of/IN/O champion/JJ/O reverse/JJ/O engineers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O moves/NNS/O illustrate/VBP/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O aggressive/JJ/O attitude/NN/O toward/IN/O patent/NN/O protection/NN/O that/IN/O patent/JJ/O experts/NNS/O say/VBP/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O starting/VBG/O to/TO/O take/VB/O ././O
Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG charges/VBZ/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O has/VBZ/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O fraudulent/JJ/O and/CC/O inequitable/JJ/O conduct/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O procurement/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG patents/NNS/O ''/''/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O MC68030/NNP/O microprocessor/NN/O chip/NN/O ././O
Translation/NN/O :/:/O Motorola/NNP/B-ORG appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG technology/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O patented/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Hitachi/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ``/``/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O look/VB/O like/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O technology/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Motorola/NNP/B-ORG either/CC/O denied/VBN/O or/CC/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O various/JJ/O charges/NNS/O ././O
Odds/NNS/O and/CC/O Ends/NNS/O
COMPUTER/NN/O chips/NNS/O that/WDT/O simulate/VBP/O human/JJ/O vision/NN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O developed/VBN/O by/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Sharp/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
They/PRP/O mimic/VBP/O the/DT/O brain/NN/O by/IN/O ``/``/O looking/VBG/O ''/''/O at/IN/O an/DT/O image/NN/O ,/,/O extracting/VBG/O the/DT/O fundamentals/NNS/O --/:/O boundaries/NNS/O ,/,/O corners/NNS/O and/CC/O lines/NNS/O --/:/O and/CC/O translating/VBG/O them/PRP/O into/IN/O computer/NN/O data/NNS/O ././O
Sharp/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O the/DT/O set/NN/O of/IN/O chips/NNS/O could/MD/O improve/VB/O fax/NN/O machines/NNS/O ,/,/O graphics/NNS/O computers/NNS/O or/CC/O identification/NN/O systems/NNS/O that/WDT/O recognize/VBP/O facial/JJ/O features/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
An/DT/O N.V/NNP/B-ORG ././I-ORG Philips/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O has/VBZ/O created/VBN/O a/DT/O computer/NN/O system/NN/O that/WDT/O processes/VBZ/O video/NN/O images/NNS/O 3,000/CD/O times/NNS/O faster/RBR/O than/IN/O conventional/JJ/O systems/NNS/O ././O
