As/IN/O Helen/NNP/B-PERSON Boehm/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O owns/VBZ/O an/DT/O art/NN/O porcelain/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O sipped/VBD/O her/PRP$/O luncheon/NN/O cocktail/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O reeled/VBD/O off/RP/O the/DT/O names/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O pals/NNS/O --/:/O Prince/NNP/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Princess/NNP/O Diana/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Sarah/NNP/B-PERSON Ferguson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Kluge/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Milton/NNP/B-PERSON Petrie/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Then/RB/O ,/,/O flashing/VBG/O a/DT/O diamond/NN/O ring/NN/O as/RB/O big/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Ritz/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O my/JJ/O day/NN/O diamond/NN/O ,/,/O darling/NN/O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O told/VBD/O her/PRP/O two/CD/O companions/NNS/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O board/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Vatican/NNP/I-ORG Museum/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Rome/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O Mrs./NNP/O Boehm/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O any/DT/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O Helen/NNP/B-PERSON Boehm/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O a/DT/O way/NN/O with/IN/O names/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Revson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O gossip/NN/O columnist/NN/O for/IN/O Newsday/NNP/B-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O son/NN/O of/IN/O Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON Revson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O founder/NN/O of/IN/O Revlon/NNP/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Like/IN/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O droppable/JJ/O and/CC/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O In/IN/O case/NN/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O forgotten/VBN/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O name/NN/O was/VBD/O Rudolph/NNP/B-PERSON Dirks/NNP/I-PERSON ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
``/``/O It/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O an/DT/O avenue/NN/O of/IN/O entrance/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O certain/JJ/O sector/NN/O of/IN/O society/NN/O .../:/O ././O
It/PRP/O provides/VBZ/O some/DT/O people/NNS/O a/DT/O needed/JJ/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O affiliation/NN/O and/CC/O can/MD/O help/VB/O open/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O conversation/NN/O with/IN/O someone/NN/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Like/IN/O the/DT/O Long/NNP/B-LOC Island/NNP/I-LOC matron/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O theater/NN/O district/NN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O day/NN/O who/WP/O swore/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O stranger/NN/O that/IN/O she/PRP/O once/RB/O met/VBD/O Liza/NNP/B-PERSON Minnelli/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O having/VBG/O a/DT/O drink/NN/O in/IN/O Sardi/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ,/,/O when/WRB/O all/RB/O of/IN/O a/DT/O sudden/JJ/O I/PRP/O saw/VBD/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O 's/POS/O backside/NN/O coming/VBG/O up/RP/O the/DT/O steps/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O floor/NN/O and/CC/O she/PRP/O was/VBD/O wearing/VBG/O sequined/JJ/O slacks/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O knew/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O someone/NN/O important/JJ/O ,/,/O so/IN/O I/PRP/O followed/VBD/O her/PRP/O into/IN/O the/DT/O ladies/NNS/O room/NN/O and/CC/O sure/RB/O enough/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O Liza/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
So/IN/O I/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O `/``/O Hello/UH/O ././O '/''/O
And/CC/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O `/``/O Hello/UH/O ././O '/''/O
Can/MD/O you/PRP/O imagine/VB/O ?/./O
Liza/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O hello/UH/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O people/NNS/O must/MD/O drop/VB/O names/NNS/O --/:/O call/VB/O it/PRP/O an/DT/O irresistible/JJ/O impulse/NN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O help/VB/O talking/VBG/O about/IN/O the/DT/O big/JJ/O important/JJ/O people/NNS/O they/PRP/O know/VBP/O ,/,/O even/RB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O really/RB/O know/VB/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Dr./NNP/O Freudenberger/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O it/PRP/O innately/RB/O and/CC/O pathologically/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O while/IN/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O occasionally/RB/O get/VB/O me/PRP/O into/IN/O trouble/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O also/RB/O gotten/VBN/O me/PRP/O access/NN/O to/TO/O parties/NNS/O and/CC/O society/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O guess/VBP/O I/PRP/O might/MD/O have/VB/O asked/VBD/O Beauregard/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O leave/VB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O drops/VBZ/O so/RB/O many/JJ/O good/JJ/O names/NNS/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O let/VB/O him/PRP/O stay/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Steven/NNP/B-PERSON Greenberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O publisher/NN/O of/IN/O Fame/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O After/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O Warhol/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/O ultimate/JJ/O namedropper/NN/O ,/,/O dropping/VBG/O five/CD/O a/DT/O day/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O diaries/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O Beauregard/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O mentioned/VBN/O twice/RB/O --/:/O although/IN/O very/JJ/O briefly/NN/O and/CC/O in/IN/O passing/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Revson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O gossip/NN/O columnist/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O actually/RB/O plan/VBP/O whose/WP$/O names/NNS/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O before/IN/O attending/VBG/O a/DT/O party/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O droppers/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O flaunt/VB/O only/RB/O their/PRP$/O friendships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Trumps/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O Brooke/NNP/B-PERSON Astor/NNP/I-PERSON or/CC/O Georgette/NNP/B-PERSON Mosbacher/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O even/RB/O drop/VBP/O semi-obscure/JJ/O names/NNS/O like/IN/O Wolfgang/NNP/B-PERSON Flottl/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whom/WP/O everybody/NN/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O apparently/RB/O has/VBZ/O heard/VBN/O of/IN/O but/CC/O no/DT/O one/NN/O really/RB/O knows/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Revson/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O of/IN/O civic/JJ/O pride/NN/O and/CC/O from/IN/O the/DT/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O nullify/VB/O a/DT/O negative/JJ/O image/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O city/NN/O promoters/NNS/O seek/VBP/O to/TO/O link/VB/O their/PRP$/O municipality/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O recognizable/JJ/O names/NNS/O the/DT/O city/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O ././O
Take/VB/O Cleveland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Some/DT/O people/NNS/O call/VBP/O it/PRP/O ``/``/O The/NNP/B-GPE Mistake/NNP/I-GPE on/IN/I-GPE the/NNP/I-GPE Lake/NNP/I-GPE ''/''/O --/:/O Lake/NNP/B-LOC Erie/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O helps/VBZ/O to/TO/O point/VB/O out/RP/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O important/JJ/O people/NNS/O came/VBD/O through/IN/O Cleveland/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O their/PRP$/O way/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O top/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Miller/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Cleveland/NNP/I-ORG Campaign/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O nonprofit/JJ/O organization/NN/O devoted/VBN/O to/TO/O citing/VBG/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O strengths/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Power/NN/O names/NNS/O like/IN/O that/DT/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O hurt/VB/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O reputation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
In/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O average/JJ/O family/NN/O can/MD/O gain/VB/O cachet/NN/O from/IN/O moving/VBG/O into/IN/O a/DT/O home/NN/O vacated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O famous/JJ/O or/CC/O near/RB/O famous/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O Most/JJS/O people/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O remember/VB/O his/PRP$/O name/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Hart/NNP/I-PERSON ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
``/``/O If/IN/O Flynn/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O n't/RB/O lived/VBN/O there/EX/O ,/,/O the/DT/O property/NN/O might/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O priced/VBN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O lower/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Rambo/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O noting/VBG/O that/IN/O Flynn/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O house/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O bulldozed/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O only/RB/O the/DT/O swimming/VBG/O pool/NN/O remains/VBZ/O ././O
And/CC/O some/DT/O even/RB/O do/VBP/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O malice/NN/O aforethought/JJ/O ././O
Len/NNP/B-PERSON Kessler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O publicist/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O sometimes/RB/O uses/VBZ/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O attention/NN/O of/IN/O journalists/NNS/O who/WP/O try/VBP/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O him/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Dorfman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O columnist/NN/O with/IN/O USA/NNP/B-ORG Today/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O returned/VBD/O his/PRP$/O phone/NN/O calls/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O leaves/VBZ/O messages/NNS/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Dorfman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O office/NN/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O story/NN/O on/IN/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Trump/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Meshulam/NNP/B-PERSON Riklis/NNP/I-PERSON or/CC/O Marvin/NNP/B-PERSON Davis/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O admits/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O story/NN/O on/IN/O any/DT/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O on/IN/O these/DT/O occasions/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O get/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O return/VB/O my/PRP$/O calls/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O makes/VBZ/O me/PRP/O feel/VB/O better/RBR/O for/IN/O the/DT/O times/NNS/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O given/VBN/O me/PRP/O the/DT/O brushoff/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Kessler/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Jeffry/NNP/B-PERSON Thal/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O publicity/NN/O agent/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Lantz/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O warns/VBZ/O that/IN/O dropping/VBG/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O name/NN/O labels/VBZ/O the/DT/O dropper/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O fake/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O fraud/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Get/VB/O caught/VBN/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O dead/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O water/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Thal/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Thal/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/IN/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON Taylor/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O client/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O hates/VBZ/O being/VBG/O called/VBN/O `/``/O Liz/NNP/B-PERSON ././O '/''/O .../:/O
If/IN/O directors/NNS/O or/CC/O producers/NNS/O phone/VBP/O me/PRP/O and/CC/O say/VB/O they/PRP/O know/VBP/O `/``/O Liz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O '/''/O I/PRP/O know/VBP/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O never/RB/O met/VBN/O her/PRP/O ././O
She/PRP/O prefers/VBZ/O `/``/O Elizabeth/NNP/B-PERSON ././O '/''/O ''/''/O
In/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE society/NN/O ,/,/O Pat/NNP/B-PERSON Buckley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O very/RB/O social/JJ/O wife/NN/O of/IN/O author/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Buckley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O nicknames/NNS/O ``/``/O Mrs./NNP/O Buckles/NNP/B-PERSON ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Patsy/NNP/B-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O her/PRP$/O husband/NN/O sometimes/RB/O calls/VBZ/O her/PRP/O ``/``/O Ducky/NNP/B-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O only/RB/O drop/VBP/O ``/``/O mere/JJ/O names/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Churchill/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Currently/RB/O writing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O memoirs/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Churchill/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O artist/NN/O ,/,/O tells/VBZ/O how/WRB/O tycoons/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O Jean/NNP/B-PERSON Paul/NNP/I-PERSON Getty/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O billionnaire/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O ,/,/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O only/RB/O by/IN/O one/CD/O initial/NN/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O last/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O club/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O ask/VBP/O whether/IN/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O spoken/VBN/O to/TO/O `/``/O G/NNP/B-PERSON ././O '/''/O
Now/RB/O they/PRP/O know/VBP/O who/WP/O you/PRP/O mean/VBP/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O know/VBP/O who/WP/O you/PRP/O mean/VBP/O ././O
But/CC/O no/DT/O one/NN/O else/RB/O does/VBZ/O ././O
