Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 59/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O abruptly/RB/O announced/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O leave/VB/O the/DT/O venerable/JJ/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O whose/WP$/O largest/JJS/O client/NN/O is/VBZ/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O become/VB/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O corporate/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O and/CC/O communications/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O succeed/VB/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Freeman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 57/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O retire/VB/O in/IN/O December/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Freeman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O retire/VB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O ``/``/O executive/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O an/DT/O embarrassing/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O discredit/VB/O banker/NN/O Edmond/NNP/B-PERSON Safra/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG representatives/NNS/O apparently/RB/O influenced/VBD/O the/DT/O publication/NN/O of/IN/O unfavorable/JJ/O articles/NNS/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Safra/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O later/RB/O apologized/VBD/O and/CC/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O contributions/NNS/O to/TO/O charities/NNS/O chosen/VBN/O by/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
Ad/NN/O industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O surprised/JJ/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O under/IN/O his/PRP$/O direction/NN/O ,/,/O bitterly/RB/O fought/VBD/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O attempt/NN/O by/IN/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE before/IN/O succumbing/VBG/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O ././O
Some/DT/O executives/NNS/O also/RB/O cite/VBP/O tension/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O efforts/NNS/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O man/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O costs/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O international/JJ/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O had/VBD/O overseen/VBN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG two/CD/O other/JJ/O units/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Scali/NNP/B-ORG McCabe/NNP/I-ORG Sloves/NNP/I-ORG advertising/NN/O agency/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O research/NN/O division/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O those/DT/O units/NNS/O will/MD/O now/RB/O report/VB/O directly/RB/O to/TO/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O close/RB/O to/TO/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Robinson/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O abrupt/JJ/O management/NN/O change/NN/O sparked/VBD/O widespread/JJ/O speculation/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O pushed/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O top/JJ/O spot/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O implication/NN/O that/IN/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O pushed/VBN/O aside/RB/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O accurate/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sorrell/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O traveling/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Far/NNP/I-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Mr./NNP/O Robinson/NNP/B-PERSON first/RB/O approached/VBD/O him/PRP/O about/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O September/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O brushed/VBD/O aside/RP/O reports/NNS/O about/IN/O infighting/NN/O between/IN/O him/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O successor/NN/O at/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O executives/NNS/O could/MD/O hardly/RB/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O different/JJ/O ././O
Industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O although/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O executives/NNS/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O clash/VB/O more/RBR/O frequently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG takeover/NN/O brought/VBD/O them/PRP/O closer/RB/O together/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O labeled/VBD/O reports/NNS/O of/IN/O friction/NN/O ``/``/O ridiculous/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O spent/VBD/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O boat/NN/O in/IN/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O oversee/VB/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG public/JJ/O relations/NNS/O and/CC/O government/NN/O affairs/NNS/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O advertising/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O handled/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O operating/NN/O units/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O will/MD/O sit/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O corporate/JJ/O planning/NN/O and/CC/O policy/NN/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O made/VBD/O up/RP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O and/CC/O operating/NN/O executives/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O departure/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O any/DT/O enormous/JJ/O repercussions/NNS/O at/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Kraft/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Foods/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Mattel/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O move/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O affect/VB/O their/PRP$/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O ././O
Ad/NN/O Notes/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
Billings/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O .../:/O ././O
Details/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O commercial/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O brand/NN/O 's/POS/O 1990/CD/O advertising/NN/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON becomes/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O music/NN/O stars/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Michael/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Whitney/NNP/B-PERSON Houston/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O to/TO/O appear/VB/O in/IN/O ads/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O diet/NN/O drink/NN/O ././O
