There/EX/O are/VBP/O two/CD/O versions/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Measure/NN/O for/IN/O Measure/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O stage/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Alley/NNP/I-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG here/RB/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O ambiguity/NN/O and/CC/O uneasy/JJ/O mixture/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O serious/JJ/O and/CC/O the/DT/O comic/JJ/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O doubt/NN/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O why/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O much/RB/O in/IN/O vogue/NN/O with/IN/O directors/NNS/O just/RB/O now/RB/O ././O
Last/JJ/O season/NN/O ,/,/O Hartford/NNP/B-ORG Stage/NNP/I-ORG director/NN/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON Lamos/NNP/I-PERSON mounted/VBD/O a/DT/O production/NN/O at/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O currently/RB/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O productions/NNS/O --/:/O one/CD/O just/RB/O closed/VBN|VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Old/NNP/I-ORG Globe/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O another/DT/O now/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Seattle/NNP/I-ORG Rep/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O overlap/VBP/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O directorial/JJ/O school/NN/O that/WDT/O believes/VBZ/O one/PRP/O must/MD/O find/VB/O modern/JJ/O parallels/NNS/O or/CC/O metaphors/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O Shakespeare/NN/B-PERSON accessible/JJ/O to/TO/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O audiences/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O valid/JJ/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O puts/VBZ/O a/DT/O heavy/JJ/O burden/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O director/NN/O to/TO/O show/VB/O an/DT/O uncommon/JJ/O degree/NN/O of/IN/O imagination/NN/O and/CC/O taste/NN/O ././O
Loud/JJ/O rock/NN/O music/NN/O accompanies/VBZ/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O scene/NN/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O even/RB/O those/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O convent/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O here/RB/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O concept/NN/O but/CC/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O discrimination/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O represents/VBZ/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O step/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Alley/NNP/I-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O succeeded/VBD/O Pat/NNP/B-PERSON Brown/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O fired/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Alley/NNP/B-ORG board/NN/O 18/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O dismissal/NN/O angered/VBD/O many/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O regional/JJ/O theater/NN/O establishment/NN/O and/CC/O led/VBD/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Zeisler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O Theatre/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O write/VB/O an/DT/O editorial/NN/O in/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Theatre/NNP/I-ORG magazine/NN/I-ORG condemning/VBG/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
None/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O backlash/NN/O could/MD/O change/VB/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Brown/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O regime/NN/O was/VBD/O remarkably/RB/O undistinguished/JJ/O and/CC/O unimaginative/JJ/O ././O
Only/JJ/O time/NN/O will/MD/O tell/VB/O if/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON can/MD/O restore/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Alley/NNP/B-ORG the/DT/O acclaim/NN/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O when/WRB/O its/PRP$/O founder/NN/O ,/,/O Nina/NNP/B-PERSON Vance/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O height/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O powers/NNS/O ././O
