As/IN/O expected/VBN/O ,/,/O First/NNP/B-ORG Interstate/NNP/I-ORG Bancorp/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O a/DT/O net/JJ/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 15.5/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O hemorrhaging/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O First/NNP/B-ORG Interstate/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE unit/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O report/NN/O ,/,/O First/NNP/B-ORG Interstate/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O bank/NN/O in/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O reported/VBD/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 23.5/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O quarter/NN/O ././O
