There/EX/O are/VBP/O two/CD/O versions/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Measure/NN/O for/IN/O Measure/NN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O stage/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Alley/NNP/I-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG here/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Measure/NN/O for/IN/O Measure/NN/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Shakespeare/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O problem/NN/O ''/''/O plays/NNS/O ,/,/O so/RB/O named/VBN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O fit/VB/O neatly/RB/O into/IN/O a/DT/O category/NN/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O tragedy/NN/O ,/,/O comedy/NN/O or/CC/O history/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O ambiguity/NN/O and/CC/O uneasy/JJ/O mixture/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O serious/JJ/O and/CC/O the/DT/O comic/JJ/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O doubt/NN/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O why/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O very/RB/O much/RB/O in/IN/O vogue/NN/O with/IN/O directors/NNS/O just/RB/O now/RB/O ././O
Last/JJ/O season/NN/O ,/,/O Hartford/NNP/B-ORG Stage/NNP/I-ORG director/NN/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON Lamos/NNP/I-PERSON mounted/VBD/O a/DT/O production/NN/O at/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O currently/RB/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O productions/NNS/O --/:/O one/CD/O just/RB/O closed/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Old/NNP/I-ORG Globe/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O another/DT/O now/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Seattle/NNP/I-ORG Rep/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O overlap/VBP/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O play/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Duke/NNP/O of/IN/O Vienna/NNP/B-GPE despairs/VBZ/O over/IN/O the/DT/O licentiousness/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O subjects/NNS/O and/CC/O turns/VBZ/O over/RP/O the/DT/O rule/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O puritanical/JJ/O Angelo/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O set/VB/O things/NNS/O right/JJ/O ././O
When/WRB/O Angelo/NNP/B-PERSON hears/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O young/JJ/O man/NN/O Claudio/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O his/PRP$/O fiancee/NN/O pregnant/JJ/O before/IN/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O marry/VB/O her/PRP/O ,/,/O Angelo/NNP/B-PERSON summarily/RB/O condemns/VBZ/O Claudio/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O death/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O Claudio/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sister/NN/O ,/,/O Isabella/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O novitiate/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O convent/NN/O ,/,/O goes/VBZ/O to/TO/O Angelo/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O plead/VB/O her/PRP$/O brother/NN/O 's/POS/O case/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O obdurate/JJ/O ruler/NN/O immediately/RB/O falls/VBZ/O in/IN/O love/NN/O with/IN/O her/PRP/O and/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O supreme/JJ/O act/NN/O of/IN/O hypocrisy/NN/O ,/,/O demands/VBZ/O that/IN/O Isabella/NNP/B-PERSON yield/VB/O up/RP/O her/PRP$/O virtue/NN/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O in/IN/O exchange/NN/O for/IN/O her/PRP$/O brother/NN/O 's/POS/O life/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Duke/NNP/O ,/,/O who/WP/O set/VBD/O the/DT/O original/JJ/O scheme/NN/O in/IN/O motion/NN/O ,/,/O appears/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O scene/NN/O disguised/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O friar/NN/O and/CC/O becomes/VBZ/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O intrigues/NNS/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O everyone/NN/O fearing/VBG/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O possible/JJ/O outcome/NN/O until/IN/O the/DT/O Duke/NNP/O arranges/VBZ/O a/DT/O last/JJ/O minute/NN/O reprieve/NN/O for/IN/O all/DT/O concerned/VBN/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O action/NN/O requires/VBZ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O prison/NN/O cell/NN/O ,/,/O consisting/VBG/O of/IN/O an/DT/O enlarged/JJ/O wire/NN/O cage/NN/O ,/,/O rolls/VBZ/O forward/RB/O on/IN/O iron/NN/O wheels/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O platform/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O play/NN/O 's/POS/O major/JJ/O scenes/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON demonstrates/VBZ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O firm/JJ/O grasp/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Shakespearean/JJ/O dynamic/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O Isabella/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Ellen/NNP/B-PERSON Lauren/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O confronts/VBZ/O her/PRP$/O brother/NN/O Claudio/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Matt/NNP/B-PERSON Loney/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O cell/NN/O ,/,/O explaining/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O she/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O asked/VBN/O to/TO/O secure/VB/O his/PRP$/O freedom/NN/O ;/:/O when/WRB/O Isabella/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O disguised/JJ/O Duke/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Philip/NNP/B-PERSON Kerr/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O conspire/VBP/O to/TO/O trick/VB/O Angelo/NNP/B-PERSON ;/:/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O Mariana/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Annalee/NNP/B-PERSON Jefferies/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O wronged/VBN/O by/IN/O Angelo/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O confronts/VBZ/O him/PRP/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O past/JJ/O misdeeds/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O performers/NNS/O bring/VBP/O the/DT/O dramatic/JJ/O high/JJ/O points/NNS/O to/TO/O life/NN/O with/IN/O intense/JJ/O energy/NN/O and/CC/O intelligence/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O such/JJ/O moments/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O capacity/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O superior/JJ/O interpreter/NN/O of/IN/O Shakespeare/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
When/WRB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O decides/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O modern/JJ/O ,/,/O or/CC/O more/RBR/O accurately/RB/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O decides/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O trendy/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O results/NNS/O are/VBP/O far/RB/O less/RBR/O satisfactory/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O directorial/JJ/O school/NN/O that/WDT/O believes/VBZ/O one/PRP/O must/MD/O find/VB/O modern/JJ/O parallels/NNS/O or/CC/O metaphors/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O Shakespeare/NN/B-PERSON accessible/JJ/O to/TO/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O audiences/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O valid/JJ/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O puts/VBZ/O a/DT/O heavy/JJ/O burden/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O director/NN/O to/TO/O show/VB/O an/DT/O uncommon/JJ/O degree/NN/O of/IN/O imagination/NN/O and/CC/O taste/NN/O ././O
Loud/JJ/O rock/NN/O music/NN/O accompanies/VBZ/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O scene/NN/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O even/RB/O those/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O convent/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O Claudio/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O arrested/VBN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O brought/VBN/O on/IN/O stage/NN/O nude/JJ/O except/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O manacles/NNS/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O wrists/NNS/O and/CC/O ankles/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O opportunist/NN/O Lucio/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Stehlin/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O visits/VBZ/O the/DT/O convent/NN/O to/TO/O inform/VB/O Isabella/NN/B-PERSON of/IN/O her/PRP$/O brother/NN/O 's/POS/O fate/NN/O ,/,/O Lucio/NNP/B-PERSON not/RB/O only/RB/O slaps/VBZ/O the/DT/O mother/NN/O superior/JJ/O on/IN/O her/PRP$/O rear/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O brings/VBZ/O along/RP/O a/DT/O voluptuous/JJ/O companion/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Jill/NNP/B-PERSON Powell/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O not/RB/O in/IN/O Shakespeare/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O script/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O undulate/VB/O lasciviously/RB/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O pimp/NN/O Pompey/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Glen/NNP/B-PERSON Allen/NNP/I-PERSON Pruett/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O dressed/VBN/O in/IN/O black/JJ/O leather/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O prominent/JJ/O codpiece/NN/O ,/,/O indulges/VBZ/O in/IN/O enough/JJ/O obscene/JJ/O gestures/NNS/O and/CC/O pelvic/JJ/O thrusts/NNS/O to/TO/O launch/VB/O a/DT/O space/NN/O probe/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O here/RB/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O concept/NN/O but/CC/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O discrimination/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O the/DT/O excesses/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O scorecard/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O production/NN/O has/VBZ/O many/JJ/O more/JJR/O pluses/NNS/O than/IN/O minuses/NNS/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O represents/VBZ/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O step/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Alley/NNP/I-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Measure/NN/O for/IN/O Measure/NN/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O first/JJ/O directorial/JJ/O assignment/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O theater/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O artistic/JJ/O director/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O succeeded/VBD/O Pat/NNP/B-PERSON Brown/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O fired/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Alley/NNP/B-ORG board/NN/O 18/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O dismissal/NN/O angered/VBD/O many/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O regional/JJ/O theater/NN/O establishment/NN/O and/CC/O led/VBD/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Zeisler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O Theatre/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O write/VB/O an/DT/O editorial/NN/O in/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Theatre/NNP/I-ORG magazine/NN/I-ORG condemning/VBG/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
None/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O backlash/NN/O could/MD/O change/VB/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Brown/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O regime/NN/O was/VBD/O remarkably/RB/O undistinguished/JJ/O and/CC/O unimaginative/JJ/O ././O
Now/RB/O the/DT/O Alley/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O moved/VBN/O ahead/RB/O on/IN/O both/CC/O artistic/JJ/O and/CC/O financial/JJ/O fronts/NNS/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O is/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON giving/VBG/O the/DT/O theater/NN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O adventure/NN/O and/CC/O excitement/NN/O on/IN/O stage/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O balance/NN/O sheet/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O the/DT/O theater/NN/O has/VBZ/O had/VBN/O in/IN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Admittedly/RB/O last/JJ/O season/NN/O 's/POS/O runaway/JJ/O hit/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Steel/NN/O Magnolias/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O helped/VBD/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O so/RB/O did/VBD/O cost/NN/O cutting/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O measures/NNS/O insisted/VBN/O on/IN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
Only/JJ/O time/NN/O will/MD/O tell/VB/O if/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Boyd/NNP/B-PERSON can/MD/O restore/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Alley/NNP/B-ORG the/DT/O acclaim/NN/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O when/WRB/O its/PRP$/O founder/NN/O ,/,/O Nina/NNP/B-PERSON Vance/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O at/IN/O the/DT/O height/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O powers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O clear/JJ/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O give/VB/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O shot/NN/O ././O
