Japanese/JJ/O retail/JJ/O executives/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O reason/NN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O jump/VB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O fray/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O that/DT/O --/:/O unlike/IN/O manufacturing/NN/O --/:/O retailing/NN/O is/VBZ/O extremely/RB/O sensitive/JJ/O to/TO/O local/JJ/O cultures/NNS/O and/CC/O life/NN/O styles/NNS/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O wary/JJ/O of/IN/O attracting/VBG/O negative/JJ/O publicity/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Allen/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O that/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O about/RB/O to/TO/O embark/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O buying/NN/O binge/NN/O ././O
Tokyu/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O no/DT/O agreement/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O reached/VBN/O ././O
Federated/NNP/B-ORG ran/VBD/O into/IN/O a/DT/O cash/NN/O crunch/NN/O after/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O acquired/VBN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O by/IN/O Campeau/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O which/WDT/O relied/VBD/O heavily/RB/O on/IN/O debt/NN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O Barney/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG shop/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Plans/NNS/O are/VBP/O under/IN/O way/NN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O a/DT/O Tiffany/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG in/IN/O Hawaii/NNS/B-GPE to/TO/O cater/VB/O to/TO/O Japanese/JJ/O tourists/NNS/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O run/VBN/O mostly/RB/O by/IN/O Mitsukoshi/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Some/DT/O industry/NN/O observers/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O Mitsukoshi/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O classy/JJ/O image/NN/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O match/NN/O for/IN/O Saks/NNP/B-ORG Fifth/NNP/I-ORG Avenue/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Company/NN/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O studying/VBG/O various/JJ/O proposals/NNS/O but/CC/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O discuss/VB/O details/NNS/O ././O
Takashimaya/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O oldest/JJS/O department/NN/O store/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O another/DT/O name/NN/O that/WDT/O keeps/VBZ/O popping/VBG/O up/RP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O potential/JJ/O fit/NN/O with/IN/O Saks/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Eiji/NNP/B-PERSON Nakazato/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Takashimaya/NNP/B-ORG general/JJ/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O admits/VBZ/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O image/NN/O is/VBZ/O similar/JJ/O to/TO/O Saks/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O and/CC/O that/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O some/DT/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O ././O
Marcus/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Brauchli/NNP/I-PERSON contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O regular/JJ/O 1988/CD/O deficit/NN/O amounted/VBD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 43.5/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 74.4/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O expenses/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 117.9/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O statement/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O council/NN/O of/IN/O cardinals/NNS/O said/VBD/O Catholics/NNPS/O had/VBD/O responded/VBN/O generously/RB/O to/TO/O an/DT/O appeal/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O after/IN/O 1987/CD/O 's/POS/O record/JJ/O $/$/O 63/CD/O million/CD/O deficit/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O statement/NN/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O jump/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O Peter/NNP/O 's/POS/O Pence/NNP/O ''/''/O collection/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O annual/JJ/O offering/NN/O from/IN/O Catholics/NNPS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O pope/NN/O --/:/O helped/VBD/O cover/VB/O the/DT/O deficit/NN/O ././O
Council/NN/B-ORG member/NN/O Cardinal/NNP/B-PERSON Gerald/NNP/I-PERSON Carter/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Toronto/NNP/B-GPE told/VBD/O Vatican/NNP/B-ORG Radio/NNP/I-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O Now/RB/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O say/VBP/O we/PRP/O covered/VBD/O our/PRP$/O deficit/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O relax/VB/O and/CC/O say/VB/O well/RB/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O fine/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Holy/NNP/I-ORG See/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hole/NN/O ././O
Former/NNP/O President/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Nixon/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O to/TO/O visit/VB/O China/NNP/B-GPE at/IN/O the/DT/O invitation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O beginning/VBG/O Saturday/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Foreign/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O poll/NN/O conducted/VBN/O in/IN/O 12/CD/O of/IN/O 16/CD/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG countries/NNS/O shows/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Dutch/NNPS/O appear/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O strongest/JJS/O supporters/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O alliance/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O poll/NN/O ,/,/O conducted/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Dutch/JJ/O daily/NN/O De/NNP/B-PERSON Telegraaf/NNP/I-PERSON by/IN/O Gallup/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O 81/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Dutch/JJ/O people/NNS/O supported/VBD/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Canada/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O most/RBS/O pro-NATO/JJ/B-ORG country/NN/O with/IN/O 78/CD/O %/NN/O supporting/VBG/O the/DT/O alliance/NN/O ,/,/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O 75/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O 71/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O Belgium/NN/B-GPE with/IN/O 69/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE with/IN/O 63/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
All/DT/O other/JJ/O countries/NNS/O registered/VBD/O support/NN/O below/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Israeli/NNP/O Manufacturers/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/I-ORG Association/NN/I-ORG filed/VBD/O a/DT/O police/NN/O complaint/NN/O against/IN/O an/DT/O Arab/JJ/O pasta/NN/O maker/NN/O for/IN/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O four/CD/O colors/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O outlawed/JJ/O Palestinian/JJ/O flag/NN/O on/IN/O spaghetti/NNS/O packages/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O considered/VBN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Danny/NNP/B-PERSON Leish/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O association/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O spaghetti/NNS/O is/VBZ/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Al/NNP/I-ORG Ghazel/NNP/I-ORG Macaroni/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Bethlehem/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O is/VBZ/O marketed/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O package/NN/O decorated/VBN/O with/IN/O green/JJ/O ,/,/O black/JJ/O ,/,/O red/JJ/O and/CC/O white/JJ/O stripes/NNS/O ././O
Dealers/NNS/O bought/VBD/O the/DT/O used/JJ/O stamps/NNS/O cheaply/RB/O from/IN/O charities/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Guide/NNP/I-ORG Dogs/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Blind/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O charities/NNS/O regularly/RB/O sell/VBP/O used/JJ/O stamps/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O they/PRP/O collect/VBP/O from/IN/O children/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O donors/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O funds/NNS/O ././O
Akio/NNP/B-PERSON Tanii/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Matsushita/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Industrial/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O presented/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE consul/NN/O general/JJ/O in/IN/O Osaka/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O check/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE earthquake/NN/O victims/NNS/O ././O
Several/JJ/O other/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O and/CC/O regional/JJ/O governments/NNS/O have/VBP/O sent/VBN/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Sumitomo/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG donated/VBD/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O ,/,/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE prefecture/NN/O $/$/O 15,000/CD/O and/CC/O the/DT/O city/NN/O of/IN/O Osaka/NNP/B-GPE $/$/O 10,000/CD/O ././O
Chinese/JJ/O officials/NNS/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O use/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Canton/NNP/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG Fair/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O lure/VB/O back/RP/O overseas/JJ/O traders/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O bloody/JJ/O crackdown/NN/O on/IN/O dissent/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O autumn/NN/O 's/POS/O edition/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O biannual/JJ/O fair/NN/O will/MD/O run/VB/O through/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 31/CD/O ././O
Fair/NN/B-ORG officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O 21,000/CD/O guests/NNS/O visited/VBD/O during/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O five/CD/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O spring/NN/O exhibition/NN/O ././O
British/JJ/O customs/NNS/O officers/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O 'd/MD/O arrested/VBN/O eight/CD/O men/NNS/O sneaking/VBG/O 111/CD/O rare/JJ/O snakes/NNS/O into/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O including/VBG/O one/CD/O man/NN/O who/WP/O strapped/VBD/O a/DT/O pair/NN/O of/IN/O boa/NN/O constrictors/NNS/O under/IN/O his/PRP$/O armpits/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O customs/NNS/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O arrests/NNS/O followed/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O Snake/NNP/O Day/NNP/O ''/''/O at/IN/O Utrecht/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O an/DT/O event/NN/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O some/DT/O collectors/NNS/O as/IN/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O obtain/VB/O rare/JJ/O snakes/NNS/O ././O
