Senate/NNP/B-ORG Majority/NNP/O Leader/NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Mitchell/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Maine/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O use/VB/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG procedures/NNS/O to/TO/O force/VB/O advocates/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O cut/NN/O to/TO/O come/VB/O up/RP/O with/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 60/CD/O votes/NNS/O before/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O address/VB/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O votes/NNS/O to/TO/O get/VB/O it/PRP/O passed/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Sen./NNP/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Packwood/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Ore./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O leading/JJ/O Republican/JJ/O proponent/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O cut/NN/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O disagree/VB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O sure/JJ/O what/WP/O 's/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O happen/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Previously/RB/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O the/DT/O requisite/JJ/O 60/CD/O votes/NNS/O eventually/RB/O ././O
Democrats/NNPS/O are/VBP/O holding/VBG/O up/RP/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O amendment/NN/O by/IN/O threatening/VBG/O a/DT/O filibuster/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O extended/JJ/O debate/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O a/DT/O cloture/NN/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O the/DT/O filibuster/NN/O ,/,/O Republicans/NNPS/O must/MD/O muster/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 60/CD/O votes/NNS/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Sen./NNP/O Packwood/NNP/B-PERSON acknowledged/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O votes/NNS/O for/IN/O cloture/NN/O today/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Republicans/NNPS/O show/VBP/O no/DT/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O relenting/VBG/O ././O
GOP/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O continued/VBD/O to/TO/O press/VB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O amendment/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC aid/NN/O measure/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O strategy/NN/O is/VBZ/O `/``/O Let/VB/O 's/POS/O vote/VB/O ././O '/''/O ''/''/O
Democrats/NNPS/O counter/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Republicans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O often/RB/O used/VBN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O rules/NNS/O to/TO/O suit/VB/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ends/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O also/RB/O traded/VBD/O accusations/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Packwood/NNP/B-PERSON plan/NN/O ././O
Democrats/NNPS/O asserted/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O also/RB/O would/MD/O create/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O type/NN/O of/IN/O individual/JJ/O retirement/NN/O account/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O fraught/JJ/O with/IN/O budget/NN/O gimmickry/NN/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O lose/VB/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O run/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Packwood/NNP/B-PERSON proposal/NN/O would/MD/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O long/RB/O an/DT/O asset/NN/O was/VBD/O held/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O ``/``/O generally/RB/O supportive/JJ/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Packwood/NNP/B-PERSON plan/NN/O ././O
