Yasumichi/NNP/B-PERSON Morishita/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O art/NN/O gallery/NN/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O became/VBD/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O shareholder/NN/O in/IN/O Christies/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE auction/NN/O house/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O man/NN/O who/WP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O fit/VB/O the/DT/O mold/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O known/VBN/O in/IN/O racy/JJ/O weekly/JJ/O magazines/NNS/O as/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O King/NNP/O of/IN/O Shady/NNP/O Money/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O convicted/VBN/O of/IN/O charging/VBG/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O much/RB/O higher/JJR/O than/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O law/NN/O permitted/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O evade/VB/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O by/IN/O using/VBG/O a/DT/O double/JJ/O accounting/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O 's/POS/O had/VBD/O other/JJ/O brushes/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O arrested/VBN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O not/RB/O indicted/VBN/O ,/,/O on/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O three/CD/O other/JJ/O occasions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O '60s/CD/O and/CC/O '70s/CD/O :/:/O for/IN/O assault/NN/O and/CC/O unlawful/JJ/O confinement/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O fraud/NN/O and/CC/O forgery/NN/O of/IN/O private/JJ/O documents/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O for/IN/O extortion/NN/O ././O
Christies/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O contact/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON since/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O purchase/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O happy/JJ/O to/TO/O deal/VB/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O like/VBP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O our/PRP$/O own/JJ/O judgments/NNS/O ''/''/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Davidge/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Christies/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O group/NN/O managing/VBG/O director/NN/O ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O reputation/NN/O country/NN/O by/IN/O country/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O leading/JJ/O figure/NN/O among/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O 38,000/CD/O ``/``/O machikin/FW/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O lend/VBP/O to/TO/O small/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ``/``/O sarakin/FW/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O lend/VBP/O to/TO/O individuals/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O these/DT/O financiers/NNS/O lend/VBP/O freely/RB/O ,/,/O often/RB/O without/IN/O demanding/VBG/O collateral/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O they/PRP/O charge/VBP/O are/VBP/O often/RB/O near/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O 54.75/CD/O %/NN/O legal/JJ/O limit/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Kenji/NNP/B-PERSON Utsunomiya/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O specializing/VBG/O in/IN/O loan/NN/O troubles/NNS/O ././O
Aichi/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O machikin/FW/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Utsunomiya/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ``/``/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nasty/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O describing/VBG/O that/DT/O business/NN/O in/IN/O general/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O client/NN/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O repay/VB/O the/DT/O loan/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O machikin/FW/O ``/``/O clutch/VBP/O on/RP/O like/IN/O hyenas/NNS/O ''/''/O and/CC/O even/RB/O take/VBP/O over/RP/O the/DT/O client/NN/O 's/POS/O company/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O new/JJ/O gallery/NN/O ,/,/O Aska/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O purchased/VBD/O 6.4/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Christies/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O #/#/O 33/CD/O million/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 53.3/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Acquired/VBN/O from/IN/O Carisbrook/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG U.K./NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O company/NN/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O Australian/JJ/O financier/NN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Holmes/NNP/I-PERSON a/DT/I-PERSON Court/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O stake/NN/O was/VBD/O apparently/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O kind/NN/O for/IN/O Aska/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O entity/NN/O separate/JJ/O from/IN/O Aichi/NNP/B-ORG ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O made/VBD/O Aska/NNP/B-ORG one/CD/O of/IN/O Christies/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O top/JJ/O five/CD/O shareholders/NNS/O ,/,/O left/VBD/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O wondering/VBG/O who/WP/O this/DT/O man/NN/O was/VBD/O and/CC/O what/WP/O his/PRP$/O intentions/NNS/O were/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O an/DT/O investor/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O sitting/VBG/O back/RP/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O purple/JJ/O gallery/NN/O filled/VBN/O with/IN/O some/DT/O 20/CD/O Monets/NNPS/O and/CC/O Renoirs/NNPS/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O run/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O stock/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O prices/NNS/O will/MD/O go/VB/O up/RP/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O clear/JJ/O whether/IN/O Aska/NNP/B-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O more/JJR/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON considers/VBZ/O himself/PRP/O a/DT/O connoisseur/NN/O of/IN/O art/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O collecting/VBG/O impressionist/JJ/O and/CC/O Japanese/JJ/O paintings/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O acquired/VBN/O 600/CD/O items/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O enough/JJ/O to/TO/O persuade/VB/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O start/VB/O a/DT/O museum/NN/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O spent/VBD/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O art/NN/O business/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O week/NN/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O gallery/NN/O racked/VBD/O up/RP/O a/DT/O $/$/O 23/CD/O million/CD/O tab/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O Sotheby/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG auction/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE buying/VBG/O seven/CD/O works/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O Picasso/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O makes/VBZ/O snap/JJ/O judgments/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Kiyotaka/NNP/B-PERSON Kori/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O art/NN/O gallery/NN/O 's/POS/O manager/NN/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O secretary/NN/O for/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O seven/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O main/JJ/O business/NN/O certainly/RB/O appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O thriving/VBG/O ,/,/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O numbers/NNS/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O Teikoku/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O tracks/VBZ/O company/NN/O earnings/NNS/O ,/,/O Aichi/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O revenue/NN/O rose/VBD/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 49.3/CD/O billion/CD/O yen/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 348.4/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBD/O February/NNP/O ././O
Revenue/NN/O doubled/VBD/O from/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O reported/VBD/O results/NNS/O correctly/RB/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Tokyo/NNP/I-ORG Regional/NNP/I-ORG Taxation/NNP/I-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Kori/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O tycoon/NN/O 's/POS/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O simply/RB/O resulted/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O difference/NN/O of/IN/O opinion/NN/O over/IN/O what/WP/O was/VBD/O considered/VBN/O income/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O small/JJ/O ,/,/O wiry/JJ/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON comes/VBZ/O across/RP/O as/IN/O an/DT/O outspoken/JJ/O man/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
Stretching/VBG/O his/PRP$/O arms/NNS/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O silky/JJ/O white/JJ/O shirt/NN/O and/CC/O squeaking/VBG/O his/PRP$/O black/JJ/O shoes/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O lectures/VBZ/O a/DT/O visitor/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O American/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O and/CC/O boasts/VBZ/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O friendship/NN/O with/IN/O Margaret/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON son/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O asked/VBD/O what/WP/O exactly/RB/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O in/IN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O immediately/RB/O takes/VBZ/O offense/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Are/VBP/O you/PRP/O stupid/JJ/O ?/./O ''/''/O he/PRP/O snaps/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O should/MD/O know/VB/O what/WP/O questions/NNS/O to/TO/O ask/VB/O to/TO/O get/VB/O people/NNS/O to/TO/O answer/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Not/RB/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O know/VBP/O the/DT/O details/NNS/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O business/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O source/NN/O of/IN/O rumors/NNS/O about/IN/O shady/JJ/O dealings/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON scoffs/VBZ/O at/IN/O those/DT/O stories/NNS/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O ones/NNS/O connecting/VBG/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O mob/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O never/RB/O even/RB/O dined/VBN/O with/IN/O gangsters/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O seventh/JJ/O child/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O store/NN/O owner/NN/O in/IN/O Aichi/NNP/B-GPE prefecture/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON started/VBD/O out/RP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O textile/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
From/IN/O there/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O set/VBD/O up/RP/O his/PRP$/O finance/NN/O company/NN/O and/CC/O rapidly/RB/O expanded/VBD/O from/IN/O lending/VBG/O to/TO/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O to/TO/O building/VBG/O golf/NN/O courses/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O spends/VBZ/O most/JJS/O weekends/NNS/O flying/VBG/O his/PRP$/O helicopter/NN/O to/TO/O one/CD/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O nine/CD/O courses/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O two/CD/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O were/VBD/O designed/VBN/O by/IN/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Nicklaus/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O owns/VBZ/O courses/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Although/IN/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O keen/VB/O on/IN/O going/VBG/O ,/,/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O he/PRP/O attended/VBD/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE gala/NN/O where/WRB/O his/PRP$/O daughter/NN/O made/VBD/O her/PRP$/O debut/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O leads/VBZ/O an/DT/O opulent/JJ/O life/NN/O style/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O in/IN/O Denenchofu/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O richest/JJS/O neighborhoods/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O splashy/JJ/O brick/NN/O manor/NN/O --/:/O one/CD/O of/IN/O some/RB/O 10/CD/O houses/NNS/O he/PRP/O owns/VBZ/O --/:/O outshines/VBZ/O the/DT/O neighbors/NNS/O '/POS/O ././O
Although/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O little/JJ/O about/IN/O his/PRP$/O business/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O offers/VBZ/O one/CD/O rule/NN/O to/TO/O success/NN/O :/:/O Never/RB/O gamble/VB/O too/RB/O far/RB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O quit/VBP/O after/IN/O one/CD/O try/NN/O ,/,/O whether/IN/O I/PRP/O win/VBP/O or/CC/O lose/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O done/VBN/O in/IN/O two/CD/O minutes/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Morishita/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O his/PRP$/O business/NN/O to/TO/O many/JJ/O other/JJ/O areas/NNS/O at/IN/O home/NN/O and/CC/O abroad/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O there/RB/O wherever/WRB/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O money/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O ,/,/O laughs/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Kori/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Who/WP/O knows/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O heard/VBD/O that/IN/O soybeans/NNS/O make/VBP/O money/NN/O today/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O might/MD/O be/VB/O flying/VBG/O out/IN/O to/TO/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE tomorrow/NN/O ././O
