Transportation/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Samuel/NNP/B-PERSON Skinner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O warned/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O urge/VB/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O veto/VB/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O passed/VBD/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O approved/VBN/O similar/JJ/O legislation/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Skinner/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O deputy/NN/O ,/,/O Elaine/NNP/B-PERSON Chao/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O opposed/VBD/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O ``/``/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O present/JJ/O form/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O 's/POS/O supporters/NNS/O had/VBD/O taken/VBN/O heart/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O letter/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O signed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Skinner/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O contain/VB/O a/DT/O veto/NN/O threat/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O backed/VBD/O this/DT/O bill/NN/O because/IN/O we/PRP/O thought/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O help/VB/O Skinner/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ''/''/O one/CD/O Republican/NNP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O and/CC/O now/RB/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O out/IN/O there/RB/O dangling/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wind/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Transportation/NN/B-ORG secretary/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O 30/CD/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O 20/CD/O days/NNS/O if/IN/O needed/VBN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O review/VB/O any/DT/O proposed/VBN/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE airline/NN/O 's/POS/O voting/NN/O stock/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O secretary/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O an/DT/O acquisition/NN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O concluded/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O so/RB/O weaken/VB/O an/DT/O airline/NN/O financially/RB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O hurt/VB/O safety/NN/O or/CC/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O ,/,/O or/CC/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O gave/VBD/O control/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O foreign/JJ/O interest/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O would/MD/O apply/VB/O to/TO/O any/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O airline/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O transactions/NNS/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O large/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O debt/NN/O ././O
Supporters/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O are/VBP/O concerned/VBN/O an/DT/O airline/NN/O might/MD/O sacrifice/VB/O costly/JJ/O safety/NN/O measures/NNS/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O repay/VB/O debt/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Skinner/NNP/B-PERSON disagreed/VBD/O ,/,/O calling/VBG/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O retreat/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O deregulaton/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O his/PRP$/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O Committee/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Glenn/NNP/B-PERSON Anderson/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ``/``/O would/MD/O be/VB/O at/IN/O odds/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O policies/NNS/O welcoming/VBG/O open/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O investment/NN/O and/CC/O market/NN/O allocation/NN/O of/IN/O resources/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Currently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O the/DT/O authority/NN/O to/TO/O block/VB/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O concludes/VBZ/O that/IN/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O a/DT/O carrier/NN/O unfit/NN/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O department/NN/O may/MD/O revoke/VB/O its/PRP$/O certificate/NN/O ,/,/O grounding/VBG/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O ././O
Such/JJ/O authority/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O adequate/JJ/O ,/,/O say/VBP/O opponents/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O supporters/NNS/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O grounding/VBG/O an/DT/O airline/NN/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O drastic/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O department/NN/O would/MD/O hesitate/VB/O doing/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
