This/DT/O magazine/NN/O and/CC/O book/NN/O publisher/NN/O said/VBD/O three/CD/O men/NNS/O were/VBD/O elected/VBN/O directors/NNS/O ,/,/O increasing/VBG/O the/DT/O board/NN/O to/TO/O 10/CD/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O :/:/O James/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Eiszner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 62/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O and/CC/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O CPC/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ;/:/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Schwartz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 61/CD/O ,/,/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Metropolitan/NNP/B-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON V./NNP/I-PERSON Shipley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 53/CD/O ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
