Renault/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O DAF/NNP/B-ORG Trucks/NNPS/I-ORG NV/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O a/DT/O preliminary/JJ/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O jointly/RB/O manufacture/VB/O a/DT/O line/NN/O of/IN/O trucks/NNS/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Philippe/NNP/B-PERSON Gras/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Renault/NNP/B-ORG managing/VBG/O director/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O will/MD/O cover/VB/O trucks/NNS/O of/IN/O between/IN/O 2.5/CD/O tons/NNS/O and/CC/O 4.2/CD/O tons/NNS/O and/CC/O will/MD/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O at/IN/O Renault/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Bapilly/NNP/B-FAC plant/NN/O in/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O at/IN/O DAF/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O British/JJ/O plant/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gras/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O venture/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O example/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O trend/NN/O toward/IN/O cooperative/JJ/O projects/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ahead/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1992/CD/O deadline/NN/O for/IN/O eliminating/VBG/O trade/NN/O barriers/NNS/O within/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Renault/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O DAF/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O three/CD/O billion/CD/O French/JJ/O francs/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 157.8/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O FFr/SYM/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O for/IN/O design/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O costs/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O each/DT/O spend/VB/O about/IN/O FFr/SYM/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O on/IN/O tooling/NN/O up/RP/O their/PRP$/O plants/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gras/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O represents/VBZ/O considerable/JJ/O savings/NNS/O for/IN/O both/DT/O Renault/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O DAF/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O since/IN/O both/DT/O companies/NNS/O would/MD/O in/IN/O any/DT/O case/NN/O have/VB/O had/VBN/O to/TO/O renew/VB/O their/PRP$/O existing/VBG/O ranges/NNS/O of/IN/O light/JJ/O goods/NNS/O vehicles/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O pooling/VBG/O their/PRP$/O resources/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O groups/NNS/O have/VBP/O effectively/RB/O halved/VBN/O the/DT/O design/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O costs/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O otherwise/RB/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O entailed/VBN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O van/NNP/B-PERSON Doorne/NNP/I-PERSON family/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNP/B-GPE holds/VBZ/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O 11/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O DAF/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O capital/NN/O ././O
