The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O standard/JJ/O object/NN/O of/IN/O suggestions/NNS/O for/IN/O organizational/JJ/O and/CC/O institutional/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O two/CD/O reasons/NNS/O ././O
First/JJ/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O position/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O anomalous/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O unusual/JJ/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O independence/NN/O from/IN/O elected/VBN/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O authority/NN/O over/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O powerful/JJ/O of/IN/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O instruments/NNS/O --/:/O the/DT/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O supply/NN/O ././O
Thus/RB/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O condition/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O easily/RB/O described/VBN/O as/IN/O undemocratic/JJ/O ././O
Second/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O responsibilities/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O guardian/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O means/VBZ/O as/IN/O guardian/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stability/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ,/,/O sometimes/RB/O lead/VBP/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O take/VB/O measures/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O unpopular/JJ/O ././O
As/IN/O former/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON McChesney/NNP/I-PERSON Martin/NNP/I-PERSON used/VBD/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O punch/NN/O bowl/NN/O away/RB/O just/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O party/NN/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O interesting/JJ/O ././O
So/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O an/DT/O attractive/JJ/O target/NN/O for/IN/O complaint/NN/O by/IN/O politicians/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O easily/RB/O assigned/VBN/O the/DT/O blame/NN/O for/IN/O unpleasantness/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O high/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O or/CC/O slow/JJ/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O politicians/NNS/O can/MD/O escape/VB/O responsibility/NN/O by/IN/O pointing/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O independence/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O leads/VBZ/O to/TO/O proposals/NNS/O for/IN/O ``/``/O reform/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O common/JJ/O feature/NN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG more/RBR/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O to/TO/O public/JJ/O opinion/NN/O --/:/O without/IN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O any/DT/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O additional/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O politicians/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O ideas/NNS/O are/VBP/O again/RB/O under/IN/O consideration/NN/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
But/CC/O these/DT/O proposals/NNS/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O rest/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O view/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O or/CC/O ,/,/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O rest/VBP/O on/IN/O an/DT/O incorrect/JJ/O view/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O would/MD/O not/RB/O solve/VB/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O worse/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O too/RB/O unresponsive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O interest/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/O contrary/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O an/DT/O incorrect/JJ/O view/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O interest/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O average/NN/O ,/,/O something/NN/O that/WDT/O cost/VBD/O $/$/O 100/CD/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O now/RB/O costs/VBZ/O $/$/O 425/CD/O ././O
Or/CC/O ,/,/O a/DT/O wage/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O $/$/O 100/CD/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O would/MD/O buy/VB/O only/RB/O $/$/O 23.53/CD/O worth/NN/O of/IN/O stuff/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O two/CD/O occasions/NNS/O the/DT/O inflation/NN/O rate/NN/O rose/VBD/O to/TO/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O each/DT/O case/NN/O the/DT/O ending/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O unsustainable/JJ/O inflation/NN/O caused/VBD/O a/DT/O severe/JJ/O recession/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O two/CD/O worst/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O postwar/JJ/O period/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O enormous/JJ/O inflation/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O was/VBD/O largely/RB/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O happened/VBN/O without/IN/O the/DT/O support/NN/O of/IN/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O that/WDT/O provided/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O 10-fold/JJ/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O supply/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O period/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O that/DT/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O supply/NN/O would/MD/O not/RB/O have/VB/O happened/VBN/O without/IN/O the/DT/O consent/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O basic/JJ/O problem/NN/O of/IN/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O which/WDT/O reform/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O be/VB/O addressed/VBN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O a/DT/O recurrence/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O experience/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O were/VBD/O two/CD/O general/JJ/O reasons/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O mistaken/JJ/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O :/:/O
1/CD/O ././O To/TO/O some/DT/O extent/NN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG shared/VBD/O the/DT/O popular/JJ/O but/CC/O incorrect/JJ/O view/NN/O that/IN/O expansionary/JJ/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O could/MD/O yield/VB/O a/DT/O net/JJ/O improvement/NN/O in/IN/O employment/NN/O and/CC/O output/NN/O ././O
2/CD/O ././O Even/RB/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O not/RB/O share/VB/O this/DT/O view/NN/O it/PRP/O felt/VBD/O the/DT/O need/NN/O to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O ././O
Despite/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O formal/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O independence/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG seems/VBZ/O constantly/RB/O to/TO/O feel/VB/O that/IN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O uses/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O independence/NN/O too/RB/O freely/RB/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O lose/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O common/JJ/O proposals/NNS/O for/IN/O reforming/VBG/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O only/RB/O make/VB/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O worse/JJR/O ,/,/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O any/DT/O effect/NN/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
Putting/VBG/O the/DT/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Governors/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O proposals/NNS/O today/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O example/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O secretary/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O borrower/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O suffers/VBZ/O the/DT/O further/JJ/O disqualification/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O club/NN/O of/IN/O seven/CD/O finance/NN/O ministers/NNS/O who/WP/O meet/VBP/O occasionally/RB/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O what/WP/O exchange/NN/O rates/NNS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O diversion/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O business/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O stabilize/VB/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ././O
How/WRB/O should/MD/O a/DT/O reasonable/JJ/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG interpret/VB/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O put/VB/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ?/./O
Could/MD/O he/PRP/O plausibly/RB/O interpret/VB/O it/PRP/O as/IN/O encouragement/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O give/VB/O primary/JJ/O emphasis/NN/O to/TO/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ?/./O
The/DT/O answer/NN/O seems/VBZ/O perfectly/RB/O clear/JJ/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O True/JJ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O succession/NN/O of/IN/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG chairmen/NNS/O has/VBZ/O given/VBN/O color/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG belongs/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
By/IN/O their/PRP$/O constant/JJ/O readiness/NN/O to/TO/O advise/VB/O all/DT/O and/CC/O sundry/JJ/O about/IN/O federal/JJ/O budgetary/JJ/O matters/NNS/O the/DT/O chairmen/NNS/O have/VBP/O encouraged/VBN/O the/DT/O belief/NN/O that/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O policy/NN/O and/CC/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O are/VBP/O ingredients/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O common/JJ/O stew/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O case/NN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O natural/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O probably/RB/O also/RB/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O should/MD/O be/VB/O jointly/RB/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O stirring/VBG/O the/DT/O pot/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/O 's/POS/O case/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O independence/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O little/RB/O stronger/JJR/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O were/VBD/O more/RBR/O solicitous/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O independence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O independent/JJ/O ,/,/O or/CC/O too/RB/O unpolitical/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O and/CC/O can/MD/O not/RB/O help/VB/O being/VBG/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O the/DT/O more/JJR/O overtly/RB/O political/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG exercises/VBZ/O a/DT/O power/NN/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O president/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O president/NN/O accept/VBP/O no/DT/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O exercise/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O power/NN/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Critics/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O present/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O are/VBP/O correct/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O undemocratic/JJ/O ././O
What/WP/O is/VBZ/O undemocratic/JJ/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O unwillingness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O political/JJ/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O deciding/VBG/O the/DT/O basic/JJ/O question/NN/O of/IN/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O what/WDT/O priority/NN/O should/MD/O be/VB/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O leave/VB/O this/DT/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O ``/``/O independent/JJ/O ''/''/O agency/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O only/RB/O undemocratic/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O greatest/JJS/O contribution/NN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O make/VB/O at/IN/O this/DT/O time/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O declare/VB/O that/IN/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O primary/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Legislation/NN/O to/TO/O this/DT/O effect/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O introduced/VBN/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O this/DT/O session/NN/O by/IN/O Rep./NNP/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Neal/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.C/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O thing/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O enacted/VBN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O much/RB/O prefer/VB/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O the/DT/O hard/JJ/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O retain/VB/O its/PRP$/O rights/NNS/O of/IN/O complaint/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O ././O
People/NNS/O will/MD/O say/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O government/NN/O have/VBP/O other/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O true/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O other/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O other/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O and/CC/O instruments/NNS/O for/IN/O pursuing/VBG/O these/DT/O other/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O at/IN/O most/RBS/O very/RB/O limited/VBN/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O contribute/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O achievement/NN/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O by/IN/O means/NNS/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O by/IN/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O objectives/NNS/O most/RBS/O commonly/RB/O thought/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O legitimate/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O attention/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O high/JJ/O employment/NN/O and/CC/O rapid/JJ/O real/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O former/JJ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O 's/POS/O Council/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Advisers/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Stein/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O an/DT/O American/NNP/B-ORG Enterprise/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG fellow/NN/O ././O
