HealthVest/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O two/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O lenders/NNS/O have/VBP/O given/VBN/O it/PRP/O notices/NNS/O of/IN/O default/NN/O on/IN/O bank/NN/O loans/NNS/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O take/VB/O actions/NNS/O to/TO/O recover/VB/O their/PRP$/O loans/NNS/O ././O
HealthVest/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O Austin/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O investment/NN/O trust/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O lead/NN/O bank/NN/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O domestic/JJ/O bank/NN/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O told/VBD/O it/PRP/O that/IN/O if/IN/O $/$/O 3.3/CD/O million/CD/O owed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O group/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O paid/VBN/O by/IN/O today/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O group/NN/O will/MD/O call/VB/O the/DT/O $/$/O 120/CD/O million/CD/O that/IN/O HealthVest/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O outstanding/JJ/O under/IN/O the/DT/O credit/NN/O line/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bank/NN/O group/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O additional/JJ/O advances/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O credit/NN/O line/NN/O ././O
HealthVest/NNP/B-ORG missed/VBD/O a/DT/O payment/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O group/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O due/JJ/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O September/NNP/O ././O
HealthVest/NNP/B-ORG missed/VBD/O an/DT/O interest/NN/O payment/NN/O to/TO/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Tokyo/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
HealthVest/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O severe/JJ/O liquidity/NN/O bind/NN/O because/IN/O its/PRP$/O affiliate/NN/O ,/,/O Healthcare/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O about/IN/O $/$/O 10.6/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O principal/NN/O and/CC/O interest/NN/O payments/NNS/O owed/VBD/O since/IN/O August/NNP/O ././O
