Strict/JJ/O new/JJ/O regulations/NNS/O seem/VBP/O certain/JJ/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O the/DT/O state/NN/O House/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE next/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O easy/JJ/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O by/IN/O Democratic/NNP/O Gov./NNP/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Casey/NNP/I-PERSON expected/VBN/O shortly/RB/O thereafter/RB/O ././O
Legislation/NN/O to/TO/O require/VB/O the/DT/O consent/NN/O of/IN/O parents/NNS/O before/IN/O their/PRP$/O daughters/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O 18/CD/O can/MD/O have/VB/O abortions/NNS/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O pass/VB/O both/DT/O houses/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Michigan/JJ/B-GPE legislature/NN/O and/CC/O set/VB/O up/RP/O a/DT/O grinding/VBG/O battle/NN/O to/TO/O override/VB/O the/DT/O expected/VBN/O veto/NN/O of/IN/O Democratic/NNP/O Gov./NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Blanchard/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O in/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O follow/VB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O collapse/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O session/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE legislature/NN/O to/TO/O enact/VB/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O abortions/NNS/O in/IN/O that/DT/O state/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O here/RB/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O permit/VB/O federally/RB/O paid/VBN/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O poor/JJ/O women/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O or/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O more/JJR/O times/NNS/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O feel/VB/O good/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O 15/CD/O is/VBZ/O another/DT/O question/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O But/CC/O it/PRP/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O shown/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O win/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O state/NN/O like/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O abortion/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O clearly/RB/O an/DT/O electoral/JJ/O issue/NN/O and/CC/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O been/VBN/O an/DT/O emotional/JJ/O issue/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Freind/NNP/B-PERSON legislation/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O House/NNP/B-ORG Judiciary/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG approved/VBD/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O Harrisburg/NN/B-GPE this/DT/O week/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE House/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O next/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O --/:/O includes/VBZ/O a/DT/O provision/NN/O to/TO/O ban/VB/O abortions/NNS/O after/IN/O 24/CD/O weeks/NNS/O of/IN/O pregnancy/NN/O ,/,/O except/IN/O to/TO/O avert/VB/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mother/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Freind/NNP/B-PERSON calculates/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O provision/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O attacks/VBZ/O the/DT/O trimester/NN/O standards/NNS/O that/IN/O Roe/NNP/O established/VBD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O ``/``/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O necessary/JJ/O ''/''/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O review/VB/O Roe/NNP/O and/CC/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O overturn/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE measure/NN/O also/RB/O includes/VBZ/O an/DT/O ``/``/O informed/JJ/O consent/NN/O ''/''/O provision/NN/O that/WDT/O may/MD/O become/VB/O widely/RB/O imitated/VBN/O by/IN/O abortion/NN/O foes/NNS/O who/WP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O women/NNS/O contemplating/VBG/O abortion/NN/O as/RB/O uncomfortable/JJ/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O procedure/NN/O and/CC/O with/IN/O themselves/PRP/O ././O
Under/IN/O this/DT/O legislation/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O informed/VBN/O 24/CD/O hours/NNS/O before/IN/O the/DT/O operation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O details/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O procedure/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O risks/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Regardless/RB/O of/IN/O whether/IN/O one/NN/O supports/VBZ/O or/CC/O opposes/VBZ/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Freind/NNP/B-PERSON argues/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O virtually/RB/O impossible/JJ/O for/IN/O any/DT/O rational/JJ/O human/NN/O being/VBG/O to/TO/O disagree/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O concept/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O woman/NN/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O appropriate/JJ/O materials/NNS/O and/CC/O advice/NN/O made/VBN/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O her/PRP/O before/IN/O she/PRP/O makes/VBZ/O a/DT/O decision/NN/O which/WDT/O ,/,/O one/CD/O way/NN/O or/CC/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O ,/,/O might/MD/O remain/VB/O with/IN/O her/PRP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O her/PRP$/O life/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O proponents/NNS/O believe/VBP/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O shake/VB/O enough/JJ/O votes/NNS/O loose/JJ/O to/TO/O override/VB/O the/DT/O veto/NN/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O successful/JJ/O in/IN/O portraying/VBG/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O matter/NN/O of/IN/O parents/NNS/O '/POS/O rights/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O lawmakers/NNS/O will/MD/O vote/VB/O before/IN/O next/JJ/O spring/NN/O on/IN/O legislation/NN/O requiring/VBG/O physicians/NNS/O to/TO/O perform/VB/O tests/NNS/O on/IN/O fetuses/NNS/O at/IN/O 20/CD/O weeks/NNS/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O their/PRP$/O gestational/JJ/O age/NN/O ,/,/O weight/NN/O and/CC/O lung/NN/O maturity/NN/O along/IN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O provision/NN/O requiring/VBG/O that/IN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O fetuses/NNS/O survive/VBP/O an/DT/O abortion/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O doctor/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O on/IN/O hand/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O it/PRP/O survive/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O legislation/NN/O failed/VBD/O by/IN/O one/CD/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O clear/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Rules/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O anti-abortionists/NNS/O still/RB/O may/MD/O succeed/VB/O in/IN/O bringing/VBG/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O floor/NN/O this/DT/O fall/NN/O ././O
Pamela/NNP/B-PERSON Sutherland/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Illinois/NNP/I-ORG Planned/NNP/I-ORG Parenthood/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O and/CC/O her/PRP$/O allies/NNS/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O cautiously/RB/O optimistic/JJ/O ''/''/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O defeat/VB/O it/PRP/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O comes/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O floor/NN/O vote/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O anti-abortionists/NNS/O are/VBP/O urging/VBG/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG Gov./NNP/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Clements/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O press/VB/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O session/NN/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O run/VB/O Nov./NNP/O 14/CD/O to/TO/O Dec./NNP/O 13/CD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O prognosis/NN/O is/VBZ/O only/RB/O fair/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Kathie/NNP/B-PERSON Roberts/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O administrative/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG Right/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Next/JJ/O year/NN/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O election/NN/O year/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O legislators/NNS/O just/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O do/VB/O anything/NN/O about/IN/O this/DT/O now/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
This/DT/O legislative/JJ/O activity/NN/O comes/VBZ/O as/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O are/VBP/O undertaking/VBG/O new/JJ/O mobilization/NN/O efforts/NNS/O ,/,/O plunging/VBG/O into/IN/O gubernatorial/JJ/O races/NNS/O in/IN/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O girding/VBG/O for/IN/O next/JJ/O autumn/NN/O 's/POS/O state/NN/O elections/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O abortion/NN/O foes/NNS/O have/VBP/O developed/VBN/O a/DT/O national/JJ/O legislative/JJ/O strategy/NN/O ,/,/O deciding/VBG/O to/TO/O move/VB/O on/IN/O what/WP/O Jacki/NNP/B-PERSON Ragan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Right/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/I-ORG Life/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG director/NN/O of/IN/O state/NN/O organizational/JJ/O development/NN/O ,/,/O calls/VBZ/O ``/``/O reasonable/JJ/O measures/NNS/O that/IN/O an/DT/O overwhelming/JJ/O mainstream/NN/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O support/VBP/O ././O ''/''/O
These/DT/O include/VBP/O bans/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O for/IN/O birth/NN/O control/NN/O and/CC/O sex/NN/O selection/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O public/NN/O funding/NN/O of/IN/O alternatives/NNS/O for/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Those/DT/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O side/NN/O can/MD/O hardly/RB/O oppose/VB/O alternative/NN/O funding/NN/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O continue/VBP/O to/TO/O insist/VB/O on/IN/O calling/VBG/O themselves/PRP/O `/``/O pro-choice/JJ/O '/''/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O `/``/O pro-abortion/JJ/O ,/,/O '/''/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Spaulding/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O associate/JJ/O state/NN/O legislative/JJ/O coordinator/NN/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Abortion/NNP/I-ORG Rights/NNPS/I-ORG Action/NNP/I-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG singled/VBD/O out/RP/O eight/CD/O politicians/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Freind/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O 1990/CD/O targets/NNS/O and/CC/O held/VBD/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE seminar/NN/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O train/VB/O its/PRP$/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O political/JJ/O techniques/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O put/VB/O the/DT/O anti-abortionists/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O defensive/NN/O in/IN/O state/NN/O legislatures/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O now/RB/O see/VBP/O pro-choice/JJ/O legislators/NNS/O going/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O offensive/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Kate/NNP/B-PERSON Michelman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O group/NN/O ././O
