Sir/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON succeeds/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Plastow/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
Sir/NNP/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O also/RB/O a/DT/O non-executive/JJ/O director/NN/O at/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Westminister/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O NatWest/NNP/B-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
