Combustion/NNP/B-ORG Engineering/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O sold/VBD/O and/CC/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O several/JJ/O investments/NNS/O and/CC/O nonstrategic/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O for/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O for/IN/O reducing/VBG/O debt/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O purposes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O transactions/NNS/O are/VBP/O unrelated/JJ/O ././O
Combustion/NNP/B-ORG Engineering/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O provides/VBZ/O engineered/VBN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O systems/NNS/O and/CC/O services/NNS/O for/IN/O power/NN/O generation/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O sold/VBD/O Illinois/NNP/B-ORG Minerals/NNPS/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Cairo/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ill/NNP/B-GPE ././O
That/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Georgia/NNP/B-ORG Kaolin/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O was/VBD/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Unimin/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Assets/NNPS/O of/IN/O Construction/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O were/VBD/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O Essex/NNP/B-ORG Crane/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O Elgin/NNP/B-ORG Electronics/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Erie/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Pa./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O were/VBD/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O Charter/NNP/B-ORG Technologies/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
