AFTERSHOCKS/NNS/O RATTLED/VBD/O Northern/NNP/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC amid/IN/O an/DT/O earthquake/NN/O cleanup/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O power/NN/O and/CC/O commuters/NNS/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O much/RB/O of/IN/O downtown/NN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O since/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O temblor/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NN/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ,/,/O three/CD/O strong/JJ/O aftershocks/NNS/O ,/,/O one/CD/O measuring/VBG/O 5.0/CD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Richter/NNP/O scale/NN/O ,/,/O jolted/VBD/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
Serious/JJ/O injuries/NNS/O or/CC/O damages/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O reported/VBN/O ././O
Thousands/NNS/O remained/VBD/O homeless/JJ/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O to/TO/O visit/VB/O the/DT/O area/NN/O today/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O officials/NNS/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE estimated/VBD/O that/IN/O emergency/NN/O assistance/NN/O would/MD/O total/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O earthquakes/NNS/O struck/VBD/O northern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O killing/VBG/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 29/CD/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O injuring/VBG/O hundreds/NNS/O and/CC/O razing/VBG/O about/IN/O 8,000/CD/O homes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Xinhua/NNP/I-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG rejected/VBD/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O sought/VBN/O by/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O prohibit/VB/O desecration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE flag/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O considered/VBN/O a/DT/O victory/NN/O for/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O favor/VBP/O a/DT/O law/NN/O barring/VBG/O flag/NN/O burning/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG approved/VBD/O an/DT/O $/$/O 837/CD/O million/CD/O aid/NN/O package/NN/O for/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O nearly/RB/O double/JJ/O what/WP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O requested/VBN/O ././O
Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O chief/NN/O justice/NN/O quashed/VBD/O the/DT/O murder/NN/O convictions/NNS/O of/IN/O four/CD/O people/NNS/O for/IN/O Irish/NNP/B-ORG Republican/NNP/I-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG bombings/NNS/O that/WDT/O killed/VBD/O seven/CD/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O 1974/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O reversal/NN/O came/VBD/O after/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O conceded/VBD/O that/IN/O investigators/NNS/O may/MD/O have/VB/O faked/VBN/O evidence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Guildford/NNP/I-PERSON Four/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O ''/''/O three/CD/O Irishmen/NNPS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O Englishwoman/NNP/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O imprisoned/VBN/O since/IN/O 1975/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Nobel/NNP/O Prize/NNP/O in/IN/O literature/NN/O was/VBD/O won/VBN/O by/IN/O Camilo/NNP/B-PERSON Jose/NNP/I-PERSON Cela/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Spanish/JJ/O writer/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O 1942/CD/O novel/NN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Family/NNP/O of/IN/O Pascual/NNP/O Duarte/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O popular/JJ/O work/NN/O of/IN/O fiction/NN/O in/IN/O Spanish/NNP/O since/IN/O Cervantes/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O Don/NNP/O Quixote/NNP/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O published/VBN/O 400/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O Pravda/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O dismissed/VBN/O and/CC/O succeeded/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O confidant/NN/O of/IN/O Soviet/NNP/O leader/NN/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Communist/NNP/B-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG daily/RB/O ,/,/O viewed/VBD/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE most/JJS/O authoritative/JJ/O newspaper/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O considered/VBN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O significant/JJ/O development/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O week/NN/O of/IN/O Kremlin/NNP/B-ORG wrangling/VBG/O over/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O sharp/JJ/O criticism/NN/O from/IN/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE new/JJ/O leader/NN/O met/VBD/O with/IN/O Lutheran/NNP/B-ORG Church/NNP/I-ORG officials/NNS/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O a/DT/O growing/VBG/O opposition/NN/O movement/NN/O demanding/VBG/O democratic/JJ/O freedoms/NNS/O ././O
Police/NN/O in/IN/O Prague/NNP/B-GPE raided/VBD/O an/DT/O international/JJ/O meeting/NN/O on/IN/O human/JJ/O rights/NNS/O ,/,/O detaining/VBG/O Czechoslovakia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O former/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O minister/NN/O ,/,/O Jiri/NNP/B-PERSON Hajak/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O 14/CD/O other/JJ/O activists/NNS/O ././O
Dissident/JJ/O playwright/NN/O Vaclav/NNP/B-PERSON Havel/NNP/I-PERSON reportedly/RB/O escaped/VBD/O the/DT/O crackdown/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O against/IN/O activists/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O days/NNS/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON met/VBD/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O discussed/VBD/O what/WP/O the/DT/O president/NN/O called/VBD/O ``/``/O the/DT/O unique/JJ/O role/NN/O ''/''/O that/IN/O Madrid/NNP/B-GPE can/MD/O play/VB/O in/IN/O furthering/VBG/O democracy/NN/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Gonzalez/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O pledged/VBD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O monitor/VB/O voting/NN/O in/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O said/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O carrying/VBG/O proposals/NNS/O for/IN/O free/JJ/O elections/NNS/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Galileo/NNP/O spacecraft/NN/O sped/VBD/O unerringly/RB/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O planet/NN/O Jupiter/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O while/IN/O five/CD/O astronauts/NNS/O aboard/IN/O the/DT/O space/NN/O shuttle/NN/O Atlantis/NNP/O measured/VBD/O the/DT/O Earth/NN/B-LOC 's/POS/O ozone/NN/O layer/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O robot/NN/O probe/NN/O was/VBD/O dispatched/VBN/O Wednesday/NNP/O by/IN/O the/DT/O shuttle/NN/O crew/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O conduct/VB/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O medical/JJ/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O experiments/NNS/O before/IN/O their/PRP$/O scheduled/VBN/O landing/NN/O Monday/NNP/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Argentina/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O diplomatic/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O relations/NNS/O ,/,/O seven/CD/O years/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O nations/NNS/O battled/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Falkland/NNP/I-GPE Islands/NNPS/I-GPE ././O
Rebel/NN/O artillerists/NNS/O bombarded/VBD/O the/DT/O capital/NN/O of/IN/O Afghanistan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O killing/VBG/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 12/CD/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE was/VBD/O reported/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O airlifting/VBG/O arms/NNS/O and/CC/O food/NN/O to/TO/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O forces/NNS/O ././O
Fighting/NN/O also/RB/O was/VBD/O reported/VBN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O strategic/JJ/O town/NN/O of/IN/O Khost/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O near/IN/O the/DT/O Pakistani/JJ/O border/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O talks/NNS/O came/VBD/O as/IN/O Lebanese/JJ/O negotiations/NNS/O on/IN/O political/JJ/O changes/NNS/O appeared/VBD/O deadlocked/VBN/O ././O
GOP/NNP/B-ORG Sen./NNP/O Specter/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O vote/VB/O to/TO/O acquit/VB/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O Alcee/NNP/B-PERSON Hastings/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O his/PRP$/O impeachment/NN/O trial/NN/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O perjury/NN/O and/CC/O bribery/NN/O conspiracy/NN/O ././O
Specter/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O evidence/NN/O panel/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O insufficient/JJ/O evidence/NN/O to/TO/O convict/VB/O ''/''/O the/DT/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE jurist/NN/O ././O
