International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O their/PRP$/O Discovision/NNP/B-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE units/NNS/O of/IN/O Pioneer/NNP/B-ORG Electronic/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O partners/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O believe/VB/O the/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O systems/NNS/O was/VBD/O developing/VBG/O as/RB/O rapidly/RB/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O hoped/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O licenses/VBZ/O optically/RB/O based/VBN/O data/NNS/O storage/NN/O and/CC/O retrieval/NN/O devices/NNS/O ././O
James/NNP/B-PERSON N./NNP/I-PERSON Fiedler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Discovision/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O a/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O MCA/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O n't/RB/O planned/VBN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O the/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O profitable/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O Pioneer/NNP/B-ORG approached/VBD/O Discovision/NNP/B-ORG earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O certain/JJ/O whether/IN/O Discovision/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O current/JJ/O management/NN/O will/MD/O remain/VB/O when/WRB/O Pioneer/NNP/B-ORG buys/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O is/VBZ/O contingent/JJ/O on/IN/O certain/JJ/O government/NN/O approvals/NNS/O and/CC/O should/MD/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O later/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
