Sebastian/NNP/B-PERSON Guzman/NNP/I-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON took/VBD/O over/RP/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O workers/NNS/O union/NN/O ,/,/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/JJS/O powerful/JJ/O labor/NN/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O last/JJ/O January/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O even/RB/O in/IN/O that/DT/O short/JJ/O time/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O as/IN/O controversial/JJ/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O way/NN/O as/IN/O his/PRP$/O deposed/VBN/O predecessor/NN/O ,/,/O Joaquin/NNP/B-PERSON Hernandez/NNP/I-PERSON Galicia/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O La/NNP/B-PERSON Quina/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O facing/VBG/O accusations/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O a/DT/O company/NN/O man/NN/O as/IN/O La/NNP/B-PERSON Quina/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O a/DT/O crook/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O recent/JJ/O contract/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON accepted/VBD/O major/JJ/O concessions/NNS/O that/WDT/O greatly/RB/O curtail/VBP/O the/DT/O union/NN/O 's/POS/O role/NN/O in/IN/O subcontracting/NN/O ,/,/O long/RB/O a/DT/O source/NN/O of/IN/O millions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O illicit/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O with/IN/O the/DT/O quiet/JJ/O pragmatism/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON replacing/VBG/O the/DT/O prickly/JJ/O populism/NN/O of/IN/O La/NNP/B-PERSON Quina/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O government/NN/O technocrats/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O given/VBN/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O hand/NN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O the/DT/O petrochemical/NN/O sector/NN/O to/TO/O wider/JJR/O private/JJ/O and/CC/O foreign/JJ/O investment/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O new/JJ/O order/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O arrived/VBN/O without/IN/O resistance/NN/O ././O
Brawls/NNS/O between/IN/O union/NN/O factions/NNS/O still/RB/O erupt/VB/O at/IN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG installations/NNS/O ././O
Leftist/JJ/O leader/NN/O Cuauhtemoc/NNP/B-PERSON Cardenas/NNP/I-PERSON publicly/RB/O questioned/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O moral/JJ/O quality/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O suggesting/VBG/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O conspiracy/NN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O over/RP/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O oil/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O symbol/NN/O of/IN/O Mexican/JJ/O nationalism/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O foreigners/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O union/NN/O leadership/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE ././O
We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O afraid/JJ/O of/IN/O associating/VBG/O with/IN/O private/JJ/O or/CC/O foreign/JJ/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Pemex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O produces/VBZ/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O government/NN/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O desperately/RB/O needs/VBZ/O new/JJ/O investment/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O world/NN/O oil/NN/O prices/NNS/O collapsed/VBD/O in/IN/O 1982/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O siphoned/VBN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O coffers/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O payments/NNS/O on/IN/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O $/$/O 97/CD/O billion/CD/O foreign/JJ/O debt/NN/O ././O
Little/JJ/O money/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O returned/VBN/O to/TO/O upgrade/VB/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O aging/VBG/O facilities/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O drains/VBZ/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG from/IN/O above/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O union/NN/O has/VBZ/O drained/VBN/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O below/IN/O ././O
A/DT/O bloated/JJ/O payroll/NN/O and/CC/O pervasive/JJ/O graft/NN/O caused/VBD/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O operating/VBG/O costs/NNS/O to/TO/O balloon/VB/O to/TO/O 95/CD/O cents/NNS/O of/IN/O each/DT/O $/$/O 1/CD/O in/IN/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O far/RB/O above/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O norm/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O declines/NNS/O in/IN/O investment/NN/O and/CC/O efficiency/NN/O explain/VBP/O in/IN/O part/NN/O why/WRB/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O importing/VBG/O gasoline/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O projections/NNS/O show/VBP/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE importing/VBG/O crude/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O century/NN/O ,/,/O barring/VBG/O an/DT/O overhaul/NN/O of/IN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Whatever/WDT/O you/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O change/VB/O ,/,/O whether/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O cutting/VBG/O costs/NNS/O or/CC/O attracting/VBG/O new/JJ/O partners/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O big/JJ/O obstacle/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O union/NN/O leadership/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O oil/NN/O consultant/NN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Baker/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Enter/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O clear/JJ/O understanding/NN/O of/IN/O where/WRB/O union/NN/O leaders/NNS/O fit/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pro-enterprise/JJ/O regime/NN/O of/IN/O President/NNP/O Salinas/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Beginning/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O laborer/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O refinery/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON put/VBP/O in/RP/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 40/CD/O years/NNS/O at/IN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG before/IN/O being/VBG/O pushed/VBN/O into/IN/O retirement/NN/O by/IN/O La/NNP/B-PERSON Quina/NNP/I-PERSON after/IN/O a/DT/O dispute/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
Though/IN/O he/PRP/O also/RB/O long/RB/O benefited/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O built/VBN/O by/IN/O La/NNP/B-PERSON Quina/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O union/NN/O perks/NNS/O had/VBD/O simply/RB/O gotten/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O hand/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O at/IN/O the/DT/O base/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O of/IN/O corruption/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Thus/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O contract/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON gave/VBD/O up/RP/O the/DT/O union/NN/O 's/POS/O right/NN/O to/TO/O assign/VB/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O outside/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O --/:/O an/DT/O enormous/JJ/O source/NN/O of/IN/O kickbacks/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O union/NN/O also/RB/O ceded/VBD/O the/DT/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O commission/NN/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O on/IN/O all/DT/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG maintenance/NN/O contracts/NNS/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O The/DT/O union/NN/O will/MD/O keep/VB/O a/DT/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O commission/NN/O on/IN/O construction/NN/O projects/NNS/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
About/IN/O 9,800/CD/O technical/JJ/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O notably/RB/O chemists/NNS/O and/CC/O lawyers/NNS/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O switched/VBN/O to/TO/O non-union/JJ/O status/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O because/IN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O reduced/VBN/O capital/NN/O budget/NN/O ,/,/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O phased/VBN/O out/RP/O about/IN/O 50,000/CD/O transitory/JJ/O construction/NN/O workers/NNS/O ,/,/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O work/NN/O force/NN/O to/TO/O about/IN/O 140,000/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O union/NN/O leader/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O union/NN/O 's/POS/O sacrifices/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O offset/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O wage/NN/O and/CC/O benefit/NN/O package/NN/O that/WDT/O amounts/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O 22/CD/O %/NN/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O compensation/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG managers/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O ones/NNS/O most/RBS/O thrilled/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O retaking/VBG/O the/DT/O instruments/NNS/O of/IN/O administration/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Raul/NNP/B-PERSON Robles/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG subdirector/NN/O ././O
Pemex/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O money/NN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O contract/NN/O would/MD/O save/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O one/CD/O previous/JJ/O government/NN/O estimate/NN/O pegged/VBD/O savings/NNS/O at/IN/O around/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O customers/NNS/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O pleased/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O spirit/NN/O ././O
Grupo/NNP/B-ORG Desc/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O conglomerate/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O long/RB/O depended/VBN/O on/IN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG petrochemicals/NNS/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O plastic/JJ/O packing/NN/O material/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG plant/NN/O shut/VBD/O down/RP/O for/IN/O an/DT/O annual/JJ/O overhaul/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O never/RB/O give/VB/O notice/VB/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O customers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O capriciousness/NN/O would/MD/O completely/RB/O disrupt/VB/O our/PRP$/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Ernesto/NNP/B-PERSON Vega/NNP/I-PERSON Velasco/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Desc/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O finance/NN/O director/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Desc/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O customers/NNS/O were/VBD/O consulted/VBN/O well/RB/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG plant/NN/O 's/POS/O shutdown/NN/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O minimal/JJ/O inconvenience/NN/O ././O
Taming/VBG/O the/DT/O union/NN/O complements/VBZ/O previous/JJ/O moves/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O private/JJ/O investment/NN/O in/IN/O petrochemicals/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O import/VB/O in/IN/O large/JJ/O quantities/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O May/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O unveiled/VBD/O new/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O investment/NN/O regulations/NNS/O that/WDT/O create/VBP/O special/JJ/O trusts/NNS/O allowing/VBG/O foreigners/NNS/O ,/,/O long/RB/O limited/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O secondary/JJ/O petrochemical/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O to/TO/O own/VB/O up/IN/O to/TO/O 100/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Later/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O reclassified/VBD/O several/JJ/O basic/JJ/O petrochemicals/NNS/O as/IN/O secondary/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O courtship/NN/O with/IN/O private/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O especially/RB/O foreign/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O controversial/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O country/NN/O where/WRB/O oil/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O symbol/NN/O of/IN/O national/JJ/O sovereignty/NN/O since/IN/O foreign/JJ/O oil/NN/O holdings/NNS/O were/VBD/O nationalized/VBN/O in/IN/O 1938/CD/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O are/VBP/O preparing/VBG/O the/DT/O workers/NNS/O for/IN/O what/WP/O 's/VBZ/O coming/VBG/O :/:/O foreign/JJ/O control/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O wrote/VBD/O Heberto/NNP/B-PERSON Castillo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O leftist/JJ/O leader/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O insist/VBP/O that/IN/O foreigners/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O limited/VBN/O to/TO/O investing/VBG/O in/IN/O secondary/JJ/O petroleum/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O integrate/VB/O into/IN/O this/DT/O new/JJ/O world/NN/O of/IN/O interdependence/NN/O ,/,/O sooner/RBR/O or/CC/O later/RB/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O become/VB/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O own/JJ/O isolation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
