Sebastian/NNP/B-PERSON Guzman/NNP/I-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON took/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O oil/NN/O workers/NNS/O union/NN/O ,/,/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/JJS/O powerful/JJ/O labor/NN/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O only/RB/O last/JJ/O January/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O new/JJ/O order/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O arrived/VBN/O without/IN/O resistance/NN/O ././O
Brawls/NNS/O between/IN/O union/NN/O factions/NNS/O still/RB/O erupt/VB/O at/IN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG installations/NNS/O ././O
Leftist/JJ/O leader/NN/O Cuauhtemoc/NNP/B-PERSON Cardenas/NNP/I-PERSON publicly/RB/O questioned/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O moral/JJ/O quality/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O suggesting/VBG/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O conspiracy/NN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O oil/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O symbol/NN/O of/IN/O Mexican/JJ/O nationalism/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O foreigners/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O afraid/JJ/O of/IN/O associating/VBG/O with/IN/O private/JJ/O or/CC/O foreign/JJ/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Pemex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O produces/VBZ/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O government/NN/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O desperately/RB/O needs/VBZ/O new/JJ/O investment/NN/O ././O
Little/JJ/O money/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O returned/VBN/O to/TO/O upgrade/VB/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O aging/VBG/O facilities/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O bloated/JJ/O payroll/NN/O and/CC/O pervasive/JJ/O graft/NN/O caused/VBD/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O operating/VBG/O costs/NNS/O to/TO/O balloon/VB/O to/TO/O 95/CD/O cents/NNS/O of/IN/O each/DT/O $/$/O 1/CD/O in/IN/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O far/RB/O above/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O norm/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O declines/NNS/O in/IN/O investment/NN/O and/CC/O efficiency/NN/O explain/VBP/O in/IN/O part/NN/O why/WRB/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O importing/VBG/O gasoline/NN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O projections/NNS/O show/VBP/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE importing/VBG/O crude/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O century/NN/O ,/,/O barring/VBG/O an/DT/O overhaul/NN/O of/IN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Enter/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O clear/JJ/O understanding/NN/O of/IN/O where/WRB/O union/NN/O leaders/NNS/O fit/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pro-enterprise/JJ/O regime/NN/O of/IN/O President/NNP/O Salinas/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O at/IN/O the/DT/O base/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O of/IN/O corruption/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O union/NN/O also/RB/O ceded/VBD/O the/DT/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O commission/NN/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O on/IN/O all/DT/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG maintenance/NN/O contracts/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O union/NN/O 's/POS/O sacrifices/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O offset/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O wage/NN/O and/CC/O benefit/NN/O package/NN/O that/WDT/O amounts/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O 22/CD/O %/NN/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O compensation/NN/O ././O
Pemex/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O money/NN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O contract/NN/O would/MD/O save/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O one/CD/O previous/JJ/O government/NN/O estimate/NN/O pegged/VBD/O savings/NNS/O at/IN/O around/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Pemex/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O customers/NNS/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O pleased/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O spirit/NN/O ././O
Grupo/NNP/B-ORG Desc/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O conglomerate/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O long/RB/O depended/VBN/O on/IN/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG petrochemicals/NNS/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O plastic/JJ/O packing/NN/O material/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Desc/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O customers/NNS/O were/VBD/O consulted/VBN/O well/RB/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Pemex/NNP/B-ORG plant/NN/O 's/POS/O shutdown/NN/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O minimal/JJ/O inconvenience/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guzman/NNP/B-PERSON Cabrera/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O insist/VBP/O that/IN/O foreigners/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O limited/VBN/O to/TO/O investing/VBG/O in/IN/O secondary/JJ/O petroleum/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
