Is/VBZ/O an/DT/O American/JJ/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG seriously/RB/O suggesting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG should/MD/O help/VB/O govern/VB/O Cambodia/NNP/B-GPE ?/./O
Apparently/RB/O so/RB/O ././O
Now/RB/O that/IN/O Vietnam/NNP/B-GPE appears/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O pulled/VBN/O out/RP/O its/PRP$/O occupation/NN/O army/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O talking/VBG/O again/RB/O about/IN/O accepting/VBG/O an/DT/O ``/``/O interim/JJ/O ''/''/O coalition/NN/O government/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Cambodian/JJ/O capital/NN/O of/IN/O Phnom/NNP/B-GPE Penh/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O aim/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O end/VB/O the/DT/O guerrilla/NN/O war/NN/O for/IN/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Cambodia/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O allowing/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG a/DT/O small/JJ/O share/NN/O of/IN/O power/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG says/VBZ/O that/IN/O any/DT/O Khmer/NNP/B-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG participation/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O ``/``/O minimal/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O usual/JJ/O problem/NN/O with/IN/O including/VBG/O communists/NNS/O in/IN/O ``/``/O interim/JJ/O ''/''/O coalition/NN/O governments/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O ideology/NN/O and/CC/O methods/NNS/O require/VBP/O they/PRP/O squeeze/VBP/O out/RP/O everyone/NN/O else/RB/O ././O
Recall/VB/O that/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Sandinistas/NNPS/O came/VBD/O into/IN/O Managua/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O partners/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O coalition/NN/O government/NN/O with/IN/O anti-Somoza/JJ/B-PERSON moderates/NNS/O ././O
Within/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O moderates/NNS/O were/VBD/O exiled/VBN/O or/CC/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O ,/,/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O gone/VBN/O communist/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Sandinistas/NNPS/O were/VBD/O building/VBG/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O armies/NNS/O in/IN/O Latin/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O threatening/VBG/O their/PRP$/O neighbors/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Laos/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Western/JJ/O powers/NNS/O bowed/VBD/O to/TO/O pressure/VB/O for/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O coalition/NN/O it/PRP/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O opening/VBG/O the/DT/O door/NN/O to/TO/O communist/NN/O domination/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O complicates/VBZ/O the/DT/O scene/NN/O in/IN/O Cambodia/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O regime/NN/O is/VBZ/O already/RB/O communist/JJ/O ,/,/O as/IN/O are/VBP/O its/PRP$/O Vietnamese/JJ/O overseers/NNS/O back/RB/O in/IN/O Hanoi/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O as/IN/O are/VBP/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O strongest/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O guerrilla/NN/O groups/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O clear/JJ/O which/WDT/O crew/NN/O of/IN/O communists/NNS/O might/MD/O prevail/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O coalition/NN/O government/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O one/CD/O good/JJ/O bet/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O non-communists/NNS/O would/MD/O disappear/VB/O ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O leave/VB/O Hun/NNP/B-PERSON Sen/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Hun/NNP/B-PERSON Sen/NNP/I-PERSON regime/NN/O has/VBZ/O sent/VBN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O conscript/JJ/O laborers/NNS/O to/TO/O die/VB/O of/IN/O malaria/NN/O and/CC/O malnourishment/NN/O while/IN/O building/VBG/O Cambodia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O equivalent/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Berlin/NNP/I-FAC Wall/NNP/I-FAC near/IN/O the/DT/O Thai/NNP/O border/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O carry/VBP/O an/DT/O unsurpassed/JJ/O record/NN/O for/IN/O Cambodian/JJ/O tyranny/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O utopians/NNS/O caused/VBD/O the/DT/O deaths/NNS/O --/:/O by/IN/O starvation/NN/O ,/,/O disease/NN/O or/CC/O execution/NN/O --/:/O of/IN/O well/RB/O over/IN/O one/CD/O million/CD/O Cambodians/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O Cambodian/JJ/O horror/NN/O was/VBD/O so/RB/O bad/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Vietnamese/JJ/O occupation/NN/O in/IN/O 1978/CD/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O perverse/JJ/O form/NN/O of/IN/O relief/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O world/NN/O might/MD/O want/VB/O to/TO/O believe/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG ca/MD/O n't/RB/O still/RB/O be/VB/O such/JJ/O bad/JJ/O guys/NNS/O ,/,/O just/RB/O as/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1970s/CD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O credit/VB/O the/DT/O reports/NNS/O of/IN/O genocide/NN/O then/RB/O taking/VBG/O place/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O solid/JJ/O evidence/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O changed/VBN/O ././O
So/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O swallow/VB/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O conditions/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O help/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG set/VBD/O up/RP/O shop/NN/O again/RB/O in/IN/O Phnom/NNP/B-GPE Penh/NNP/I-GPE ././O
True/JJ/O ,/,/O Prince/NNP/O Sihanouk/NNP/B-PERSON backs/VBZ/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O of/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O coalition/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O for/IN/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Prince/NNP/O Sihanouk/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O backed/VBN/O all/DT/O sorts/NNS/O of/IN/O ideas/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O done/VBN/O rather/RB/O better/RB/O by/IN/O himself/PRP/O than/IN/O by/IN/O Cambodia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Nor/CC/O should/MD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE worry/VB/O much/RB/O about/IN/O offending/VBG/O China/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O still/RB/O aids/VBZ/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O time/NN/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG recognized/VBD/O that/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE does/VBZ/O not/RB/O play/VB/O by/IN/O gentlemen/NNS/O 's/POS/O rules/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O lend/VB/O even/RB/O the/DT/O slightest/JJS/O support/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O infamous/JJ/O killers/NNS/O on/IN/O Indochina/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O bleak/JJ/O scene/NN/O could/MD/O only/RB/O disturb/VB/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O allies/NNS/O elsewhere/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O entirely/RB/O rational/JJ/O for/IN/O communist/NN/O insurgents/NNS/O in/IN/O countries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Philippines/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O Peru/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O conclude/VB/O the/DT/O following/NN/O :/:/O Fight/VB/O viciously/RB/O enough/RB/O and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O under/IN/O the/DT/O banner/NN/O of/IN/O pragmatism/NN/O ,/,/O might/MD/O eventually/RB/O help/VB/O negotiate/VB/O your/PRP$/O way/NN/O to/TO/O victory/NN/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE diplomacy/NN/O has/VBZ/O done/VBN/O it/PRP/O before/IN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O likely/RB/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O again/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG have/VBP/O lately/RB/O tangoed/VBD/O around/IN/O the/DT/O idea/NN/O of/IN/O sending/VBG/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O Cambodia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O non-communists/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O now/RB/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O diplomatic/JJ/O movement/NN/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Vietnam/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O withdrawal/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Baker/NNP/B-PERSON initiative/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O has/VBZ/O put/VBN/O that/DT/O plan/NN/O on/IN/O hold/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O proviso/NN/O that/IN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O going/NN/O got/VBD/O rough/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O then/RB/O rearm/VB/O the/DT/O opposition/NN/O ././O
Why/WRB/O the/DT/O timidity/NN/O ?/./O
At/IN/O the/DT/O very/RB/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O odds/NNS/O are/VBP/O heavily/RB/O weighted/VBN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O prospects/NNS/O of/IN/O preventing/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Khmer/NNP/I-ORG Rouge/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Cambodia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O communists/NNS/O from/IN/O ultimately/RB/O moving/VBG/O against/IN/O their/PRP$/O opponents/NNS/O ././O
When/WRB/O that/DT/O day/NN/O comes/VBZ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O particularly/RB/O awful/JJ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE sat/VBD/O on/IN/O military/JJ/O aid/NN/O and/CC/O deprived/VBD/O these/DT/O people/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O means/NNS/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O their/PRP$/O fate/NN/O with/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O honor/NN/O ././O
