Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O General/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Shannon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O opposing/VBG/O the/DT/O license/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O appeal/VB/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O NRC/NNP/B-ORG rejected/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Shannon/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O argument/NN/O that/IN/O Public/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O share/NN/O of/IN/O Seabrook/NNP/B-FAC ,/,/O and/CC/O 11/CD/O other/JJ/O owners/NNS/O are/VBP/O financially/RB/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O guarantee/VB/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O 's/POS/O safe/JJ/O operation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Shannon/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O waiver/NN/O of/IN/O NRC/NNP/B-ORG policy/NN/O that/WDT/O ignores/VBZ/O financial/JJ/O considerations/NNS/O in/IN/O making/VBG/O licensing/NN/O decisions/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O its/PRP$/O ruling/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O NRC/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O because/IN/O Seabrook/NNP/B-FAC will/MD/O be/VB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O charge/VB/O rates/NNS/O sufficient/JJ/O to/TO/O run/VB/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O and/CC/O make/VB/O payments/NNS/O on/IN/O past/JJ/O construction/NN/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O consideration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O owners/NNS/O '/POS/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O is/VBZ/O pointless/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O commissioners/NNS/O found/VBD/O the/DT/O circumstances/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O undercut/JJ/O the/DT/O assurance/NN/O from/IN/O government/NN/O rate/NN/O setters/NNS/O of/IN/O available/JJ/O funds/NNS/O adequate/JJ/O for/IN/O safe/JJ/O operation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O commission/NN/O spokesman/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O January/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O utility/NN/O filed/VBD/O for/IN/O protection/NN/O under/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O ,/,/O allowing/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O while/IN/O protected/VBN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O '/POS/O lawsuits/NNS/O ././O
