``/``/O The/DT/O carpetbaggers/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O snorts/VBZ/O the/DT/O narrator/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O Texas/JJ/B-GPE twang/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O have/VBP/O packed/VBN/O their/PRP$/O bags/NNS/O and/CC/O went/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O continues/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O forgetting/VBG/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O all/DT/O Texans/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/B-GPE Lone/NNP/I-GPE Star/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O rise/NN/O again/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O the/DT/O music/NN/O swells/NNS/O ,/,/O viewers/NNS/O discover/VBP/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O watching/VBG/O a/DT/O commercial/NN/O for/IN/O Lone/NNP/O Star/NNP/O Beer/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O pride/NN/O of/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O product/NN/O of/IN/O G./NNP/B-ORG Heileman/NNP/I-ORG Brewing/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O La/NNP/B-GPE Crosse/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Wis./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O ad/NN/O 's/POS/O tone/NN/O implies/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE spirit/NN/O is/VBZ/O pretty/RB/O xenophobic/JJ/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Lone/NNP/O Star/NNP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O alone/RB/O in/IN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O take/VB/O advantage/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O ././O
From/IN/O Chevy/NNP/B-ORG trucks/NNS/O to/TO/O Lipton/NNP/B-ORG iced/JJ/O tea/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O host/NN/O of/IN/O battling/VBG/O banks/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O state/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O inundated/VBN/O with/IN/O broadcast/NN/O commercials/NNS/O and/CC/O print/NN/O advertising/NN/O campaigns/NNS/O celebrating/VBG/O Texans/NNPS/O and/CC/O castigating/VBG/O outsiders/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O advertisers/NNS/O have/VBP/O long/RB/O appealed/VBN/O to/TO/O Texans/NNPS/O '/POS/O state/NN/O pride/NN/O and/CC/O prejudices/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O trend/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O sparked/VBN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O by/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O hard/JJ/O economic/JJ/O times/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O swagger/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O natives/NNS/O who/WP/O like/VBP/O to/TO/O brag/VB/O that/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O state/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O once/RB/O a/DT/O nation/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O increased/VBN/O their/PRP$/O legendary/JJ/O resentment/NN/O of/IN/O outsiders/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ,/,/O writes/VBZ/O Houston/NNP/B-ORG Chronicle/NNP/I-ORG columnist/NN/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Barlow/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O outlanders/NNS/O were/VBD/O accepted/VBN/O only/RB/O after/IN/O passing/VBG/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O tests/NNS/O to/TO/O prove/VB/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O right/JJ/O ''/''/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE attitudes/NNS/O and/CC/O ``/``/O of/IN/O course/NN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O dipped/VBN/O for/IN/O parasites/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Lone/NNP/O Star/NNP/O 's/POS/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG parent/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O hails/VBZ/O from/IN/O Perth/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
North/NNPS/O Carolinians/NNPS/O ,/,/O New/NNPS/O Yorkers/NNPS/O ,/,/O Californians/NNPS/O ,/,/O Chicagoans/NNPS/O and/CC/O Ohioans/NNPS/O own/VBP/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE banks/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O the/DT/O beloved/JJ/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE Cowboys/NNPS/B-ORG were/VBD/O bought/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O Arkansas/NNP/B-GPE oil/NN/O man/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O lost/VBN/O its/PRP$/O distinctiveness/NN/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O Texans/NNPS/O with/IN/O a/DT/O hunger/NN/O to/TO/O feel/VB/O proud/JJ/O about/IN/O themselves/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Klineberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O sociology/NN/O professor/NN/O at/IN/O Rice/NNP/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O plays/VBZ/O right/RB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O advertising/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Real/JJ/O Texans/NNPS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O play/VB/O paddleball/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O I/PRP/O hope/VBP/O not/RB/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O football/NN/O country/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O another/DT/O thing/NN/O --/:/O real/JJ/O Texans/NNPS/O drink/VBP/O Lipton/NNP/B-ORG iced/JJ/O tea/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O developing/VBG/O that/DT/O theme/NN/O at/IN/O Interpublic/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Cos/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG '/''/O Lintas/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE unit/NN/O ,/,/O account/NN/O supervisor/NN/O Lisa/NNP/B-PERSON Buksbaum/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O couple/NN/O of/IN/O phone/NN/O calls/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ad/NN/O friends/NNS/O and/CC/O reported/VBD/O her/PRP/O ``/``/O findings/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O a/DT/O team/NN/O of/IN/O writers/NNS/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O findings/NNS/O ?/./O
``/``/O You/PRP/O know/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O stereotypical/JJ/O stuff/NN/O like/IN/O armadillos/NNS/O ,/,/O cowboys/NNS/O and/CC/O football/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Not/RB/O exactly/RB/O sophisticated/JJ/O market/NN/O research/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O who/WP/O cares/VBZ/O as/RB/O long/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O campaigns/NNS/O work/VBP/O ././O
And/CC/O ad/NN/O agencies/NNS/O insist/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O ././O
Never/RB/O mind/VB/O that/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Gibraltar/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O failed/VBN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE thrifts/NNS/O taken/VBN/O over/RP/O by/IN/O outsiders/NNS/O --/:/O in/IN/O this/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O investor/NN/O group/NN/O headed/VBN/O by/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE financier/NN/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Perelman/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/B-ORG North/NNP/I-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG Chevy/NNP/I-ORG Dealers/NNPS/I-ORG recently/RB/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O record/NN/O sales/NNS/O month/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O debut/NN/O of/IN/O ad/NN/O campaign/NN/O that/WDT/O thumbs/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O nose/NN/O at/IN/O elite/NN/O Easterners/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O deposits/VBZ/O at/IN/O NCNB/NNP/B-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O NCNB/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Charlotte/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O have/VBP/O increased/VBN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O since/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O after/IN/O heavy/JJ/O advertising/NN/O stressing/VBG/O commitment/NN/O to/TO/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O Obviously/RB/O ,/,/O pride/NN/O sells/VBZ/O in/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O for/IN/O Bozell/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Omaha/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Neb./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O represents/VBZ/O
The/DT/O ad/NN/O campaigns/NNS/O usually/RB/O follow/VBP/O one/CD/O of/IN/O three/CD/O tracks/NNS/O --/:/O stressing/VBG/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O `/``/O Texasness/NN/O ,/,/O '/''/O pointing/VBG/O out/RP/O the/DT/O competition/NN/O 's/POS/O lack/NN/O thereof/RB/O ,/,/O or/CC/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O Texan/JJ/O than/IN/O Texans/NNPS/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG trucks/NNS/O may/MD/O outsell/VB/O Chevy/NNP/B-ORG trucks/NNS/O in/IN/O places/NNS/O like/IN/O ``/``/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Long/NNP/B-GPE Island/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O sniffs/VBZ/O a/DT/O commercial/NN/O for/IN/O Chevrolet/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O division/NN/O of/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNPS/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Because/IN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O a/DT/O truck/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE tough/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O commercial/NN/O concludes/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Texans/NNPS/O drive/VBP/O Chevy/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O style/NN/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O surviving/VBG/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE banking/NN/O institutions/NNS/O are/VBP/O busily/RB/O pitching/VBG/O themselves/PRP/O as/IN/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O lenders/NNS/O who/WP/O truly/RB/O care/VBP/O about/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
Supporting/VBG/O banks/NNS/O will/MD/O sign/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O Texas/NNP/O Declaration/NNP/O of/IN/O Independents/NNPS/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O video/NN/O sent/VBN/O to/TO/O association/NN/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O featuring/VBG/O shots/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Alamo/NNP/B-FAC ,/,/O cowboys/NNS/O ,/,/O fajitas/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O statue/NN/O of/IN/O Sam/NNP/B-PERSON Houston/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mince/VB/O words/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Texans/NNPS/O can/MD/O sniff/VB/O a/DT/O phony/NN/O a/DT/O mile/NN/O away/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O narrator/NN/O warns/VBZ/O outsiders/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O So/RB/O ,/,/O do/VB/O n't/RB/O come/VB/O and/CC/O try/VB/O to/TO/O con/VB/O us/PRP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O howdy/UH/O y'all/PRP/O or/CC/O a/DT/O cowboy/NN/O hat/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O board/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O impending/JJ/O search/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O its/PRP$/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 5/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 6/CD/O million/CD/O account/NN/O ././O
Ad/NNP/O Notes/NNPS/O .../:/O ././O
NEW/NNP/O ACCOUNT/NNP/O :/:/O
The/DT/O account/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O at/IN/O Della/NNP/B-ORG Femina/NNP/I-ORG McNamee/NNP/I-ORG WCRS/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
MEDIA/NNP/O POLICY/NNP/O :/:/O
It/PRP/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O pull/VB/O its/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O '/POS/O ads/NNS/O from/IN/O those/DT/O magazines/NNS/O ././O
COKE/NNP/B-ORG ADS/NNPS/O :/:/O
The/DT/O ad/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Classic/NNP/O Coke/NNP/O 's/POS/O 1990/CD/O ad/NN/O campaign/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O tag/NN/O line/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Ca/MD/O n't/RB/O beat/VB/O the/DT/O Real/NNP/O Thing/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
Basketball/NN/O star/NN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Jordan/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O singer/NN/O Randy/NNP/B-PERSON Travis/NNP/I-PERSON have/VBP/O also/RB/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O appear/VB/O in/IN/O ads/NNS/O ././O
