Michael/NNP/B-PERSON F./NNP/I-PERSON Harris/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 53/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O named/VBN/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O business/NN/O newspaper/NN/O published/VBN/O by/IN/O this/DT/O company/NN/O that/WDT/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O interests/NNS/O in/IN/O book/NN/O publishing/NN/O ,/,/O fine/JJ/O china/NN/O ,/,/O oil/NN/O services/NNS/O and/CC/O investment/NN/O banking/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Harris/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O newspaper/NN/O 's/POS/O advertising/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O takes/VBZ/O additional/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O newspaper/NN/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Laurance/NNP/B-PERSON V./NNP/I-PERSON Allen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 44/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O director/NN/O for/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O resigned/VBD/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O other/JJ/O business/NN/O interests/NNS/O and/CC/O do/VB/O some/DT/O consulting/NN/O ././O
