Lonrho/NNP/B-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O to/TO/O come/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O rescue/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O French/JJ/O distribution/NN/O group/NN/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG Commerciale/NNP/I-ORG de/IN/I-ORG l'Ouest/NNP/I-ORG Africaine/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O an/DT/O operation/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O engineered/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG financial/JJ/O group/NN/O ,/,/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG Commerciale/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG main/JJ/O shareholder/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O rescue/NN/O operation/NN/O will/MD/O consist/VB/O of/IN/O a/DT/O capital/NN/O boost/NN/O for/IN/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG Commerciale/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O one/CD/O billion/CD/O francs/NNS/O through/IN/O issues/NNS/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O shares/NNS/O and/CC/O convertible/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O will/MD/O give/VB/O Paribas/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Lonrho/NNP/B-ORG joint/JJ/O control/NN/O of/IN/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG Commerciale/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Paribas/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O Lonrho/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O participate/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O forthcoming/JJ/O capital/NN/O boost/NN/O for/IN/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG Commerciale/NNP/I-ORG ././O
