Sony/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O both/DT/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O legal/JJ/O battle/NN/O with/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG over/IN/O the/DT/O services/NNS/O of/IN/O producers/NNS/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Guber/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Jon/NNP/B-PERSON Peters/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Sony/NNP/B-ORG added/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O hearing/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O set/VBN/O for/IN/O Thursday/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Delaware/NNP/I-ORG Chancery/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O suits/NNS/O ././O
