A/DT/O group/NN/O bidding/NN/O for/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O formally/RB/O received/VBD/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O financing/NN/O needed/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O about/IN/O 86/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O hospital/NN/O operator/NN/O 's/POS/O stock/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O offer/NN/O from/IN/O IMA/NNP/B-ORG Acquisition/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 63/CD/O million/CD/O shares/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O set/VBN/O to/TO/O expire/VB/O Wednesday/NNP/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O IMA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O senior/JJ/O debt/NN/O financing/NN/O from/IN/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O six/CD/O other/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ;/:/O Chemical/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O highly/RB/O confident/JJ/O ''/''/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O arrange/VB/O the/DT/O balance/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 509/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG composite/NN/O trading/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG closed/VBD/O at/IN/O $/$/O 23.625/CD/O ,/,/O up/IN/O $/$/O 1.875/CD/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O new/JJ/O ``/``/O expressions/NNS/O of/IN/O interest/NN/O ''/''/O from/IN/O two/CD/O previous/JJ/O bidders/NNS/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O pursue/VB/O the/DT/O inquiries/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O identify/VB/O them/PRP/O unless/IN/O they/PRP/O make/VBP/O firm/JJ/O offers/NNS/O ././O
