A/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O government/NN/O agency/NN/O conditionally/RB/O approved/VBD/O proposed/VBN/O exports/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE of/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O from/IN/O big/JJ/O ,/,/O untapped/JJ/O fields/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC River/NNP/I-LOC delta/JJ/I-LOC area/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O western/JJ/O Canadian/NNP/B-LOC Arctic/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Three/CD/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O Esso/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Shell/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Gulf/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG Resources/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O applied/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Canadian/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O export/VB/O 9.2/CD/O trillion/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O of/IN/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC delta/NN/I-LOC natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O over/IN/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O starting/VBG/O in/IN/O 1996/CD/O ././O
To/TO/O be/VB/O economically/RB/O feasible/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O 11/CD/O billion/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollar/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 9.37/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O project/NN/O requires/VBZ/O almost/RB/O a/DT/O doubling/NN/O of/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O export/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O faces/VBZ/O numerous/JJ/O other/JJ/O hurdles/NNS/O including/VBG/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O pipeline/NN/O route/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O gas/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O board/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O export/NN/O licenses/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O issued/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O condition/NN/O that/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O interests/NNS/O would/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O bid/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Mackenzie/NNP/B-LOC delta/NN/I-LOC gas/NN/O on/IN/O terms/NNS/O similar/JJ/O to/TO/O those/DT/O offered/VBN/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE customers/NNS/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE buyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O already/RB/O been/VBN/O lined/VBN/O up/IN/O ././O
They/PRP/O include/VBP/O Enron/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-ORG Eastern/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Interstate/NNP/I-ORG Transmission/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Tennessee/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG Pipeline/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O project/NN/O could/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE taking/VBG/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O supplies/NNS/O from/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O up/IN/O from/IN/O about/IN/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O currently/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O bring/VB/O 13/CD/O gas/NN/O fields/NNS/O into/IN/O production/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O combined/VBN/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 1.2/CD/O billion/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O board/NN/O estimated/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O building/VBG/O a/DT/O pipeline/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Mackenzie/NNP/I-LOC delta/NN/I-LOC to/TO/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O be/VB/O about/IN/O C$/$/O 5.9/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O projections/NNS/O of/IN/O surging/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE demand/NN/O for/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O and/CC/O price/NN/O forecasts/NNS/O of/IN/O C$/$/O 5.25/CD/O per/IN/O thousand/CD/O cubic/JJ/O feet/NNS/O by/IN/O 2005/CD/O would/MD/O make/VB/O the/DT/O project/NN/O economically/RB/O viable/JJ/O ././O
