Aussedat/NNP/B-ORG Rey/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O French/JJ/O paper/NN/O producer/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O concluded/VBD/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Fuji/NNP/B-ORG Photo/NNP/I-ORG Film/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG that/WDT/O will/MD/O allow/VB/O Aussedat/NNP/B-ORG Rey/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O manufacture/VB/O and/CC/O sell/VB/O thermal/JJ/O paper/NN/O using/VBG/O Fuji/NNP/B-ORG technology/NN/O ././O
Aussedat/NNP/B-ORG Rey/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O leading/VBG/O French/JJ/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O copying/NN/O and/CC/O electronic/JJ/O printing/NN/O paper/NN/O ././O
Thermal/JJ/O paper/NN/O is/VBZ/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O facsimile/JJ/O machines/NNS/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
