The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Mortgage/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O 39/CD/O lenders/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O home/NN/O loans/NNS/O under/IN/O Fannie/NNP/B-ORG Mae/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG pilot/NN/O program/NN/O for/IN/O elderly/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O
Prudential/NNP/B-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Newark/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Fannie/NNP/B-ORG Mae/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O loans/NNS/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O Seniors/NNS/O '/POS/O Housing/NNP/O Opportunities/NNPS/O pilot/NN/O program/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O offers/VBZ/O four/CD/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O people/NNS/O 62/CD/O years/NNS/O of/IN/O age/NN/O or/CC/O older/JJR/O to/TO/O help/VB/O them/PRP/O maintain/VB/O their/PRP$/O home/NN/O or/CC/O obtain/VB/O housing/NN/O ././O
Fannie/NNP/B-ORG Mae/NNP/I-ORG makes/VBZ/O a/DT/O secondary/JJ/O market/NN/O in/IN/O home/NN/O loans/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O buys/VBZ/O loans/NNS/O from/IN/O lenders/NNS/O ,/,/O packages/VBZ/O some/DT/O into/IN/O securities/NNS/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O to/TO/O investors/NNS/O and/CC/O holds/VBZ/O the/DT/O remainder/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O portfolio/NN/O ././O
