Computer/NNP/B-ORG Sciences/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O El/NNP/B-GPE Segundo/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Aeronautics/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Space/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O negotiate/VB/O details/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O contract/NN/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 170/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O software/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ames/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG ././O
NASA/NNP/B-ORG awarded/VBD/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O CSC/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O November/NNP/O but/CC/O an/DT/O appeal/NN/O by/IN/O Sterling/NNP/B-ORG Software/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE sent/VBD/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Contract/NNP/I-ORG Appeals/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O board/NN/O required/VBN/O NASA/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O re-evaluate/VB/O bidders/NNS/O '/POS/O proposals/NNS/O ././O
