Gold/NN/O and/CC/O silver/NN/O broker/NN/O Preston/NNP/B-PERSON Semel/NNP/I-PERSON asked/VBD/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O to/TO/O halt/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Commodity/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG from/IN/O imposing/VBG/O a/DT/O record/NN/O $/$/O 550,000/CD/O fine/NN/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O firm/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O fine/NN/O and/CC/O suspension/NN/O ,/,/O announced/VBN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O stiffest/JJS/O sanctions/NNS/O the/DT/O Comex/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O ever/RB/O ordered/VBN/O against/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O members/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O disciplinary/JJ/O proceedings/NNS/O stem/VBP/O from/IN/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O commission/NN/O denied/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O request/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O fine/NN/O and/CC/O suspension/NN/O be/VB/O delayed/VBN/O pending/VBG/O the/DT/O appeal/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Comex/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
