That/DT/O has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O swagger/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O natives/NNS/O who/WP/O like/VBP/O to/TO/O brag/VB/O that/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O state/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O once/RB/O a/DT/O nation/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O increased/VBN/O their/PRP$/O legendary/JJ/O resentment/NN/O of/IN/O outsiders/NNS/O ././O
Lone/NNP/O Star/NNP/O 's/POS/O Bond/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG parent/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O hails/VBZ/O from/IN/O Perth/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Australia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
North/NNPS/O Carolinians/NNPS/O ,/,/O New/NNPS/O Yorkers/NNPS/O ,/,/O Californians/NNPS/O ,/,/O Chicagoans/NNPS/O and/CC/O Ohioans/NNPS/O own/VBP/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE banks/NNS/O ././O
Real/JJ/O Texans/NNPS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O play/VB/O paddleball/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O I/PRP/O hope/VBP/O not/RB/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O football/NN/O country/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG North/NNP/I-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG Chevy/NNP/I-ORG Dealers/NNPS/I-ORG recently/RB/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O record/NN/O sales/NNS/O month/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O debut/NN/O of/IN/O ad/NN/O campaign/NN/O that/WDT/O thumbs/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O nose/NN/O at/IN/O elite/NN/O Easterners/NNS/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG trucks/NNS/O may/MD/O outsell/VB/O Chevy/NNP/B-ORG trucks/NNS/O in/IN/O places/NNS/O like/IN/O ``/``/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Long/NNP/B-GPE Island/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O sniffs/VBZ/O a/DT/O commercial/NN/O for/IN/O Chevrolet/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O division/NN/O of/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNPS/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
A/DT/O video/NN/O sent/VBN/O to/TO/O association/NN/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O featuring/VBG/O shots/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Alamo/NNP/B-FAC ,/,/O cowboys/NNS/O ,/,/O fajitas/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O statue/NN/O of/IN/O Sam/NNP/B-PERSON Houston/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mince/VB/O words/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O board/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O impending/JJ/O search/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O ad/NN/O agency/NN/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O its/PRP$/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 5/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 6/CD/O million/CD/O account/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O account/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O at/IN/O Della/NNP/B-ORG Femina/NNP/I-ORG McNamee/NNP/I-ORG WCRS/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O pull/VB/O its/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O '/POS/O ads/NNS/O from/IN/O those/DT/O magazines/NNS/O ././O
Basketball/NN/O star/NN/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Jordan/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O singer/NN/O Randy/NNP/B-PERSON Travis/NNP/I-PERSON have/VBP/O also/RB/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O appear/VB/O in/IN/O ads/NNS/O ././O
