Doman/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Duncan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O founded/VBN/O and/CC/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Harbanse/NNP/B-PERSON Doman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O its/PRP$/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O president/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O purchase/NN/O would/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O 10th/JJ/O largest/JJS/O forest/NN/O products/NNS/O company/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fletcher/NNP/B-ORG Challenge/NNP/I-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG stake/NN/O was/VBD/O then/RB/O canceled/VBN/O ,/,/O Doman/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ,/,/O raising/VBG/O Doman/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Western/NNP/B-ORG Forest/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O 56/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Doman/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O also/RB/O granted/VBN/O an/DT/O option/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O 44/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Western/NNP/B-ORG Forest/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O currently/RB/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O two/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ././O
