Coastal/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O terms/NNS/O ././O
Coastal/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O October/NNP/O 1990/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O install/VB/O additional/JJ/O processing/VBG/O units/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O refinery/NN/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O higher/JJR/O octane/NN/O gasolines/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O leasing/VBG/O the/DT/O site/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O refinery/NN/O from/IN/O Aruba/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Exxon/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG built/VBD/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O but/CC/O closed/VBD/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O and/CC/O sold/VBD/O off/IN/O much/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O equipment/NN/O to/TO/O dismantling/VBG/O contractors/NNS/O ,/,/O from/IN/O whom/WP/O Coastal/NNP/B-ORG bought/VBD/O back/RB/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O equipment/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Coastal/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O expense/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O refurbish/VB/O the/DT/O refinery/NN/O but/CC/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O much/RB/O that/IN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O of/IN/O Aruba/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O cost/VB/O around/IN/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
