Xtra/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O transportation/NN/O leasing/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O no/DT/O comment/NN/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gintel/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O plans/NNS/O until/IN/O ``/``/O further/JJ/O information/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O disclosed/VBN/O by/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O 1990/CD/O annual/JJ/O meeting/NN/O has/VBZ/O not/RB/O been/VBN/O scheduled/VBN/O ././O
Xtra/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O recently/RB/O bought/VBD/O back/RB/O approximately/RB/O 55,000/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O pursuant/JJ/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O existing/VBG/O authorization/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 650,000/CD/O shares/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gintel/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O filed/VBN/O suit/NN/O in/IN/O Delaware/NNP/B-ORG Chancery/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O seeking/VBG/O to/TO/O block/NN/O Xtra/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O anti-takeover/JJ/O tactic/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O filing/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gintel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Xtra/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O has/VBZ/O pursued/VBN/O business/NN/O strategies/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O interest/NN/O of/IN/O stockholders/NNS/O ././O
