Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE Attorney/NNP/O General/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Shannon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O opposing/VBG/O the/DT/O license/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O appeal/VB/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O NRC/NNP/B-ORG rejected/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Shannon/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O argument/NN/O that/IN/O Public/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE Hampshire/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O share/NN/O of/IN/O Seabrook/NNP/B-FAC ,/,/O and/CC/O 11/CD/O other/JJ/O owners/NNS/O are/VBP/O financially/RB/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O guarantee/VB/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O 's/POS/O safe/JJ/O operation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Shannon/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O waiver/NN/O of/IN/O NRC/NNP/B-ORG policy/NN/O that/WDT/O ignores/VBZ/O financial/JJ/O considerations/NNS/O in/IN/O making/VBG/O licensing/NN/O decisions/NNS/O ././O
