Ford/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Merkur/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O new/JJ/O car/NN/O franchise/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE since/IN/O the/DT/O Edsel/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O unveiled/VBN/O in/IN/O 1957/CD/O ,/,/O now/RB/O will/MD/O share/VB/O Edsel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O fate/NN/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O halt/VB/O imports/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Merkur/NNP/B-ORG Scorpio/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O $/$/O 28,000/CD/O luxury/NN/O sedan/NN/O built/VBN/O by/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O European/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Merkur/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O demise/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O setback/NN/O for/IN/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O image/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE auto/NN/O maker/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O golden/JJ/O touch/NN/O is/VBZ/O showing/VBG/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O strain/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O No./NN/O 2/CD/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O Thunderbird/NNP/O and/CC/O Mercury/NNP/B-ORG Cougar/NNP/O models/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O met/VBN/O sales/NNS/O expectations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O since/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O introduced/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O trucks/NNS/O are/VBP/O losing/VBG/O ground/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O GM/NNP/B-ORG rivals/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O fall/NN/O ,/,/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG introduced/VBD/O only/RB/O one/CD/O new/JJ/O product/NN/O :/:/O A/DT/O restyled/VBN/O version/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O hulking/VBG/O Lincoln/NNP/B-ORG Town/NNP/O Car/NNP/O luxury/NN/O model/NN/O ././O
Total/NNP/O Merkur/NNP/B-ORG sales/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O nine/CD/O months/NNS/O dropped/VBD/O 46/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ago/IN/O to/TO/O just/RB/O 6,320/CD/O cars/NNS/O ././O
Merkur/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O European/JJ/O luxury/NN/O brand/NN/O having/VBG/O problems/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O assault/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O luxury/NN/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O rapidly/RB/O overshadowing/VBG/O such/JJ/O European/JJ/O makes/NNS/O as/IN/O Audi/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Saab/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O have/VBP/O clear/JJ/O brand/NN/O images/NNS/O ././O
Merkur/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O an/DT/O import/NN/O on/IN/O domestic/JJ/O car/NN/O lots/NNS/O ,/,/O suffered/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O image/NN/O confusion/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O hobbling/VBG/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O imports/NNS/O at/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Motors/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Chrysler/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O brand/NN/O had/VBD/O trouble/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O start/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O Merkur/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O XR4Ti/NNP/O ,/,/O went/VBD/O on/IN/O sale/NN/O in/IN/O early/JJ/O 1985/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O May/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG began/VBD/O importing/VBG/O the/DT/O Scorpio/NNP/O sedan/NN/O from/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O sell/VB/O next/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O redesigned/VBN/O XR4Ti/NNP/O in/IN/O showrooms/NNS/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expected/VBD/O the/DT/O two/CD/O Merkurs/NNPS/B-ORG would/MD/O sell/VB/O about/IN/O 15,000/CD/O cars/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O they/PRP/O reached/VBD/O that/DT/O goal/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O sales/NNS/O hit/VBD/O 15,261/CD/O cars/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O downhill/RB/O from/IN/O there/EX/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
One/CD/O major/JJ/O factor/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O decline/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O began/VBD/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O after/IN/O Merkur/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 1985/CD/O launch/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O German/NNP/O currency/NN/O rose/VBD/O ,/,/O so/RB/O did/VBD/O Merkur/NNP/B-ORG prices/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Merkur/NNP/B-ORG cars/NNS/O also/RB/O suffered/VBD/O from/IN/O spotty/JJ/O quality/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O dealers/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
But/CC/O by/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O of/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O Scorpios/NNPS/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O satisfaction/NN/O rating/NN/O in/IN/O internal/JJ/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG studies/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Apparently/RB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O improvement/NN/O came/VBD/O too/RB/O late/JJ/O ././O
Last/JJ/O fall/NN/O ,/,/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG announced/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O discontinue/VB/O the/DT/O XR4Ti/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1989/CD/O model/NN/O year/NN/O ././O
Ford/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O then/RB/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O Scorpio/NNP/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Scorpio/NNP/O sales/NNS/O plummeted/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O at/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O sales/NNS/O pace/NN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O take/VB/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG 242/CD/O days/NNS/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O off/RP/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O Scorpio/NNP/O inventory/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 4,600/CD/O cars/NNS/O ././O
