Capital/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O requested/VBD/O and/CC/O received/VBD/O the/DT/O resignation/NN/O of/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Franco/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O its/PRP$/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O an/DT/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O life/NN/O insurance/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Franco/NNP/B-PERSON developed/VBD/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O establish/VB/O a/DT/O business/NN/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O be/VB/O competitive/JJ/O with/IN/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Accumulation/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O Mr./NNP/O Franco/NNP/B-PERSON headed/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O temporarily/RB/O will/MD/O report/VB/O to/TO/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Bailey/NNP/I-PERSON II/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Franco/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 47/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O telephone/NN/O interview/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O considering/VBG/O and/CC/O discussing/VBG/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O possible/JJ/O business/NN/O ventures/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O ``/``/O nothing/NN/O is/VBZ/O at/IN/O a/DT/O mature/JJ/O stage/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O ``/``/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O argue/VB/O with/IN/O ''/''/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O his/PRP$/O resignation/NN/O because/IN/O contemplating/VBG/O outside/IN/O business/NN/O ventures/NNS/O can/MD/O distract/VB/O an/DT/O executive/NN/O from/IN/O performing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O best/JJS/O ``/``/O at/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O paid/VBN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Martin/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Ruby/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O managing/VBG/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Accumulation/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O also/RB/O resigned/VBD/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O other/JJ/O business/NN/O interests/NNS/O ,/,/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/DT/O his/PRP$/O resignation/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O mutual/JJ/O decision/NN/O with/IN/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG management/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O actually/RB/O asked/VBN/O to/TO/O resign/VB/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Accumulation/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O investment/NN/O operations/NNS/O of/IN/O all/DT/O Capital/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG insurance/NN/O businesses/NNS/O and/CC/O markets/NNS/O guaranteed/VBN/O investment/NN/O contracts/NNS/O to/TO/O bank/VB/O trust/NN/O departments/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bailey/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O name/VB/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O group/NN/O president/NN/O to/TO/O head/VB/O that/DT/O operation/NN/O following/VBG/O the/DT/O Nov./NNP/O 8/CD/O board/NN/O meeting/NN/O ././O
