The/DT/O legislation/NN/O would/MD/O open/VB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O telephone/NN/O services/NNS/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O competition/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O business/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O provinces/NNS/O ,/,/O federal/JJ/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O initiative/NN/O follows/VBZ/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O Canadian/NNP/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG decision/NN/O that/WDT/O held/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O telephone/NN/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Saskatchewan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Manitoba/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Atlantic/JJ/B-LOC coast/NN/O provinces/NNS/O were/VBD/O interprovincial/JJ/O undertakings/NNS/O and/CC/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O federal/JJ/O legislative/JJ/O authority/NN/O ././O
Prior/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O had/VBD/O regulated/VBN/O only/RB/O the/DT/O telephone/NN/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O Quebec/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ontario/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Northwest/NNP/I-GPE Territories/NNPS/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O governments/NNS/O of/IN/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Saskatchewan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Manitoba/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O strongly/RB/O opposed/VBN/O federal/JJ/O regulation/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O telephone/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
