Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG Enterprises/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O umbrella/NN/O organization/NN/O for/IN/O companies/NNS/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Helmsley/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
These/DT/O include/VBP/O office/NN/O and/CC/O residential/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O giant/NN/O ,/,/O HelmsleySpear/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG Hotels/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O insurance/NN/O brokerage/NN/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O a/DT/O fragment/NN/O of/IN/O Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O vast/JJ/O empire/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O stripped/VBN/O away/RB/O since/IN/O last/JJ/O summer/NN/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Helmsley/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Leona/NNP/B-PERSON Helmsley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O found/VBN/O guilty/JJ/O of/IN/O tax/NN/O evasion/NN/O ././O
Industry/NN/O sources/NNS/O estimate/VBP/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O brokers/NNS/O property/NN/O and/CC/O casualty/NN/O premiums/NNS/O worth/JJ/O about/IN/O $/$/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O annually/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O standard/JJ/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O commission/NN/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O insurance/NN/O firm/NN/O acts/VBZ/O as/IN/O a/DT/O broker/NN/O on/IN/O policies/NNS/O covering/VBG/O buildings/NNS/O managed/VBN/O by/IN/O HelmsleySpear/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O properties/NNS/O are/VBP/O owned/VBN/O through/IN/O limited/VBN/O partnerships/NNS/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Helmsley/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE State/NNP/I-GPE law/NN/O prohibits/VBZ/O insurance/NN/O brokerages/NNS/O from/IN/O deriving/VBG/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O revenue/NN/O from/IN/O insuring/VBG/O affiliated/VBN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O insurance/NN/O division/NN/O had/VBD/O slightly/RB/O exceeded/VBN/O that/DT/O percentage/NN/O ,/,/O sources/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O division/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O considered/VBN/O significant/JJ/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O restructured/VBN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O at/IN/O a/DT/O difficult/JJ/O time/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O ././O
Adverse/JJ/O publicity/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O scandal/NN/O surrounding/VBG/O its/PRP$/O founder/NN/O 's/POS/O wife/NN/O and/CC/O related/VBN/O management/NN/O strife/NN/O have/VBP/O put/VBN/O pressure/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG organization/NN/O ././O
Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O insurance/NN/O premiums/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O transferred/VBN/O to/TO/O several/JJ/O different/JJ/O insurance/NN/O brokerage/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Frank/NNP/B-ORG B./NNP/I-ORG Hall/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Briarcliff/NNP/B-GPE Manor/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O reportedly/RB/O working/VBG/O out/IN/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Officials/NNS/O there/RB/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O did/VBD/O Helmsley/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O ././O
