Clinton/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O a/DT/O contract/NN/O from/IN/O Timken/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Canton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O manage/VB/O the/DT/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O purchasing/NN/O ,/,/O scheduling/NN/O and/CC/O transportation/NN/O activities/NNS/O for/IN/O Timken/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O seven/CD/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O two/CD/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE plants/NNS/O ././O
Clinton/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Timken/NNP/B-ORG agreed/VBD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O ././O
Timken/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O bearings/NNS/O and/CC/O specialty/NN/O steel/NN/O ,/,/O already/RB/O buys/VBZ/O gas/NN/O from/IN/O Clinton/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Clinton/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O in/IN/O Columbus/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O Clinton/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG Marketing/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O line/VB/O up/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O gas/NN/O management/NN/O contracts/NNS/O ././O
Manufacturers/NNS/O frequently/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O anyone/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O specialist/NN/O in/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O ,/,/O Clinton/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O specialist/NN/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Clinton/NNP/B-ORG can/MD/O save/VB/O them/PRP/O substantial/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ././O
