Mr./NNP/O Agnos/NNP/B-PERSON complained/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O ticked/VBN/O off/RP/O ''/''/O that/IN/O Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O Dan/NNP/B-PERSON Quayle/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O toured/VBD/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O site/NN/O Wednesday/NNP/O ,/,/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O schedule/VB/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O meeting/NN/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O mayor/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Quayle/NNP/B-PERSON visit/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O a/DT/O publicity/NN/O stunt/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Quayle/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O staff/NN/O had/VBD/O invited/VBN/O the/DT/O mayor/NN/O to/TO/O two/CD/O meetings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O groups/NNS/O of/IN/O local/JJ/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O offered/VBN/O to/TO/O dispatch/VB/O a/DT/O helicopter/NN/O to/TO/O pick/VB/O him/PRP/O up/IN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Agnos/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O the/DT/O invitations/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Marlin/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzwater/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG press/NN/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O asserted/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Agnos/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O failed/VBN/O to/TO/O return/VB/O telephone/NN/O calls/NNS/O from/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Sununu/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG chief/NN/O of/IN/O staff/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O regret/VBP/O very/RB/O much/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O mayor/NN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O decided/VBN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O cooperate/VB/O with/IN/O us/PRP/O on/IN/O this/DT/O matter/NN/O in/IN/O making/VBG/O sure/JJ/O that/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O adequate/JJ/O federal/JJ/O support/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O disaster/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O city/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Fitzwater/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
By/IN/O late/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O appeared/VBD/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O bury/VB/O the/DT/O hatchet/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Agnos/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O mayors/NNS/O of/IN/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Alameda/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O to/TO/O accompany/VB/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O a/DT/O tour/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O area/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O one/CD/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG official/NN/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Agnos/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O been/VBN/O ``/``/O very/RB/O helpful/JJ/O ''/''/O in/IN/O making/VBG/O arrangements/NNS/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O hastily/RB/O scheduled/VBN/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
