-LRB-/-LRB-/O During/IN/O its/PRP$/O centennial/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O report/VB/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O century/NN/O that/WDT/O stand/VBP/O as/IN/O milestones/NNS/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O business/NN/O history/NN/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
But/CC/O few/JJ/O knew/VBD/O it/PRP/O then/RB/O and/CC/O most/RBS/O still/RB/O think/VBP/O all/DT/O pencils/NNS/O are/VBP/O wooden/JJ/O ././O
Eagle/NNP/B-ORG Pencil/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Shelbyville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Tenn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ``/``/O Pencil/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE U.S.A./NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O ''/''/O had/VBD/O made/VBN/O its/PRP$/O earliest/JJS/O pilot/NN/O plastic/NN/O pencils/NNS/O in/IN/O 1971/CD/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O until/IN/O after/IN/O it/PRP/O hired/VBD/O Arthur/NNP/B-ORG D./NNP/I-ORG Little/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Cambridge/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O research/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O product/NN/O was/VBD/O refined/VBN/O for/IN/O commercial/JJ/O sale/NN/O in/IN/O 1973/CD/O ././O
Three/CD/O A.D.L./NNP/B-ORG inventors/NNS/O applied/VBD/O April/NNP/O 6/CD/O ,/,/O 1973/CD/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O patent/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O assigned/VBN/O and/CC/O awarded/VBN/O in/IN/O 1976/CD/O to/TO/O Hasbro/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O then/RB/O Eagle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O parent/NN/O ././O
Pencil/NN/O pushers/NNS/O chew/VBP/O and/CC/O put/VBP/O the/DT/O plastic/NN/O models/NNS/O behind/IN/O their/PRP$/O ears/NNS/O just/RB/O like/IN/O traditional/JJ/O pencils/NNS/O made/VBN/O of/IN/O glued/VBN/O strips/NNS/O of/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE incense/NN/O cedar/NN/O filled/VBN/O with/IN/O ceramic/JJ/O lead/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O takes/VBZ/O five/CD/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O standard/JJ/O pencils/NNS/O ,/,/O just/RB/O one/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O plastic/NN/O type/NN/O ././O
``/``/O After/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O 200/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O something/NN/O new/JJ/O has/VBZ/O happened/VBN/O to/TO/O pencils/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Arthur/NNP/B-ORG D./NNP/I-ORG Little/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O 1974/CD/O report/NN/O that/WDT/O publicly/RB/O described/VBD/O the/DT/O previously/RB/O secret/JJ/O item/NN/O ././O
Eagle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O plastic/JJ/O type/NN/O sharpens/VBZ/O and/CC/O looks/VBZ/O like/IN/O a/DT/O wooden/JJ/O pencil/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O major/JJ/O difference/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O a/DT/O snapped/JJ/O wooden/JJ/O pencil/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O slivered/VBN/O break/NN/O while/IN/O a/DT/O plastic/NN/O model/NN/O will/MD/O break/VB/O cleanly/RB/O ././O
Artists/NNS/O and/CC/O draftsmen/NNS/O need/VBP/O harder/JJR/O ``/``/O leads/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O trade/NN/O secret/NN/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O were/VBD/O plastic/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O most/JJS/O writers/NNS/O still/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O what/WP/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O using/VBG/O ././O
