Few/JJ/O specialists/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expect/VBP/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O much/RB/O of/IN/O an/DT/O effect/NN/O on/IN/O most/JJS/O California/NNP/B-GPE property/NN/O values/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O California/NNP/B-GPE prices/NNS/O were/VBD/O already/RB/O coming/VBG/O down/IN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O help/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON T./NNP/I-PERSON Rosen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Real/NNP/I-ORG Estate/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Urban/NNP/I-ORG Economics/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/I-ORG Berkeley/NNP/I-ORG ././O
State/NN/O housing/NN/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O a/DT/O median/NN/O $/$/O 201,028/CD/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O declined/VBN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O months/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O potential/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O '/POS/O inability/NN/O to/TO/O afford/VB/O homes/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE neighborhood/NN/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O test/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Rosen/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O theory/NN/O soon/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O fashionable/JJ/O Marina/NNP/B-LOC district/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O boasts/VBZ/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O home/NN/O prices/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O district/NN/O ,/,/O built/VBN/O on/IN/O landfill/NN/O ,/,/O suffered/VBN/O heavy/JJ/O quake/NN/O damage/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O collapsed/VBN/O buildings/NNS/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O city/NN/O demolished/VBD/O two/CD/O dwellings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O district/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O severe/JJ/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 19/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O district/NN/O 's/POS/O 350/CD/O dwellings/NNS/O might/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O razed/VBN/O ././O
Because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O ,/,/O few/JJ/O relocation/NN/O specialists/NNS/O expect/VBP/O a/DT/O widespread/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O flight/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O 's/POS/O aftermath/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O will/MD/O force/VB/O some/DT/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O relocate/VB/O or/CC/O expand/VB/O part/NN/O or/CC/O all/DT/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O operations/NNS/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ././O
``/``/O What/WP/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O get/VB/O is/VBZ/O `/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O put/VB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O eggs/NNS/O in/IN/O one/CD/O basket/NN/O '/''/O theory/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O James/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Renzas/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Location/NNP/B-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O relocation/NN/O concern/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Renzas/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O among/IN/O others/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O will/MD/O prod/VB/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O certain/JJ/O industries/NNS/O ,/,/O like/IN/O semiconductors/NNS/O ,/,/O computers/NNS/O and/CC/O aerospace/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O moving/VBG/O operations/NNS/O that/WDT/O involve/VBP/O particularly/RB/O sensitive/JJ/O machinery/NN/O to/TO/O locations/NNS/O outside/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O threat/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O some/DT/O firms/NNS/O have/VBP/O evaluated/VBN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O shore/VB/O up/RP/O their/PRP$/O buildings/NNS/O and/CC/O compared/VBN/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O building/VBG/O it/PRP/O elswehere/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
One/CD/O Southern/NNP/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC aerospace/NN/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O two/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/IN/O asked/VBD/O Location/NNP/B-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O compare/VB/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O of/IN/O reinforcing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O building/NN/O against/IN/O earthquakes/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O building/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O structure/NN/O elsewhere/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Renzas/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/CC/O determined/VBN/O what/WP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O ././O
