Some/DT/O employers/NNS/O initiate/VBP/O referrals/NNS/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O if/IN/O work/NN/O problems/NNS/O threaten/VBP/O a/DT/O top/JJ/O manager/NN/O 's/POS/O job/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O couples/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O like/IN/O ships/NNS/O passing/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O night/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O communications/NNS/O gulf/NN/O that/WDT/O sparks/VBZ/O problems/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O and/CC/O at/IN/O home/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O psychologist/NN/O Harry/NNP/B-PERSON Levinson/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
His/PRP$/O Levinson/NNP/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Belmont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O seen/VBN/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O a/DT/O doubling/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O executives/NNS/O and/CC/O spouses/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O weeklong/JJ/O counseling/NN/O program/NN/O ././O
Employers/NNS/O foot/VBP/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O figuring/VBG/O what/WP/O 's/VBZ/O good/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O couple/NN/O is/VBZ/O good/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O East/NNP/B-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC manufacturing/VBG/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O faced/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O job/NN/O transfer/NN/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O resented/VBD/O ,/,/O found/VBD/O that/IN/O counseling/NN/O helped/VBD/O them/PRP/O both/DT/O come/VB/O to/TO/O grips/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O move/NN/O ././O
Her/PRP$/O Institute/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Family/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Work/NNP/I-ORG Relationships/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O La/NNP/B-GPE Jolla/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O noted/VBN/O a/DT/O doubling/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O couples/NNS/O seeking/VBG/O help/NN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
She/PRP/O urges/VBZ/O client/NN/O couples/NNS/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O detoxification/NN/O ''/''/O period/NN/O ,/,/O purging/VBG/O social/JJ/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O nonproductive/JJ/O activities/NNS/O and/CC/O setting/VBG/O time/NN/O apart/RB/O for/IN/O themselves/PRP/O ././O
Each/DT/O new/JJ/O employee/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O submit/VB/O four/CD/O daily/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O job/NN/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O favor/VB/O suggestions/NNS/O ``/``/O that/WDT/O go/VBP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O home/NN/O runs/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Gary/NNP/B-PERSON Floss/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O corporate/JJ/O quality/NN/O at/IN/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
That/DT/O helps/VBZ/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O American/JJ/O employers/NNS/O grant/VBP/O an/DT/O average/JJ/O award/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 604.72/CD/O per/IN/O suggestion/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O payment/NN/O is/VBZ/O $/$/O 3.23/CD/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O developing/VBG/O management/NN/O teams/NNS/O are/VBP/O wrestling/VBG/O with/IN/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O individual/JJ/O suggestion/NN/O systems/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O separate/JJ/O study/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O extent/NN/O of/IN/O employee/NN/O misconduct/NN/O linked/VBD/O general/JJ/O job/NN/O satisfaction/NN/O to/TO/O property/NN/O loss/NN/O ././O
Pilferage/NN/O climbed/VBD/O dramatically/RB/O as/IN/O many/JJ/O angry/JJ/O employees/NNS/O ``/``/O felt/VBD/O abandoned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O former/JJ/O owners/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Florida/NNP/I-ORG sociologist/NN/O ././O
Security/NN/O consultant/NN/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON Dalton/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Ventura/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O thinks/VBZ/O mergers/NNS/O often/RB/O trigger/VBP/O longer/JJR/O lunch/NN/O hours/NNS/O and/CC/O increased/VBN/O absenteeism/NN/O ,/,/O conduct/NN/O which/WDT/O can/MD/O sap/VB/O the/DT/O bottom/NN/O line/NN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O thefts/NNS/O ././O
New/JJ/O management/NN/O can/MD/O take/VB/O several/JJ/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O dishonesty/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dalton/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O recommends/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O establish/VB/O a/DT/O rumor/NN/O control/NN/O center/NN/O and/CC/O move/VB/O swiftly/RB/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O morale/NN/O ././O
