The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O standard/JJ/O object/NN/O of/IN/O suggestions/NNS/O for/IN/O organizational/JJ/O and/CC/O institutional/JJ/O changes/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O two/CD/O reasons/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O unusual/JJ/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O independence/NN/O from/IN/O elected/VBN/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O still/RB/O has/VBZ/O authority/NN/O over/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O powerful/JJ/O of/IN/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O instruments/NNS/O --/:/O the/DT/O control/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O money/NN/O supply/NN/O ././O
Second/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O responsibilities/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O guardian/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O means/VBZ/O as/IN/O guardian/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stability/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ,/,/O sometimes/RB/O lead/VBP/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O take/VB/O measures/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O unpopular/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O easily/RB/O assigned/VBN/O the/DT/O blame/NN/O for/IN/O unpleasantness/NN/O ,/,/O like/IN/O high/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O or/CC/O slow/JJ/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O politicians/NNS/O can/MD/O escape/VB/O responsibility/NN/O by/IN/O pointing/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O independence/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O leads/VBZ/O to/TO/O proposals/NNS/O for/IN/O ``/``/O reform/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O common/JJ/O feature/NN/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG more/RBR/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O to/TO/O public/JJ/O opinion/NN/O --/:/O without/IN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O any/DT/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O additional/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O politicians/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O ideas/NNS/O are/VBP/O again/RB/O under/IN/O consideration/NN/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
They/PRP/O would/MD/O not/RB/O solve/VB/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O worse/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O too/RB/O unresponsive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O interest/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O enormous/JJ/O inflation/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O was/VBD/O largely/RB/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O basic/JJ/O problem/NN/O of/IN/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O which/WDT/O reform/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG should/MD/O be/VB/O addressed/VBN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O a/DT/O recurrence/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O experience/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O common/JJ/O proposals/NNS/O for/IN/O reforming/VBG/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O only/RB/O make/VB/O the/DT/O situation/NN/O worse/JJR/O ,/,/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O any/DT/O effect/NN/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
Putting/VBG/O the/DT/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Governors/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O proposals/NNS/O today/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O example/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O secretary/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O borrower/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O suffers/VBZ/O the/DT/O further/JJ/O disqualification/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O club/NN/O of/IN/O seven/CD/O finance/NN/O ministers/NNS/O who/WP/O meet/VBP/O occasionally/RB/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O what/WP/O exchange/NN/O rates/NNS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O diversion/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O real/JJ/O business/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O stabilize/VB/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O problem/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O independent/JJ/O ,/,/O or/CC/O too/RB/O unpolitical/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O and/CC/O can/MD/O not/RB/O help/VB/O being/VBG/O responsive/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O the/DT/O more/JJR/O overtly/RB/O political/JJ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG exercises/VBZ/O a/DT/O power/NN/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O by/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O president/NN/O ././O
Critics/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O present/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O are/VBP/O correct/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O undemocratic/JJ/O ././O
What/WP/O is/VBZ/O undemocratic/JJ/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O unwillingness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O political/JJ/O parts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O deciding/VBG/O the/DT/O basic/JJ/O question/NN/O of/IN/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O what/WDT/O priority/NN/O should/MD/O be/VB/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O greatest/JJS/O contribution/NN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O make/VB/O at/IN/O this/DT/O time/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O declare/VB/O that/IN/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O primary/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O thing/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O enacted/VBN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O much/RB/O prefer/VB/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O the/DT/O hard/JJ/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O retain/VB/O its/PRP$/O rights/NNS/O of/IN/O complaint/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O ././O
People/NNS/O will/MD/O say/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O government/NN/O have/VBP/O other/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O price/NN/O level/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O true/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O other/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O and/CC/O instruments/NNS/O for/IN/O pursuing/VBG/O these/DT/O other/JJ/O objectives/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O objectives/NNS/O most/RBS/O commonly/RB/O thought/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O legitimate/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O attention/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O high/JJ/O employment/NN/O and/CC/O rapid/JJ/O real/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O former/JJ/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O 's/POS/O Council/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Advisers/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Stein/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O an/DT/O American/NNP/B-ORG Enterprise/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG fellow/NN/O ././O
