The/DT/O deposits/NNS/O ,/,/O assets/NNS/O and/CC/O certain/JJ/O liabilities/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O thrifts/NNS/O were/VBD/O transferred/VBN/O to/TO/O newly/RB/O chartered/VBN/O federal/JJ/O mutual/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O Century/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Phoenix/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O closed/VBN/O by/IN/O Arizona/NNP/B-GPE banking/NN/O officials/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Deposit/NNP/I-ORG Insurance/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG approved/VBD/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O Century/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O deposits/NNS/O and/CC/O fully/RB/O secured/VBN/O liabilities/NNS/O by/IN/O a/DT/O newly/RB/O chartered/VBN/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Valley/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O institution/NN/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O called/VBN/O Century/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O failed/VBN/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O five/CD/O offices/NNS/O will/MD/O reopen/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O failed/VBN/O bank/NN/O had/VBD/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 129.6/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O newly/RB/O chartered/VBN/O bank/NN/O will/MD/O assume/VB/O about/IN/O $/$/O 125.7/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 10,300/CD/O deposit/NN/O accounts/NNS/O and/CC/O pay/VB/O the/DT/O FDIC/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O purchase/NN/O premium/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.9/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O will/MD/O buy/VB/O about/IN/O $/$/O 91.7/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O FDIC/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O advance/VB/O $/$/O 31.8/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O assuming/VBG/O bank/NN/O ././O
