Strict/JJ/O new/JJ/O regulations/NNS/O seem/VBP/O certain/JJ/O to/TO/O pass/VB/O the/DT/O state/NN/O House/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE next/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O easy/JJ/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O by/IN/O Democratic/NNP/O Gov./NNP/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Casey/NNP/I-PERSON expected/VBN/O shortly/RB/O thereafter/RB/O ././O
Legislation/NN/O to/TO/O require/VB/O the/DT/O consent/NN/O of/IN/O parents/NNS/O before/IN/O their/PRP$/O daughters/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O 18/CD/O can/MD/O have/VB/O abortions/NNS/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O pass/VB/O both/DT/O houses/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Michigan/JJ/B-GPE legislature/NN/O and/CC/O set/VB/O up/IN/O a/DT/O grinding/VBG/O battle/NN/O to/TO/O override/VB/O the/DT/O expected/VBN/O veto/NN/O of/IN/O Democratic/NNP/O Gov./NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Blanchard/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O action/NN/O in/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O follow/VB/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O collapse/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O session/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE legislature/NN/O to/TO/O enact/VB/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O abortions/NNS/O in/IN/O that/DT/O state/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O here/RB/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O permit/VB/O federally/RB/O paid/VBN/O abortions/NNS/O for/IN/O poor/JJ/O women/NNS/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O rape/NN/O or/CC/O incest/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Freind/NNP/B-PERSON legislation/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O House/NNP/B-ORG Judiciary/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG approved/VBD/O it/PRP/O in/IN/O Harrisburg/NN/B-GPE this/DT/O week/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE House/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O up/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O next/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O --/:/O includes/VBZ/O a/DT/O provision/NN/O to/TO/O ban/VB/O abortions/NNS/O after/IN/O 24/CD/O weeks/NNS/O of/IN/O pregnancy/NN/O ,/,/O except/IN/O to/TO/O avert/VB/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mother/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Freind/NNP/B-PERSON calculates/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O provision/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O attacks/VBZ/O the/DT/O trimester/NN/O standards/NNS/O that/IN/O Roe/NNP/O established/VBD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O ``/``/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O necessary/JJ/O ''/''/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O review/VB/O Roe/NNP/O and/CC/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O overturn/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O legislation/NN/O failed/VBD/O by/IN/O one/CD/O vote/NN/O to/TO/O clear/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Rules/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Tuesday/NNP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O anti-abortionists/NNS/O still/RB/O may/MD/O succeed/VB/O in/IN/O bringing/VBG/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O floor/NN/O this/DT/O fall/NN/O ././O
Pamela/NNP/B-PERSON Sutherland/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Illinois/NNP/I-ORG Planned/NNP/I-ORG Parenthood/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O she/PRP/O and/CC/O her/PRP$/O allies/NNS/O are/VBP/O ``/``/O cautiously/RB/O optimistic/JJ/O ''/''/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O defeat/VB/O it/PRP/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O comes/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O floor/NN/O vote/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O anti-abortionists/NNS/O are/VBP/O urging/VBG/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG Gov./NNP/O Bill/NNP/B-PERSON Clements/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O press/VB/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O session/NN/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O run/VB/O Nov./NNP/O 14/CD/O to/TO/O Dec./NNP/O 13/CD/O ././O
This/DT/O legislative/JJ/O activity/NN/O comes/VBZ/O as/IN/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O are/VBP/O undertaking/VBG/O new/JJ/O mobilization/NN/O efforts/NNS/O ,/,/O plunging/VBG/O into/IN/O gubernatorial/JJ/O races/NNS/O in/IN/O Virginia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O girding/VBG/O for/IN/O next/JJ/O autumn/NN/O 's/POS/O state/NN/O elections/NNS/O ././O
These/DT/O include/VBP/O bans/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O abortion/NN/O for/IN/O birth/NN/O control/NN/O and/CC/O sex/NN/O selection/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O public/NN/O funding/NN/O of/IN/O alternatives/NNS/O for/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
