UGI/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O AmeriGas/NNP/B-ORG subsidiary/NN/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O previously/RB/O announced/JJ/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O air/NN/O separation/NN/O plant/NN/O and/CC/O related/JJ/O assets/NNS/O in/IN/O Waukesha/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wis./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O AGA/NNP/B-ORG Gas/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Cleveland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O price/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O transaction/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O UGI/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O continuing/VBG/O program/NN/O to/TO/O shed/VB/O AmeriGas/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O industrial/JJ/O gas/NN/O interests/NNS/O and/CC/O expand/VB/O the/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O 's/POS/O propane/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O June/NNP/O ,/,/O AmeriGas/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O netted/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O from/IN/O industrial/JJ/O gas/NN/O divestitures/NNS/O and/CC/O reinvested/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O three/CD/O propane/NN/O distributors/NNS/O ././O
UGI/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O gas/NN/O and/CC/O electric/JJ/O utility/NN/O and/CC/O distributes/VBZ/O propane/NN/O nationally/RB/O through/IN/O its/PRP$/O AmeriGas/NNP/B-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ././O
