Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG won/VBD/O a/DT/O pretrial/JJ/O order/NN/O blocking/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sales/NNS/O of/IN/O Justin/NNP/B-ORG Products/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG ``/``/O My/PRP$/O Own/JJ/O ''/''/O line/NN/O of/IN/O portable/JJ/O audio/JJ/O players/NNS/O for/IN/O children/NNS/O ././O
Judge/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Sprizzo/NNP/I-PERSON issued/VBD/O the/DT/O order/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE federal/JJ/O court/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O accused/VBN/O the/DT/O tiny/JJ/O company/NN/O of/IN/O illegally/RB/O knocking/VBG/O off/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O My/PRP$/O First/JJ/O Sony/NNP/O ''/''/O line/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O held/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O combination/NN/O of/IN/O colors/NNS/O used/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG products/NNS/O is/VBZ/O distinctive/JJ/O and/CC/O subject/NN/O to/TO/O protection/NN/O under/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE state/NN/O law/NN/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O federal/JJ/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O legal/JJ/O fight/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Wall/NNP/B-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG story/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Justin/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Baxley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O Justin/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O ask/VB/O an/DT/O appeals/NNS/O court/NN/O to/TO/O set/VB/O aside/RB/O the/DT/O order/NN/O temporarily/RB/O ,/,/O pending/VBG/O an/DT/O expedited/VBN/O appeal/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O repeated/VBD/O Justin/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O denial/NN/O of/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O charges/NNS/O ././O
