-LCB-/-LRB-/O During/IN/O its/PRP$/O centennial/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O report/VB/O events/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O century/NN/O that/DT/O stand/NN/O as/IN/O milestones/NNS/O of/IN/O American/JJ/O business/NN/O history/NN/O ././O -RCB-/-RRB-/O
CREATIVE/JJ/O ACCOUNTING/NN/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O by/IN/O conglomerates/NNS/O ,/,/O forced/VBD/O CPAs/NNS/O to/TO/O change/VB/O their/PRP$/O way/NN/O of/IN/O setting/VBG/O standards/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O corporations/NNS/O reporting/VBG/O financial/JJ/O results/NNS/O ,/,/O standards/NNS/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O become/VBN/O all/RB/O too/RB/O flexible/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O Financial/NNP/B-ORG Accounting/NNP/I-ORG Standards/NNPS/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O FASB/NNP/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O was/VBD/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O 1972/CD/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O the/DT/B-ORG Accounting/NNP/I-ORG Principles/NNPS/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Certified/NNP/I-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG Accountants/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
Francis/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Wheat/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Securities/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG member/NN/O ,/,/O headed/VBD/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O studied/VBN/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O proposed/VBD/O the/DT/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O March/NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O 1972/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O climate/NN/O was/VBD/O right/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1960s/NNS/O some/DT/O CPAs/NNS/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O correct/VB/O such/JJ/O abuses/NNS/O as/IN/O clients/NNS/O picking/VBG/O permissive/JJ/O rules/NNS/O that/IN/O hyped/VBD/O earnings/NNS/O and/CC/O stock/NN/O prices/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O in/IN/O November/NNP/O 1970/CD/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O passed/VBN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O act/NN/O to/TO/O overrule/VB/O one/CD/O board/NN/O rule/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Needham/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG commissioner/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O 1972/CD/O had/VBD/O warned/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O might/MD/O face/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O federal/JJ/O agency/NN/O writing/VBG/O accounting/NN/O rules/NNS/O ''/''/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O rejected/VBD/O the/DT/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG idea/NN/O ././O
Keepers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O books/NNS/O ,/,/O dubbed/VBN/O ``/``/O figure/NN/O filberts/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O loathed/VBD/O the/DT/O threat/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O its/PRP$/O initial/JJ/O meeting/NN/O on/IN/O March/NNP/O 28/CD/O ,/,/O 1973/CD/O ././O
On/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 13/CD/O ,/,/O 1973/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O issued/VBD/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O rule/NN/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O required/VBD/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O disclose/VB/O foreign/JJ/O currency/NN/O translations/NNS/O in/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE dollars/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG since/IN/O then/RB/O has/VBZ/O issued/VBN/O 102/CD/O rules/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O some/DT/O still/RB/O rile/VBP/O industry/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O late/RB/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O put/VBN/O off/RP/O a/DT/O rule/NN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O deferred/JJ/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O because/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O continuing/VBG/O controversy/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
