As/IN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lung/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 42/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O succeeds/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O father/NN/O ,/,/O Mervin/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Lung/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 66/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O founded/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O in/IN/O 1959/CD/O ././O
Mervin/NNP/B-PERSON Lung/NNP/I-PERSON remains/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
David/NNP/B-PERSON Lung/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O with/IN/O Patrick/NNP/B-ORG since/IN/O 1970/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O served/VBN/O as/IN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O administration/NN/O and/CC/O purchasing/NN/O since/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
