CHICAGO/NNP/B-GPE -/:/O Options/NNS/O traders/NNS/O were/VBD/O among/IN/O the/DT/O big/JJ/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O plunging/VBG/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O one/CD/O small/JJ/O firm/NN/O that/WDT/O required/VBD/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O bailout/NN/O ././O
Options/NNS/O traders/NNS/O were/VBD/O hurt/VBN/O worse/RBR/O than/IN/O others/NNS/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O highly/RB/O volatile/JJ/O nature/NN/O of/IN/O options/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O often/RB/O rise/VBP/O or/CC/O fall/VBP/O in/IN/O value/NN/O several/JJ/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O price/NN/O change/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O individual/JJ/O stock/NN/O or/CC/O index/NN/O of/IN/O stocks/NNS/O on/IN/O which/WDT/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O based/VBN/O ././O
Thus/RB/O ,/,/O options/NNS/O traders/NNS/O Friday/NNP/O were/VBD/O stuck/VBN/O with/IN/O losses/NNS/O that/WDT/O also/RB/O were/VBD/O several/JJ/O times/NNS/O larger/JJR/O than/IN/O those/DT/O suffered/VBN/O by/IN/O many/JJ/O stock/NN/O traders/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
That/DT/O may/MD/O just/RB/O be/VB/O the/DT/O nature/NN/O of/IN/O these/DT/O highly/RB/O leveraged/JJ/O little/JJ/O creatures/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
An/DT/O options/NNS/O contract/NN/O gives/VBZ/O the/DT/O holder/NN/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O call/VB/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O or/CC/O sell/VB/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O put/VB/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O a/DT/O specific/JJ/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O stock/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O in/IN/O this/DT/O case/NN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O stock/NN/O index/NN/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O predetermined/VBN/O price/NN/O within/IN/O a/DT/O given/VBN/O time/NN/O period/NN/O ././O
Options/NNS/O traders/NNS/O who/WP/O ,/,/O in/IN/O return/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O fee/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O premium/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O previously/RB/O sold/VBN/O put/JJ/O options/NNS/O on/IN/O stocks/NNS/O or/CC/O stock/NN/O indexes/NNS/O were/VBD/O forced/VBN/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O those/DT/O contracts/NNS/O back/RP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O previously/RB/O agreed/VBN/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O were/VBD/O substantially/RB/O above/IN/O those/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O falling/VBG/O ././O
They/PRP/O then/RB/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O choice/NN/O in/IN/O many/JJ/O cases/NNS/O but/CC/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O the/DT/O contracts/NNS/O at/IN/O prevailing/VBG/O prices/NNS/O --/:/O in/IN/O most/JJS/O cases/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O substantial/JJ/O loss/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O latest/JJS/O round/NN/O of/IN/O losses/NNS/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O serious/JJ/O blow/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O never/RB/O fully/RB/O recovered/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O aftershock/NN/O of/IN/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O investors/NNS/O fled/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O huge/JJ/O losses/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O while/IN/O the/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG reopened/VBD/O a/DT/O half/NN/O hour/NN/O later/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG remained/VBD/O closed/JJ/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O many/JJ/O options/NNS/O traders/NNS/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O trades/NNS/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O have/VB/O reduced/VBN/O the/DT/O losses/NNS/O ././O
CBOE/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Alger/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/I-PERSON Duke/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Chapman/NN/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O unlike/IN/O the/DT/O futures/NNS/O market/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O options/NNS/O exchange/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O open/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O rotation/NN/O that/WDT/O allows/VBZ/O each/DT/O different/JJ/O options/NNS/O series/NN/O to/TO/O trade/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O damage/NN/O was/VBD/O so/RB/O bad/JJ/O at/IN/O Fossett/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O options/NNS/O trading/NN/O firm/NN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O transfer/VB/O its/PRP$/O accounts/NNS/O to/TO/O First/NNP/B-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Continental/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O options/NNS/O trading/NN/O losses/NNS/O ././O
Fosset/NNP/B-ORG so/RB/O far/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O member/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O exchange/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O over/RP/O by/IN/O another/DT/O firm/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O rout/NN/O ././O
Fossett/NNP/B-ORG still/RB/O had/VBD/O several/JJ/O million/CD/O dollars/NNS/O in/IN/O capital/NN/O left/VBN/O after/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O close/NN/O of/IN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O not/RB/O enough/RB/O that/IN/O regulators/NNS/O ,/,/O worried/VBN/O about/IN/O another/DT/O potential/JJ/O market/NN/O plunge/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O let/VB/O it/PRP/O reopen/VB/O for/IN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O options/NNS/O exchange/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Thus/RB/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O unprecedented/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O underscoring/VBG/O the/DT/O seriousness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transfer/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG Clearing/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O owner/NN/O ,/,/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Fossett/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O put/VBN/O up/RP/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O guarantee/VB/O the/DT/O customer/NN/O positions/NNS/O being/VBG/O transferred/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O subsidiary/NN/O in/IN/O case/NN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O plunged/VBD/O again/RB/O yesterday/RB/O ././O
S./NNP/B-PERSON Waite/NNP/I-PERSON Rawls/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Continental/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O First/NNP/B-ORG Options/NNP/I-ORG '/POS/I-ORG parent/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O took/VBD/O on/RP/O about/IN/O 160/CD/O accounts/NNS/O formerly/RB/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O Fossett/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O almost/RB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O belonging/VBG/O to/TO/O professional/JJ/O floor/NN/O traders/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O firm/NN/O were/VBD/O still/RB/O worth/JJ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Rawls/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O A/DT/O package/NN/O of/IN/O credit/NN/O support/NN/O was/VBD/O put/VBN/O together/RP/O --/:/O including/VBG/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O firm/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O bailout/NN/O was/VBD/O cobbled/VBN/O together/RP/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O officials/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Securities/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Comptroller/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Currency/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O options/NNS/O exchanges/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O great/JJ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O luxury/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Rawls/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
At/IN/O one/CD/O point/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O options/NNS/O industry/NN/O official/NN/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O talk/VB/O the/DT/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/O night/NN/O watchman/NN/O into/IN/O giving/VBG/O him/PRP/O the/DT/O home/NN/O phone/NN/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Silas/NNP/B-PERSON Keene/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Chicago/NNP/B-ORG Fed/NNP/I-ORG president/NN/O ././O
First/NNP/B-ORG Options/NNP/I-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O put/VB/O any/DT/O money/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O bailout/NN/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O rally/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O ,/,/O futures/NNS/O and/CC/O options/NNS/O markets/NNS/O led/VBD/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O to/TO/O conclude/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O guarantees/NNS/O almost/RB/O certainly/RB/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O need/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O tapped/VBN/O by/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Fossett/NNP/B-PERSON firm/NN/O had/VBD/O some/DT/O losses/NNS/O and/CC/O liquidity/NN/O problems/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O October/NNP/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O as/IN/O well/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Rawls/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O federal/JJ/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Continental/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG worked/VBD/O with/IN/O securities/NNS/O and/CC/O banking/NN/O regulators/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O to/TO/O fashion/VB/O the/DT/O Fossett/NNP/B-ORG bailout/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O conditions/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O dictated/VBN/O by/IN/O those/DT/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O their/PRP$/O business/NN/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O at/IN/O Options/NNPS/B-ORG Clearing/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O processes/VBZ/O all/DT/O options/NNS/O trades/NNS/O for/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE exchanges/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O guarantee/NN/O was/VBD/O unprecedented/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O was/VBD/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O help/VB/O insure/VB/O the/DT/O integrity/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O options/NNS/O markets/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O extraordinary/JJ/O situation/NN/O that/WDT/O needed/VBD/O extraordinary/JJ/O steps/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Stevens/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O OCC/NNP/B-ORG president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O operating/VBG/O officer/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stevens/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O give/VB/O the/DT/O specific/JJ/O contributions/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O guarantee/NN/O from/IN/O each/DT/O participant/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O Options/NNPS/B-ORG Clearing/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG contributed/VBD/O $/$/O 20/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O guarantee/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG put/VBD/O up/RP/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG added/VBD/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 18/CD/O million/CD/O came/VBD/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Fossett/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O own/JJ/O assets/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Fossett/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
