Most/JJS/O have/VBP/O read/VBN/O the/DT/O pre-trial/NN/O documents/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O estimate/VBP/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O ordered/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O for/IN/O infringing/VBG/O on/IN/O seven/CD/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG patents/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O may/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O patent/NN/O award/NN/O ever/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O well/RB/O below/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 12/CD/O billion/CD/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG seeks/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O highest/JJS/O patent/NN/O damage/NN/O award/NN/O to/TO/O date/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Smith/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O ordered/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O $/$/O 205/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O Baker/NNP/B-ORG Hughes/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O infringing/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O patent/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O drilling/NN/O bit/NN/O seal/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O later/RB/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O for/IN/O $/$/O 95/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Few/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O worth/JJ/O their/PRP$/O time/NN/O to/TO/O slog/VB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG trial/NN/O testimony/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O like/IN/O panning/VBG/O for/IN/O gold/JJ/O outside/NN/O of/IN/O Grand/NNP/B-FAC Central/NNP/I-FAC Station/NNP/I-FAC ././O
And/CC/O Eugene/NNP/B-PERSON Glazer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O Dean/NNP/B-ORG Witter/NNP/I-ORG Reynolds/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O If/IN/O you/PRP/O hired/VBD/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O there/RB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O time/NN/O and/CC/O give/VB/O you/PRP/O a/DT/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O prediction/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O of/IN/O the/DT/O eventual/JJ/O award/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O bet/VB/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O off/RP/O ''/''/O by/IN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O main/JJ/O issues/NNS/O remaining/VBG/O are/VBP/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O calculate/VB/O damages/NNS/O and/CC/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O infringement/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O willful/JJ/O and/CC/O deliberate/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
If/IN/O so/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O damages/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O tripled/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O Carr/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O many/JJ/O occasions/NNS/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O various/JJ/O features/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O patent/NN/O positions/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG followed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O advice/NN/O in/IN/O every/DT/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Crary/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
But/CC/O Irving/NNP/B-PERSON Kayton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O patent/NN/O expert/NN/O at/IN/O George/NNP/B-ORG Mason/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Law/NNP/I-ORG who/WP/O is/VBZ/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O seven/CD/O patents/NNS/O were/VBD/O infringed/VBN/O ``/``/O suggests/VBZ/O that/DT/O infringement/NN/O was/VBD/O willful/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O that/IN/O consistently/RB/O wrong/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG claims/VBZ/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O have/VB/O manufactured/VBN/O and/CC/O sold/VBN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O instant/NN/O cameras/NNS/O and/CC/O film/NN/O sold/VBN/O by/IN/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG if/IN/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O n't/RB/O entered/VBN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG contends/VBZ/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O have/VB/O sold/VBN/O them/PRP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O higher/JJR/O price/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O thus/RB/O made/VBD/O higher/JJR/O profits/NNS/O --/:/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O match/VB/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O lower/JJR/O prices/NNS/O ././O
Each/DT/O side/NN/O has/VBZ/O called/VBN/O a/DT/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG professor/NN/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O on/IN/O that/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Kodak/NN/B-ORG hired/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Buzzell/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG brought/VBD/O in/RP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Dolan/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O that/WDT/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O people/NNS/O at/IN/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG school/NN/I-ORG have/VBP/O to/TO/O agree/VB/O with/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Buzzell/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Testimony/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O until/IN/O early/JJ/O December/NNP/O ././O
A/DT/O decision/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O until/IN/O some/DT/O time/NN/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
