Selwyn/NNP/B-PERSON B./NNP/I-PERSON Kossuth/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O named/VBN/O executive/NN/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O ,/,/O effective/JJ/O early/JJ/O November/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kossuth/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 52/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O succeeds/VBZ/O Ermanno/NNP/B-PERSON Pascutto/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 36/CD/O ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O to/TO/O join/VB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE Securities/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kossuth/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O director/NN/O ,/,/O corporate/JJ/O finance/NN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O Nesbitt/NNP/B-ORG Thomson/NNP/I-ORG Deacon/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Toronto/NNP/B-GPE investment/NN/O dealer/NN/O ././O
