An/DT/O ebullient/JJ/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON Iverson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Nucor/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O plant/NN/O eventually/RB/O will/MD/O make/VB/O a/DT/O ton/NN/O of/IN/O steel/NN/O in/IN/O 1.5/CD/O man/NN/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O four/CD/O to/TO/O six/CD/O man/NN/O hours/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O conventional/JJ/O mill/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O that/RB/O major/JJ/O steelmakers/NNS/O have/VBP/O blithely/RB/O ignored/VBN/O high/JJ/O technology/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O beat/VB/O everyone/NN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O steelmakers/NNS/O more/RBR/O involved/JJ/O in/IN/O computers/NNS/O and/CC/O artificial/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O :/:/O They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O saddled/VBN/O with/IN/O huge/JJ/O plants/NNS/O that/WDT/O require/VBP/O costly/JJ/O maintenance/NN/O ././O
Armco/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O representatives/NNS/O visit/VBP/O the/DT/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Fairfax/NN/B-LOC assembly/NN/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mo./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O two/CD/O or/CC/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
Battelle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O McCall/NNP/B-PERSON thinks/VBZ/O steelmakers/NNS/O should/MD/O concentrate/VB/O more/RBR/O on/IN/O construction/NN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O steelmakers/NNS/O envision/VBP/O steel/NN/O roofs/NNS/O covering/VBG/O suburbia/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O steelmaker/NN/O reactivated/VBD/O its/PRP$/O overseas/JJ/O sales/NNS/O operation/NN/O ././O
Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Crandall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Brookings/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O agrees/VBZ/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O and/CC/O European/JJ/O steelmakers/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O led/VBN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O technology/NN/O developments/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O anxiously/RB/O awaiting/VBG/O the/DT/O lifting/NN/O of/IN/O trade/NN/O restraints/NNS/O in/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
