No/DT/O strikeout/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O certainly/RB/O no/DT/O home/NN/O run/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O quite/RB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O money/NN/O managers/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O buying/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
Weakening/VBG/O corporate/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O prescription/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O bull/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ai/VBP/O n't/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O do/VB/O much/RB/O of/IN/O anything/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O a/DT/O while/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Neff/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Wellington/NNP/B-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O runs/VBZ/O the/DT/O $/$/O 8.3/CD/O billion/CD/O Windsor/NNP/B-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O suspects/VBZ/O that/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O market/NN/O decline/NN/O may/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O leg/NN/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O later/RB/O on/RB/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O grossly/RB/O overvalued/VBN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O cheap/JJ/O either/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Collins/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mutual/JJ/O fund/NN/O company/NN/O T./NNP/B-ORG Rowe/NNP/I-ORG Price/NNP/I-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Baltimore/NNP/B-GPE ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O Institutional/NNP/B-ORG Brokers/NNPS/I-ORG Estimate/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O market/NN/O strategists/NNS/O see/VBP/O only/RB/O a/DT/O 2.4/CD/O %/NN/O jump/NN/O in/IN/O company/NN/O profits/NNS/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O --/:/O unlike/IN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O profits/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O out/RB/O looked/VBN/O good/JJ/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O soar/VB/O 36/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Our/PRP$/O view/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O may/MD/O see/VB/O a/DT/O profit/NN/O decline/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O think/VBP/O investors/NNS/O should/MD/O sell/VB/O into/IN/O rallies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O wind/VB/O down/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Gerald/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Perritt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE money/NN/O manager/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Things/NNS/O are/VBP/O a/DT/O little/RB/O less/RBR/O overpriced/JJ/O ''/''/O after/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O jolt/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O stocks/NNS/O to/TO/O decline/VB/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG perhaps/RB/O bottoming/VBG/O out/RP/O between/IN/O 2000/CD/O and/CC/O 2100/CD/O ``/``/O between/IN/O now/RB/O and/CC/O June/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O found/VBD/O 85/CD/O still/RB/O overvalued/VBN/O and/CC/O 15/CD/O fairly/RB/O valued/VBN/O ././O
Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Parks/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE money/NN/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O expects/VBZ/O the/DT/O market/NN/O to/TO/O decline/VB/O about/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Generalizations/NNS/O about/IN/O value/NN/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O useful/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE money/NN/O manager/NN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON LeFrere/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Delta/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Money/NN/O manager/NN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Ross/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O Duncan/NNP/B-ORG Ross/NNP/I-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Vancouver/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O stocks/NNS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O before/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O competitive/JJ/O with/IN/O less/RBR/O risky/JJ/O investment/NN/O alternatives/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O bulls/NNS/O out/IN/O there/RB/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O still/RB/O think/VBP/O we/PRP/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O 3000/CD/O Dow/NNP/O ,/,/O whether/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O six/CD/O months/NNS/O or/CC/O 12/CD/O months/NNS/O from/IN/O now/RB/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Dreman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O managing/NN/O partner/NN/O of/IN/O Dreman/NNP/B-ORG Value/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O doing/VBG/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O buying/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O some/DT/O stocks/NNS/O ``/``/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O really/RB/O been/VBN/O smashed/VBN/O down/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Many/JJ/O brokerage/NN/O house/NN/O officials/NNS/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O optimistic/JJ/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Dean/NNP/B-ORG Witter/NNP/I-ORG all/DT/O increased/VBD/O the/DT/O proportion/NN/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O they/PRP/O recommend/VBP/O investors/NNS/O commit/VBP/O to/TO/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
Dean/NNP/B-ORG Witter/NNP/I-ORG now/RB/O recommends/VBZ/O 85/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG 65/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG 50/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O healthy/JJ/O cleansing/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Holland/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O runs/VBZ/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Asset/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O fundamentals/NNS/O are/VBP/O pretty/RB/O strong/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Dreman/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O see/VB/O this/DT/O as/IN/O a/DT/O bear/NN/O market/NN/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O recognition/NN/O that/IN/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O much/RB/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O fluff/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O LBO/NNP/O market/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O big/JJ/O fall/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O just/RB/O a/DT/O blunder/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Connolly/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O strategist/NN/O for/IN/O Dean/NNP/B-ORG Witter/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O overreaction/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O event/NN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O failure/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O management/NN/O and/CC/O union/NN/O group/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O bank/NN/O financing/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O takeover/NN/O of/IN/O UAL/NNP/B-ORG -RCB-/-RRB-/O that/WDT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O that/IN/O much/JJ/O to/TO/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O stocks/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Many/JJ/O investors/NNS/O have/VBP/O nagging/JJ/O worries/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Newspapers/NNS/O are/VBP/O full/JJ/O of/IN/O headlines/NNS/O about/IN/O companies/NNS/O defaulting/VBG/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O debts/NNS/O and/CC/O banks/NNS/O writing/VBG/O off/RP/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O loans/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O hurts/VBZ/O investors/NNS/O '/POS/O confidence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O and/CC/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
Not/RB/O even/RB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O see/VBP/O clear/JJ/O sailing/NN/O ahead/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Disappointing/JJ/O profits/NNS/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O worse/RBR/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O two/CD/O quarters/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Farrell/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O market/NN/O strategist/NN/O at/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG ././O
She/PRP/O thinks/VBZ/O the/DT/O market/NN/O could/MD/O drop/VB/O about/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O recover/VBP/O and/CC/O go/VBP/O higher/JJR/O ././O
Companies/NNS/O with/IN/O steady/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O growth/NN/O could/MD/O do/VB/O well/RB/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O while/IN/O others/NNS/O with/IN/O high/JJ/O debt/NN/O or/CC/O poor/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O could/MD/O see/VB/O their/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O decline/VBP/O far/RB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
