Amcore/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Central/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Illinois/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O stock/NN/O swap/NN/O ././O
Shareholders/NNS/O of/IN/O Central/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Sterling/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ill./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O will/MD/O receive/VB/O Amcore/NNP/B-ORG stock/NN/O equal/JJ/O to/TO/O 10/CD/O times/NNS/O Central/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O 1989/CD/O earnings/NNS/O ,/,/O Amcore/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Amcore/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O also/RB/O a/DT/O bank/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.06/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Central/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O assets/NNS/O are/VBP/O $/$/O 240/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
