No/DT/O trading/VBG/O existed/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O vast/JJ/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O junk/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O securities/NNS/O industry/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Bonds/NNS/O issued/VBN/O by/IN/O Kroger/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Duracell/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Safeway/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O American/NNP/B-ORG Standard/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O showed/VBD/O big/JJ/O gains/NNS/O ,/,/O recovering/VBG/O almost/RB/O all/DT/O their/PRP$/O losses/NNS/O from/IN/O Friday/NNP/O and/CC/O early/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ``/``/O bounced/VBD/O off/IN/O the/DT/O floor/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Minella/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O benchmark/JJ/O junk/NN/O issues/NNS/O ``/``/O recovered/VBD/O all/DT/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O losses/NNS/O ''/''/O from/IN/O Friday/NNP/O and/CC/O early/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Traders/NNS/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O rally/NN/O was/VBD/O fueled/VBN/O by/IN/O insurance/NN/O companies/NNS/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O bargains/NNS/O after/IN/O a/DT/O drastic/JJ/O slide/NN/O in/IN/O prices/NNS/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O good/JJ/O shape/NN/O ././O
