Stanislav/NNP/B-PERSON Ovcharenko/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O airline/NN/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG here/RB/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O some/DT/O visions/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O wild/JJ/O even/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O standards/NNS/O of/IN/O perestroika/FW/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O all/DT/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Aer/NNP/B-ORG Rianta/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Irish/JJ/O airport/NN/O authority/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O build/VB/O a/DT/O cargo/NN/O terminal/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Aer/NNP/B-ORG Lingus/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O discussions/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O carrier/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O cargo/NN/O venture/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O possibilities/NNS/O ././O
Aer/NNP/B-ORG Rianta/NNP/I-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O so/RB/O many/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O with/IN/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG that/IN/O its/PRP$/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O is/VBZ/O studying/VBG/O Russian/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O groups/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O together/RB/O since/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1970s/NNS/O ,/,/O long/RB/O before/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O joint/NN/O ventures/NNS/O were/VBD/O the/DT/O rage/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O ././O
Aeroflot/NNP/O carried/VBD/O about/IN/O 125/CD/O million/CD/O passengers/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O transit/NN/O airport/NN/O outside/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O saw/VBD/O 1,400/CD/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG flights/NNS/O and/CC/O 250,000/CD/O passengers/NNS/O pass/VB/O through/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O airport/NN/O 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O supplier/NN/O of/IN/O aircraft/NN/O fuel/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Tankers/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Latvian/JJ/O port/NN/O of/IN/O Ventspils/NNP/B-GPE each/DT/O year/NN/O unload/VBP/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O gallons/NNS/O of/IN/O fuel/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O tank/NN/O farm/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O airport/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O all/DT/O ././O
Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O international/JJ/O fleet/NN/O of/IN/O 285/CD/O planes/NNS/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O repainted/VBN/O and/CC/O refurbished/VBN/O at/IN/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC ././O
Jamaica/NNP/B-GPE costs/VBZ/O 504/CD/O punts/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O formal/JJ/O blessing/NN/O of/IN/O sorts/NNS/O was/VBD/O bestowed/VBN/O on/IN/O this/DT/O friendship/NN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O when/WRB/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Raisa/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON stopped/VBD/O here/RB/O for/IN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Irish/JJ/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Haughey/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
New/JJ/O trade/NN/O accords/NNS/O were/VBD/O signed/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O all/DT/O started/VBN/O with/IN/O geography/NN/O ././O
Advances/NNS/O in/IN/O aircraft/NN/O fuel/NN/O efficiency/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC stop/NN/O unnecessary/JJ/O for/IN/O most/JJS/O Western/JJ/O air/NN/O fleets/VBZ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG still/RB/O flies/VBZ/O inefficient/JJ/O Ilyushins/NNPS/O that/WDT/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O Managua/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O one/CD/O hop/NN/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O Aer/NNP/B-ORG Rianta/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O a/DT/O heap/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O Soviet/NNP/O friendship/NN/O ././O
