But/CC/O the/DT/O junk/NN/O recovery/NN/O ,/,/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O bellwether/NN/O RJR/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O precarious/JJ/O ././O
No/DT/O trading/VBG/O existed/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O vast/JJ/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O junk/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O securities/NNS/O industry/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
On/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O trading/NN/O in/IN/O practically/RB/O every/DT/O issue/NN/O ground/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O halt/NN/O as/IN/O potential/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O fled/VBD/O and/CC/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O were/VBD/O unwilling/JJ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O bid/NN/O and/CC/O offer/NN/O prices/NNS/O for/IN/O most/JJS/O issues/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O fairly/RB/O active/JJ/O day/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
At/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG Burnham/NNP/I-ORG Lambert/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O underwriter/NN/O of/IN/O junk/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O prepared/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O very/RB/O bad/JJ/O mood/NN/O tonight/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Feinman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O junk/NN/O bond/NN/O trader/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Now/RB/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O feel/VBP/O maybe/RB/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O bit/NN/O of/IN/O euphoria/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Bonds/NNS/O issued/VBN/O by/IN/O Kroger/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Duracell/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Safeway/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O American/NNP/B-ORG Standard/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O showed/VBD/O big/JJ/O gains/NNS/O ,/,/O recovering/VBG/O almost/RB/O all/DT/O their/PRP$/O losses/NNS/O from/IN/O Friday/NNP/O and/CC/O early/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Liquidity/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O vast/JJ/O middle/JJ/O ground/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Minella/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O deadbeats/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O deadbeats/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Feinman/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O whole/JJ/O bunch/NN/O of/IN/O stuff/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O money/NN/O good/JJ/O and/CC/O a/DT/O whole/JJ/O bunch/NN/O of/IN/O stuff/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O so/RB/O good/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Almost/RB/O $/$/O 8/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O junk/NN/O bonds/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O considered/VBN/O untradeable/JJ/O include/VBP/O issues/NNS/O from/IN/O SCI/NNP/B-ORG TV/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Gillette/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O not/RB/O related/JJ/O to/TO/O Gillette/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O Interco/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Seaman/NNP/B-ORG Furniture/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Allied/NNP/B-ORG Stores/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Federated/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG Stores/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O National/NNP/B-ORG Gypsum/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O M.D.C./NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Micropolis/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Leaseway/NNP/B-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Price/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O You/PRP/O could/MD/O still/RB/O have/VB/O some/DT/O very/RB/O bad/JJ/O times/NNS/O ahead/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bachmann/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O possible/JJ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O default/NN/O rate/NN/O in/IN/O one/CD/O year/NN/O ,/,/O because/IN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O already/RB/O seeing/VBG/O big/JJ/O problems/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O midst/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O pretty/RB/O strong/JJ/O economy/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O certainly/RB/O not/RB/O comfortable/JJ/O saying/VBG/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O seen/VBN/O the/DT/O bottom/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O rally/NN/O among/IN/O ``/``/O good/JJ/O ''/''/O junk/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O badly/RB/O needed/JJ/O tonic/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O issues/NNS/O ``/``/O bounced/VBD/O off/IN/O the/DT/O floor/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Minella/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O benchmark/JJ/O junk/NN/O issues/NNS/O ``/``/O recovered/VBD/O all/DT/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O losses/NNS/O ''/''/O from/IN/O Friday/NNP/O and/CC/O early/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O contrast/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O The/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O gained/VBD/O back/RP/O only/RB/O about/IN/O half/NN/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O lost/VBN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O government/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O bond/NN/O market/NN/O lost/VBN/O about/IN/O half/NN/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O gained/VBN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
Traders/NNS/O said/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O rally/NN/O was/VBD/O fueled/VBN/O by/IN/O insurance/NN/O companies/NNS/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O bargains/NNS/O after/IN/O a/DT/O drastic/JJ/O slide/NN/O in/IN/O prices/NNS/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O month/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Sometimes/RB/O a/DT/O shakeout/NN/O is/VBZ/O healthy/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Drexel/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Feinman/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O will/MD/O learn/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O more/RBR/O circumspect/JJ/O ././O
If/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O good/JJ/O credit/NN/O analysis/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O avoid/VB/O the/DT/O hand/NN/O grenades/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O market/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O good/JJ/O shape/NN/O ././O
