The/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O haunted/JJ/O house/NN/O ././O
Living/VBG/O there/RB/O for/IN/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O was/VBD/O really/RB/O scary/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O ghosts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O are/VBP/O everywhere/RB/O :/:/O They/PRP/O are/VBP/O kept/VBN/O at/IN/O bay/NN/O only/RB/O by/IN/O feeding/VBG/O them/PRP/O vast/JJ/O quantities/NNS/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O defense/NN/O budget/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O can/MD/O be/VB/O bought/VBN/O off/RP/O relatively/RB/O cheaply/RB/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O Korean/NNP/O War/NNP/O ,/,/O Gen./NNP/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON MacArthur/NNP/I-PERSON demanded/VBD/O and/CC/O got/VBD/O ,/,/O in/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O U.N./NNP/B-ORG command/NN/O in/IN/O Korea/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O naval/JJ/O command/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O NavforJapan/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Those/DT/O obsolete/JJ/O operations/NNS/O cost/VBP/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O keep/VBP/O Mac/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O quiet/JJ/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O about/IN/O all/DT/O it/PRP/O costs/VBZ/O to/TO/O appease/VB/O Adm./NNP/O Erich/NNP/B-PERSON Raeder/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1941/CD/O ,/,/O Raeder/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O German/JJ/O navy/NN/O threatened/VBD/O to/TO/O attack/VB/O the/DT/B-FAC Panama/NNP/I-FAC Canal/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O so/RB/O we/PRP/O created/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG Command/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG Command/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O grown/VBN/O even/RB/O bigger/RBR/O since/IN/O the/DT/O war/NN/O because/IN/O Raeder/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O sometimes/RB/O runs/VBZ/O through/IN/O the/DT/O E/NN/O ring/NN/O dressed/VBN/O like/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O Command/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O huge/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O is/VBZ/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O analyze/VB/O whether/IN/O leaders/NNS/O of/IN/O coups/NNS/O against/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON meet/VBP/O the/DT/O War/NNP/O Powers/NNP/O Act/NNP/O 's/POS/O six/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON Weinberger/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON seven/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 32/CD/O points/NNS/O and/CC/O Woodrow/NNP/B-PERSON Wilson/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON 14/CD/O points/NNS/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O justify/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE support/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O far/RB/O no/DT/O one/NN/O has/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O ghost/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O brigade/NN/O discovered/VBD/O in/IN/O Cuba/NNP/B-GPE back/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O '70s/NNS/O costs/VBZ/O just/RB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O hundred/CD/O million/CD/O :/:/O the/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Caribbean/NNP/I-ORG Command/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Key/NNP/B-LOC West/NNP/I-LOC that/IN/O President/NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON created/VBD/O in/IN/O 1980/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O brigade/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O heard/VBN/O from/IN/O since/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O keep/VBP/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O around/RB/O just/RB/O in/IN/O case/NN/O ././O
George/NNP/B-PERSON Marshall/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ghost/NN/O is/VBZ/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O happy/JJ/O ././O
We/PRP/O keep/VBP/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O shrines/NNS/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O around/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O statues/NNS/O ,/,/O busts/NNS/O ,/,/O relics/NNS/O and/CC/O such/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG headquarters/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O deck/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG used/VBD/O to/TO/O burn/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O incense/NN/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG headquarters/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O deck/NN/O made/VBD/O them/PRP/O stop/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
You/PRP/O see/VBP/O ,/,/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O this/DT/O thing/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Marines/NNPS/B-ORG --/:/O he/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O them/PRP/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG but/CC/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG James/NNP/B-PERSON Forrestal/NNP/I-PERSON blocked/VBD/O him/PRP/O ././O
Now/RB/O his/PRP$/O ghost/NN/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O let/VB/O up/RP/O till/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O done/VBN/O ././O
To/TO/O keep/VB/O him/PRP/O quiet/VB/O we/PRP/O invent/VBP/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O unified/JJ/O command/NN/O every/DT/O year/NN/O or/CC/O so/RB/O run/VB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O put/VBD/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Marines/NNPS/B-ORG under/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O we/PRP/O still/RB/O hear/VBP/O him/PRP/O moaning/VBG/O at/IN/O night/NN/O because/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O ships/NNS/O left/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O satisfy/VB/O him/PRP/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sea/NN/O lift/NN/O forces/NNS/O were/VBD/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O Air/NNP/B-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG bureaucracy/NN/O in/IN/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O its/PRP$/O space/NN/O operations/NNS/O to/TO/O another/DT/O command/NN/O in/IN/O Colorado/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O frogmen/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O Army/NNP/B-ORG bureaucracy/NN/O in/IN/O Fort/NNP/B-GPE Bragg/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Indian/NNP/B-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O Persian/NNP/B-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC forces/NNS/O to/TO/O an/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG bureaucracy/NN/O in/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Which/WDT/O brings/VBZ/O up/RP/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O and/CC/O meanest/JJS/O ghost/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O --/:/O the/DT/O ghost/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O of/IN/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE ././O
When/WRB/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O died/VBD/O ,/,/O President/NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O so/RB/O scared/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O would/MD/O blame/VB/O him/PRP/O for/IN/O shoving/VBG/O him/PRP/O out/RP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O way/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O ayatollah/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O declared/VBD/O the/DT/O Carter/NNP/O Doctrine/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O war/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O anyone/NN/O from/IN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O grab/VB/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O ghost/NN/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O settle/VB/O for/IN/O words/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O money/NN/O and/CC/O people/NNS/O --/:/O lots/NNS/O ././O
So/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON formed/VBD/O three/CD/O new/JJ/O Army/NNP/B-ORG divisions/NNS/O and/CC/O gave/VBD/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O in/IN/O Tampa/NNP/B-GPE called/VBN/O the/DT/B-ORG Rapid/NNP/I-ORG Deployment/NNP/I-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O ghost/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O fooled/VBN/O ;/:/O he/PRP/O knew/VBD/O the/DT/O RDF/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O neither/CC/O rapid/JJ/O nor/CC/O deployable/JJ/O nor/CC/O a/DT/O force/NN/O --/:/O even/RB/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O cost/VBD/O $/$/O 8/CD/O billion/CD/O or/CC/O $/$/O 10/CD/O billion/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O defeated/VBN/O in/IN/O 1980/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O claimed/VBD/O the/DT/O credit/NN/O and/CC/O then/RB/O went/VBD/O after/IN/O President/NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON Weinberger/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
I/PRP/O saw/VBD/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O to/TO/O them/PRP/O firsthand/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O made/VBD/O my/PRP$/O shoelaces/NNS/O dance/VB/O with/IN/O terror/NN/O ././O
Why/WRB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O lay/VB/O in/IN/O wait/NN/O for/IN/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON ;/:/O suddenly/RB/O he/PRP/O 'd/MD/O leap/VB/O from/IN/O behind/IN/O some/DT/O statue/NN/O of/IN/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON onto/IN/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O chest/NN/O and/CC/O grab/VB/O him/PRP/O by/IN/O the/DT/O throat/NN/O and/CC/O choke/VB/O him/PRP/O till/IN/O he/PRP/O coughed/VBD/O up/RP/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O or/CC/O so/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O bought/VBD/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O prepositioning/JJ/O ships/NNS/O and/CC/O $/$/O 7/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O ammo/NN/O and/CC/O equipment/NN/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O parked/VBD/O them/PRP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O $/$/O 6/CD/O billion/CD/O base/NN/O at/IN/O Diego/NNP/B-LOC Garcia/NNP/I-LOC in/IN/O the/DT/O middle/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Indian/NNP/I-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC ././O
He/PRP/O dedicated/VBD/O all/PDT/O these/DT/O new/JJ/O forces/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-LOC Persian/NNP/I-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC ././O
One/CD/O night/NN/O both/DT/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O together/RB/O caught/VBN/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O threw/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O ground/NN/O ././O
Before/IN/O they/PRP/O let/VB/O him/PRP/O go/VB/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O a/DT/O thousand/CD/O bureaucrats/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O RDF/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Tampa/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O renamed/VBD/O it/PRP/O Central/NNP/B-ORG Command/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O gave/VBD/O those/DT/O bureaucrats/NNS/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O naval/JJ/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Persian/NNP/B-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O Indian/NNP/B-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON figured/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O good/JJ/O training/NN/O for/IN/O those/DT/O soldiers/NNS/O --/:/O someday/RB/O maybe/RB/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O get/VB/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
They/PRP/O had/VBD/O fun/NN/O moving/VBG/O the/DT/O carriers/NNS/O around/RP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O forgotten/VBN/O all/DT/O about/IN/O mine/JJ/O sweepers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O still/RB/O kept/VBD/O leaping/VBG/O out/RP/O at/IN/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O so/RB/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON bought/VBD/O a/DT/O hundred/CD/O merchant/NN/O ships/NNS/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O $/$/O 7/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O loading/NN/O barges/NNS/O ,/,/O ramps/NNS/O ,/,/O etc./FW/O ,/,/O in/IN/O order/NN/O that/IN/O those/DT/O seven/CD/O new/JJ/O Army/NNP/B-ORG divisions/NNS/O and/CC/O three/CD/O Marine/NNP/B-ORG brigades/NNS/O could/MD/O unload/VB/O from/IN/O all/PDT/O those/DT/O new/JJ/O ships/NNS/O and/CC/O aircraft/NN/O and/CC/O go/VB/O to/TO/O war/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Zagros/NNP/I-LOC mountains/NNS/I-LOC ././O
Then/RB/O suddenly/RB/O Ike/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O visit/VB/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O What/WP/O the/DT/O hell/NN/O are/VBP/O you/PRP/O doing/VBG/O planning/VBG/O for/IN/O a/DT/O land/NN/O war/NN/O in/IN/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC 12,000/CD/O miles/NNS/O away/RB/O ?/./O
We/PRP/O 'd/MD/O get/VB/O our/PRP$/O asses/NNS/O kicked/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Lucky/JJ/O for/IN/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Ike/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O easygoing/JJ/O and/CC/O soon/RB/O went/VBD/O away/RB/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O --/:/O he/PRP/O kept/VBD/O coming/VBG/O back/RB/O ././O
So/RB/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE found/VBD/O itself/PRP/O paying/VBG/O about/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O baksheesh/NN/O to/TO/O various/JJ/O Arab/JJ/O potentates/NNS/O for/IN/O basing/VBG/O rights/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Indian/NNP/I-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC ././O
We/PRP/O had/VBD/O great/JJ/O success/NN/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O then/RB/O it/PRP/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O that/IN/O President/NNP/O Siad/NNP/B-PERSON Barrah/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O not/RB/O at/IN/O all/DT/O a/DT/O nice/JJ/O person/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG pointed/VBD/O out/RP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O base/NN/O he/PRP/O promised/VBD/O us/PRP/O in/IN/O Berbera/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O silted/VBN/O up/RP/O about/IN/O a/DT/O hundred/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O and/CC/O anyway/RB/O was/VBD/O 1,244/CD/O miles/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O mouth/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Gulf/NNP/B-LOC ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O But/CC/O who/WP/O 's/VBZ/O counting/VBG/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Berbera/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O we/PRP/O could/MD/O get/VB/O ,/,/O so/RB/O we/PRP/O stay/VBP/O in/IN/O bed/NN/O with/IN/O President/NNP/O Barrah/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
All/PDT/O these/DT/O reports/NNS/O about/IN/O him/PRP/O committing/VBG/O genocide/NN/O are/VBP/O probably/RB/O exaggerated/JJ/O anyway/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O you/PRP/O know/VB/O ,/,/O now/RB/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O spending/VBG/O jillions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O have/VBP/O built/VBN/O those/DT/O new/JJ/O divisions/NNS/O and/CC/O new/JJ/O air/NN/O wings/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O have/VBP/O positioned/VBN/O all/PDT/O these/DT/O ships/NNS/O and/CC/O supplies/NNS/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O the/DT/O Russians/NNPS/O in/IN/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O Russians/NNPS/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O lost/VBN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O subject/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O cutting/VBG/O huge/JJ/O chunks/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O defense/NN/O budget/NN/O ././O
Could/MD/O n't/RB/O we/PRP/O save/VB/O $/$/O 20/CD/O billion/CD/O or/CC/O $/$/O 30/CD/O billion/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O by/IN/O shifting/VBG/O that/DT/O stuff/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O reserves/NNS/O ?/./O
And/CC/O why/WRB/O not/RB/O save/VB/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O thousand/CD/O bureaucrats/NNS/O by/IN/O abolishing/VBG/O Central/NNP/B-ORG Command/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O putting/VBG/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O Gulf/NNP/B-LOC naval/JJ/O operations/NNS/O back/RB/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O belongs/VBZ/O ,/,/O afloat/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O task/NN/O force/NN/O commander/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Gulf/NNP/B-LOC ?/./O
And/CC/O where/WRB/O were/VBD/O all/RB/O our/PRP$/O handsomely/RB/O paid/VBN/O Indian/NNP/B-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC allies/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O when/WRB/O our/PRP$/O convoys/NNS/O were/VBD/O being/VBG/O attacked/VBN/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Questions/NNS/O like/JJ/O that/DT/O really/RB/O stir/VBP/O up/RP/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O appeared/VBD/O late/JJ/O one/CD/O night/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bedroom/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O defense/NN/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O Dick/NNP/B-PERSON Cheney/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON came/VBD/O clanking/VBG/O in/RP/O like/JJ/O Marley/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O dragging/VBG/O those/DT/O chains/NNS/O of/IN/O brigades/NNS/O and/CC/O air/NN/O wings/NNS/O and/CC/O links/NNS/O with/IN/O Arab/JJ/O despots/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O leave/VB/O until/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Cheney/NNP/B-PERSON promised/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O whatever/WDT/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG systems/NNS/O analysts/NNS/O told/VBD/O him/PRP/O ././O
On/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O hand/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Cheney/NNP/B-PERSON retained/VBD/O all/PDT/O those/DT/O new/JJ/O land/NN/O forces/NNS/O ././O
Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O is/VBZ/O satisfied/JJ/O for/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O back/RB/O ././O
What/WP/O with/IN/O Halloween/NNP/O coming/VBG/O and/CC/O bigger/JJR/O defense/NN/O cuts/NNS/O looming/VBG/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG bureaucrats/NNS/O are/VBP/O crawling/VBG/O under/IN/O their/PRP$/O desks/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O know/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O hold/VB/O off/RP/O the/DT/O ghosts/NNS/O only/RB/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O while/NN/O longer/RB/O by/IN/O cutting/VBG/O carriers/NNS/O and/CC/O ships/NNS/O ././O
Then/RB/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O thing/NN/O will/MD/O start/VB/O to/TO/O collapse/VB/O ,/,/O just/RB/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 1970s/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O ghosts/NNS/O and/CC/O banshees/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O howling/VBG/O through/IN/O the/DT/O place/NN/O turning/VBG/O people/NNS/O 's/POS/O hair/NN/O white/JJ/O ././O
Gives/VBZ/O me/PRP/O the/DT/O willies/NNS/O just/RB/O thinking/VBG/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lehman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON Navy/NNP/B-ORG secretary/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O managing/NN/O director/NN/O of/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG ././O
