The/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O haunted/JJ/O house/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ghosts/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O are/VBP/O everywhere/RB/O :/:/O They/PRP/O are/VBP/O kept/VBN/O at/IN/O bay/NN/O only/RB/O by/IN/O feeding/VBG/O them/PRP/O vast/JJ/O quantities/NNS/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O defense/NN/O budget/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O can/MD/O be/VB/O bought/VBN/O off/RB/O relatively/RB/O cheaply/RB/O ././O
Those/DT/O obsolete/JJ/O operations/NNS/O cost/VBP/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O keep/VBP/O Mac/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O quiet/JJ/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O about/IN/O all/DT/O it/PRP/O costs/VBZ/O to/TO/O appease/VB/O Adm./NNP/O Erich/NNP/B-PERSON Raeder/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Southern/NNP/I-ORG Command/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O grown/VBN/O even/RB/O bigger/RBR/O since/IN/O the/DT/O war/NN/O because/IN/O Raeder/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O sometimes/RB/O runs/VBZ/O through/IN/O the/DT/O E/NN/O ring/NN/O dressed/VBN/O like/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O Command/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O huge/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O is/VBZ/O needed/VBN/O to/TO/O analyze/VB/O whether/IN/O leaders/NNS/O of/IN/O coups/NNS/O against/IN/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON meet/VBP/O the/DT/O War/NNP/O Powers/NNP/O Act/NNP/O 's/POS/O six/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON Weinberger/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON seven/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 32/CD/O points/NNS/O and/CC/O Woodrow/NNP/B-PERSON Wilson/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON 14/CD/O points/NNS/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O justify/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE support/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ghost/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O brigade/NN/O discovered/VBD/O in/IN/O Cuba/NNP/B-GPE back/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O '70s/NNS/O costs/VBZ/O just/RB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O hundred/CD/O million/CD/O :/:/O the/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Caribbean/NNP/I-ORG Command/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Key/NNP/B-LOC West/NNP/I-LOC that/IN/O President/NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON created/VBD/O in/IN/O 1980/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O brigade/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O heard/VBN/O from/IN/O since/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O keep/VBP/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O around/RB/O just/RB/O in/IN/O case/NN/O ././O
George/NNP/B-PERSON Marshall/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ghost/NN/O is/VBZ/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O happy/JJ/O ././O
We/PRP/O keep/VBP/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O shrines/NNS/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O around/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O statues/NNS/O ,/,/O busts/NNS/O ,/,/O relics/NNS/O and/CC/O such/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG headquarters/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O deck/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG used/VBD/O to/TO/O burn/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O incense/NN/O to/TO/O him/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG headquarters/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O deck/NN/O made/VBD/O them/PRP/O stop/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
You/PRP/O see/VBP/O ,/,/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O this/DT/O thing/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Marines/NNPS/B-ORG --/:/O he/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O make/VB/O them/PRP/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Army/NNP/B-ORG but/CC/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG James/NNP/B-PERSON Forrestal/NNP/I-PERSON blocked/VBD/O him/PRP/O ././O
Which/WDT/O brings/VBZ/O up/RB/O the/DT/O worst/JJS/O and/CC/O meanest/JJS/O ghost/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O --/:/O the/DT/O ghost/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O of/IN/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O go/VB/O to/TO/O war/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O anyone/NN/O from/IN/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O grab/VB/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE ././O
I/PRP/O saw/VBD/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O to/TO/O them/PRP/O firsthand/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O made/VBD/O my/PRP$/O shoelaces/NNS/O dance/VB/O with/IN/O terror/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O bought/VBD/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O prepositioning/JJ/O ships/NNS/O and/CC/O $/$/O 7/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O ammo/NN/O and/CC/O equipment/NN/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O parked/VBD/O them/PRP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O $/$/O 6/CD/O billion/CD/O base/NN/O at/IN/O Diego/NNP/B-LOC Garcia/NNP/I-LOC in/IN/O the/DT/O middle/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Indian/NNP/I-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC ././O
He/PRP/O dedicated/VBD/O all/PDT/O these/DT/O new/JJ/O forces/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-LOC Persian/NNP/I-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC ././O
One/CD/O night/NN/O both/DT/O Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O together/RB/O caught/VBN/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O threw/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O ground/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O gave/VBD/O those/DT/O bureaucrats/NNS/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O all/DT/O naval/JJ/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Persian/NNP/B-LOC Gulf/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O Indian/NNP/B-LOC Ocean/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON figured/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O good/JJ/O training/NN/O for/IN/O those/DT/O soldiers/NNS/O --/:/O someday/RB/O maybe/RB/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O get/VB/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG ././O
They/PRP/O had/VBD/O fun/NN/O moving/VBG/O the/DT/O carriers/NNS/O around/RP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O turned/VBD/O out/RB/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O forgotten/VBN/O all/DT/O about/IN/O mine/JJ/O sweepers/NNS/O ././O
Lucky/JJ/O for/IN/O Cap/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Ike/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O easygoing/JJ/O and/CC/O soon/RB/O went/VBD/O away/RB/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O shah/NN/O --/:/O he/PRP/O kept/VBD/O coming/VBG/O back/RB/O ././O
We/PRP/O had/VBD/O great/JJ/O success/NN/O in/IN/O Somalia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
All/PDT/O these/DT/O reports/NNS/O about/IN/O him/PRP/O committing/VBG/O genocide/NN/O are/VBP/O probably/RB/O exaggerated/JJ/O anyway/RB/O ././O
He/PRP/O appeared/VBD/O late/JJ/O one/CD/O night/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bedroom/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O defense/NN/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O Dick/NNP/B-PERSON Cheney/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON came/VBD/O clanking/VBG/O in/IN/O like/JJ/O Marley/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O dragging/VBG/O those/DT/O chains/NNS/O of/IN/O brigades/NNS/O and/CC/O air/NN/O wings/NNS/O and/CC/O links/NNS/O with/IN/O Arab/JJ/O despots/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O leave/VB/O until/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Cheney/NNP/B-PERSON promised/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O whatever/WDT/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG systems/NNS/O analysts/NNS/O told/VBD/O him/PRP/O ././O
Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ghost/NN/O is/VBZ/O satisfied/JJ/O for/IN/O now/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O back/RB/O ././O
What/WP/O with/IN/O Halloween/NNP/O coming/VBG/O and/CC/O bigger/JJR/O defense/NN/O cuts/NNS/O looming/VBG/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG bureaucrats/NNS/O are/VBP/O crawling/VBG/O under/IN/O their/PRP$/O desks/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O know/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O hold/VB/O off/RP/O the/DT/O ghosts/NNS/O only/RB/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O while/NN/O longer/RB/O by/IN/O cutting/VBG/O carriers/NNS/O and/CC/O ships/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lehman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON Navy/NNP/B-ORG secretary/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O managing/NN/O director/NN/O of/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG ././O
