That/DT/O may/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O patent/NN/O award/NN/O ever/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O well/RB/O below/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 12/CD/O billion/CD/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG seeks/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O highest/JJS/O patent/NN/O damage/NN/O award/NN/O to/TO/O date/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Smith/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O ordered/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O $/$/O 205/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O Baker/NNP/B-ORG Hughes/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O infringing/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O patent/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O drilling/NN/O bit/NN/O seal/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O later/RB/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O for/IN/O $/$/O 95/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Few/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O worth/JJ/O their/PRP$/O time/NN/O to/TO/O slog/VB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG trial/NN/O testimony/NN/O ././O
Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG claims/VBZ/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O have/VB/O manufactured/VBN/O and/CC/O sold/VBN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O instant/NN/O cameras/NNS/O and/CC/O film/NN/O sold/VBN/O by/IN/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG if/IN/O Kodak/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O n't/RB/O entered/VBN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Each/DT/O side/NN/O has/VBZ/O called/VBN/O a/DT/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG professor/NN/O to/TO/O testify/VB/O on/IN/O that/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
Kodak/NN/B-ORG hired/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Buzzell/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG brought/VBD/O in/RP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Dolan/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Testimony/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O until/IN/O early/JJ/O December/NNP/O ././O
A/DT/O decision/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expected/VBN/O until/IN/O some/DT/O time/NN/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
