No/DT/O strikeout/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O certainly/RB/O no/DT/O home/NN/O run/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O suspects/VBZ/O that/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O market/NN/O decline/NN/O may/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O leg/NN/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O a/DT/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O drop/NN/O later/RB/O on/RB/O ././O
Some/DT/O think/VBP/O investors/NNS/O should/MD/O sell/VB/O into/IN/O rallies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O wind/VB/O down/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Gerald/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Perritt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE money/NN/O manager/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O found/VBD/O 85/CD/O still/RB/O overvalued/VBN/O and/CC/O 15/CD/O fairly/RB/O valued/VBN/O ././O
Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Parks/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE money/NN/O manager/NN/O ,/,/O expects/VBZ/O the/DT/O market/NN/O to/TO/O decline/VB/O about/IN/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Money/NN/O manager/NN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Ross/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O Duncan/NNP/B-ORG Ross/NNP/I-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Vancouver/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O stocks/NNS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O fall/VB/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O before/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O competitive/JJ/O with/IN/O less/RBR/O risky/JJ/O investment/NN/O alternatives/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O bulls/NNS/O out/IN/O there/RB/O ././O
Many/JJ/O brokerage/NN/O house/NN/O officials/NNS/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O optimistic/JJ/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG Sachs/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Dean/NNP/B-ORG Witter/NNP/I-ORG all/DT/O increased/VBD/O the/DT/O proportion/NN/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O they/PRP/O recommend/VBP/O investors/NNS/O commit/VBP/O to/TO/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
Dean/NNP/B-ORG Witter/NNP/I-ORG now/RB/O recommends/VBZ/O 85/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O Goldman/NNP/B-ORG 65/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG 50/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O big/JJ/O fall/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O just/RB/O a/DT/O blunder/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Connolly/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O strategist/NN/O for/IN/O Dean/NNP/B-ORG Witter/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Many/JJ/O investors/NNS/O have/VBP/O nagging/JJ/O worries/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Newspapers/NNS/O are/VBP/O full/JJ/O of/IN/O headlines/NNS/O about/IN/O companies/NNS/O defaulting/VBG/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O debts/NNS/O and/CC/O banks/NNS/O writing/VBG/O off/RP/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O loans/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O hurts/VBZ/O investors/NNS/O '/POS/O confidence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O and/CC/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
She/PRP/O thinks/VBZ/O the/DT/O market/NN/O could/MD/O drop/VB/O about/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O recover/VBP/O and/CC/O go/VBP/O higher/JJR/O ././O
Companies/NNS/O with/IN/O steady/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O growth/NN/O could/MD/O do/VB/O well/RB/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O while/IN/O others/NNS/O with/IN/O high/JJ/O debt/NN/O or/CC/O poor/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O could/MD/O see/VB/O their/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O decline/VBP/O far/RB/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
