Stanislav/NNP/B-PERSON Ovcharenko/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O airline/NN/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG here/RB/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O some/DT/O visions/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O wild/JJ/O even/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O standards/NNS/O of/IN/O perestroika/FW/O ././O
In/IN/O his/PRP$/O office/NN/O overlooking/VBG/O the/DT/O runway/NN/O of/IN/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Ovcharenko/NNP/B-PERSON enthusiastically/RB/O throws/VBZ/O out/RP/O what/WP/O he/PRP/O calls/VBZ/O ``/``/O just/RB/O ideas/NNS/O ''/''/O :/:/O
First/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O suggests/VBZ/O ,/,/O GPA/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O international/JJ/O aircraft/NN/O leasing/NN/O company/NN/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Ireland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O could/MD/O lease/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG jetliners/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O airline/NN/O ././O
Then/RB/O Aer/NNP/B-ORG Lingus/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Irish/JJ/O flag/NN/O carrier/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O teach/VB/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG pilots/NNS/O to/TO/O fly/VB/O the/DT/O Boeings/NNPS/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O fleet/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O based/VBN/O here/RB/O at/IN/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O all/DT/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Aer/NNP/B-ORG Rianta/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Irish/JJ/O airport/NN/O authority/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O build/VB/O a/DT/O cargo/NN/O terminal/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Have/VBP/O the/DT/O freedoms/NNS/O of/IN/O glasnost/FW/O gone/VBN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Ovcharenko/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O head/NN/O ?/./O
Hardly/RB/O ././O
Aer/NNP/B-ORG Lingus/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O in/IN/O discussions/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O carrier/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O cargo/NN/O venture/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O possibilities/NNS/O ././O
Aer/NNP/B-ORG Rianta/NNP/I-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O so/RB/O many/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O with/IN/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG that/IN/O its/PRP$/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O is/VBZ/O studying/VBG/O Russian/NNP/O ././O
Unlikely/RB/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O seem/VB/O ,/,/O tiny/JJ/O ,/,/O politically/RB/O neutral/JJ/O Ireland/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O penetrated/VBN/O the/DT/O mighty/JJ/O Soviet/JJ/O airline/NN/O bureaucracy/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O as/IN/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG struggles/VBZ/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O its/PRP$/O service/NN/O standards/NNS/O ,/,/O upgrade/VB/O its/PRP$/O fleet/NN/O and/CC/O pursue/VB/O commercial/JJ/O opportunities/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Irish/JJ/O aviation/NN/O industry/NN/O seems/VBZ/O poised/VBN/O to/TO/O benefit/VB/O ././O
``/``/O Irish/JJ/O and/CC/O Soviet/JJ/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O similar/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Ovcharenko/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O look/VBP/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O very/RB/O friendly/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O Irish/JJ/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O small/JJ/O but/CC/O spunky/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O study/VB/O their/PRP$/O experience/NN/O very/RB/O well/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O must/MD/O find/VB/O any/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O business/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O two/CD/O groups/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O working/VBG/O together/RP/O since/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1970s/NNS/O ,/,/O long/RB/O before/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O joint/NN/O ventures/NNS/O were/VBD/O the/DT/O rage/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O ././O
Aeroflot/NNP/O carried/VBD/O about/IN/O 125/CD/O million/CD/O passengers/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O transit/NN/O airport/NN/O outside/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O saw/VBD/O 1,400/CD/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG flights/NNS/O and/CC/O 250,000/CD/O passengers/NNS/O pass/VB/O through/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O airport/NN/O 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O supplier/NN/O of/IN/O aircraft/NN/O fuel/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Tankers/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Latvian/JJ/O port/NN/O of/IN/O Ventspils/NNP/B-GPE each/DT/O year/NN/O unload/VBP/O 25/CD/O million/CD/O gallons/NNS/O of/IN/O fuel/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O tank/NN/O farm/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O airport/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O all/DT/O ././O
Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O international/JJ/O fleet/NN/O of/IN/O 285/CD/O planes/NNS/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O repainted/VBN/O and/CC/O refurbished/VBN/O at/IN/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC ././O
Jamaica/NNP/B-GPE costs/VBZ/O 504/CD/O punts/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O formal/JJ/O blessing/NN/O of/IN/O sorts/NNS/O was/VBD/O bestowed/VBN/O on/IN/O this/DT/O friendship/NN/O in/IN/O April/NNP/O when/WRB/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Raisa/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON stopped/VBD/O here/RB/O for/IN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Irish/JJ/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Haughey/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
New/JJ/O trade/NN/O accords/NNS/O were/VBD/O signed/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O all/DT/O started/VBN/O with/IN/O geography/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O it/PRP/O opened/VBN/O in/IN/O 1939/CD/O ,/,/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC was/VBD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O landfall/NN/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC for/IN/O thirsty/JJ/O airplanes/NNS/O flying/VBG/O from/IN/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Advances/NNS/O in/IN/O aircraft/NN/O fuel/NN/O efficiency/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC stop/NN/O unnecessary/JJ/O for/IN/O most/JJS/O Western/JJ/O air/NN/O fleets/VBZ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG still/RB/O flies/VBZ/O inefficient/JJ/O Ilyushins/NNPS/O that/WDT/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O Managua/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O one/CD/O hop/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O Aer/NNP/B-ORG Lingus/NNP/I-ORG started/VBD/O ferrying/VBG/O Russians/NNPS/O from/IN/O Shannon/NNP/B-FAC to/TO/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE when/WRB/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE stripped/VBD/O Aeroflot/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE landing/NN/O rights/NNS/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O Aer/NNP/B-ORG Rianta/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O a/DT/O heap/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O Soviet/NNP/O friendship/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O with/IN/O those/DT/O contacts/NNS/O in/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O be/VB/O relatively/RB/O simple/JJ/O to/TO/O add/VB/O Aer/NNP/B-ORG Lingus/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O GPA/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O the/DT/O team/NN/O ././O
Then/RB/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Ovcharenko/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ideas/NNS/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O sound/VB/O like/IN/O so/RB/O much/JJ/O blarney/NN/O ././O
