Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O service/NN/O supplies/VBZ/O weekly/JJ/O reports/NNS/O on/IN/O school/NN/O and/CC/O college/NN/O construction/NN/O plans/NNS/O ././O
Market/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Retrieval/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O compiler/NN/O of/IN/O educational/JJ/O information/NN/O and/CC/O provides/VBZ/O related/JJ/O services/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O plans/NNS/O include/VBP/O a/DT/O subway/NN/O system/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O congress/NN/O center/NN/O ,/,/O floating/JJ/O trees/NNS/O ,/,/O fanciful/JJ/O fountains/NNS/O --/:/O and/CC/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 60,000/CD/O additional/JJ/O tourists/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
Expo/NN/O enthusiasts/NNS/O argue/VBP/O that/IN/O holding/VBG/O the/DT/O fair/NN/O would/MD/O attract/VB/O businesses/NNS/O ,/,/O create/VBP/O jobs/NNS/O and/CC/O help/VB/O renovate/VB/O abandoned/VBN/O sections/NNS/O of/IN/O town/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O gambling/NN/O casinos/NNS/O have/VBP/O opened/VBN/O in/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O three/CD/O establishments/NNS/O --/:/O two/CD/O in/IN/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O one/CD/O in/IN/O Krakow/NNP/B-GPE --/:/O accept/VB/O only/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O currency/NN/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O joint/JJ/O ventures/NNS/O between/IN/O Polish/JJ/O firms/NNS/O and/CC/O Western/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Middle/NNP/I-ORG East/NNP/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG Survey/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O North/JJ/O African/JJ/O nation/NN/O is/VBZ/O holding/VBG/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O adding/VBG/O a/DT/O fourth/JJ/O pipe/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O section/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Trans-Mediterranean/NNP/B-FAC pipeline/NN/O ,/,/O expanding/VBG/O capacity/NN/O by/IN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O six/CD/O billion/CD/O cubic/JJ/O meters/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O from/IN/O 12.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Algeria/NNP/B-GPE also/RB/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O pipeline/NN/O through/IN/O Morocco/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O across/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Strait/NNP/I-LOC of/IN/I-LOC Gibraltar/NNP/I-LOC to/TO/O supply/VB/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE with/IN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O 15/CD/O billion/CD/O cubic/JJ/O meters/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1990s/NNS/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE National/NNP/B-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Mineworkers/NNPS/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O suspend/VB/O the/DT/O strike/NN/O by/IN/O diamond/NN/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O resume/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O with/IN/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG Consolidated/NNP/I-ORG Mines/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG over/IN/O their/PRP$/O wage/NN/O dispute/NN/O ,/,/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O union/NN/O had/VBD/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O for/IN/O further/JJ/O talks/NNS/O tomorrow/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O strike/NN/O at/IN/O five/CD/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG mines/NNS/O began/VBD/O last/JJ/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O with/IN/O 9,500/CD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O 10,000/CD/O NUM/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O employed/VBN/O on/IN/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG mines/NNS/O participating/VBG/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O union/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O 7,800/CD/O participants/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O union/NN/O has/VBZ/O demanded/VBN/O a/DT/O 37.6/CD/O %/NN/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O minimum/NN/O wage/NN/O while/IN/O De/NNP/B-ORG Beers/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG final/JJ/O offer/NN/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O increase/NN/O of/IN/O 17/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O gathering/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O curbing/VBG/O the/DT/O fouling/NN/O of/IN/O rivers/NNS/O and/CC/O lakes/NNS/O ,/,/O limiting/VBG/O damage/NN/O from/IN/O industrial/JJ/O accidents/NNS/O and/CC/O improving/VBG/O the/DT/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O harmful/JJ/O chemicals/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE joined/VBD/O every/DT/O European/JJ/O country/NN/O except/IN/O Albania/NNP/B-GPE at/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O 13,000/CD/O more/JJR/O copies/NNS/O were/VBD/O sent/VBN/O to/TO/O Estonia/NNP/B-GPE because/IN/O of/IN/O strong/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Swedish/JJ/O publishing/NN/O company/NN/O Bonniers/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O 51/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Are/NNP/B-ORG Paev/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Estonian/JJ/O management/NN/O company/NN/O Minor/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O 49/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gurria/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O optimism/NN/O contrasts/VBZ/O with/IN/O some/DT/O bankers/NNS/O '/POS/O views/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O may/MD/O require/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O arm/NN/O twisting/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Treasury/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O other/JJ/O two/CD/O options/NNS/O consist/VBP/O of/IN/O swapping/VBG/O loans/NNS/O for/IN/O bonds/NNS/O with/IN/O 6.25/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O providing/VBG/O fresh/JJ/O loans/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O amount/NN/O is/VBZ/O equal/JJ/O to/TO/O about/IN/O 30/CD/O years/NNS/O earnings/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O average/JJ/O peasant/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O makes/VBZ/O $/$/O 145/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O .../:/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O spend/VB/O $/$/O 9.45/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O urgent/JJ/O maintenance/NN/O on/IN/O Tibet/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Potala/NNP/B-FAC Palace/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O former/JJ/O home/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Dalai/NNP/O Lama/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG China/NNP/I-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Dalai/NNP/O Lama/NNP/O ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O just/RB/O awarded/VBN/O the/DT/O Nobel/NNP/O Peace/NNP/O Prize/NNP/O ,/,/O lives/VBZ/O in/IN/O exile/NN/O in/IN/O India/NNP/B-GPE ././O
