Japanese/JJ/O Firms/NNS/O Push/VBP/O Posh/JJ/O Car/NN/O Showrooms/NNS/O
But/CC/O some/DT/O dealers/NNS/O are/VBP/O negotiating/VBG/O looser/JJR/O terms/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O others/NNS/O decline/VBP/O to/TO/O deal/VB/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ././O
Nissan/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Infiniti/NNP/B-ORG division/NN/O likes/VBZ/O to/TO/O insist/VB/O that/IN/O every/DT/O dealer/NN/O construct/VB/O and/CC/O furnish/VB/O a/DT/O building/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O style/NN/O ././O
Specifications/NNS/O include/VBP/O a/DT/O polished/JJ/O bronze/NN/O sculpture/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O of/IN/O each/DT/O showroom/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O tile/NN/O bridge/NN/O spanning/VBG/O a/DT/O stream/NN/O that/WDT/O flows/VBZ/O into/IN/O the/DT/O building/NN/O from/IN/O outside/RB/O ././O
Toyota/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Lexus/NNP/B-ORG division/NN/O also/RB/O provides/VBZ/O specifications/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O are/VBP/O even/RB/O coming/VBG/O up/RP/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O novel/NN/O designs/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ky./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Peterson/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O built/VBN/O a/DT/O Lexus/NNP/B-ORG dealership/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O showroom/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O floor/NN/O ././O
Yet/CC/O some/DT/O dealers/NNS/O have/VBP/O turned/VBN/O down/RP/O Infiniti/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O Lexus/NNP/B-ORG franchises/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O unwilling/JJ/O or/CC/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O the/DT/O design/NN/O requirements/NNS/O ././O
Lee/NNP/B-PERSON Seidman/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Cleveland/NNP/B-GPE says/VBZ/O Infiniti/NNP/B-ORG ``/``/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O bear/NN/O on/IN/O interiors/NNS/O ''/''/O but/CC/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O let/VB/O him/PRP/O retrofit/VB/O an/DT/O existing/VBG/O building/NN/O --/:/O without/IN/O the/DT/O stream/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Seidman/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O turned/VBD/O down/RP/O a/DT/O Lexus/NNP/B-ORG franchise/NN/O in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O building/NN/O was/VBD/O gorgeous/JJ/O but/CC/O very/RB/O expensive/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Dictation/NN/O Device/NN/O 's/POS/O Saga/NN/O Plays/VBZ/O Back/RP/O a/DT/O Lesson/NN/O
PRODUCTS/NNS/O DON'T/VB/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O first/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O winners/NNS/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O lesson/NN/O offered/VBN/O through/IN/O one/CD/O case/NN/O study/NN/O featured/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O design/NN/O exhibit/NN/O ././O
Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O caught/VBN/O off/IN/O guard/NN/O in/IN/O 1974/CD/O when/WRB/O its/PRP$/O main/JJ/O competitor/NN/O ,/,/O Lanier/NNP/B-ORG Office/NNP/I-ORG Products/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Japan/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O introduced/VBD/O a/DT/O microcassette/NN/O dictation/NN/O recorder/NN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O standard/JJ/O cassette/NN/O devices/NNS/O ././O
Blocked/VBN/O by/IN/O patent/NN/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O following/VBG/O suit/RB/O ,/,/O Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG decided/VBD/O to/TO/O go/VB/O a/DT/O step/NN/O further/RBR/O and/CC/O cut/VB/O the/DT/O cassette/NN/O in/IN/O half/NN/O again/RB/O --/:/O down/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O length/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O paperclip/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O designers/NNS/O and/CC/O engineers/NNS/O at/IN/O Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Pitney/NNP/B-ORG Bowes/NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O produced/VBN/O a/DT/O working/JJ/O model/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O picocassette/NN/O ''/''/O recorder/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O 1982/CD/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O patent/NN/O status/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Lanier/NNP/B-ORG microcassette/NN/O had/VBD/O changed/VBN/O ,/,/O permitting/VBG/O Dictaphone/NN/B-ORG to/TO/O develop/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O competitive/JJ/O micro/JJ/O system/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O ././O
Marketing/NN/O and/CC/O sales/NNS/O departments/NNS/O then/RB/O urged/VBD/O abandonment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pico/NN/O project/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O others/NNS/O said/VBD/O pico/NN/O should/MD/O proceed/VB/O ././O
Both/DT/O were/VBD/O right/JJ/O ././O
Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG went/VBD/O ahead/RB/O and/CC/O introduced/VBD/O the/DT/O pico/NN/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O sold/VBN/O well/RB/O ././O
To/TO/O date/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Emil/NNP/B-PERSON Jachmann/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O ``/``/O broken/VBN/O even/RB/O or/CC/O shown/VBN/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O loss/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O device/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O successful/JJ/O in/IN/O other/JJ/O ways/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O helped/VBD/O Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG attract/VB/O better/JJR/O engineers/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O provided/VBD/O new/JJ/O technology/NN/O for/IN/O other/JJ/O company/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O gave/VBD/O me/PRP/O great/JJ/O pride/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O the/DT/O inventor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O microcassette/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE look/VB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O pico/NN/O and/CC/O shake/VB/O his/PRP$/O head/NN/O and/CC/O say/VB/O `/``/O unbelievable/JJ/O ,/,/O '/''/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Jachmann/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Dictaphone/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O picocassette/NN/O recorder/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O 13/CD/O case/NN/O studies/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O TRIAD/NNP/O Design/NNP/O Project/NNP/O ,/,/O sponsored/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Design/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Boston/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O studies/NNS/O are/VBP/O on/IN/O exhibit/NN/O at/IN/O Harvard/NNP/B-ORG this/DT/O month/NN/O and/CC/O will/MD/O travel/VB/O to/TO/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Institute/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Design/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/I-ORG Berkeley/NN/I-ORG ././O
A/DT/O Rake/NN/O 's/POS/O Progress/NN/O Means/VBZ/O Branching/NNP/O Out/RB/O
ONE/CD/O DAY/NNP/O Carl/NNP/B-PERSON Barrett/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Mobile/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ala./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O raking/VBG/O some/DT/O sycamore/NN/O leaves/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O rake/NN/O kept/VBD/O riding/VBG/O up/RP/O over/IN/O the/DT/O piles/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O harder/RBR/O he/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O push/VB/O them/PRP/O into/IN/O large/JJ/O piles/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O closer/RBR/O he/PRP/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O breaking/VBG/O the/DT/O rake/NN/O and/CC/O straining/VBG/O his/PRP$/O back/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O crude/JJ/O device/NN/O worked/VBD/O :/:/O The/DT/O lower/JJR/O teeth/NNS/O gathered/VBD/O the/DT/O leaves/NNS/O into/IN/O a/DT/O pile/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O higher/JJR/O ,/,/O harder/JJR/O teeth/NNS/O moved/VBD/O the/DT/O top/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pile/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O other/JJ/O rake/NN/O makers/NNS/O have/VBP/O their/PRP$/O doubts/NNS/O ././O
Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Mason/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Ames/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Parkersburg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O W./NNP/B-GPE Va./NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Barrett/NNP/B-PERSON rake/NN/O ``/``/O makes/VBZ/O sense/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O tough/JJ/O ''/''/O to/TO/O explain/VB/O to/TO/O consumers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O either/RB/O pick/VBP/O it/PRP/O up/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O or/CC/O they/PRP/O start/VBP/O pulling/VBG/O from/IN/O a/DT/O fresh/JJ/O direction/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Odds/NNS/O and/CC/O Ends/NNS/O
NO/DT/O MORE/RB/O STUBBED/VBN/O toes/NNS/O or/CC/O bruised/VBN/O shins/NNS/O ,/,/O promises/VBZ/O Geste/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Goshen/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ind./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O designer/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O bed/NN/O support/NN/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O traditional/JJ/O frames/NNS/O ././O
Four/CD/O tubular/JJ/O steel/NN/O ``/``/O Bedfellows/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O each/DT/O roughly/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O shape/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O W/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O are/VBP/O attached/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bottom/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O box/NN/O spring/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O recessed/VBN/O position/NN/O .../:/O ././O
Nearly/RB/O half/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE consumers/NNS/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O pay/VB/O up/RB/O to/TO/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O more/JJR/O for/IN/O packaging/NN/O that/DT/O can/MD/O be/VB/O recycled/VBN/O or/CC/O is/VBZ/O biodegradable/JJ/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O survey/NN/O commissioned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Michael/NNP/I-ORG Peters/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O design/NN/O consultant/NN/O ././O
