CREATIVE/JJ/O ACCOUNTING/NN/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O by/IN/O conglomerates/NNS/O ,/,/O forced/VBD/O CPAs/NNS/O to/TO/O change/VB/O their/PRP$/O way/NN/O of/IN/O setting/VBG/O standards/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O corporations/NNS/O reporting/VBG/O financial/JJ/O results/NNS/O ,/,/O standards/NNS/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O become/VBN/O all/RB/O too/RB/O flexible/JJ/O ././O
Francis/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Wheat/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Securities/NNPS/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG member/NN/O ,/,/O headed/VBD/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O studied/VBN/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O and/CC/O proposed/VBD/O the/DT/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O March/NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O 1972/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O climate/NN/O was/VBD/O right/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Keepers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O books/NNS/O ,/,/O dubbed/VBN/O ``/``/O figure/NN/O filberts/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O loathed/VBD/O the/DT/O threat/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O its/PRP$/O initial/JJ/O meeting/NN/O on/IN/O March/NNP/O 28/CD/O ,/,/O 1973/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O FASB/NNP/B-ORG since/IN/O then/RB/O has/VBZ/O issued/VBN/O 102/CD/O rules/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O some/DT/O still/RB/O rile/VBP/O industry/NN/O ././O
