An/DT/O ebullient/JJ/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON Iverson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Nucor/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O plant/NN/O eventually/RB/O will/MD/O make/VB/O a/DT/O ton/NN/O of/IN/O steel/NN/O in/IN/O 1.5/CD/O man/NN/O hours/NNS/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O four/CD/O to/TO/O six/CD/O man/NN/O hours/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O conventional/JJ/O mill/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O had/VBD/O the/DT/O Russians/NNPS/O and/CC/O Chinese/NNPS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O people/NNS/O from/IN/O India/NNP/B-GPE visiting/VBG/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Iverson/NNP/B-PERSON beams/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Everyone/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O is/VBZ/O watching/VBG/O us/PRP/O very/RB/O closely/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Especially/RB/O his/PRP$/O neighbors/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE steelmakers/NNS/O ././O
Already/RB/O ,/,/O USX/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Armco/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG are/VBP/O studying/VBG/O Nucor/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O technology/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O adopt/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O the/DT/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O Midwest/NNP/B-LOC steel/NN/O company/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O damn/RB/O worrisome/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O revolution/NN/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O ultimately/RB/O change/VB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O we/PRP/O market/VBP/O and/CC/O distribute/VBP/O steel/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Dennis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O manufacturing/NN/O and/CC/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Iron/NNP/I-ORG Ore/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O that/RB/O major/JJ/O steelmakers/NNS/O have/VBP/O blithely/RB/O ignored/VBN/O high/JJ/O technology/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O spent/VBN/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O the/DT/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O continously/RB/O cast/VBN/O steel/NN/O to/TO/O 60.9/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O from/IN/O 39.6/CD/O %/NN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O before/RB/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O balance/NN/O sheets/NNS/O are/VBP/O rich/JJ/O with/IN/O diversity/NN/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O old/JJ/O plants/NNS/O shuttered/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O work/NN/O forces/NNS/O lean/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O suffice/VB/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O enough/JJ/O to/TO/O beat/VB/O the/DT/O guy/NN/O down/IN/O the/DT/O street/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O beat/VB/O everyone/NN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O steelmakers/NNS/O more/RBR/O involved/JJ/O in/IN/O computers/NNS/O and/CC/O artificial/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O problem/NN/O :/:/O They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O saddled/VBN/O with/IN/O huge/JJ/O plants/NNS/O that/WDT/O require/VBP/O costly/JJ/O maintenance/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O try/VB/O plying/VBG/O new/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O free/RB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O market/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O softening/VBG/O ,/,/O hurt/JJ/O by/IN/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O dollar/NN/O and/CC/O concerned/JJ/O about/IN/O overcapacity/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O Darth/NNP/B-PERSON Vadar/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O technology/NN/O revolution/NN/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O very/RB/O threatening/JJ/O to/TO/O established/JJ/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Marcus/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O with/IN/O PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBN/O too/RB/O much/RB/O invested/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O stuff/NN/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O their/PRP$/O workers/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O flexible/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O process/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O without/IN/O its/PRP$/O headaches/NNS/O ././O
Because/IN/O all/DT/O operations/NNS/O are/VBP/O connected/VBN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O equipment/NN/O failure/NN/O forces/VBZ/O a/DT/O complete/JJ/O plant/NN/O shutdown/NN/O ././O
On/IN/O some/DT/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Nucor/NNP/B-ORG plant/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O produce/VB/O anything/NN/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O with/IN/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O steel/NN/O not/RB/O growing/VBG/O fast/RB/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O absorb/VB/O capacity/NN/O ,/,/O steelmakers/NNS/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O change/VB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O business/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Armco/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O economist/NN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Corey/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O steelmakers/NNS/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O product/NN/O and/CC/O set/VBD/O it/PRP/O out/RP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O loading/NN/O dock/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O said/VBD/O :/:/O `/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBN/O a/DT/O product/NN/O :/:/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O want/VBP/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O buy/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O '/''/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O :/:/O ``/``/O Now/RB/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O figuring/VBG/O out/RP/O what/WP/O people/NNS/O need/VBP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O back/RP/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Armco/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O representatives/NNS/O visit/VBP/O the/DT/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Motors/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Fairfax/NN/B-LOC assembly/NN/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mo./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O two/CD/O or/CC/O three/CD/O days/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O they/PRP/O determined/VBD/O that/IN/O GM/NNP/B-ORG needed/VBD/O parts/NNS/O more/RBR/O quickly/RB/O ,/,/O Armco/NNP/B-ORG convinced/VBD/O a/DT/O steel/NN/O service/NN/O center/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O processing/NN/O plant/NN/O nearby/RB/O so/IN/O shipments/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O delivered/VBN/O within/IN/O 15/CD/O minutes/NNS/O ././O
Cementing/VBG/O such/JJ/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O major/JJ/O clients/NNS/O --/:/O car/NN/O and/CC/O appliance/NN/O makers/NNS/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O means/NN/O of/IN/O survival/NN/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O when/WRB/O those/DT/O key/JJ/O clients/NNS/O are/VBP/O relying/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O smaller/JJR/O pool/NN/O of/IN/O producers/NNS/O and/CC/O flirting/VBG/O with/IN/O plastic/NN/O and/CC/O aluminum/NN/O makers/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O steelmakers/NNS/O must/MD/O also/RB/O find/VB/O new/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
Battelle/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O McCall/NNP/B-PERSON thinks/VBZ/O steelmakers/NNS/O should/MD/O concentrate/VB/O more/RBR/O on/IN/O construction/NN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O steelmakers/NNS/O envision/VBP/O steel/NN/O roofs/NNS/O covering/VBG/O suburbia/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O others/NNS/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O overseas/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O steelmaker/NN/O reactivated/VBD/O its/PRP$/O overseas/JJ/O sales/NNS/O operation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O like/IN/O everyone/NN/O climbing/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O QE/NNP/O II/NNP/O and/CC/O getting/VBG/O into/IN/O a/DT/O lifeboat/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Jacobson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O with/IN/O AUS/NNP/B-ORG Consultants/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O After/IN/O a/DT/O while/NN/O ,/,/O someone/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O go/VB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O side/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Although/IN/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O any/DT/O bankruptcies/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O see/VB/O more/JJR/O plants/NNS/O being/VBG/O sold/VBN/O or/CC/O closed/VBN/O ././O
Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Crandall/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Brookings/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O agrees/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Unless/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O enormous/JJ/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O or/CC/O a/DT/O further/JJR/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O that/IN/O consumption/NN/O of/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE produced/VBN/O steel/NN/O will/MD/O grow/VB/O sufficiently/RB/O to/TO/O offset/VB/O the/DT/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O minimills/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Not/RB/O to/TO/O mention/VB/O the/DT/O incursion/NN/O of/IN/O imports/NNS/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O and/CC/O European/JJ/O steelmakers/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O led/VBN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O technology/NN/O developments/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O anxiously/RB/O awaiting/VBG/O the/DT/O lifting/NN/O of/IN/O trade/NN/O restraints/NNS/O in/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O think/VBP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O steel/NN/O business/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O old/JJ/O and/CC/O mundane/JJ/O smokestack/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Iverson/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O 're/VBP/O dead/RB/O wrong/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
\*/SYM/O USX/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O LTV/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Bethlehem/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Inland/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Armco/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O National/NNP/B-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG
\*\*/SYM/O Projected/VBN/O
