President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON chose/VBD/O Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Allday/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O longtime/JJ/O friend/NN/O from/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Regulatory/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Allday/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O succeed/VB/O Martha/NNP/B-PERSON Hesse/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O resigning/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Ms./NNP/O Hesse/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE businesswoman/NN/O who/WP/O previously/RB/O held/VBD/O posts/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O FERC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O leaving/VBG/O to/TO/O become/VB/O a/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Allday/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O in/IN/O Midland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O solicitor/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Interior/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O met/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O the/DT/O 1950s/NNS/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O president/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O young/JJ/O oil/NN/O man/NN/O in/IN/O Midland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Allday/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O a/DT/O lawyer/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O firm/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Allday/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O appointment/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O confirmation/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O date/NN/O for/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Hesse/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O departure/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O set/VBN/O ././O
