AN/DT/O EARTHQUAKE/NN/O STRUCK/VBD/O Northern/JJ/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O killing/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 50/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O tremor/NN/O was/VBD/O centered/VBN/O near/IN/O Hollister/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O southeast/NN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O felt/VBN/O as/RB/O far/RB/O as/IN/O 200/CD/O miles/NNS/O away/RB/O ././O
Numerous/JJ/O injuries/NNS/O were/VBD/O reported/VBN/O ././O
Some/DT/O buildings/NNS/O collapsed/VBD/O ,/,/O gas/NN/O and/CC/O water/NN/O lines/NNS/O ruptured/VBD/O and/CC/O fires/NNS/O raged/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O quake/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O also/RB/O caused/VBD/O damage/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Berkeley/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O knocked/VBD/O out/RP/O electricity/NN/O and/CC/O telephones/NNS/O ,/,/O cracked/VBD/O roadways/NNS/O and/CC/O disrupted/VBD/O subway/NN/O service/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC Area/NN/I-LOC ././O
Major/JJ/O injuries/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O reported/VBN/O at/IN/O Candlestick/NNP/B-FAC Park/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O game/NN/O of/IN/O baseball/NN/O 's/POS/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O was/VBD/O canceled/VBN/O and/CC/O fans/NNS/O evacuated/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O stadium/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O pledge/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O Democratic/JJ/O Sen./NNP/O Byrd/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O came/VBD/O ahead/RB/O of/IN/O an/DT/O expected/JJ/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG vote/NN/O on/IN/O spending/NN/O legislation/NN/O containing/VBG/O the/DT/O provision/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG World/NNP/I-ORG Psychiatric/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG voted/VBD/O at/IN/O an/DT/O Athens/NNP/B-GPE parley/NN/O to/TO/O conditionally/RB/O readmit/VB/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O left/VBD/O the/DT/O group/NN/O in/IN/O 1983/CD/O to/TO/O avoid/VB/O explusion/NN/O over/IN/O allegations/NNS/O that/IN/O political/JJ/O dissidents/NNS/O were/VBD/O being/VBG/O certified/VBN/O as/IN/O insane/JJ/O ,/,/O could/MD/O be/VB/O suspended/VBN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O misuse/NN/O of/IN/O psychiatry/NN/O against/IN/O dissenters/NNS/O is/VBZ/O discovered/VBN/O during/IN/O a/DT/O review/NN/O within/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
NASA/NNP/B-ORG postponed/VBD/O the/DT/O liftoff/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O space/NN/O shuttle/NN/O Atlantis/NNP/O because/RB/O of/IN/O rain/NN/O near/IN/O the/DT/O site/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O launch/NN/O pad/NN/O in/IN/O Cape/NNP/B-GPE Canaveral/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Fla/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O flight/NN/O was/VBD/O rescheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O today/NN/O ././O
Senate/NNP/B-ORG Democratic/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O enough/RB/O votes/NNS/O to/TO/O defeat/VB/O a/DT/O proposed/VBN/O constitutional/JJ/O amendment/NN/O to/TO/O ban/VB/O flag/NN/O burning/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Cancer/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O projected/VBD/O that/DT/O overall/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE mortality/NN/O rates/NNS/O from/IN/O lung/NN/O cancer/NN/O should/MD/O begin/VB/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O in/IN/O several/JJ/O years/NNS/O if/IN/O cigarette/NN/O smoking/NN/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O abate/VB/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON met/VBD/O with/IN/O South/JJ/O Korean/JJ/O President/NNP/O Roh/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O indicated/VBD/O that/IN/O Seoul/NNP/B-GPE plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O further/RBR/O ease/VB/O trade/NN/O rules/NNS/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O that/DT/O its/PRP$/O economy/NN/O becomes/VBZ/O as/RB/O open/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O industrialized/JJ/O nations/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1990s/NNS/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON assured/VBD/O Roh/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O stand/VB/O by/IN/O its/PRP$/O security/NN/O commitments/NNS/O ``/``/O as/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O threat/NN/O ''/''/O from/IN/O Communist/NNP/O North/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O an/DT/O understanding/NN/O with/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O ease/VB/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE involvement/NN/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O coups/NNS/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O leader/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O while/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O n't/RB/O alter/VB/O a/DT/O longstanding/JJ/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O such/JJ/O involvement/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O clarification/NN/O needed/VBN/O ''/''/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O interpretation/NN/O ././O
India/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Gandhi/NNP/B-PERSON called/VBD/O for/IN/O parliamentary/JJ/O elections/NNS/O next/IN/O month/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE abstained/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O U.N./NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Assembly/NNP/I-ORG vote/NN/O to/TO/O reject/VB/O Israel/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O credentials/NNS/O ././O
Black/JJ/O activist/NN/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Sisulu/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG African/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O reject/VB/O violence/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O pressure/NN/O the/DT/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O government/NN/O into/IN/O concessions/NNS/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O lead/VB/O to/TO/O negotiations/NNS/O over/IN/O apartheid/NN/O ././O
London/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O concluded/VBN/O that/IN/O Austrian/JJ/O President/NNP/O Waldheim/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O n't/RB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O execution/NN/O of/IN/O six/CD/O British/JJ/O commandos/NNS/O in/IN/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O ,/,/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O probably/RB/O was/VBD/O aware/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O slayings/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O report/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Ministry/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O rejected/VBD/O allegations/NNS/O that/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE covered/VBD/O up/RP/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O Waldheim/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O activities/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O German/JJ/O army/NN/O officer/NN/O ././O
An/DT/O international/JJ/O group/NN/O approved/VBD/O a/DT/O formal/JJ/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O ivory/JJ/O trade/NN/O despite/IN/O objections/NNS/O from/IN/O southern/JJ/O African/JJ/O governments/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O threatened/VBD/O to/TO/O find/VB/O alternative/JJ/O channels/NNS/O for/IN/O selling/VBG/O elephant/NN/O tusks/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O assassin/NN/O in/IN/O Colombia/NNP/B-GPE killed/VBD/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O Medellin/NNP/B-GPE street/NN/O ././O
Libyan/JJ/O leader/NN/O Gadhafi/NNP/B-PERSON met/VBN/O with/IN/O Egypt/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O President/NNP/O Mubarak/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O two/CD/O officials/NNS/O pledged/VBD/O to/TO/O respect/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O 's/POS/O laws/NNS/O ,/,/O security/NN/O and/CC/O stability/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O stopped/VBD/O short/RB/O of/IN/O resuming/VBG/O diplomatic/JJ/O ties/NNS/O ,/,/O severed/VBN/O in/IN/O 1979/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O reconciliation/NN/O talks/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Libyan/JJ/O desert/NN/O town/NN/O of/IN/O Tobruk/NNP/B-GPE followed/VBD/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O Monday/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Egyptian/JJ/O resort/NN/O of/IN/O Mersa/NNP/B-ORG Metruh/NNP/I-ORG ././O
