``/``/O Since/IN/O deregulation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O producers/NNS/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O much/RB/O more/RBR/O intensely/RB/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O both/DT/O transportation/NN/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Maier/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O ``/``/O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O matter/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O close/JJ/O to/TO/O those/DT/O suppliers/NNS/O ;/:/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O those/DT/O companies/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O us/PRP/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O should/MD/O ././O ''/''/O
TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG transports/VBZ/O all/DT/O gas/NN/O that/WDT/O moves/VBZ/O eastward/RB/O from/IN/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE ././O
That/DT/O includes/VBZ/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O gas/NN/O consumed/VBN/O in/IN/O Ontario/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Quebec/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O bulk/NN/O of/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O gas/NN/O exports/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O
``/``/O Having/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O token/JJ/O presence/NN/O here/RB/O should/MD/O enhance/VB/O communications/NNS/O and/CC/O business/NN/O relationships/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Litvinchuk/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O ``/``/O
Since/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O transporting/VBG/O gas/NN/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O important/JJ/O to/TO/O producers/NNS/O '/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O helps/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O input/NN/O and/CC/O access/NN/O to/TO/O transportation/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O move/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O could/MD/O cost/VB/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 42.5/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O relocation/NN/O and/CC/O severance/NN/O payments/NNS/O ,/,/O should/MD/O be/VB/O complete/JJ/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Maier/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O will/MD/O save/VB/O between/IN/O C$/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O C$/$/O 6/CD/O million/CD/O annually/RB/O in/IN/O office/NN/O expenses/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O administrative/JJ/O costs/NNS/O by/IN/O moving/VBG/O to/TO/O Calgary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Maier/NNP/B-PERSON added/VBD/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O both/PDT/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O savings/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O passed/VBN/O on/RP/O to/TO/O shippers/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG pipeline/NN/O through/IN/O tolls/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pipeline/NN/O system/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O operating/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
