October/NNP/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O edgy/JJ/O month/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O practitioners/NNS/O of/IN/O glasnost/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O official/JJ/O Soviet/JJ/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O allowing/VBG/O more/JJR/O candor/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O media/NNS/O ././O
Why/WRB/O had/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Korotich/NNP/B-PERSON been/VBN/O called/VBN/O ?/./O
``/``/O I/PRP/O told/VBD/O my/PRP$/O driver/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O taking/VBG/O my/PRP$/O butt/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG so/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O .../:/O ''/''/O whack/VB/O ,/,/O whack/VB/O ,/,/O whack/VB/O his/PRP$/O hand/NN/O made/VBD/O vigorous/JJ/O spanking/JJ/O gestures/NNS/O on/IN/O his/PRP$/O left/JJ/O palm/NN/O ././O ``/``/O
They/PRP/O feel/VBP/O the/DT/O need/NN/O from/IN/O time/NN/O to/TO/O time/NN/O to/TO/O `/``/O educate/VB/O '/''/O me/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
And/CC/O indeed/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O later/RB/O reported/VBD/O ,/,/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O import/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O ././O
Anxious/JJ/O allies/NNS/O of/IN/O President/NNP/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON are/VBP/O cautioning/VBG/O media/NNS/O leaders/NNS/O to/TO/O take/VB/O it/PRP/O easy/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O careful/JJ/O not/RB/O to/TO/O do/VB/O anything/NN/O that/WDT/O could/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O opponents/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O nervous/JJ/O ././O
We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O standing/VBG/O in/IN/O gasoline/NN/O ,/,/O so/RB/O do/VB/O n't/RB/O smoke/VB/O !/./O ''/''/O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O northern/JJ/O European/JJ/O diplomats/NNS/O confirm/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Korotich/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O assessment/NN/O that/IN/O glasnost/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O no/DT/O immediate/JJ/O danger/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O day/NN/O after/IN/O that/DT/O conversation/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O residence/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ambassador/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Brezhnevite/NNP/O editor/NN/O of/IN/O Pravda/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON Afnasjev/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O replaced/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O college/NN/O classmate/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ././O
Brezhnevite/NNP/O holdovers/NNS/O have/VBP/O more/JJR/O to/TO/O fear/VB/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON than/IN/O the/DT/O verbal/JJ/O spanking/NN/O he/PRP/O gave/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O press/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O very/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Mr./NNP/O Korotich/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O called/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Ogonyok/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O again/RB/O demonstrating/VBG/O its/PRP$/O independence/NN/O by/IN/O printing/VBG/O a/DT/O poll/NN/O that/WDT/O showed/VBD/O that/IN/O 35/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O population/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O plurality/NN/O ,/,/O believed/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O economic/JJ/O reforms/NNS/O ,/,/O perestroika/FW/O ,/,/O would/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O only/JJ/O insignificant/JJ/O change/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Korotich/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O it/PRP/O over/RP/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O sold/VBD/O 250,000/CD/O copies/NNS/O ;/:/O today/NN/O it/PRP/O sells/VBZ/O 3.4/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Pravda/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O retained/VBN/O only/RB/O 57/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 1986/CD/O readership/NN/O ././O
Glasnost/FW/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O celebrities/NNS/O of/IN/O men/NNS/O like/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Korotich/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Prevented/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Communist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG from/IN/O getting/VBG/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O slate/NN/O of/IN/O nominees/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Soviet/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O stood/VBD/O as/IN/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O candidate/NN/O for/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG from/IN/O his/PRP$/O native/JJ/O Ukraine/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O won/VBD/O with/IN/O 84/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O same/JJ/O evening/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O summoned/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O warning/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Party/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O cheered/VBN/O by/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O supporters/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O rally/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O can/MD/O only/RB/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O the/DT/O Korotich/NNP/B-PERSON party/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O as/RB/O astounding/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O already/RB/O occurred/VBN/O are/VBP/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O fragility/NN/O to/TO/O glasnost/FW/O ././O
Censorship/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O Marxist/JJ/O invention/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O czars/NNS/O were/VBD/O no/RB/O civil/JJ/O libertarians/NNS/O ././O
As/RB/O late/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O 1890s/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Russian/JJ/O government/NN/O prevented/VBD/O any/DT/O coverage/NN/O of/IN/O famines/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O even/RB/O directed/VBD/O newspapers/NNS/O not/RB/O to/TO/O publish/VB/O anything/NN/O that/WDT/O might/MD/O stain/VB/O the/DT/O honor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Turkish/JJ/O sultan/NN/O 's/POS/O wives/NNS/O ././O
So/IN/O glasnost/FW/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O value/NN/O woven/VBN/O with/IN/O steel/NN/O threads/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O fabric/NN/O of/IN/O Russian/JJ/O society/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O public/JJ/O relations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O sophistication/NN/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O recognizes/VBZ/O that/IN/O credibility/NN/O is/VBZ/O enhanced/VBN/O by/IN/O honesty/NN/O --/:/O up/IN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O point/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O point/NN/O ?/./O
Will/MD/O Ogonyok/NNP/B-ORG begin/VB/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O reports/NNS/O analyzing/VBG/O the/DT/O failures/NNS/O of/IN/O perestroika/FW/O ?/./O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O be/VB/O destroying/VBG/O myself/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O replies/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Korotich/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O then/RB/O asks/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O What/WP/O would/MD/O that/DT/O accomplish/VB/O ?/./O
''/''/O His/PRP$/O answer/NN/O reveals/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O vulnerability/NN/O --/:/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O draws/VBZ/O the/DT/O line/NN/O that/IN/O Soviet/JJ/O society/NN/O must/MD/O cross/VB/O to/TO/O enter/VB/O the/DT/O normal/JJ/O dialogue/NN/O of/IN/O Western/JJ/O culture/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O line/NN/O beyond/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O press/NN/O can/MD/O report/VB/O not/RB/O only/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O bankruptcy/NN/O of/IN/O factories/NNS/O but/CC/O on/IN/O the/DT/O failures/NNS/O of/IN/O even/RB/O admirable/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ayers/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O editor/NN/O and/CC/O publisher/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Anniston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ala./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Star/NNP/B-ORG ././O
