There/EX/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O truce/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O war/NN/O of/IN/O nerves/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG over/IN/O how/WRB/O this/DT/O country/NN/O conducts/VBZ/O secret/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O operations/NNS/O abroad/RB/O ././O
That/DT/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O always/RB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O handled/VBD/O such/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG never/RB/O fully/RB/O trusted/VBD/O former/JJ/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG chief/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Casey/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O National/NNP/O Security/NNP/O Adviser/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Poindexter/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O honor/VB/O the/DT/O ban/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O removed/VBN/O a/DT/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG use/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O contingency/NN/O fund/NN/O for/IN/O covert/JJ/O acts/NNS/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O wipe/VB/O away/RB/O some/DT/O tortured/JJ/O and/CC/O legalistic/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O coup/NN/O planning/NN/O put/VBN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O back/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O game/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O understanding/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O spring/VB/O to/TO/O life/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O spontaneous/JJ/O eruption/NN/O of/IN/O sweetness/NN/O and/CC/O light/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG used/VBD/O television/NN/O appearances/NNS/O and/CC/O leaks/NNS/O to/TO/O argue/VB/O that/IN/O congressionally/RB/O imposed/VBN/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O covert/JJ/O actions/NNS/O made/VBD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE support/NN/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O coups/NNS/O difficult/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O president/NN/O also/RB/O hinted/VBD/O he/PRP/O might/MD/O veto/VB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O intelligence/NN/O authorization/NN/O bill/NN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O restrictive/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG got/VBD/O the/DT/O better/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O but/CC/O took/VBD/O care/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O press/VB/O its/PRP$/O advantage/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O constitutional/JJ/O confrontation/NN/O sought/VBN/O by/IN/O conservative/JJ/O Republicans/NNPS/O who/WP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O any/DT/O congressional/JJ/O oversight/NN/O of/IN/O intelligence/NN/O activities/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O senators/NNS/O responded/VBD/O in/IN/O kind/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON happily/RB/O told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O that/IN/O there/EX/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O minds/NNS/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O had/VBD/O given/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O a/DT/O clean/JJ/O slate/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O free/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O impediments/NNS/O imposed/VBN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON years/NNS/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O relationship/NN/O has/VBZ/O reverted/VBN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O pre-Reagan/JJ/B-PERSON character/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O some/DT/O details/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O nailed/VBN/O down/IN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O reserving/VBG/O the/DT/O right/NN/O in/IN/O ``/``/O rare/JJ/O ''/''/O instances/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O dark/NN/O ,/,/O asserting/VBG/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O prerogative/NN/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O recognize/VB/O ././O
Some/DT/O conservatives/NNS/O will/MD/O accuse/VB/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O promising/JJ/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG too/RB/O much/RB/O ././O
