American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG will/MD/O expand/VB/O its/PRP$/O trans-Atlantic/JJ/B-LOC service/NN/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O beginning/VBG/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O with/IN/O six/CD/O new/JJ/O daily/JJ/O flights/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O officials/NNS/O announced/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
American/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O airline/NN/O ././O
Chicago/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O population/NN/O of/IN/O citizens/NNS/O of/IN/O Polish/JJ/O heritage/NN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O city/NN/O outside/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O service/NN/O ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O fly/VB/O 161/CD/O flights/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O to/TO/O 17/CD/O European/JJ/O cities/NNS/O ././O
