Out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O mouths/NNS/O of/IN/O revolutionaries/NNS/O are/VBP/O coming/VBG/O words/NNS/O of/IN/O moderation/NN/O ././O
Here/RB/O ,/,/O at/IN/O a/DT/O soccer/NN/O stadium/NN/O near/IN/O the/DT/O black/JJ/O township/NN/O of/IN/O Soweto/NNP/B-GPE yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O eight/CD/O leaders/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG African/NNP/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Congress/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O seven/CD/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O had/VBD/O spent/VBN/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O adult/NN/O lives/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O for/IN/O sabotage/NN/O and/CC/O conspiracy/NN/O to/TO/O overthrow/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
Here/RB/O were/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 70,000/CD/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG supporters/NNS/O ,/,/O gathering/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG rally/NN/O inside/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE since/IN/O the/DT/O black/JJ/O liberation/NN/O movement/NN/O was/VBD/O banned/VBN/O in/IN/O 1960/CD/O ././O
Here/RB/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O state/NN/O security/NN/O appartus/NN/O poised/VBN/O to/TO/O pounce/VB/O on/IN/O any/DT/O words/NNS/O or/CC/O acts/NNS/O of/IN/O provocation/NN/O ,/,/O let/VB/O alone/JJ/O revolution/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O words/NNS/O that/WDT/O boomed/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O loudspeakers/NNS/O bore/VBD/O messages/NNS/O of/IN/O peace/NN/O ,/,/O unity/NN/O ,/,/O negotiation/NN/O and/CC/O discipline/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O stand/VBP/O for/IN/O peace/NN/O today/NN/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O will/MD/O stand/VB/O for/IN/O peace/NN/O tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Sisulu/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O former/JJ/O secretary/NN/O general/NN/O who/WP/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O five/CD/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O ,/,/O served/VBD/O 26/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O before/IN/O being/VBG/O released/VBN/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
Some/DT/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O crowd/NN/O shouted/VBD/O ``/``/O Viva/FW/O peace/NN/O ,/,/O viva/FW/O ././O ''/''/O
These/DT/O are/VBP/O curious/JJ/O times/NNS/O in/IN/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O politics/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O bitterest/JJS/O of/IN/O enemies/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O elaborate/JJ/O mating/NN/O dance/NN/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O entice/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O negotiating/VBG/O table/NN/O ././O
Pretoria/NN/B-GPE releases/VBZ/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O were/VBD/O serving/VBG/O life/NN/O sentences/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O allows/VBZ/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O speak/VB/O freely/RB/O ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O abandon/VB/O its/PRP$/O use/NN/O of/IN/O violence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O speak/VBP/O in/IN/O tones/NNS/O of/IN/O moderation/NN/O ,/,/O emphasizing/VBG/O discipline/NN/O ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O the/DT/O government/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O encouraged/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O further/JJ/O steps/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O freeing/VBG/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Mandela/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O prominent/JJ/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG figure/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O unbanning/VBG/O the/DT/O organization/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O of/IN/O President/NNP/B-PERSON F.W./NNP/I-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON Klerk/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O using/VBG/O this/DT/O situation/NN/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O its/PRP$/O international/JJ/O image/NN/O and/CC/O head/VB/O off/RP/O further/JJ/O economic/JJ/O sanctions/NNS/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O many/JJ/O organizations/NNS/O inside/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O that/WDT/O back/VBP/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O taking/VBG/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O regain/VB/O their/PRP$/O strength/NN/O and/CC/O mobilize/VB/O their/PRP$/O supporters/NNS/O even/RB/O though/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O emergency/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O severely/RB/O curtailed/VBN/O black/JJ/O opposition/NN/O ,/,/O remains/VBZ/O in/IN/O force/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O unthinkable/JJ/O and/CC/O illogical/JJ/O are/VBP/O happening/VBG/O ././O
Six/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O government/NN/O approval/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG rally/NN/O was/VBD/O inconceivable/JJ/O ././O
Equally/RB/O inconceivable/JJ/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O a/DT/O rally/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O extend/VB/O a/DT/O hand/NN/O ,/,/O albeit/IN/O warily/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O message/NN/O read/VBN/O out/RP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O rally/NN/O ,/,/O exiled/VBD/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG President/NNP/O Oliver/NNP/B-PERSON Tambo/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O legally/RB/O be/VB/O quoted/VBN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O country/NN/O was/VBD/O at/IN/O a/DT/O crossroads/NNS/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON Klerk/NNP/I-PERSON ``/``/O may/MD/O yet/RB/O earn/VB/O a/DT/O place/NN/O among/IN/O the/DT/O peacemakers/NNS/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O country/NN/O ''/''/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O chooses/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O path/NN/O of/IN/O genuine/JJ/O political/JJ/O settlement/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O this/DT/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O that/IN/O either/CC/O the/DT/O government/NN/O or/CC/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O changing/VBG/O stripes/NNS/O --/:/O or/CC/O that/IN/O either/DT/O has/VBZ/O moved/VBN/O significantly/RB/O closer/RBR/O to/TO/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O may/MD/O ease/VB/O repression/NN/O in/IN/O some/DT/O areas/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O still/RB/O keeps/VBZ/O a/DT/O tight/JJ/O grip/NN/O in/IN/O others/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O releases/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON without/IN/O conditions/NNS/O ,/,/O yet/RB/O his/PRP$/O son/NN/O ,/,/O Zwelakhe/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O newspaper/NN/O editor/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O restricted/VBN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O home/NN/O much/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O work/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O journalist/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG vows/VBZ/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O up/RP/O pressure/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
Speakers/NNS/O yesterday/NN/O called/VBD/O on/IN/O foreign/JJ/O governments/NNS/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O sanctions/NNS/O against/IN/O Pretoria/NN/B-GPE and/CC/O urged/VBD/O supporters/NNS/O inside/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O defying/VBG/O emergency/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O and/CC/O racial/JJ/O segregation/NN/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O apartheid/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O can/MD/O not/RB/O wait/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O changes/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O pace/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Because/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG remains/VBZ/O banned/VBN/O ,/,/O both/PDT/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O approved/VBD/O the/DT/O rally/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O organizers/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O orchestrated/VBD/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O denied/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG rally/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O both/DT/O called/VBD/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O ``/``/O welcome/JJ/O home/NN/O ''/''/O gathering/NN/O ././O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O an/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG rally/NN/O by/IN/O any/DT/O other/JJ/O name/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O an/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG rally/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O recently/RB/O released/VBN/O leaders/NNS/O sat/VBD/O high/RB/O atop/IN/O a/DT/O podium/NN/O in/IN/O one/CD/O section/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stadium/NN/O stands/NNS/O ././O
Behind/IN/O them/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG flag/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O even/RB/O bigger/JJR/O sign/NN/O that/WDT/O said/VBD/O ``/``/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG Lives/VBZ/O ,/,/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG Leads/VBZ/O ././O ''/''/O
Next/JJ/O to/TO/O them/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O red/JJ/O flag/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O outlawed/VBN/O South/NNP/B-ORG African/NNP/I-ORG Communist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O long/RB/O been/VBN/O an/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ally/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Today/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O captured/VBN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O stage/NN/O of/IN/O political/JJ/O life/NN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O a/DT/O police/NN/O helicopter/NN/O circled/VBD/O overhead/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON repeated/VBD/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O demands/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O create/VB/O a/DT/O climate/NN/O for/IN/O negotiations/NNS/O :/:/O Release/VB/O all/DT/O political/JJ/O prisoners/NNS/O unconditionally/RB/O ;/:/O lift/VB/O all/DT/O bans/NNS/O and/CC/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O individuals/NNS/O and/CC/O organizations/NNS/O ;/:/O remove/VB/O all/DT/O troops/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O black/JJ/O townships/NNS/O ;/:/O end/VB/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O emergency/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O cease/VB/O all/DT/O political/JJ/O trials/NNS/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O executions/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O these/DT/O conditions/NNS/O are/VBP/O met/VBN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O discuss/VB/O suspending/VBG/O its/PRP$/O guerrilla/NN/O activities/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O can/MD/O be/VB/O no/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O unilaterally/RB/O abandoning/VBG/O the/DT/O armed/VBN/O struggle/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O ``/``/O
To/TO/O date/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O see/VBP/O no/DT/O clear/JJ/O indication/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O serious/JJ/O about/IN/O negotiations/NNS/O ././O
All/PDT/O their/PRP$/O utterances/NNS/O are/VBP/O vague/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Echoing/VBG/O a/DT/O phrase/NN/O from/IN/O Mr./NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON Klerk/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sisulu/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Let/VB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O who/WP/O love/VBP/O this/DT/O country/NN/O engage/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O task/NN/O of/IN/O building/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE ././O
