But/CC/O now/RB/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O enjoying/VBG/O a/DT/O resurgence/NN/O in/IN/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O both/DT/O steam/NN/O and/CC/O combustion/NN/O turbines/NNS/O and/CC/O may/MD/O even/RB/O join/VB/O the/DT/O growing/VBG/O legion/NN/O of/IN/O independent/JJ/O electric/JJ/O producers/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O venture/NN/O with/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Heavy/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O announced/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O poised/VBN/O to/TO/O penetrate/VB/O growing/VBG/O markets/NNS/O overseas/RB/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1970s/CD/O ,/,/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG this/DT/O year/NN/O has/VBZ/O seen/VBN/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O orders/NNS/O for/IN/O power/NN/O plants/NNS/O ././O
Most/JJS/O are/VBP/O from/IN/O independent/JJ/O producers/NNS/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O regulated/JJ/O utilities/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG believes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O ride/VB/O a/DT/O wave/NN/O of/IN/O demand/NN/O stretching/VBG/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O agree/VBP/O ,/,/O predicting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O revived/VBN/O market/NN/O could/MD/O significantly/RB/O boost/VB/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O bottom/NN/O line/NN/O in/IN/O coming/VBG/O years/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O earnings/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O materially/RB/O enhanced/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1990s/CD/O or/CC/O sooner/RBR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Russell/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Leavitt/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O of/IN/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O expects/VBZ/O a/DT/O need/NN/O for/IN/O 140,000/CD/O megawatts/NNS/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O generation/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O decade/NN/O ././O
Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O own/JJ/O role/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O supplier/NN/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O changing/VBG/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O usually/RB/O took/VBD/O token/JJ/O equity/NN/O positions/NNS/O in/IN/O power/NN/O plants/NNS/O it/PRP/O supplied/VBD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O kicker/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O close/VB/O deals/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O decided/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O strategy/NN/O yet/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O could/MD/O become/VB/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O producer/NN/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O whether/IN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O the/DT/O developer/NN/O or/CC/O just/RB/O the/DT/O supplier/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Theodore/NNP/B-PERSON Stern/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O energy/NN/O and/CC/O utility/NN/O systems/NNS/O group/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG hopes/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O venture/NN/O with/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O help/VB/O fend/VB/O off/RP/O growing/VBG/O competition/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O from/IN/O such/JJ/O European/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O as/IN/O Asea/NNP/B-ORG Brown/NNP/I-ORG Boveri/NNP/I-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Siemens/NNP/B-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O British/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O smaller/JJR/O combustion/NN/O turbines/NNS/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O Japanese/JJ/O partner/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O package/VB/O and/CC/O sell/VB/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O generators/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O equipment/NN/O ././O
Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O jointly/RB/O will/MD/O bid/VB/O on/IN/O projects/NNS/O with/IN/O Misubishi/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O giving/VBG/O it/PRP/O an/DT/O edge/NN/O in/IN/O developing/VBG/O Asian/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O will/MD/O develop/VB/O new/JJ/O steam/NN/O turbine/NN/O technology/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O plants/NNS/O ordered/VBN/O by/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O even/RB/O utilize/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O 's/POS/O plants/NNS/O at/IN/O times/NNS/O to/TO/O take/VB/O advantage/NN/O of/IN/O currency/NN/O fluctuations/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Even/RB/O though/IN/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O still/RB/O compete/VB/O against/IN/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O also/RB/O work/VB/O jointly/RB/O on/IN/O some/DT/O projects/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O gain/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O sourcing/VBG/O flexibility/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Stern/NNP/B-PERSON contends/VBZ/O ././O
Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG carefully/RB/O crafted/VBD/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O because/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Justice/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O successfully/RB/O challenged/VBD/O a/DT/O proposed/VBN/O steam/NN/O turbine/NN/O joint/NN/O venture/NN/O with/IN/O Asea/NNP/B-ORG Brown/NNP/I-ORG Boveri/NNP/I-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O surge/NN/O in/IN/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O new/JJ/O power/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O filled/VBN/O primarily/RB/O by/IN/O independent/JJ/O producers/NNS/O which/WDT/O ,/,/O unlike/IN/O utilities/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O regulated/VBN/O and/CC/O therefore/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O need/VB/O government/NN/O approval/NN/O to/TO/O construct/VB/O new/JJ/O plants/NNS/O ././O
Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG expects/VBZ/O about/IN/O half/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O orders/NNS/O for/IN/O turbines/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O from/IN/O independent/JJ/O producers/NNS/O for/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG acknowledges/VBZ/O that/IN/O demand/NN/O from/IN/O independent/JJ/O producers/NNS/O could/MD/O evaporate/VB/O if/IN/O prices/NNS/O for/IN/O fuel/NN/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O or/CC/O oil/NN/O rise/VBP/O sharply/RB/O or/CC/O if/IN/O utilities/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O pressured/VBN/O by/IN/O regulators/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O down/IN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O suddenly/RB/O freed/VBN/O to/TO/O add/VB/O significant/JJ/O generating/VBG/O capacity/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O that/DT/O scenario/NN/O occurs/VBZ/O ,/,/O Westinghouse/NNP/B-ORG figures/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O prepared/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O already/RB/O is/VBZ/O gearing/VBG/O up/RP/O for/IN/O a/DT/O renaissance/NN/O of/IN/O nuclear/JJ/O power/NN/O even/RB/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O received/VBN/O an/DT/O order/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O domestic/JJ/O nuclear/JJ/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Marous/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O a/DT/O commercial/JJ/O order/NN/O by/IN/O 1995/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O AP600/NN/B-FAC nuclear/JJ/O power/NN/O plant/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O under/IN/O development/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Once/RB/O we/PRP/O see/VBP/O an/DT/O order/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O expect/VBP/O it/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O on/IN/O line/NN/O by/IN/O 2000/CD/O ././O
