Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O his/PRP$/O comments/NNS/O during/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O detailing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O plans/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O ././O
Surrounded/VBN/O by/IN/O stacks/NNS/O of/IN/O paper/NN/O ,/,/O two/CD/O computers/NNS/O and/CC/O photos/NNS/O of/IN/O himself/PRP/O boating/VBG/O and/CC/O flying/VBG/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON laid/VBD/O out/RP/O several/JJ/O changes/NNS/O he/PRP/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O ././O
First/RB/O and/CC/O foremost/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O client/NN/O service/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON recently/RB/O freed/VBD/O himself/PRP/O up/RP/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O more/JJR/O time/NN/O with/IN/O clients/NNS/O by/IN/O delegating/VBG/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O administrative/JJ/O work/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O deputy/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O to/TO/O know/VB/O clients/NNS/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O closer/JJR/O to/TO/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Lever/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O are/VBP/O planning/VBG/O joint/JJ/O visits/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O clients/NNS/O to/TO/O attempt/VB/O to/TO/O smoothly/RB/O hand/VB/O over/RP/O the/DT/O reins/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Clients/NNS/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O see/VB/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O senior/JJ/O people/NNS/O involved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O business/NN/O --/:/O not/RB/O once/IN/O a/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O two/CD/O or/CC/O three/CD/O times/NNS/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O finally/RB/O implement/VB/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O announced/VBN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O but/CC/O put/VBN/O on/IN/O hold/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG takeover/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O ,/,/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O name/VB/O one/CD/O executive/NN/O on/IN/O each/DT/O account/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O client/NN/O service/NN/O director/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O work/VB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O client/NN/O 's/POS/O single/JJ/O contact/NN/O for/IN/O all/PDT/O those/DT/O services/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O little/JJ/O or/CC/O no/DT/O integration/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O work/NN/O ,/,/O quality/NN/O is/VBZ/O spotty/JJ/O ,/,/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O single/JJ/O focus/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON complained/VBD/O to/TO/O staffers/NNS/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O was/VBD/O announced/VBN/O ././O
Industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O and/CC/O analysts/NNS/O are/VBP/O divided/VBN/O on/IN/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O up/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O task/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O one/CD/O thing/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON clearly/RB/O does/VBZ/O have/VB/O going/VBG/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O is/VBZ/O continuity/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O certain/JJ/O if/IN/O that/DT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O enough/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O indeed/RB/O quite/RB/O similar/JJ/O in/IN/O substance/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O not/RB/O in/IN/O style/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O workaholic/NN/O detailsman/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O rather/RB/O delegate/VB/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O him/PRP/O time/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O interests/NNS/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O office/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O by/IN/O contrast/NN/O ,/,/O seems/VBZ/O rarely/RB/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O loose/JJ/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O appear/VB/O at/IN/O Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Halloween/NNP/O party/NN/O Friday/NNP/O decked/VBN/O out/RP/O in/IN/O duck/NN/O feet/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O duck/NN/O hat/NN/O ,/,/O costumed/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O lame/JJ/O duck/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O expected/VBN/O margin/NN/O improvement/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O all/DT/O but/CC/O inevitable/JJ/O ,/,/O given/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O profitability/NN/O was/VBD/O dragged/VBN/O down/RP/O this/DT/O year/NN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O expensive/JJ/O move/NN/O to/TO/O luxurious/JJ/O ,/,/O oversized/JJ/O new/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE headquarters/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O ,/,/O budgeted/VBN/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 7/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O actually/RB/O came/VBD/O in/RP/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG eliminated/VBD/O the/DT/O mail/NN/O room/NN/O staff/NN/O ,/,/O closed/VBD/O the/DT/O executive/NN/O dining/NN/O room/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O after/IN/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O ,/,/O let/VBD/O go/VB/O half/PDT/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O financial/JJ/O executives/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O will/MD/O now/RB/O be/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE company/NN/O ,/,/O under/IN/O British/JJ/O accounting/NN/O rules/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O also/RB/O make/VB/O the/DT/O profit/NN/O picture/NN/O look/VB/O better/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O an/DT/O internal/JJ/O memo/NN/O ,/,/O Alex/NNP/B-PERSON Kroll/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Klein/NNP/B-PERSON decided/VBD/O to/TO/O remove/VB/O himself/PRP/O to/TO/O minimize/VB/O ``/``/O negative/JJ/O reaction/NN/O ''/''/O from/IN/O prospective/JJ/O clients/NNS/O and/CC/O others/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O prepare/VB/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O defense/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Klein/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O return/VB/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O post/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O trial/NN/O ``/``/O at/IN/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O vindicated/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Klein/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O work/VB/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Kroll/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O activities/NNS/O and/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O while/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O is/VBZ/O pending/VBG/O ././O
Wells/NNP/B-ORG Rich/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG New/NNP/O Partner/NNP/O
Wells/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/I-ORG Rich/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/I-ORG Greene/NNP/I-ORG named/VBD/O Cheryl/NNP/B-PERSON Heller/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O an/DT/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O creative/JJ/O partner/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O image/NN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O concentrates/VBZ/O on/IN/O fashion/NN/O and/CC/O visually/RB/O oriented/VBN/O advertising/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 35/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O billings/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O dissolved/VBN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O staffers/NNS/O absorbed/VBN/O by/IN/O WCRS/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Della/NNP/B-ORG Femina/NNP/I-ORG McNamee/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O in/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Heller/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O early/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O what/WP/O would/MD/O happen/VB/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Reebok/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Wells/NNP/B-ORG Rich/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O status/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O account/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O did/VBD/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
