Well/UH/O ,/,/O the/DT/O arrogant/JJ/O East/NNP/B-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC media/NNS/O have/VBP/O spoken/VBN/O again/RB/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O Going/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Green/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O editorial/NN/O ,/,/O Oct./NNP/O 17/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Having/VBG/O resided/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O great/JJ/O state/NN/O of/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O seven/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O find/VBP/O it/PRP/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O ignore/VB/O our/PRP$/O environmental/JJ/O problems/NNS/O when/WRB/O I/PRP/O start/VBP/O my/PRP$/O commute/NN/O to/TO/O work/NN/O with/IN/O eyes/NNS/O tearing/VBG/O and/CC/O head/NN/O aching/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O polluted/JJ/O air/NN/O ;/:/O when/WRB/O I/PRP/O try/VBP/O to/TO/O enjoy/VB/O the/DT/O beaches/NNS/O and/CC/O come/VBD/O home/NN/O covered/VBN/O with/IN/O tar/NN/O and/CC/O oil/NN/O ;/:/O when/WRB/O I/PRP/O hear/VBP/O of/IN/O numerous/JJ/O deaths/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O irresponsible/JJ/O processing/NN/O of/IN/O cheese/NN/O and/CC/O use/NN/O of/IN/O chemicals/NNS/O in/IN/O fruit/NN/O growing/NN/O ././O
Strange/JJ/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O hear/VB/O similar/JJ/O criticisms/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O East/NNP/B-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC activists/NNS/O who/WP/O seek/VBP/O to/TO/O clean/VB/O up/RP/O Boston/NNP/B-LOC Harbor/NNP/I-LOC or/CC/O rid/VB/O their/PRP$/O beaches/NNS/O of/IN/O medical/JJ/O waste/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O nothing/NN/O else/RB/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O initiatives/NNS/O as/IN/O these/DT/O will/MD/O provide/VB/O an/DT/O awareness/NN/O to/TO/O citizens/NNS/O and/CC/O lawmakers/NNS/O and/CC/O encourage/VB/O appropriate/JJ/O corrective/JJ/O action/NN/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Barry/NNP/I-PERSON Ventura/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
I/PRP/O realize/VBP/O you/PRP/O were/VBD/O just/RB/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O something/NN/O snotty/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O about/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O its/PRP$/O environmental/JJ/O movement/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O picking/VBG/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lloyd/NNP/I-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O say/VB/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O you/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O bad/JJ/O call/NN/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O Wright/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O all/PDT/O his/PRP$/O life/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O greatest/JJS/O lessons/NNS/O he/PRP/O learned/VBD/O were/VBD/O derived/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O study/NN/O of/IN/O nature/NN/O ././O
Obviously/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O lost/VBN/O on/IN/O you/PRP/O that/IN/O about/IN/O 75/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O these/DT/O days/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O and/CC/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O consider/VBP/O themselves/PRP/O environmentalists/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O for/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE being/VBG/O a/DT/O state/NN/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O liberal/JJ/O environmental/JJ/O loonies/NNS/O ,/,/O let/VB/O 's/PRP/O not/RB/O forget/VB/O where/WRB/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON came/VBD/O from/IN/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O Mr./NNP/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O claimed/VBD/O that/IN/O air/NN/O pollution/NN/O is/VBZ/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O trees/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O man/NN/O you/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O quoting/VBG/O to/TO/O back/VB/O up/RP/O your/PRP$/O position/NN/O that/IN/O economics/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O important/JJ/O than/IN/O the/DT/O Earth/NN/B-LOC ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lloyd/NNP/I-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON who/WP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Is/VBZ/O this/DT/O not/RB/O Anti-Christ/NNP/O ?/./O
The/DT/O Moloch/NNP/O that/WDT/O knows/VBZ/O no/DT/O God/NNP/O but/CC/O more/JJR/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Borden/NNP/I-PERSON Santa/NNP/B-GPE Monica/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE
Your/PRP$/O editorial/NN/O was/VBD/O commendable/JJ/O and/CC/O neatly/RB/O matched/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O readers/NNS/O '/POS/O comments/NNS/O in/IN/O letters/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O editor/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Alar/NN/O :/:/O Scaring/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Side/NN/O of/IN/O Caution/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
We/PRP/O may/MD/O all/DT/O hope/VB/O that/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O voters/NNS/O will/MD/O heed/VB/O the/DT/O scientific/JJ/O realities/NNS/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O university/NN/O 's/POS/O renowned/JJ/O Prof./NNP/O Tom/NNP/B-PERSON Jukes/NNP/I-PERSON provides/VBZ/O them/PRP/O and/CC/O ignore/VB/O the/DT/O charlatanry/NN/O profferred/VBN/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O ``/``/O wealthy/JJ/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE weepers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
I/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O approach/NN/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O ,/,/O not/RB/O only/RB/O to/TO/O Californians/NNPS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O to/TO/O all/DT/O Americans/NNPS/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O country/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O law/NN/O should/MD/O restrict/VB/O citizens/NNS/O as/RB/O little/JJ/O as/IN/O is/VBZ/O consistent/JJ/O with/IN/O good/JJ/O manners/NNS/O and/CC/O public/JJ/O safety/NN/O ././O
W./NNP/B-PERSON Brown/NNP/I-PERSON Morton/NNP/I-PERSON Jr/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O 170/CD/O airlines/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Transport/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG last/JJ/O year/NN/O posted/VBD/O group/NN/O net/JJ/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 125.1/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O association/NN/O 's/POS/O annual/JJ/O report/NN/O ,/,/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O released/VBN/O today/NN/O in/IN/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O IATA/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O posted/VBN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O performance/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1970s/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O attributed/VBD/O the/DT/O strong/JJ/O results/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O favorable/JJ/O economic/JJ/O climate/NN/O ,/,/O rising/VBG/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O air/NN/O travel/NN/O and/CC/O improved/VBN/O average/JJ/O yield/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O revenue/NN/O received/VBN/O per/IN/O ton/NN/O of/IN/O traffic/NN/O transported/VBN/O a/DT/O kilometer/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Systemwide/NNP/O ,/,/O IATA/NNP/B-ORG airlines/NNS/O carried/VBD/O 632/CD/O million/CD/O passengers/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O association/NN/O said/VBD/O that/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O airport/NN/O and/CC/O air/NN/O space/NN/O capacity/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O problem/NN/O facing/VBG/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O KGB/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O abolished/VBN/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O known/VBN/O for/IN/O persecuting/VBG/O dissidents/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O newspaper/NN/O Izvestia/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O newspaper/NN/O quoted/VBD/O KGB/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O Vladimir/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Kryuchkov/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O definition/NN/O of/IN/O anti-Soviet/JJ/O crimes/NNS/O had/VBD/O narrowed/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O laws/NNS/O had/VBD/O changed/VBN/O and/CC/O people/NNS/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O fear/VB/O a/DT/O simple/JJ/O slip/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tongue/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Kryuchkov/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O infamous/JJ/O 5th/JJ/B-ORG Directorate/NN/I-ORG a/DT/O new/JJ/O unit/NN/O would/MD/O work/VB/O ``/``/O to/TO/O foil/VB/O the/DT/O conspiracies/NNS/O of/IN/O foreign/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O create/VB/O and/CC/O use/VB/O organized/VBN/O anti-government/JJ/O groups/NNS/O in/IN/O our/PRP$/O country/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Rising/VBG/O inflation/NN/O in/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE makes/VBZ/O Czechoslovak/JJ/O food/NN/O ,/,/O clothing/NN/O and/CC/O shoes/NNS/O relatively/RB/O cheap/JJ/O for/IN/O visitors/NNS/O from/IN/O these/DT/O countries/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O paper/NN/O gave/VBD/O no/DT/O details/NNS/O of/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O restrictions/NNS/O would/MD/O entail/VB/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O measures/NNS/O were/VBD/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O domestic/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE biggest/JJS/O union/NN/O ,/,/O IG/NNP/B-ORG Metall/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O back/VB/O demands/NNS/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O pay/NN/O and/CC/O shorter/JJR/O hours/NNS/O with/IN/O strikes/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O automotive/JJ/O ,/,/O steel/NN/O and/CC/O engineering/NN/O industries/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O major/JJ/O goal/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O the/DT/O working/VBG/O week/NN/O to/TO/O 35/CD/O hours/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O present/JJ/O 37/CD/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O came/VBD/O news/NN/O of/IN/O alarm/NN/O in/IN/O Venice/NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O tap/VB/O gas/NN/O fields/NNS/O off/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O coast/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O comes/VBZ/O word/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O scientist/NN/O that/IN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O century/NN/O Venice/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O sink/VB/O nearly/RB/O three/CD/O times/NNS/O faster/RBR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O present/JJ/O rate/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O greenhouse/NN/O effect/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O Global/JJ/O warming/NN/O means/VBZ/O higher/JJR/O tides/NNS/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O lower/VB/O Venice/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O another/DT/O 23/CD/O inches/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O 100/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Giovanni/NNP/B-PERSON Cecconi/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG the/DT/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG Venice/NNP/I-ORG Consortium/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O consortium/NN/O of/IN/O scientists/NNS/O and/CC/O companies/NNS/O was/VBD/O set/VBN/O up/RP/O by/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O help/VB/O preserve/VB/O the/DT/O fabled/JJ/O city/NN/O of/IN/O canals/NNS/O ././O
Venice/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O sunk/VBN/O 10/CD/O inches/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O century/NN/O ././O
Intermoda/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O initially/RB/O only/RB/O send/VB/O the/DT/O textile/NN/O and/CC/O clothing/NN/O section/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Quelle/NNP/B-ORG catalog/NN/O ,/,/O translated/VBN/O into/IN/O Russian/NNP/O ,/,/O to/TO/O Soviet/JJ/O customers/NNS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O access/NN/O to/TO/O convertible/JJ/O currency/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O commission/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O EC/NNP/B-ORG television/NN/O producers/NNS/O lost/VBD/O ``/``/O important/JJ/O market/NN/O shares/NNS/O ''/''/O and/CC/O suffered/VBD/O an/DT/O ``/``/O unsustainable/JJ/O ''/''/O pressure/NN/O on/IN/O prices/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Korean/JJ/O companies/NNS/O '/POS/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O pricing/NN/O policies/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O said/VBD/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O in/IN/O clear/JJ/O violation/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O trade/NN/O rules/NNS/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE have/VBP/O no/DT/O diplomatic/JJ/O relations/NNS/O but/CC/O exchanged/VBD/O trade/NN/O offices/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Many/JJ/O programs/NNS/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O now/RB/O come/VBP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O West/NN/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O suitable/JJ/O to/TO/O our/PRP$/O culture/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O government/NN/O minister/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O star/NN/O attraction/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O national/JJ/O network/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O ``/``/O Dynasty/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O .../:/O
