I/PRP/O realize/VBP/O you/PRP/O were/VBD/O just/RB/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O something/NN/O snotty/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O about/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O its/PRP$/O environmental/JJ/O movement/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O picking/VBG/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lloyd/NNP/I-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O say/VB/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O you/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O bad/JJ/O call/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O approach/NN/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O ,/,/O not/RB/O only/RB/O to/TO/O Californians/NNPS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O to/TO/O all/DT/O Americans/NNPS/O ././O
The/DT/O 170/CD/O airlines/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Transport/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG last/JJ/O year/NN/O posted/VBD/O group/NN/O net/JJ/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.5/CD/O billion/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 125.1/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Systemwide/NNP/O ,/,/O IATA/NNP/B-ORG airlines/NNS/O carried/VBD/O 632/CD/O million/CD/O passengers/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O association/NN/O said/VBD/O that/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O airport/NN/O and/CC/O air/NN/O space/NN/O capacity/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O problem/NN/O facing/VBG/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O KGB/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O abolished/VBN/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O known/VBN/O for/IN/O persecuting/VBG/O dissidents/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O newspaper/NN/O Izvestia/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O newspaper/NN/O quoted/VBD/O KGB/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O Vladimir/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Kryuchkov/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O definition/NN/O of/IN/O anti-Soviet/JJ/O crimes/NNS/O had/VBD/O narrowed/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O laws/NNS/O had/VBD/O changed/VBN/O and/CC/O people/NNS/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O fear/VB/O a/DT/O simple/JJ/O slip/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O tongue/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O paper/NN/O gave/VBD/O no/DT/O details/NNS/O of/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O restrictions/NNS/O would/MD/O entail/VB/O but/CC/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O measures/NNS/O were/VBD/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O the/DT/O domestic/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE biggest/JJS/O union/NN/O ,/,/O IG/NNP/B-ORG Metall/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O back/VB/O demands/NNS/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O pay/NN/O and/CC/O shorter/JJR/O hours/NNS/O with/IN/O strikes/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O automotive/JJ/O ,/,/O steel/NN/O and/CC/O engineering/NN/O industries/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O major/JJ/O goal/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O cut/VB/O the/DT/O working/VBG/O week/NN/O to/TO/O 35/CD/O hours/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O present/JJ/O 37/CD/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O came/VBD/O news/NN/O of/IN/O alarm/NN/O in/IN/O Venice/NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O tap/VB/O gas/NN/O fields/NNS/O off/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O coast/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O consortium/NN/O of/IN/O scientists/NNS/O and/CC/O companies/NNS/O was/VBD/O set/VBN/O up/IN/O by/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O help/VB/O preserve/VB/O the/DT/O fabled/JJ/O city/NN/O of/IN/O canals/NNS/O ././O
Venice/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O sunk/VBN/O 10/CD/O inches/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O century/NN/O ././O
Intermoda/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O initially/RB/O only/RB/O send/VB/O the/DT/O textile/NN/O and/CC/O clothing/NN/O section/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Quelle/NNP/B-ORG catalog/NN/O ,/,/O translated/VBN/O into/IN/O Russian/NNP/O ,/,/O to/TO/O Soviet/JJ/O customers/NNS/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O access/NN/O to/TO/O convertible/JJ/O currency/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O commission/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O EC/NNP/B-ORG television/NN/O producers/NNS/O lost/VBD/O ``/``/O important/JJ/O market/NN/O shares/NNS/O ''/''/O and/CC/O suffered/VBD/O an/DT/O ``/``/O unsustainable/JJ/O ''/''/O pressure/NN/O on/IN/O prices/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Korean/JJ/O companies/NNS/O '/POS/O marketing/NN/O and/CC/O pricing/NN/O policies/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O it/PRP/O said/VBD/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O in/IN/O clear/JJ/O violation/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O trade/NN/O rules/NNS/O ././O
South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE have/VBP/O no/DT/O diplomatic/JJ/O relations/NNS/O but/CC/O exchanged/VBD/O trade/NN/O offices/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
