Judge/NNP/O Albert/NNP/B-PERSON Green/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O Cook/NNP/B-ORG County/NNP/I-ORG Circuit/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O also/RB/O recognized/VBD/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O ,/,/O filed/VBN/O last/JJ/O May/NNP/O by/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Cynthia/NNP/B-PERSON Langendorf/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O class/NN/O action/NN/O covering/VBG/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O Irving/NNP/B-ORG customers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O plaintiffs/NNS/O accused/VBD/O Irving/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O paying/VBG/O less/JJR/O interest/NN/O than/IN/O promised/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O marketing/NN/O brochure/NN/O ././O
Irving/NNP/B-ORG maintained/VBD/O --/:/O and/CC/O still/RB/O does/VBZ/O --/:/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O actions/NNS/O were/VBD/O proper/JJ/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O account/NN/O agreements/NNS/O with/IN/O customers/NNS/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O settlement/NN/O ,/,/O customers/NNS/O with/IN/O valid/JJ/O claims/NNS/O --/:/O to/TO/O be/VB/O submitted/VBN/O by/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 15/CD/O --/:/O will/MD/O receive/VB/O ``/``/O valuable/JJ/O bank/NN/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O credit/NN/O cards/NNS/O with/IN/O reduced/VBN/O finance/NN/O charges/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Larry/NNP/B-PERSON Drury/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O attorney/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O plaintiffs/NNS/O ,/,/O valued/VBD/O the/DT/O settlement/NN/O at/IN/O between/IN/O $/$/O 6/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O Bank/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O in/IN/O Manhattan/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Owen/NNP/B-PERSON Brady/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O maximum/JJ/O ,/,/O outside/JJ/O figure/NN/O ././O
