Upset/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O says/VBZ/O are/VBP/O its/PRP$/O exclusive/JJ/O trademarks/NNS/O ,/,/O Hells/NNP/B-ORG Angels/NNP/I-ORG Motorcycle/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O fighting/VBG/O back/RB/O --/:/O in/IN/O court/NN/O ././O
Nam/NNP/O Angels/NNPS/O depicts/VBZ/O a/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O cycle/NN/O gang/NN/O 's/POS/O members/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O mercenary/JJ/O mission/NN/O to/TO/O Viet/NNP/B-GPE Nam/NNP/I-GPE during/IN/O the/DT/O war/NN/O years/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O being/VBG/O broadcast/VBN/O on/IN/O cable/NN/O television/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O movie/NN/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O distributed/VBN/O on/IN/O videocassettes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O alleges/VBZ/O in/IN/O seeking/VBG/O unspecified/JJ/O damages/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O named/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O is/VBZ/O Media/NNP/B-ORG Home/NNP/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Culver/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O its/PRP$/O parent/NN/O ,/,/O Heron/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O Broadstar/NNP/B-ORG Television/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O holders/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O copyright/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O movie/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O Concord/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O ``/``/O unfounded/JJ/O ''/''/O but/CC/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O further/RB/O ././O
Besides/IN/O being/VBG/O upset/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O film/NN/O 's/POS/O use/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Hells/NNP/B-ORG Angels/NNPS/I-ORG name/NN/O and/CC/O logos/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Angels/NNPS/B-ORG are/VBP/O angry/JJ/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O depiction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O movie/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O absolutely/RB/O no/DT/O way/NN/O our/PRP$/O board/NN/O or/CC/O membership/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O approved/VBN/O the/DT/O portrayal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Hells/NNP/I-ORG Angels/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O this/DT/O movie/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Christie/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O club/NN/O 's/POS/O Ventura/NNP/B-GPE chapter/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Portrayal/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O members/NNS/O as/IN/O disloyal/JJ/O to/TO/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O is/VBZ/O totally/RB/O contrary/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O important/JJ/O values/NNS/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O organization/NN/O --/:/O loyalty/NN/O and/CC/O trust/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Nam/NNP/O Angels/NNPS/O shows/VBZ/O Angels/NNPS/O fighting/VBG/O with/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O and/CC/O also/RB/O depicts/VBZ/O them/PRP/O as/IN/O showing/VBG/O no/DT/O remorse/NN/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O member/NN/O is/VBZ/O killed/VBN/O ././O
Both/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O actions/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O characteristic/JJ/O of/IN/O real/JJ/O Hells/NNP/B-ORG Angels/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Christie/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Hells/NNP/B-ORG Angels/NNPS/I-ORG was/VBD/O formed/VBN/O in/IN/O 1948/CD/O and/CC/O incorporated/VBN/O in/IN/O 1966/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O 26/CD/O chapters/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O 40/CD/O chapters/NNS/O in/IN/O foreign/JJ/O countries/NNS/O ././O
