Insurance/NN/O premiums/NNS/O for/IN/O one/CD/O small/JJ/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE concern/NN/O went/VBD/O up/RB/O 130/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O increase/NN/O coming/VBG/O after/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O three/CD/O workers/NNS/O developed/VBD/O a/DT/O herniated/VBN/O disk/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O her/PRP$/O employer/NN/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O afford/VB/O the/DT/O rate/NN/O increases/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O she/PRP/O fears/VBZ/O she/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O find/VB/O another/DT/O job/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O benefit/NN/O plan/NN/O covering/VBG/O her/PRP$/O ailment/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O lawmakers/NNS/O may/MD/O seek/VB/O legislation/NN/O to/TO/O limit/VB/O overly/RB/O restrictive/JJ/O insurance/NN/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O business/NN/O analysts/NNS/O blame/VBP/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O on/IN/O tough/JJ/O competition/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O say/VBP/O insurance/NN/O companies/NNS/O use/VBP/O policies/NNS/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O excluding/VBG/O bad/JJ/O risks/NNS/O because/IN/O their/PRP$/O competitors/NNS/O do/VBP/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Waxman/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Democratic/NNP/O Sen./NNP/O Edward/NNP/B-PERSON Kennedy/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O proposed/VBN/O regulation/NN/O to/TO/O deal/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O contends/VBZ/O that/IN/O similar/JJ/O mandates/NNS/O have/VBP/O driven/VBN/O up/IN/O insurance/NN/O costs/NNS/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dorsch/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O HIAA/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O proposal/NN/O to/TO/O establish/VB/O a/DT/O privately/RB/O funded/VBN/O reinsurance/NN/O mechanism/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O cover/VB/O small/JJ/O groups/NNS/O that/WDT/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O insurance/NN/O without/IN/O excluding/VBG/O certain/JJ/O employees/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O complexities/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O insurance/NN/O problem/NN/O make/VBP/O the/DT/O outcome/NN/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O predict/VB/O ././O
