In/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O step/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O that/WDT/O began/VBD/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O create/VB/O a/DT/B-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Space/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O consolidate/VB/O several/JJ/O divisions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O were/VBD/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O mediator/NN/O this/DT/O morning/NN/O ././O
Boeing/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O said/VBN/O repeatedly/RB/O it/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O expand/VB/O its/PRP$/O offer/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O machinists/NNS/O have/VBP/O responded/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O good/JJ/O enough/RB/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O resolve/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O striking/JJ/O 57,000/CD/O machinists/NNS/O might/MD/O be/VB/O weakening/VBG/O ././O
About/IN/O 1,000/CD/O strikers/NNS/O signed/VBD/O petitions/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O calling/VBG/O for/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Machinists/NNPS/B-ORG representatives/NNS/O to/TO/O schedule/VB/O new/JJ/O meetings/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O met/VBN/O since/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 18/CD/O ././O
While/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O commercial/JJ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O booming/JJ/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O military/JJ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O feeling/VBG/O the/DT/O effects/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O declining/VBG/O defense/NN/O budget/NN/O after/IN/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O buildup/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/JJ/B-PERSON presidency/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O May/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O consolidated/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Aerospace/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Electronics/NNP/I-ORG groups/NNS/O ;/:/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Space/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O contain/VB/O the/DT/O Aerospace/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Electronics/NNP/I-ORG division/NN/O and/CC/O Advanced/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O both/DT/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Seattle/NNP/B-GPE area/NN/O ;/:/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG Helicopters/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG Military/NNP/I-ORG Airplanes/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O Wichita/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kan./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O ArgoSystems/NNPS/B-ORG in/IN/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
B./NNP/B-PERSON Dan/NNP/I-PERSON Pinick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG Aerospace/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Electronics/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O become/VB/O president/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O become/VB/O operational/JJ/O Jan./NNP/O 2/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O will/MD/O reorganize/VB/O all/PDT/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O in/IN/O Wichita/NNP/B-GPE into/IN/O military/JJ/O and/CC/O commercial/JJ/O divisions/NNS/O ././O
All/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O will/MD/O reduce/VB/O its/PRP$/O overhead/NN/O and/CC/O streamline/VB/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O agreed/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Howard/NNP/B-PERSON Rubel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O with/IN/O C.J./NNP/B-ORG Lawrence/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/I-ORG Morgan/NNP/I-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O shift/NN/O reflects/VBZ/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG confidence/NN/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Pinick/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O described/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Rubel/NNP/B-PERSON as/IN/O an/DT/O expert/NN/O on/IN/O doing/VBG/O business/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O military/NN/O ././O
``/``/O His/PRP$/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O business/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O successful/JJ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O environment/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Rubel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
