The/DT/O media/NNS/O 's/POS/O treatment/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG during/IN/O the/DT/O Vietnam/NNP/O War/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Carter/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O 's/POS/O denigration/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O public/NN/O scapegoating/NN/O of/IN/O Lt./NNP/O Col./NNP/O Oliver/NNP/B-PERSON North/NNP/I-PERSON have/VBP/O all/DT/O served/VBD/O to/TO/O emasculate/VB/O the/DT/O poor/JJ/O souls/NNS/O who/WP/O live/VBP/O there/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O resulting/VBG/O haunted/VBN/O house/NN/O tends/VBZ/O to/TO/O reward/VB/O followership/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O leadership/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O creates/VBZ/O guilt/NN/O about/IN/O wearing/VBG/O the/DT/O uniform/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O raises/VBZ/O doubt/NN/O about/IN/O having/VBG/O the/DT/O will/NN/O to/TO/O fulfill/VB/O the/DT/O ghosts/NNS/O '/POS/O role/NN/O ,/,/O i.e./FW/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O win/VB/O if/IN/O called/VBN/O on/IN/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O the/DT/O Halloween/NNP/O season/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O time/NN/O for/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O be/VB/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O funding/NN/O for/IN/O some/DT/O ghostbusting/NN/O equipment/NN/O ././O
Mike/NNP/B-PERSON Greece/NNP/I-PERSON Former/NNP/O Air/NNP/B-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG Career/NNP/O Officer/NNP/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE
Where/WRB/O does/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Lehman/NNP/B-PERSON get/VB/O off/RP/O castigating/VBG/O Gen./NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Marshall/NNP/I-PERSON for/IN/O muscling/VBG/O in/RP/O on/IN/O naval/JJ/O prerogatives/NNS/O ?/./O
Ever/RB/O since/IN/O the/DT/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON Thayer/NNP/I-PERSON Mahan/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE naval/JJ/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O naval/JJ/O historian/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON Roosevelt/NNP/I-PERSON the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O service/NN/O most/RBS/O favored/VBN/O by/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE officialdom/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lehman/NNP/B-PERSON overlooks/VBZ/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG possesses/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O air/NN/O force/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O carrier/NN/O fleet/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O army/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O Marines/NNPS/B-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O has/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O air/NN/O force/NN/O ././O
Of/IN/O course/NN/O these/DT/O turf/JJ/O battles/NNS/O are/VBP/O unseemly/JJ/O ,/,/O wasteful/JJ/O and/CC/O potentially/RB/O dangerous/JJ/O and/CC/O should/MD/O be/VB/O resolved/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O interest/NN/O of/IN/O national/JJ/O security/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Lehman/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O answer/NN/O ././O
L.H./NNP/B-PERSON Blum/NNP/I-PERSON Beaumont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE
I/PRP/O agree/VBP/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lehman/NNP/B-PERSON 100/CD/O %/NN/O !/./O
I/PRP/O personally/RB/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O hasten/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Lehman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O demise/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O I/PRP/O can/MD/O see/VB/O him/PRP/O figuring/VBG/O prominently/RB/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O article/NN/O ././O
Carl/NNP/B-PERSON Banerian/NNP/I-PERSON Jr/NNP/I-PERSON ././I-PERSON Birmingham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mich/NNP/B-GPE ././O
