Margaret/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON instinctive/JJ/O response/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O upheaval/NN/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O promise/VB/O business/NN/O as/IN/O usual/JJ/O ././O
That/DT/O may/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O thing/NN/O she/PRP/O needs/VBZ/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O clears/VBZ/O from/IN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O storm/NN/O of/IN/O resignations/NNS/O and/CC/O reshufflings/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O faces/VBZ/O a/DT/O daunting/VBG/O job/NN/O of/IN/O rebuilding/VBG/O confidence/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O policies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O and/CC/O her/PRP$/O new/JJ/O chancellor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O exchequer/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O untested/JJ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Major/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O need/VBP/O to/TO/O haul/VB/O the/DT/O country/NN/O through/IN/O something/NN/O like/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O down/RP/O inflation/NN/O and/CC/O set/VB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O moving/VBG/O again/RB/O ././O
Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O to/TO/O come/VB/O to/TO/O terms/NNS/O with/IN/O European/JJ/O economic/JJ/O integration/NN/O ,/,/O beginning/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Monetary/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O committed/VBN/O to/TO/O joining/VBG/O fully/RB/O someday/RB/O ././O
Finally/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O convince/VB/O a/DT/O rattled/JJ/O financial/JJ/O community/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O voters/NNS/O --/:/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O proceeding/VBG/O coherently/RB/O toward/IN/O its/PRP$/O goals/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O sounds/VBZ/O like/IN/O the/DT/O work/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O deadline/NN/O is/VBZ/O late/RB/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O call/VB/O another/DT/O national/JJ/O election/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O worrying/VBG/O her/PRP$/O supporters/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O cycle/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O kilter/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O political/JJ/O timetable/NN/O ././O
She/PRP/O could/MD/O end/VB/O up/RP/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O fourth/JJ/O term/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O economy/NN/O sick/JJ/O with/IN/O inflation/NN/O ,/,/O high/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O heavy/JJ/O trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O ././O
Though/NNP/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O pulled/VBN/O through/IN/O other/JJ/O crises/NNS/O ,/,/O supporters/NNS/O wonder/VBP/O if/IN/O her/PRP$/O steely/JJ/O ,/,/O autocratic/JJ/O ways/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O formula/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O 's/POS/O insistence/NN/O on/IN/O keeping/VBG/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O coterie/NN/O of/IN/O advisers/NNS/O --/:/O including/VBG/O an/DT/O economic/JJ/O guru/NN/O who/WP/O openly/RB/O criticized/VBD/O former/JJ/O Chancellor/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Exchequer/NNP/O Nigel/NNP/B-PERSON Lawson/NNP/I-PERSON --/:/O confused/VBD/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O community/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O strategy/NN/O of/IN/O playing/VBG/O the/DT/O two/CD/O experts/NNS/O off/IN/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O blew/VBD/O up/IN/O :/:/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON quit/VBP/O in/IN/O exasperation/NN/O and/CC/O Sir/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Walters/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O adviser/NN/O ,/,/O announced/VBD/O his/PRP$/O resignation/NN/O within/IN/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O confusion/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O costly/JJ/O ././O
Currency/NN/O traders/NNS/O ,/,/O suspecting/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Major/NNP/B-PERSON wo/MD/O n't/RB/O defend/VB/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O strenuously/RB/O ,/,/O sent/VBD/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O currency/NN/O sharply/RB/O lower/JJR/O Friday/NNP/O against/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O and/CC/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O mark/NN/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O expect/VBP/O further/JJ/O jitters/NNS/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O continuing/VBG/O slide/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O could/MD/O force/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O push/VB/O through/IN/O another/DT/O rise/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O base/NN/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O currently/RB/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O could/MD/O shove/VB/O a/DT/O weak/JJ/O economy/NN/O into/IN/O recession/NN/O ././O
Economists/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O anticipating/VBG/O a/DT/O slump/NN/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O now/RB/O say/VBP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O deeper/JJR/O and/CC/O longer/JJR/O than/IN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O thought/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O mild/JJ/O slowdown/NN/O probably/RB/O would/MD/O have/VB/O run/VBN/O its/PRP$/O course/NN/O by/IN/O early/JJ/O 1991/CD/O ,/,/O economists/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O grueling/VBG/O downturn/NN/O now/RB/O expected/VBN/O could/MD/O stretch/VB/O into/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Recovery/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O hampered/VBN/O if/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O major/JJ/O trading/VBG/O partners/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O enjoying/VBG/O robust/JJ/O economic/JJ/O activity/NN/O ,/,/O cool/VBP/O off/RB/O as/RB/O expected/VBN/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O 1990/CD/O and/CC/O 1991/CD/O ././O
That/DT/O would/MD/O leave/VB/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON little/JJ/O room/NN/O for/IN/O maneuver/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O the/DT/O Tories/NNPS/O to/TO/O win/VB/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O election/NN/O ,/,/O voters/NNS/O will/MD/O need/VB/O to/TO/O sense/VB/O economic/JJ/O improvement/NN/O for/IN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O beforehand/RB/O ././O
Though/NNP/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O need/VB/O to/TO/O call/VB/O an/DT/O election/NN/O until/IN/O June/NNP/O 1992/CD/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O would/MD/O prefer/VB/O doing/VBG/O so/RB/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O 1991/CD/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O shows/VBZ/O no/DT/O sign/NN/O of/IN/O turning/VBG/O around/RB/O in/IN/O about/IN/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O time/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O very/RB/O vulnerable/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Barnes/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O lecturer/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG London/NNP/I-ORG School/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economics/NNP/I-ORG ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O equally/RB/O pressing/VBG/O deadline/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O to/TO/O define/VB/O its/PRP$/O monetary/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG ././O
At/IN/O a/DT/O June/NNP/O EC/NNP/B-ORG summit/NN/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON appeared/VBD/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O her/PRP$/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O full/JJ/O EMS/NNP/B-ORG membership/NN/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O join/VB/O once/RB/O its/PRP$/O inflation/NN/O rate/NN/O fell/VBD/O and/CC/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG liberalized/VBD/O capital/NN/O movements/NNS/O ././O
Since/IN/O then/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O left/VBN/O observers/NNS/O wondering/VBG/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O ever/RB/O meant/VBD/O to/TO/O join/VB/O ././O
That/DT/O produced/VBD/O little/JJ/O reaction/NN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O boss/NN/O ,/,/O reinforcing/VBG/O speculation/NN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O would/MD/O use/VB/O its/PRP$/O two/CD/O conditions/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O pretext/NN/O for/IN/O avoiding/VBG/O full/JJ/O EMS/NNP/B-ORG membership/NN/O ././O
Sir/NNP/O Geoffrey/NNP/B-PERSON Howe/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O deputy/JJ/O prime/JJ/O minister/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON ally/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O EMS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O signaled/VBN/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O pressing/VBG/O for/IN/O early/JJ/O membership/NN/O ././O
Of/IN/O immediate/JJ/O concern/NN/O is/VBZ/O whether/IN/O the/DT/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON government/NN/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O policy/NN/O of/IN/O tracking/VBG/O the/DT/O monetary/JJ/O policies/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O German/NNP/O Bundesbank/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O responding/VBG/O in/IN/O kind/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE authorities/NNS/O move/VBP/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O Conservatives/NNPS/O rally/VBP/O around/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON during/IN/O the/DT/O crisis/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O harbor/VBP/O hopes/NNS/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O debacle/NN/O will/MD/O prompt/VB/O change/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O more/JJR/O of/IN/O this/DT/O wayward/JJ/O behavior/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Sir/NNP/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Hordern/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O backbench/JJ/O Tory/NNP/O member/NN/O of/IN/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O party/NN/O is/VBZ/O fed/VBN/O up/RP/O with/IN/O sackings/NNS/O of/IN/O good/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O an/DT/O unrealistic/JJ/O expectation/NN/O ././O
As/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON declared/VBD/O she/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O debate/NN/O in/IN/O her/PRP$/O cabinet/NN/O ;/:/O she/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O strong/JJ/O government/NN/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O she/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O intend/VB/O to/TO/O change/VB/O her/PRP$/O style/NN/O and/CC/O denied/VBD/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O authoritarian/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O Nonsense/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O told/VBD/O an/DT/O interviewer/NN/O yesterday/NN/O on/IN/O London/NNP/B-ORG Weekend/NNP/I-ORG Television/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O staying/VBG/O my/PRP$/O own/JJ/O sweet/JJ/O ,/,/O reasonable/JJ/O self/NN/O ././O
