In/IN/O the/DT/O aftermath/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE massacre/NN/O on/IN/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O ,/,/O economists/NNS/O advanced/VBD/O wildly/RB/O divergent/JJ/O views/NNS/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE would/MD/O be/VB/O affected/VBN/O ././O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O upbeat/NN/O was/VBD/O BT/NNP/B-ORG Brokerage/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG Asia/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Ltd/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O June/NNP/O 5/CD/O reaction/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Bankers/NNPS/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O proclaimed/VBD/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O ``/``/O shockproof/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Others/NNS/O were/VBD/O more/RBR/O cautious/JJ/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O July/NNP/O analysis/NN/O titled/VBN/O ``/``/O From/IN/O Euphoria/NNP/O to/TO/O Despair/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O W.I./NNP/B-ORG Carr/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG Far/NNP/I-ORG East/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O securities/NNS/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O eroding/VBG/O confidence/NN/O might/MD/O undermine/VB/O future/JJ/O economic/JJ/O development/NN/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O business/NN/O activity/NN/O in/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE staggering/VBG/O along/RB/O at/IN/O an/DT/O uneven/JJ/O pace/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O itself/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O locked/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O struggle/NN/O between/IN/O hope/NN/O and/CC/O fear/NN/O ././O
Manufacturers/NNS/O have/VBP/O survived/VBN/O the/DT/O turmoil/NN/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE largely/RB/O unscathed/JJ/O ././O
Waning/JJ/O demand/NN/O reported/VBN/O by/IN/O importers/NNS/O ,/,/O retailers/NNS/O and/CC/O even/RB/O fancy/JJ/O restaurants/NNS/O all/DT/O reinforce/VBP/O a/DT/O profile/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O community/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O sharply/RB/O tightening/VBG/O its/PRP$/O belt/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O many/JJ/O economists/NNS/O and/CC/O businessmen/NNS/O see/VBP/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O those/DT/O incongruities/NNS/O underscore/VBP/O a/DT/O paradox/NN/O that/WDT/O seems/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O bedevil/VB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O 1990s/CD/O ././O
That/DT/O paradox/NN/O is/VBZ/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE economically/RB/O rewarding/JJ/O yet/CC/O politically/RB/O perilous/JJ/O relationship/NN/O with/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O model/NN/O of/IN/O capitalist/JJ/O efficiency/NN/O on/IN/O southern/JJ/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O doorstep/NN/O ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE prospects/NNS/O look/VBP/O good/JJ/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O land/NN/O and/CC/O labor/NN/O offer/VBP/O inexpensive/JJ/O alternatives/NNS/O to/TO/O local/JJ/O industry/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O decade/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O communist/NN/O nation/NN/O emerged/VBD/O from/IN/O isolation/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O burgeoning/VBG/O trade/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O West/NN/O has/VBZ/O lifted/VBN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE status/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O regional/JJ/O business/NN/O center/NN/O ././O
These/DT/O benefits/NNS/O seem/VBP/O secure/JJ/O despite/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O current/JJ/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O political/JJ/O troubles/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O to/TO/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O China/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O purely/RB/O business/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O the/DT/O sovereign/JJ/O power/NN/O that/IN/O ,/,/O come/VB/O 1997/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O take/VB/O over/RP/O this/DT/O British/JJ/O colony/NN/O ././O
China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leaders/NNS/O have/VBP/O promised/VBN/O generous/JJ/O liberties/NNS/O for/IN/O post-1997/JJ/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ././O
That/DT/O promise/NN/O sounds/VBZ/O shaky/JJ/O now/RB/O that/IN/O those/DT/O same/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O have/VBP/O fallen/VBN/O back/RB/O on/IN/O Marxist/JJ/O dogma/NN/O and/CC/O brute/JJ/O force/NN/O to/TO/O crush/VB/O their/PRP$/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O democracy/NN/O movement/NN/O ././O
Outflows/NNS/O of/IN/O people/NNS/O and/CC/O capital/NN/O from/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE have/VBP/O been/VBN/O growing/VBG/O since/IN/O the/DT/O sovereignty/NN/O issue/NN/O first/RB/O arose/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/CD/O ././O
A/DT/O widely/RB/O held/VBN/O assumption/NN/O all/DT/O along/IN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O that/IN/O ,/,/O given/VBN/O its/PRP$/O robust/JJ/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE will/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O attract/VB/O sufficient/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O money/NN/O and/CC/O talent/NN/O to/TO/O comfortably/RB/O offset/VB/O the/DT/O outflows/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O emigration/NN/O and/CC/O investment/NN/O abroad/RB/O soaring/VBG/O since/IN/O June/NNP/O 4/CD/O ,/,/O that/DT/O assumption/NN/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O seems/VBZ/O so/RB/O safe/JJ/O ././O
Investment/NN/O and/CC/O emigration/NN/O plans/NNS/O take/VBP/O time/NN/O to/TO/O come/VB/O to/TO/O fruition/NN/O ././O
Only/RB/O four/CD/O months/NNS/O have/VBP/O passed/VBN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE massacre/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O few/JJ/O are/VBP/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O predict/VB/O its/PRP$/O ultimate/JJ/O impact/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O consensus/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O and/CC/O people/NNS/O may/MD/O leave/VB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE than/IN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O thought/VBN/O likely/RB/O ././O
This/DT/O expected/VBN/O blow/NN/O has/VBZ/O cast/VBN/O a/DT/O pall/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O 's/POS/O prospects/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O question/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O see/VBP/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O how/WRB/O long/JJ/O such/JJ/O uncertainty/NN/O will/MD/O last/VB/O ././O
Maureen/NNP/B-PERSON Fraser/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O economist/NN/O with/IN/O W.I./NNP/B-ORG Carr/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O France/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Banque/NNP/B-ORG Indosuez/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O believes/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O territory/NN/O may/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O regain/VB/O its/PRP$/O momentum/NN/O until/IN/O some/DT/O time/NN/O after/IN/O 1997/CD/O ././O
It/PRP/O may/MD/O experience/VB/O an/DT/O upswing/NN/O or/CC/O two/CD/O in/IN/O between/IN/O ././O
But/CC/O with/IN/O local/JJ/O investors/NNS/O shaken/VBN/O by/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O political/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O turmoil/NN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O a/DT/O genuine/JJ/O recovery/NN/O may/MD/O not/RB/O arrive/VB/O until/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE can/MD/O prove/VB/O itself/PRP/O secure/JJ/O under/IN/O Chinese/JJ/O sovereignty/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Investors/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O significant/JJ/O slowdown/NN/O in/IN/O economic/JJ/O activity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O runup/NN/O to/TO/O 1997/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O advise/VB/O caution/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O are/VBP/O split/VBN/O roughly/RB/O between/IN/O optimists/NNS/O who/WP/O expect/VBP/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O hum/VB/O along/RB/O as/RB/O before/IN/O and/CC/O pessimists/NNS/O who/WP/O foresee/VBP/O irreparable/JJ/O chaos/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O interviews/NNS/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
The/DT/O consensus/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O dubs/VBZ/O ``/``/O realists/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O economy/NN/O will/MD/O grow/VB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O 1990s/CD/O at/IN/O annual/JJ/O rates/NNS/O averaging/VBG/O between/IN/O 3/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Such/PDT/O a/DT/O pace/NN/O of/IN/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O respectable/JJ/O for/IN/O mature/JJ/O industrialized/VBN/O economies/NNS/O ,/,/O would/MD/O be/VB/O unusually/RB/O slow/JJ/O for/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Only/RB/O twice/RB/O since/IN/O the/DT/O 1960s/CD/O has/VBZ/O annual/JJ/O gross/JJ/O domestic/JJ/O product/NN/O growth/NN/O here/RB/O fallen/VBN/O below/IN/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O consecutive/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O has/VBZ/O averaged/VBN/O 8.3/CD/O %/NN/O annually/RB/O ././O
Given/VBN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE record/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mushkat/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O realists/NNS/O ''/''/O might/MD/O have/VB/O sounded/VBN/O unduly/RB/O conservative/JJ/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O interviews/NNS/O took/VBD/O place/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O circumstances/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O scenario/NN/O no/RB/O longer/RB/O seems/VBZ/O unrealistic/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O city/NN/O could/MD/O lose/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O entrepreneurial/JJ/O flavor/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O could/MD/O lose/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O dynamism/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Mushkat/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Baring/NNP/B-ORG Securities/NNPS/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG Hong/NNP/I-ORG Kong/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Barings/NNPS/B-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ././O ``/``/O
It/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O disaster/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O just/RB/O means/VBZ/O that/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE would/MD/O become/VB/O a/DT/O less/RBR/O exciting/JJ/O place/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Going/VBG/O by/IN/O official/JJ/O forecasts/NNS/O of/IN/O GDP/NNP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O measures/VBZ/O the/DT/O colony/NN/O 's/POS/O output/NN/O of/IN/O goods/NNS/O and/CC/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O minus/CC/O foreign/JJ/O income/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Mushkat/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O realists/NNS/O ''/''/O seem/VBP/O relatively/RB/O close/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O mark/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O taking/VBG/O into/IN/O account/NN/O the/DT/O fallout/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O China/NNP/B-GPE crisis/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O projected/VBN/O 1989/CD/O GDP/NNP/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O updated/VBN/O forecast/NN/O ,/,/O published/VBN/O Aug./NNP/O 25/CD/O ,/,/O compares/VBZ/O with/IN/O an/DT/O earlier/JJR/O forecast/NN/O of/IN/O 6/CD/O %/NN/O published/VBN/O March/NNP/O 1/CD/O and/CC/O a/DT/O 7.4/CD/O %/NN/O rate/NN/O achieved/VBN/O in/IN/O
Sir/NNP/O Piers/NNP/B-PERSON Jacobs/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE financial/JJ/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O a/DT/O further/RB/O downward/JJ/O revision/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O justified/VBN/O unless/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O stages/VBZ/O a/DT/O more/RBR/O convincing/JJ/O rally/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O anything/NN/O like/IN/O a/DT/O doomsday/NN/O scenario/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O clearly/RB/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O entering/VBG/O a/DT/O difficult/JJ/O period/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Many/JJ/O factors/NNS/O besides/IN/O a/DT/O dread/NN/O of/IN/O 1997/CD/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O bearing/NN/O on/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE economy/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O concerns/VBZ/O Japanese/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ././O
Barely/RB/O visible/JJ/O on/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE property/NN/O scene/NN/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O by/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O become/VBN/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O investor/NN/O ,/,/O spending/VBG/O $/$/O 602/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O has/VBZ/O grown/VBN/O relatively/RB/O quiet/JJ/O since/IN/O the/DT/O China/NNP/B-GPE crisis/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O if/IN/O the/DT/O Japanese/NNPS/O return/VBP/O in/IN/O force/NN/O ,/,/O their/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O might/NN/O could/MD/O compensate/VB/O to/TO/O some/DT/O extent/NN/O for/IN/O local/JJ/O investors/NNS/O '/POS/O waning/VBG/O commitment/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O --/:/O and/CC/O critical/JJ/O --/:/O factor/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE biggest/JJS/O export/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O China/NNP/B-GPE crisis/NN/O ,/,/O weak/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE demand/NN/O was/VBD/O slowing/VBG/O local/JJ/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
Conversely/RB/O ,/,/O strong/JJ/O consumer/NN/O spending/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O helped/VBD/O propel/VB/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O economy/NN/O at/IN/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O twice/RB/O its/PRP$/O current/JJ/O rate/NN/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O economists/NNS/O maintain/VBP/O that/IN/O global/JJ/O forces/NNS/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O govern/VB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE economic/JJ/O rhythm/NN/O ././O
Once/IN/O external/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE demand/NN/O ,/,/O swing/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O territory/NN/O 's/POS/O favor/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O argue/VBP/O ,/,/O local/JJ/O businessmen/NNS/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O overcome/VB/O their/PRP$/O 1997/CD/O worries/NNS/O and/CC/O continue/VB/O doing/VBG/O business/NN/O as/IN/O usual/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O economic/JJ/O arguments/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O solid/JJ/O ,/,/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O necessarily/RB/O impress/VB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE 5.7/CD/O million/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
Many/DT/O are/VBP/O refugees/NNS/O ,/,/O having/VBG/O fled/VBN/O China/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O unending/JJ/O cycles/NNS/O of/IN/O political/JJ/O repression/NN/O and/CC/O poverty/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Communist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG took/VBD/O power/NN/O in/IN/O 1949/CD/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O those/DT/O now/RB/O planning/VBG/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ca/MD/O n't/RB/O easily/RB/O be/VB/O swayed/VBN/O by/IN/O momentary/JJ/O improvements/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O colony/NN/O 's/POS/O political/JJ/O and/CC/O economic/JJ/O climate/NN/O ././O
Emigration/NN/O applications/NNS/O soared/VBD/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O China/NNP/B-GPE ratified/VBD/O their/PRP$/O accord/NN/O on/IN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE future/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE most/JJS/O prosperous/JJ/O year/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O 30,000/CD/O left/VBD/O ,/,/O up/IN/O 58/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O 45,000/CD/O went/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O predicts/VBZ/O that/IN/O annual/JJ/O outflows/NNS/O will/MD/O level/VB/O off/RB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O at/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O 60,000/CD/O --/:/O a/DT/O projection/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O widely/RB/O regarded/VBN/O as/RB/O unrealistically/RB/O low/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O leaving/VBG/O are/VBP/O managers/NNS/O and/CC/O professionals/NNS/O ././O
While/IN/O no/DT/O one/NN/O professes/VBZ/O to/TO/O know/VB/O the/DT/O exact/JJ/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O ``/``/O brain/NN/O drain/NN/O ''/''/O to/TO/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O hardly/RB/O anyone/NN/O doubts/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O poses/VBZ/O a/DT/O threat/NN/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O loses/VBZ/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O portion/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O work/NN/O force/NN/O that/WDT/O also/RB/O happens/VBZ/O to/TO/O include/VB/O its/PRP$/O most/JJS/O productive/JJ/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O is/VBZ/O bound/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O affected/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Anthong/NNP/B-PERSON Wong/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O economist/NN/O with/IN/O Hang/NNP/B-ORG Seng/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ././O
