TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG transports/VBZ/O all/DT/O gas/NN/O that/WDT/O moves/VBZ/O eastward/RB/O from/IN/O Alberta/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O will/MD/O save/VB/O between/IN/O C$/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O C$/$/O 6/CD/O million/CD/O annually/RB/O in/IN/O office/NN/O expenses/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O administrative/JJ/O costs/NNS/O by/IN/O moving/VBG/O to/TO/O Calgary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Maier/NNP/B-PERSON added/VBD/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O both/PDT/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O savings/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O passed/VBN/O on/IN/O to/TO/O shippers/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O TransCanada/NNP/B-ORG pipeline/NN/O through/IN/O tolls/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O are/VBP/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O pipeline/NN/O system/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O operating/VBG/O it/PRP/O ././O
