Pacific/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O signed/VBD/O a/DT/O non-binding/JJ/O letter/NN/O of/IN/O intent/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O construction/NN/O lending/NN/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Old/NNP/B-ORG Stone/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Terms/NNS/O have/VBP/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O finalized/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O close/VB/O by/IN/O year/NN/O end/NN/O ,/,/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O unit/NN/O has/VBZ/O 30/CD/O employees/NNS/O in/IN/O four/CD/O California/NNP/B-GPE offices/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Pacific/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG owns/VBZ/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG First/NNP/I-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Savings/NNP/I-ORG Banks/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O firms/NNS/O ././O
