Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/RBS/O famous/JJ/O raider/NN/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O one/CD/O ././O
Werner/NNP/B-PERSON K./NNP/I-PERSON Rey/NNP/I-PERSON believes/VBZ/O fortunes/NNS/O are/VBP/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O being/VBG/O friendly/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O achieved/VBD/O this/DT/O in/IN/O part/NN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O uncanny/JJ/O talent/NN/O for/IN/O getting/VBG/O his/PRP$/O foot/NN/O peacefully/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O door/NN/O of/IN/O established/VBN/O European/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Shareholders/NNS/O must/MD/O approve/VB/O the/DT/O merger/NN/O at/IN/O general/JJ/O meetings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O November/NNP/O ././O
This/DT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O his/PRP$/O return/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O original/JJ/O investment/NN/O of/IN/O between/IN/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O and/CC/O 80/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O Renoir/NNP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O wall/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O years/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O machinery/NN/O producer/NN/O Ateliers/NNP/B-ORG de/NNP/I-ORG Constructions/NNP/I-ORG Mecaniques/NNP/I-ORG de/NNP/I-ORG Vevey/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O to/TO/O become/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON empire/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O major/JJ/O boost/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O respectability/NN/O among/IN/O the/DT/O Swiss/NNPS/O came/VBD/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O sold/VBD/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O Phibro/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O Swiss/JJ/O cantonal/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O renamed/VBD/O it/PRP/O Swiss/NNP/B-ORG Cantobank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O are/VBP/O using/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O abroad/RB/O ././O
Sulzer/NNP/B-ORG preferred/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O financier/NN/O Tito/NNP/B-PERSON Tettamanti/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O secretive/JJ/O raid/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O stock/NN/O had/VBD/O led/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O bitter/JJ/O battle/NN/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O branch/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O empire/NN/O runs/VBZ/O under/IN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O Omnicorp/NNP/B-ORG Offering/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O handles/VBZ/O mergers/NNS/O and/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O ,/,/O placement/NN/O of/IN/O securities/NNS/O and/CC/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O yet/RB/O another/DT/O example/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O conservatism/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O points/VBZ/O out/IN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O guarantees/NNS/O for/IN/O bank/NN/O loans/NNS/O for/IN/O corporate/JJ/O development/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O ``/``/O influence/VB/O ''/''/O but/CC/O not/RB/O ``/``/O manage/VB/O ''/''/O companies/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O around/IN/O me/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O person/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O want/VBP/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O stand/VB/O alone/RB/O ././O
