When/WRB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O stumbled/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O mid-1970s/CD/O ,/,/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG NV/NNP/I-ORG fell/VBD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O bed/NN/O ././O
Towering/VBG/O overcapacity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O synthetic/JJ/O fiber/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O accounted/VBD/O for/IN/O half/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Dutch/JJ/O chemical/NN/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O led/VBD/O to/TO/O huge/JJ/O losses/NNS/O and/CC/O left/VBD/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O survival/NN/O in/IN/O doubt/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O until/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1980s/CD/O that/IN/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG nursed/VBD/O itself/PRP/O back/RB/O to/TO/O health/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O downturn/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O chemical/NN/O industry/NN/O looms/VBZ/O ,/,/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O far/RB/O better/JJR/O shape/NN/O to/TO/O cope/VB/O ././O
Investment/NN/O analysts/NNS/O generally/RB/O agree/VBP/O ././O
Aside/RB/O from/IN/O slashing/VBG/O costs/NNS/O and/CC/O investing/VBG/O heavily/RB/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O spent/VBN/O 3.9/CD/O billion/CD/O guilders/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 1.88/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O on/IN/O acquisitions/NNS/O since/IN/O 1983/CD/O to/TO/O give/VB/O it/PRP/O better/JJR/O balance/NN/O ././O
During/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O period/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O about/IN/O 1.6/CD/O billion/CD/O guilders/NNS/O of/IN/O assets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O fibers/NNS/O business/NN/O ,/,/O whose/WP$/O products/NNS/O go/VBP/O into/IN/O textiles/NNS/O ,/,/O carpeting/NN/O and/CC/O myriad/JJ/O industrial/JJ/O uses/NNS/O ,/,/O now/RB/O accounts/VBZ/O for/IN/O only/RB/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O found/VBN/O a/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O achieve/VB/O another/DT/O goal/NN/O :/:/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O presence/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O for/IN/O prescription/NN/O drugs/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bergsma/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O prices/NNS/O for/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE pharmaceutical/JJ/O companies/NNS/O remain/VBP/O too/RB/O high/JJ/O ,/,/O making/VBG/O it/PRP/O unlikely/JJ/O that/IN/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O pursue/VB/O any/DT/O major/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O in/IN/O that/DT/O area/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O Akzo/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O ``/``/O alliances/NNS/O ''/''/O with/IN/O American/JJ/O drug/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O elaborate/VB/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O expect/VBP/O the/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O show/VB/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 225/CD/O million/CD/O guilders/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O 9/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O 206.3/CD/O million/CD/O guilders/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O earlier/RBR/O ././O
A/DT/O bigger/JJR/O test/NN/O will/MD/O come/VB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O if/IN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O many/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O expect/VBP/O ,/,/O bulk/JJ/O chemical/NN/O prices/NNS/O slump/VBP/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
He/PRP/O figures/VBZ/O Akzo/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O few/JJ/O major/JJ/O chemical/NN/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O show/VB/O profit/NN/O growth/NN/O next/IN/O year/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O only/RB/O minor/JJ/O petrochemical/NN/O operations/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O small/JJ/O in/IN/O plastics/NNS/O and/CC/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O make/VB/O fertilizers/NNS/O ././O
Thus/RB/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG profited/VBD/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O many/JJ/O rivals/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O boom/NN/O of/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O petrochemicals/NNS/O and/CC/O plastics/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O less/JJR/O to/TO/O fear/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O slump/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O exposed/VBN/O to/TO/O bulk/NN/O chemicals/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
A/DT/O decline/NN/O may/MD/O come/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O of/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O market/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O appear/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O verge/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O severe/JJ/O downturn/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O reduce/VB/O the/DT/O danger/NN/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O pricing/NN/O cycles/NNS/O ,/,/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O invested/VBN/O heavily/RB/O in/IN/O specialty/NN/O chemicals/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O highly/RB/O specific/JJ/O industrial/JJ/O uses/NNS/O and/CC/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O much/JJ/O higher/JJR/O profit/NN/O margins/NNS/O than/IN/O do/VBP/O bulk/JJ/O chemicals/NNS/O ././O
Akzo/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O move/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O area/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Stauffer/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG specialty/NN/O chemical/NN/O business/NN/O for/IN/O $/$/O 625/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O less/RBR/O glamorous/JJ/O field/NN/O ,/,/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O industrial/JJ/O salt/NN/O ,/,/O used/VBD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O raw/JJ/O material/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O chemical/JJ/O industry/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O tasks/NNS/O as/IN/O melting/VBG/O ice/NN/O ././O
Akzo/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O makes/VBZ/O products/NNS/O derived/VBN/O from/IN/O salt/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O chlorine/NN/O and/CC/O caustic/JJ/O soda/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O fibers/NNS/O division/NN/O ,/,/O profit/NN/O remains/VBZ/O weak/JJ/O ,/,/O largely/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O persistent/JJ/O overcapacity/NN/O ././O
Akzo/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Twaron/NNP/B-ORG aramid/NN/O fiber/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O distant/JJ/O second/NN/O to/TO/O Du/NNP/B-ORG Pont/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Kevlar/NNP/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O dominates/VBZ/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ././O
Sales/NNS/O growth/NN/O of/IN/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O seems/VBZ/O possible/JJ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG expects/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O Twaron/NNP/B-ORG business/NN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O profitable/JJ/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
Akzo/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O has/VBZ/O spent/VBN/O heavily/RB/O on/IN/O acquisitions/NNS/O in/IN/O paints/NNS/O ,/,/O auto/NN/O finishes/NNS/O and/CC/O industrial/JJ/O coatings/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O $/$/O 110/CD/O million/CD/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Reliance/NNP/B-ORG Universal/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE maker/NN/O of/IN/O industrial/JJ/O coatings/NNS/O for/IN/O wood/NN/O ,/,/O metals/NNS/O and/CC/O plastics/NNS/O ,/,/O from/IN/O Tyler/NNP/B-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bergsma/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Akzo/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O strong/JJ/O profit/NN/O growth/NN/O from/IN/O coatings/NNS/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O realizes/VBZ/O cost/NN/O savings/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O benefits/NNS/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O greater/JJR/O scale/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O Akzo/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O drug/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O profits/NNS/O have/VBP/O shown/VBN/O litle/JJ/O change/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bergsma/NNP/B-PERSON predicted/VBD/O moderate/JJ/O profit/NN/O growth/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bergsma/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Akzo/NNP/B-PERSON hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O approval/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O Marvelon/NNP/O pill/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O 1992/CD/O ././O
Akzo/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O has/VBZ/O small/JJ/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O diagnostic/JJ/O tests/NNS/O ,/,/O generic/JJ/O drugs/NNS/O and/CC/O veterinary/JJ/O products/NNS/O ././O
Veterinary/JJ/O products/NNS/O are/VBP/O showing/VBG/O especially/RB/O strong/JJ/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bergsma/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Among/IN/O the/DT/O leading/VBG/O products/NNS/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O flu/NN/O shot/NN/O for/IN/O horses/NNS/O ././O
