That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O two/CD/O scripts/NNS/O would/MD/O diverge/VB/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG tells/VBZ/O another/DT/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON claims/VBZ/O he/PRP/O reminded/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Daly/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Terry/NNP/B-PERSON Semel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O executives/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG studio/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O ``/``/O repeatedly/RB/O agreed/VBN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O every/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O ''/''/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG denies/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON ever/RB/O said/VBD/O any/DT/O such/JJ/O thing/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O denies/VBZ/O virtually/RB/O everything/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON say/VBP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O affidavits/NNS/O ././O
Tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O file/VB/O another/DT/O batch/NN/O of/IN/O documents/NNS/O contending/VBG/O that/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O essence/NN/O of/IN/O everything/NN/O these/DT/O guys/NNS/O are/VBP/O saying/VBG/O is/VBZ/O basically/RB/O lies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/NN/O outside/JJ/O counsel/NN/O ,/,/O Stuart/NNP/B-PERSON Rabinowitz/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O battery/NN/O of/IN/O legal/JJ/O documents/NNS/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O connection/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O provide/VBP/O a/DT/O peek/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O inner/JJ/O workings/NNS/O of/IN/O this/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE dogfight/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O matter/NN/O may/MD/O never/RB/O even/RB/O be/VB/O tried/VBN/O in/IN/O court/NN/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O merging/VBG/O with/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O court/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O much/RB/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O protracted/JJ/O battle/NN/O ././O
Sony/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O part/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O decide/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG settlement/NN/O or/CC/O court/NN/O fight/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O high/JJ/O ,/,/O choosing/VBG/O instead/RB/O to/TO/O find/VB/O someone/NN/O else/RB/O to/TO/O run/VB/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O although/IN/O that/DT/O too/RB/O would/MD/O be/VB/O costly/JJ/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O already/RB/O guaranteed/VBN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O affidavit/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O movie/NN/O 's/POS/O staff/NN/O was/VBD/O told/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O ``/``/O taking/VBG/O over/IN/O ''/''/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O another/DT/O producer/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O giving/VBG/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O orders/NNS/O ././O
Hubert/NNP/B-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON la/NNP/I-PERSON Bouillaire/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O editor/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O film/NN/O ,/,/O backs/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O sworn/VBN/O declaration/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON la/NNP/I-PERSON Bouillaire/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG production/NN/O president/NN/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON Canton/NNP/I-PERSON called/VBD/O him/PRP/O Oct./NNP/O 19/CD/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O ``/``/O off/IN/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O editor/NN/O also/RB/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O producer/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O film/NN/O ,/,/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Baird/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O told/VBD/O editors/NNS/O to/TO/O screen/VB/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O without/IN/O telling/VBG/O stars/NNS/O Sylvester/NNP/B-PERSON Stallone/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Kurt/NNP/B-PERSON Russell/NNP/I-PERSON or/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O contractual/JJ/O producers/NNS/O with/IN/O consultation/NN/O rights/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O invited/VBN/O to/TO/O screenings/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O give/VB/O their/PRP$/O input/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O film/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O crossed/VBN/O out/IN/O ``/``/O MGM/NNP/B-ORG ''/''/O with/IN/O a/DT/O red/JJ/O pen/NN/O and/CC/O written/VBN/O in/IN/O ``/``/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O giving/VBG/O the/DT/O document/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O affidavit/NN/O ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O any/DT/O hugging/NN/O or/CC/O congratulating/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O contact/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Daly/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O that/IN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O conference/NN/O call/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O three/CD/O agreed/VBD/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O let/VB/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O affidavit/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Daly/NNP/B-PERSON instructed/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O tell/VB/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O terminate/VB/O their/PRP$/O agreement/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O in/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE suggest/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O encouragement/NN/O from/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG studio/NN/O executives/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Canton/NNP/B-PERSON too/RB/O literally/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rabinowitz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG attorney/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O still/RB/O wants/VBZ/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O back/RB/O and/CC/O fulfill/VB/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O ././O
