Arthur/NNP/B-PERSON Price/NNP/I-PERSON abruptly/RB/O quit/VBD/O as/IN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE production/NN/O company/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O fallen/VBN/O on/IN/O hard/JJ/O times/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 61/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O also/RB/O stepped/VBD/O down/IN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O of/IN/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O TV/NN/O company/NN/O that/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O bought/VBD/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O TV/NN/O programs/NNS/O as/IN/O ``/``/O Hill/NNP/O Street/NNP/O Blues/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O The/NNP/O Mary/NNP/O Tyler/NNP/O Moore/NNP/O Show/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O plans/NNS/O ././O
James/NNP/B-PERSON Gatward/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O ``/``/O assume/VB/O overall/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O operations/NNS/O until/IN/O a/DT/O successor/NN/O is/VBZ/O named/VBN/O ././O
Industry/NN/O analysts/NNS/O speculated/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sudden/JJ/O departure/NN/O may/MD/O have/VB/O stemmed/VBN/O from/IN/O conflicts/NNS/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gatward/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O run/VB/O the/DT/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG business/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O may/MD/O have/VB/O regretted/VBN/O selling/VBG/O the/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O suggested/VBD/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Denton/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O managing/VBG/O director/NN/O of/IN/O Zenith/NNP/B-ORG Productions/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Carlton/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gatward/NNP/B-PERSON declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG statement/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ``/``/O leaving/VBG/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O a/DT/O very/RB/O difficult/JJ/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O time/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O change/NN/O .../:/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O $/$/O 320/CD/O million/CD/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG represented/VBD/O an/DT/O audacious/JJ/O international/JJ/O move/NN/O for/IN/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O then/RB/O was/VBD/O about/IN/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE concern/NN/O 's/POS/O size/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gatward/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O his/PRP$/O friendship/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O smoothed/VBN/O the/DT/O way/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O link/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O small/JJ/O British/JJ/O company/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG stunned/VBD/O industry/NN/O analysts/NNS/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O by/IN/O disclosing/VBG/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O expected/VBD/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O post/VB/O an/DT/O operating/NN/O loss/NN/O for/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O that/DT/O announcement/NN/O ,/,/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O trimming/VBG/O production/NN/O finance/NN/O and/CC/O hiring/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE sales/NNS/O manager/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gatward/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O spent/VBN/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O since/IN/O late/JJ/O September/NNP/O at/IN/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O headquarters/NN/O ;/:/O he/PRP/O eliminated/VBD/O three/CD/O departments/NNS/O and/CC/O fired/VBD/O six/CD/O executives/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
Further/JJ/O staff/NN/O cuts/NNS/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O indicated/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Obviously/RB/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O making/VBG/O economies/NNS/O across/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
TVS/NNP/B-ORG blames/VBZ/O difficulties/NNS/O in/IN/O peddling/JJ/O reruns/NNS/O of/IN/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG shows/NNS/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE broadcasters/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O problems/NNS/O at/IN/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O reruns/NNS/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O local/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE broadcasters/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O weak/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O three/CD/O or/CC/O four/CD/O seasons/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tinker/NNP/B-PERSON later/RB/O left/VBD/O to/TO/O become/VB/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Price/NNP/B-PERSON still/RB/O holds/VBZ/O about/IN/O an/DT/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG stake/NN/O ,/,/O acquired/VBD/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O MTM/NNP/B-ORG acquisition/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O late/RB/O trading/NN/O on/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Stock/NNP/B-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O TVS/NNP/B-ORG shares/NNS/O rose/VBD/O four/CD/O pence/NN/O to/TO/O 195/CD/O pence/NN/O a/DT/O share/NN/O ././O
