Mr./NNP/O Straszheim/NNP/B-PERSON expects/VBZ/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O take/VB/O some/DT/O heat/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O right/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O forecasts/NNS/O were/VBD/O widely/RB/O disseminated/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O splashy/JJ/O ad/NN/O campaign/NN/O launched/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O summer/NN/O of/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG urged/VBD/O investors/NNS/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O bonds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O firm/NN/O also/RB/O raised/VBD/O the/DT/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O bonds/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O model/NN/O portfolio/NN/O from/IN/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 45/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O later/RB/O to/TO/O 55/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O softened/VBD/O the/DT/O talk/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bostian/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O that/IN/O his/PRP$/O macroeconomic/JJ/O index/NN/O signaled/VBD/O recession/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Shilling/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG chief/NN/O economist/NN/O from/IN/O 1967/CD/O to/TO/O 1971/CD/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O heralded/VBN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O quiet/JJ/O economic/JJ/O science/NN/O practiced/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O universities/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O commercial/JJ/O version/NN/O ././O
No/DT/O sophisticated/JJ/O professional/NN/O expects/VBZ/O economists/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O right/RB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O smaller/JJR/O clients/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O seem/VB/O to/TO/O notice/VB/O his/PRP$/O switch/NN/O ././O
Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON O'Brien/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O treasurer/NN/O of/IN/O Commonwealth/NNP/B-ORG Edison/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O adopts/VBZ/O a/DT/O polite/JJ/O approach/NN/O ,/,/O waiting/VBG/O for/IN/O an/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O ask/VB/O about/IN/O the/DT/O forecast/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O all/DT/O in/IN/O this/DT/O handout/NN/O you/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O look/VB/O at/IN/O ././O
We/PRP/O could/MD/O still/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ''/''/O at/IN/O some/DT/O point/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Straszheim/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O recurring/VBG/O themes/NNS/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O simple/JJ/O black/JJ/O or/CC/O white/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O especially/RB/O the/DT/O employment/NN/O numbers/NNS/O ,/,/O look/VBP/O much/RB/O better/RB/O than/IN/O he/PRP/O expected/VBD/O ;/:/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O have/VBP/O generally/RB/O declined/VBN/O ;/:/O inflation/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O run/VB/O amok/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Shilling/NNP/B-PERSON understands/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Straszheim/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O problems/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O indeed/RB/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O back/VB/O away/RB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O widely/RB/O publicized/VBN/O forecast/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Straszheim/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O fidgeting/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O handcuffs/NNS/O on/IN/O this/DT/O trip/NN/O ././O
