We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O sorry/JJ/O to/TO/O see/VB/O Nigel/NNP/B-PERSON Lawson/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON departure/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O government/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O politician/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O courage/NN/O of/IN/O true/JJ/O conviction/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O in/IN/O summarily/RB/O sacking/VBG/O exchange/NN/O controls/NNS/O and/CC/O in/IN/O particular/JJ/O slashing/VBG/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O income/NN/O taxation/NN/O to/TO/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O his/PRP$/O resignation/NN/O as/IN/O Chancellor/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Exchequer/NNP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O thing/NN/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O works/VBZ/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O no/DT/O doubt/NN/O intends/VBZ/O --/:/O by/IN/O forcing/VBG/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O her/PRP$/O counterparts/NNS/O elsewhere/RB/O to/TO/O confront/VB/O the/DT/O genuine/JJ/O intellectual/JJ/O issues/NNS/O involved/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O early/JJ/O omens/NNS/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O admit/VBP/O ,/,/O scarcely/RB/O suggest/VBP/O so/RB/O wholesome/JJ/O an/DT/O outcome/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Fleet/NNP/B-FAC Street/NNP/I-FAC reaction/NN/O was/VBD/O captured/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Guardian/NNP/B-ORG headline/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Departure/NN/O Reveals/VBZ/O Thatcher/NNP/O Poison/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
British/JJ/O politicians/NNS/O divide/VBP/O into/IN/O two/CD/O groups/NNS/O of/IN/O chickens/NNS/O ,/,/O those/DT/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O necks/NNS/O cut/VBN/O and/CC/O those/DT/O screaming/VBG/O the/DT/O sky/NN/O is/VBZ/O falling/VBG/O ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O see/VB/O only/RB/O two/CD/O persons/NNS/O are/VBP/O behaving/VBG/O with/IN/O a/DT/O dignity/NN/O recognizing/VBG/O the/DT/O seriousness/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O issues/NNS/O :/:/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Sir/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Walters/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O counterpoint/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Chancellor/NNP/O 's/POS/O difficulties/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O also/RB/O resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O personal/JJ/O adviser/NN/O to/TO/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O strict/JJ/O monetarists/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O floating/VBG/O exchange/NN/O rates/NNS/O free/VBP/O an/DT/O economy/NN/O to/TO/O stabilize/VB/O its/PRP$/O price/NN/O level/NN/O by/IN/O stabilizing/VBG/O the/DT/O monetary/JJ/O aggregates/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O not/RB/O only/RB/O for/IN/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON but/CC/O for/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O shown/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O ongoing/JJ/O bickering/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O between/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Mulford/NNP/I-ORG Treasury/NNP/I-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O not/RB/O only/RB/O slashed/VBD/O marginal/JJ/O tax/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O initially/RB/O sparking/VBG/O fresh/JJ/O growth/NN/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O he/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O regulate/VB/O monetary/JJ/O policy/NN/O by/IN/O targeting/VBG/O exchange/NN/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O indeed/RB/O joining/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Monetary/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ././O
To/TO/O make/VB/O matters/NNS/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O confusing/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O earlier/JJR/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE experience/NN/O made/VBD/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O tax/NN/O cuts/NNS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O profound/JJ/O effects/NNS/O on/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O international/JJ/O accounts/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O sterling/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O accounting/VBG/O definitions/NNS/O ,/,/O this/DT/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O a/DT/O sudden/JJ/O trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O this/DT/O point/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O options/NNS/O were/VBD/O :/:/O Crunch/VB/O money/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O the/DT/O boost/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O aggregates/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O Sir/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON surely/RB/O advised/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O forget/VB/O the/DT/O soaring/VBG/O pound/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O push/VB/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O even/RB/O lower/RBR/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O cure/VB/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O deficit/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O policy/NN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O repeatedly/RB/O proved/VBN/O disastrous/JJ/O ././O
Or/CC/O to/TO/O supply/VB/O enough/JJ/O money/NN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O the/DT/O increased/VBN/O demand/NN/O and/CC/O stabilize/VB/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Chancellor/NNP/O argued/VBD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ensure/VB/O the/DT/O permanence/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O policy/NN/O by/IN/O joining/VBG/O the/DT/O EMS/NNP/B-ORG ././O
But/CC/O this/DT/O devastated/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE manufacturing/NN/O sector/NN/O ,/,/O laying/VBG/O the/DT/O seeds/NNS/O of/IN/O protectionism/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O though/IN/O not/RB/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O join/VB/O the/DT/O EMS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O chose/VBD/O to/TO/O ``/``/O shadow/VB/O ''/''/O the/DT/O deutsche/NN/O mark/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O reaped/VBD/O inflation/NN/O along/IN/O with/IN/O rapid/JJ/O growth/NN/O ,/,/O no/DT/O doubt/NN/O validating/VBG/O Sir/NNP/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O predictions/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O 's/POS/O mind/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O more/RBR/O recently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O pound/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O falling/VBG/O with/IN/O high/JJ/O inflation/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O also/RB/O seemed/VBN/O almost/RB/O impervious/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O high/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON deployed/VBD/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
So/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O experience/NN/O presents/VBZ/O a/DT/O genuine/JJ/O puzzle/NN/O that/WDT/O reaches/VBZ/O far/RB/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O shores/NNS/O of/IN/O Albion/NNP/B-GPE ././O
To/TO/O begin/VB/O with/IN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O should/MD/O note/VB/O that/IN/O in/IN/O contrast/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE deficit/NN/O ,/,/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O running/VBG/O largish/JJ/O budget/NN/O surpluses/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O should/MD/O also/RB/O add/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O own/JJ/O explanation/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O we/PRP/O understand/VBP/O it/PRP/O ././O
Unlike/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE never/RB/O achieved/VBD/O even/RB/O a/DT/O momentary/JJ/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O real/JJ/O wages/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O wage/NN/O stickiness/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O OECD/NNP/B-ORG studies/NNS/O confirm/VBP/O is/VBZ/O particularly/RB/O high/JJ/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O gives/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O economy/NN/O a/DT/O structural/JJ/O bias/NN/O toward/IN/O inflation/NN/O ././O
Inflation/NN/O is/VBZ/O easier/JJR/O to/TO/O spark/VB/O and/CC/O harder/JJR/O to/TO/O control/VB/O ././O
We/PRP/O should/MD/O also/RB/O concede/VB/O that/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O experience/NN/O the/DT/O monetarist/NN/O cause/NN/O regains/VBZ/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O credibility/NN/O it/PRP/O lost/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE experience/NN/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O shock/NN/O of/IN/O tax/NN/O cuts/NNS/O is/VBZ/O after/IN/O all/DT/O best/JJS/O absorbed/VBN/O by/IN/O floating/VBG/O rates/NNS/O ,/,/O though/IN/O of/IN/O course/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O event/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON resigned/VBD/O over/IN/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O support/VB/O a/DT/O weak/JJ/O pound/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O restrain/VB/O a/DT/O strong/JJ/O one/CD/O ././O
We/PRP/O recall/VBP/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roberts/NNP/B-PERSON not/RB/O only/RB/O chides/VBZ/O the/DT/O Chancellor/NNP/O for/IN/O being/VBG/O too/RB/O easy/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O constrain/VB/O sterling/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O also/RB/O led/VBD/O the/DT/O chorus/NN/O saying/VBG/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Volcker/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O too/RB/O tight/JJ/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O let/VBD/O the/DT/O dollar/NN/O rise/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O globalists/NNS/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O think/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON ran/VBD/O onto/IN/O technical/JJ/O reefs/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O that/DT/O matter/NN/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O he/PRP/O fixed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O wrong/JJ/O currency/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O sympathize/VBP/O with/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O reluctance/NN/O to/TO/O tie/VB/O her/PRP$/O currency/NN/O to/TO/O one/CD/O governed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O domestic/JJ/O political/JJ/O imperatives/NNS/O of/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Reynolds/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Polyconomics/NNP/B-ORG adds/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O suspicion/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O unrecognized/JJ/O inflationary/JJ/O culprit/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O surplus/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Reynolds/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O notes/VBZ/O that/IN/O since/IN/O British/JJ/O banks/NNS/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O reserve/NN/O requirements/NNS/O ,/,/O high/JJ/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O are/VBP/O less/RBR/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O curb/VB/O inflation/NN/O than/IN/O to/TO/O cause/VB/O recession/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O would/MD/O add/VB/O that/IN/O in/IN/O political/JJ/O terms/NNS/O ,/,/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O problem/NN/O was/VBD/O failing/VBG/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Chancellor/NNP/O and/CC/O her/PRP$/O adviser/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O neither/DT/O policy/NN/O was/VBD/O followed/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O learning/VBG/O anything/NN/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O left/VBN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O mystery/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O particular/JJ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O shadowing/VBG/O ''/''/O a/DT/O currency/NN/O is/VBZ/O anything/NN/O but/CC/O fixing/VBG/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O announcement/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O rate/NN/O target/NN/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O credibility/NN/O ././O
All/PDT/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O so/RB/O when/WRB/O strong/JJ/O voices/NNS/O are/VBP/O heard/VBN/O opposing/VBG/O the/DT/O policy/NN/O ././O
Better/JJR/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O true/JJ/O monetarist/NN/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O experience/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lawson/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O to/TO/O resign/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O underlying/VBG/O situation/NN/O that/WDT/O became/VBD/O intolerable/JJ/O ././O
What/WP/O Mr./NNP/O Major/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O do/VB/O now/RB/O remains/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O seen/VBN/O ././O
They/PRP/O confront/VBP/O stubborn/JJ/O inflation/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O sagging/VBG/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O ,/,/O stagflation/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O can/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O solved/VBN/O by/IN/O provoking/VBG/O a/DT/O further/JJ/O downturn/NN/O ;/:/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O supply/NN/O of/IN/O goods/NNS/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O solve/VB/O inflation/NN/O ././O
