These/DT/O are/VBP/O curious/JJ/O times/NNS/O in/IN/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O politics/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O bitterest/JJS/O of/IN/O enemies/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O engaged/VBN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O elaborate/JJ/O mating/NN/O dance/NN/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O entice/VB/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O negotiating/VBG/O table/NN/O ././O
Pretoria/NN/B-GPE releases/VBZ/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O whom/WP/O were/VBD/O serving/VBG/O life/NN/O sentences/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O allows/VBZ/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O speak/VB/O freely/RB/O ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O abandon/VB/O its/PRP$/O use/NN/O of/IN/O violence/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O speak/VBP/O in/IN/O tones/NNS/O of/IN/O moderation/NN/O ,/,/O emphasizing/VBG/O discipline/NN/O ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O the/DT/O government/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O encouraged/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O further/JJ/O steps/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O freeing/VBG/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Mandela/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O prominent/JJ/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG figure/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O unbanning/VBG/O the/DT/O organization/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O of/IN/O President/NNP/B-PERSON F.W./NNP/I-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON Klerk/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O using/VBG/O this/DT/O situation/NN/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O its/PRP$/O international/JJ/O image/NN/O and/CC/O head/VB/O off/IN/O further/JJ/O economic/JJ/O sanctions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O result/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O unthinkable/JJ/O and/CC/O illogical/JJ/O are/VBP/O happening/VBG/O ././O
Six/CD/O months/NNS/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O government/NN/O approval/NN/O for/IN/O an/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG rally/NN/O was/VBD/O inconceivable/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O government/NN/O may/MD/O ease/VB/O repression/NN/O in/IN/O some/DT/O areas/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O still/RB/O keeps/VBZ/O a/DT/O tight/JJ/O grip/NN/O in/IN/O others/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG vows/VBZ/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O up/IN/O pressure/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
Speakers/NNS/O yesterday/NN/O called/VBD/O on/IN/O foreign/JJ/O governments/NNS/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O sanctions/NNS/O against/IN/O Pretoria/NN/B-GPE and/CC/O urged/VBD/O supporters/NNS/O inside/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O defying/VBG/O emergency/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O and/CC/O racial/JJ/O segregation/NN/O ,/,/O known/VBN/O as/IN/O apartheid/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O both/DT/O called/VBD/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O ``/``/O welcome/JJ/O home/NN/O ''/''/O gathering/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O recently/RB/O released/VBN/O leaders/NNS/O sat/VBD/O high/RB/O atop/IN/O a/DT/O podium/NN/O in/IN/O one/CD/O section/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stadium/NN/O stands/NNS/O ././O
