The/DT/O former/NN/O comes/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O wave/NN/O of/IN/O political/JJ/O activism/NN/O in/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O especially/RB/O around/IN/O feminist/JJ/O issues/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O abortion/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O latter/NN/O comes/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O perception/NN/O ,/,/O on/IN/O the/DT/O part/NN/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O in/IN/O network/NN/O TV/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O only/JJ/O hope/NN/O of/IN/O keeping/VBG/O viewers/NNS/O from/IN/O defecting/VBG/O to/TO/O cable/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O the/DT/O airwaves/NNS/O with/IN/O an/DT/O increasingly/RB/O raw/JJ/O sensationalism/NN/O ././O
Put/VB/O these/DT/O together/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O get/VBP/O programs/NNS/O about/IN/O rape/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O best/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O crop/NN/O was/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O 's/POS/O season/NN/O premiere/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O In/IN/O the/DT/O Heat/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Night/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG series/NN/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O 1967/CD/O feature/NN/O film/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O black/JJ/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE police/NN/O detective/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O Southern/JJ/O town/NN/O ././O
Because/IN/O the/DT/O show/NN/O has/VBZ/O acquired/VBN/O a/DT/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O place/NN/O by/IN/O being/VBG/O filmed/VBN/O on/IN/O location/NN/O in/IN/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O this/DT/O episode/NN/O --/:/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Althea/NNP/B-PERSON gets/VBZ/O raped/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O arrogant/JJ/O white/JJ/O schoolteacher/NN/O --/:/O does/VBZ/O a/DT/O decent/JJ/O job/NN/O of/IN/O tracing/VBG/O the/DT/O social/JJ/O repercussions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O crime/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O tale/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE policewoman/NN/O returning/VBG/O home/NN/O to/TO/O find/VB/O the/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O raped/VBD/O her/PRP/O 20/CD/O years/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O is/VBZ/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Ozarks/NNPS/B-LOC ././O
The/DT/O writer/NN/O and/CC/O executive/NN/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Settle/VB/O the/DT/O Score/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Steve/NNP/B-PERSON Sohmer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O graduate/NN/O of/IN/O Yale/NNP/B-ORG who/WP/O participated/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O PBS/NNP/B-ORG documentary/NN/O ,/,/O aired/VBD/O this/DT/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O six/CD/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Yale/NNP/B-ORG class/NN/O of/IN/O 1963/CD/O ruminated/VBD/O about/IN/O their/PRP$/O lives/NNS/O since/IN/O graduation/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O one/CD/O point/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O documentary/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Sohmer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O Jewish/NNP/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O felt/VBD/O rejected/VBN/O by/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Protestants/NNPS/O and/CC/O Southerners/NNPS/O he/PRP/O met/VBD/O at/IN/O Yale/NNP/B-ORG ././O
He/PRP/O quotes/VBZ/O one/CD/O student/NN/O saying/VBG/O ,/,/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O 're/VBP/O just/RB/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O Jewboy/NN/O we/PRP/O Southerners/NNPS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O stand/VB/O ././O
''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Sohmer/NNP/B-PERSON confesses/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O partly/RB/O in/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O such/JJ/O attitudes/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O ``/``/O a/DT/O dweller/NN/O on/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O islands/NNS/O off/IN/O the/DT/O coast/NN/O of/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O is/VBZ/O exile/NN/O in/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE enough/RB/O ?/./O
Not/RB/O to/TO/O judge/VB/O by/IN/O ``/``/O Settle/VB/O the/DT/O Score/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Mr./NNP/O Sohmer/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O settling/VBG/O a/DT/O score/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O sole/JJ/O sympathetic/JJ/O character/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O prodigal/JJ/O daughter/NN/O Kate/NNP/B-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Jaclyn/NNP/B-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O tolerable/JJ/O only/RB/O by/IN/O virtue/NN/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O nothing/NN/O in/IN/O common/JJ/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O kinfolk/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O truly/RB/O benighted/JJ/O pack/NN/O of/IN/O Southern/JJ/O Protestants/NNPS/O whose/WP$/O grim/JJ/O existence/NN/O consists/VBZ/O mostly/RB/O of/IN/O growing/VBG/O peaches/NNS/O and/CC/O repressing/VBG/O sex/NN/O ././O
People/NNS/O like/IN/O Pa/NNP/O do/VBP/O exist/VB/O ,/,/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sohmer/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Ozarks/NNPS/B-LOC ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O but/IN/O the/DT/O tip/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O patriarchal/JJ/O iceberg/NN/O ././O
Every/DT/O man/NN/O Kate/NNP/B-PERSON encounters/VBZ/O is/VBZ/O either/RB/O sniggeringly/RB/O puritanical/JJ/O ,/,/O viciously/RB/O patronizing/VBG/O ,/,/O revoltingly/RB/O lecherous/JJ/O ,/,/O or/CC/O all/DT/O three/CD/O ././O
Josh/NNP/B-PERSON makes/VBZ/O clumsy/JJ/O passes/NNS/O at/IN/O Kate/NNP/B-PERSON when/WRB/O she/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O seething/VBG/O with/IN/O anger/NN/O and/CC/O fear/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O know/VBP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O outset/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O evil/JJ/O patriarchy/NN/O ././O
How/WRB/O could/MD/O he/PRP/O be/VB/O ?/./O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O local/JJ/O Planned/NNP/B-ORG Parenthood/NNP/I-ORG chapter/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O for/IN/O Lincoln/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O guess/VB/O why/WRB/O he/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O so/RB/O sweet/JJ/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O sister/NN/O when/WRB/O everybody/NN/O else/RB/O hates/VBZ/O her/PRP/O ,/,/O then/RB/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O not/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O tell/VB/O you/PRP/O ././O
As/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O women/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O pathetic/JJ/O ././O
Kate/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Ma/NNP/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Louise/NNP/B-PERSON Latham/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O moral/JJ/O coward/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O very/RB/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O appear/VB/O that/IN/O Sis/NNP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O poor/JJ/O judge/NN/O of/IN/O masculine/JJ/O charm/NN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O even/RB/O these/DT/O insulting/JJ/O caricatures/NNS/O are/VBP/O not/RB/O as/RB/O bad/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O moral/JJ/O hypocrisy/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O heart/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Settle/VB/O the/DT/O Score/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O the/DT/O aforementioned/JJ/O episode/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O In/NNP/O the/DT/O Heat/NNP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Night/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O we/PRP/O saw/VBD/O Althea/NNP/B-PERSON being/VBG/O attacked/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O invited/VBN/O to/TO/O enjoy/VB/O the/DT/O spectacle/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O this/DT/O point/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O truce/NN/O between/IN/O feminism/NN/O and/CC/O sensationalism/NN/O gets/VBZ/O mighty/RB/O uneasy/JJ/O ././O
Take/VB/O the/DT/O scene/NN/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O Kate/NNP/B-PERSON stands/VBZ/O naked/JJ/O by/IN/O a/DT/O lighted/VBN/O window/NN/O ,/,/O whispering/VBG/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O hidden/VBN/O assailant/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Look/VB/O all/DT/O you/PRP/O want/VBP/O ././O
Starting/VBG/O tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O stalking/VBG/O you/PRP/O ././O
Surely/RB/O the/DT/O question/NN/O is/VBZ/O obvious/JJ/O ././O
With/IN/O friends/NNS/O like/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Sohmer/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O do/VBP/O the/DT/O feminists/NNS/O of/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE need/VB/O enemies/NNS/O ?/./O
