Joseph/NNP/B-PERSON P./NNP/I-PERSON Jordan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 52/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O becomes/VBZ/O president/NN/O ,/,/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O company/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Jordan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O formerly/RB/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Fishkill/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Beacon/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O succeeds/VBZ/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Broderick/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O died/VBD/O at/IN/O 52/CD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O automobile/NN/O accident/NN/O ././O
