If/IN/O this/DT/O battle/NN/O were/VBD/O a/DT/O movie/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O fighting/VBG/O over/IN/O two/CD/O scripts/NNS/O with/IN/O nothing/NN/O but/CC/O an/DT/O opening/JJ/O scene/NN/O in/IN/O common/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O opener/NN/O ,/,/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNPS/I-ORG Entertainment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O transaction/NN/O valued/VBN/O at/IN/O close/RB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 5/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O two/CD/O scripts/NNS/O would/MD/O diverge/VB/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG tells/VBZ/O another/DT/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O affidavits/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O shocked/VBN/O ''/''/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON refused/VBD/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O and/CC/O made/VBD/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O stop/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON claims/VBZ/O he/PRP/O reminded/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Daly/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Terry/NNP/B-PERSON Semel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O executives/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG studio/NN/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O ``/``/O repeatedly/RB/O agreed/VBN/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O every/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O ''/''/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ././O
In/IN/O response/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON referred/VBD/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O colleagues/NNS/O at/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O an/DT/O ``/``/O obscenity/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O Tell/VB/O them/PRP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O job/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O can/MD/O take/VB/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O you/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG denies/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON ever/RB/O said/VBD/O any/DT/O such/JJ/O thing/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O denies/VBZ/O virtually/RB/O everything/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON say/VBP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O affidavits/NNS/O ././O
Tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O file/VB/O another/DT/O batch/NN/O of/IN/O documents/NNS/O contending/VBG/O that/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O essence/NN/O of/IN/O everything/NN/O these/DT/O guys/NNS/O are/VBP/O saying/VBG/O is/VBZ/O basically/RB/O lies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O chief/NN/O outside/JJ/O counsel/NN/O ,/,/O Stuart/NNP/B-PERSON Rabinowitz/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O battery/NN/O of/IN/O legal/JJ/O documents/NNS/O filed/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O connection/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O provide/VBP/O a/DT/O peek/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O inner/JJ/O workings/NNS/O of/IN/O this/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE dogfight/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O also/RB/O make/VBP/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O thing/NN/O a/DT/O judge/NN/O will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O decide/VB/O is/VBZ/O which/WDT/O ,/,/O if/IN/O any/DT/O ,/,/O version/NN/O of/IN/O events/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O morass/NN/O is/VBZ/O fiction/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O which/WDT/O fact/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O matter/NN/O may/MD/O never/RB/O even/RB/O be/VB/O tried/VBN/O in/IN/O court/NN/O ././O
Warner/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O merging/VBG/O with/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O court/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O far/RB/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O its/PRP$/O considerable/JJ/O financial/JJ/O demands/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O much/RB/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O protracted/JJ/O battle/NN/O ././O
Sony/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O part/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O decide/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG settlement/NN/O or/CC/O court/NN/O fight/NN/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O high/JJ/O ,/,/O choosing/VBG/O instead/RB/O to/TO/O find/VB/O someone/NN/O else/RB/O to/TO/O run/VB/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O although/IN/O that/DT/O too/RB/O would/MD/O be/VB/O costly/JJ/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O arrangement/NN/O already/RB/O guaranteed/VBN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O that/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON might/MD/O not/RB/O suffer/VB/O financially/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O left/VBN/O without/IN/O their/PRP$/O dream/NN/O job/NN/O of/IN/O running/VBG/O a/DT/O studio/NN/O and/CC/O with/IN/O a/DT/O considerably/RB/O scarred/VBN/O relationship/NN/O with/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O center/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O court/NN/O fight/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O differing/VBG/O interpretations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O written/VBN/O contract/NN/O between/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O two/CD/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O other/JJ/O murkier/JJR/O issues/NNS/O will/MD/O play/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O role/NN/O ././O
Just/RB/O how/WRB/O rancorous/JJ/O the/DT/O relationship/NN/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O is/VBZ/O clear/JJ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O differing/VBG/O versions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O '/POS/O current/JJ/O business/NN/O dealings/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON say/VBP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O affidavits/NNS/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG already/RB/O is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O freeze/VB/O them/PRP/O out/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O projects/NNS/O at/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O notably/RB/O the/DT/O Sylvester/NNP/B-PERSON Stallone/NNP/I-PERSON film/NN/O ``/``/O Tango/NNP/O and/CC/O Cash/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O affidavit/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O movie/NN/O 's/POS/O staff/NN/O was/VBD/O told/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O ``/``/O taking/VBG/O over/RP/O ''/''/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O another/DT/O producer/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O giving/VBG/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O orders/NNS/O ././O
Over/IN/O his/PRP$/O objections/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O film/NN/O 's/POS/O release/NN/O date/NN/O was/VBD/O moved/VBN/O up/RP/O ``/``/O by/IN/O many/JJ/O months/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O December/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O plans/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O soundtrack/NN/O ``/``/O worth/JJ/O millions/NNS/O of/IN/O dollars/NNS/O ''/''/O were/VBD/O dropped/VBN/O ././O
Hubert/NNP/B-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON la/NNP/I-PERSON Bouillaire/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O editor/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O film/NN/O ,/,/O backs/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O sworn/VBN/O declaration/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON la/NNP/I-PERSON Bouillaire/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG production/NN/O president/NN/O Mark/NNP/B-PERSON Canton/NNP/I-PERSON called/VBD/O him/PRP/O Oct./NNP/O 19/CD/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O ``/``/O off/IN/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O he/PRP/O calls/VBZ/O you/PRP/O up/IN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O tell/VB/O him/PRP/O everything/NN/O is/VBZ/O fine/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O editor/NN/O also/RB/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O producer/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O film/NN/O ,/,/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Baird/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O told/VBD/O editors/NNS/O to/TO/O screen/VB/O the/DT/O picture/NN/O without/IN/O telling/VBG/O stars/NNS/O Sylvester/NNP/B-PERSON Stallone/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Kurt/NNP/B-PERSON Russell/NNP/I-PERSON or/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O less/JJS/O they/PRP/O know/VBP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O easier/JJR/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O for/IN/O us/PRP/O ././O
If/IN/O someone/NN/O asks/VBZ/O ,/,/O just/RB/O lie/VB/O and/CC/O tell/VB/O them/PRP/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O done/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON la/NNP/I-PERSON Bouillaire/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Baird/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O them/PRP/O ././O
That/IN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Rabinowitz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O 100/CD/O %/NN/O lie/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O movie/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O post-production/NN/O stages/NNS/O of/IN/O ``/``/O cleaning/VBG/O up/RP/O the/DT/O film/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O contractual/JJ/O producers/NNS/O with/IN/O consultation/NN/O rights/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O invited/VBN/O to/TO/O screenings/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O give/VB/O their/PRP$/O input/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O film/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O crossed/VBN/O out/RP/O ``/``/O MGM/NNP/B-ORG ''/''/O with/IN/O a/DT/O red/JJ/O pen/NN/O and/CC/O written/VBN/O in/RP/O ``/``/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O giving/VBG/O the/DT/O document/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O absolutely/RB/O nothing/NN/O to/TO/O indicate/VB/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O have/VB/O any/DT/O objection/NN/O to/TO/O our/PRP$/O assuming/VBG/O management/NN/O positions/NNS/O at/IN/O Columbia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O affidavit/NN/O ,/,/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O any/DT/O hugging/NN/O or/CC/O congratulating/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON he/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O sign/VB/O any/DT/O documents/NNS/O and/CC/O that/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O apparently/RB/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O one/CD/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O would/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O very/RB/O negative/JJ/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O contact/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Daly/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O that/IN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O conference/NN/O call/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O three/CD/O agreed/VBD/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O let/VB/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O affidavit/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Daly/NNP/B-PERSON instructed/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O tell/VB/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O terminate/VB/O their/PRP$/O agreement/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON did/VBD/O convey/VB/O that/DT/O information/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O ``/``/O crazy/JJ/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Time/NNP/B-ORG deal/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O meaning/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O communicate/VB/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O new/JJ/O merger/NN/O partner/NN/O ,/,/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O agreements/NNS/O provided/VBD/O for/IN/O our/PRP$/O departure/NN/O under/IN/O these/DT/O circumstances/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O says/VBZ/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O affidavit/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Daly/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O told/VBD/O us/PRP/O that/IN/O even/RB/O if/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O not/RB/O want/VB/O us/PRP/O ,/,/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O relationship/NN/O with/IN/O us/PRP/O already/RB/O was/VBD/O irreparably/RB/O damaged/VBN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O no/DT/O way/NN/O `/``/O to/TO/O put/VB/O the/DT/O egg/NN/O together/RB/O ,/,/O '/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O sue/VB/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O tons/NNS/O of/IN/O money/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON claims/VBZ/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O him/PRP/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Ross/NNP/B-PERSON probably/RB/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O object/VB/O ``/``/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O were/VBD/O anybody/NN/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG ././O
But/CC/O Sony/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O in/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE suggest/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O encouragement/NN/O from/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG studio/NN/O executives/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Canton/NNP/B-PERSON too/RB/O literally/RB/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O this/DT/O theory/NN/O ,/,/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O ,/,/O hoping/VBG/O to/TO/O strengthen/VB/O their/PRP$/O relationships/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O encouraged/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O their/PRP$/O ambitions/NNS/O to/TO/O build/VB/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O entertainment/NN/O company/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O affidavits/NNS/O deny/VBP/O ever/RB/O telling/VBG/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O get/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O written/VBN/O contract/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rabinowitz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG attorney/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O still/RB/O wants/VBZ/O the/DT/O producers/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O back/RB/O and/CC/O fulfill/VB/O their/PRP$/O contract/NN/O ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O are/VBP/O like/IN/O a/DT/O mini-studio/NN/O ;/:/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O 50/CD/O projects/NNS/O in/IN/O development/NN/O for/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON indicates/VBZ/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O affidavit/NN/O that/IN/O not/RB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O projects/NNS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O ././O
For/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O since/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Peters/NNP/B-PERSON have/VBP/O developed/VBN/O over/IN/O 85/CD/O movie/NN/O projects/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O ``/``/O passed/VBN/O ''/''/O or/CC/O chosen/VBN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O produce/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O 76/CD/O ././O
As/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O projects/NNS/O remaining/VBG/O at/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Guber/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Mr./NNP/O Semel/NNP/B-PERSON informed/VBD/O me/PRP/O that/IN/O Warner/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O producers/NNS/O have/VBP/O already/RB/O started/VBN/O a/DT/O `/``/O feeding/NN/O frenzy/NN/O '/''/O for/IN/O our/PRP$/O projects/NNS/O ././O
