Japanese/JJ/O companies/NNS/O have/VBP/O long/RB/O been/VBN/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O sacrificing/VBG/O profit/NN/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O sales/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O taken/VBN/O that/DT/O practice/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O extreme/NN/O ././O
Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O computer/NN/O maker/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O undercut/VBD/O seven/CD/O competitors/NNS/O to/TO/O win/VB/O a/DT/O contract/NN/O to/TO/O design/VB/O a/DT/O mapping/NN/O system/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O of/IN/O Hiroshima/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O waterworks/NN/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O bid/NN/O :/:/O one/CD/O yen/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/O penny/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bid/NN/O created/VBD/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O furor/NN/O that/IN/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O offering/VBG/O to/TO/O withdraw/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O ././O
Hiroshima/NNP/B-GPE city/NN/O officials/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O to/TO/O find/VB/O out/RP/O whether/IN/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O drop/VB/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O bid/NN/O ././O
Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O issued/VBD/O the/DT/O low/JJ/O bid/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O a/DT/O foot/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O door/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O potentially/RB/O lucrative/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O desperately/RB/O wanted/VBD/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O because/IN/O we/PRP/O want/VBP/O experience/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O expect/VBP/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O market/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O ,/,/O so/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O term/NN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O profitable/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O investment/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Hiroshima/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O waterworks/NN/O bureau/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O municipal/JJ/O government/NN/O had/VBD/O budgeted/VBN/O about/IN/O 11/CD/O million/CD/O yen/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 77,500/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O for/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O flabbergasted/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Tatsuhara/NNP/B-PERSON Yamane/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bureau/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O quoted/VBN/O by/IN/O Kyodo/NNP/B-ORG news/NN/O service/NN/O as/IN/O saying/VBG/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O understand/VBP/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O enthusiasm/NN/O in/IN/O getting/VBG/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O company/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O better/JJR/O off/IN/O showing/VBG/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O more/JJR/O discretion/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O admitted/VBD/O they/PRP/O may/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O little/RB/O overzealous/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O headquarter/JJ/O officials/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O approve/VB/O the/DT/O bid/NN/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O and/CC/O will/MD/O take/VB/O measures/NNS/O so/RB/O this/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O thing/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O happen/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O contrary/JJ/O to/TO/O common/JJ/O sense/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O added/VBD/O ././O
Specifically/RB/O ,/,/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG won/VBD/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O design/VB/O the/DT/O specifications/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O computerized/NN/O system/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O show/VB/O water/NN/O lines/NNS/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O system/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O fire/NN/O or/CC/O earthquake/NN/O to/TO/O locate/VB/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O waterworks/NN/O official/NN/O said/VBD/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O design/VB/O the/DT/O system/NN/O so/IN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O compatible/JJ/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O makers/NNS/O '/POS/O equipment/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O industry/NN/O officials/NNS/O expressed/VBD/O concern/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O initial/JJ/O project/NN/O might/MD/O give/VB/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG an/DT/O edge/NN/O in/IN/O winning/VBG/O more/JJR/O lucrative/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O later/RB/O ././O
Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O hopes/VBZ/O the/DT/O Hiroshima/NNP/B-GPE contract/NN/O will/MD/O help/VB/O it/PRP/O secure/VB/O pacts/NNS/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O municipalities/NNS/O ././O
Japanese/JJ/O local/JJ/O governments/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O invest/VB/O heavily/RB/O in/IN/O computer/NN/O systems/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O companies/NNS/O expect/VBP/O that/DT/O field/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O substantial/JJ/O revenue/NN/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O the/DT/O near/JJ/O future/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O market/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O just/RB/O for/IN/O waterworks/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O for/IN/O all/DT/O mapping/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
No/DT/O foreign/JJ/O companies/NNS/O bid/VBP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Hiroshima/NNP/B-GPE project/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bureau/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Japanese/JJ/O practice/NN/O of/IN/O deep/JJ/O discounting/NN/O often/RB/O is/VBZ/O cited/VBN/O by/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O classic/JJ/O barrier/NN/O to/TO/O entry/NN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O market/NN/O ././O
Earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE complained/VBD/O that/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O supercomputer/NN/O makers/NNS/O were/VBD/O effectively/RB/O closing/VBG/O out/RP/O foreign/JJ/O competitors/NNS/O by/IN/O slashing/VBG/O prices/NNS/O as/RB/O much/RB/O as/IN/O 90/CD/O %/NN/O for/IN/O universities/NNS/O ././O
Fujitsu/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O company/NN/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O sacrifice/VB/O profit/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O competitors/NNS/O bid/VBD/O between/IN/O 300,000/CD/O yen/NN/O and/CC/O 500,000/CD/O yen/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Hiroshima/NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O office/NN/O ././O
Other/JJ/O bids/NNS/O ranged/VBD/O from/IN/O about/IN/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O yen/NN/O to/TO/O 29/CD/O million/CD/O yen/NN/O ././O
