There/EX/O may/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O truce/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O war/NN/O of/IN/O nerves/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG over/IN/O how/WRB/O this/DT/O country/NN/O conducts/VBZ/O secret/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O operations/NNS/O abroad/RB/O ././O
If/IN/O that/DT/O attitude/NN/O lasts/VBZ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O infuse/VB/O covert/JJ/O action/NN/O planning/VBG/O with/IN/O a/DT/O level/NN/O of/IN/O care/NN/O and/CC/O confidence/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O seen/VBN/O in/IN/O years/NNS/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O informed/VBN/O ,/,/O usually/RB/O in/IN/O advance/NN/O ,/,/O of/IN/O covert/JJ/O actions/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O put/VB/O key/JJ/O intelligence/NN/O decisions/NNS/O in/IN/O writing/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O always/RB/O the/DT/O way/NN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O handled/VBD/O such/JJ/O matters/NNS/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG never/RB/O fully/RB/O trusted/VBD/O former/JJ/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG chief/NN/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Casey/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O National/NNP/O Security/NNP/O Adviser/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Poindexter/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O honor/VB/O the/DT/O ban/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O objections/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O establishment/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O inspector/NN/O general/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG who/WP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O independent/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG director/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O return/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG panel/NN/O has/VBZ/O dropped/VBN/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O enact/VB/O legislation/NN/O requiring/VBG/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O to/TO/O inform/VB/O it/PRP/O within/IN/O 48/CD/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O launching/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O covert/JJ/O activity/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O removed/VBN/O a/DT/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG use/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O contingency/NN/O fund/NN/O for/IN/O covert/JJ/O acts/NNS/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O wipe/VB/O away/RB/O some/DT/O tortured/JJ/O and/CC/O legalistic/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O coup/NN/O planning/NN/O put/VBN/O in/IN/O place/NN/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O back/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O game/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O finally/RB/O been/VBN/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O convince/VB/O them/PRP/O that/IN/O Casey/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O -LCB-/-LRB-/B-PERSON Oliver/NNP/I-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON North/NNP/I-PERSON do/VBP/O n't/RB/O work/VB/O here/RB/O anymore/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O administration/NN/O official/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O understanding/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O spring/VB/O to/TO/O life/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O spontaneous/JJ/O eruption/NN/O of/IN/O sweetness/NN/O and/CC/O light/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG used/VBD/O television/NN/O appearances/NNS/O and/CC/O leaks/NNS/O to/TO/O argue/VB/O that/IN/O congressionally/RB/O imposed/VBN/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O covert/JJ/O actions/NNS/O made/VBD/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE support/NN/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O coups/NNS/O difficult/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O president/NN/O also/RB/O hinted/VBD/O he/PRP/O might/MD/O veto/VB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O intelligence/NN/O authorization/NN/O bill/NN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O restrictive/JJ/O ././O
Intelligence/NNP/B-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Boren/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Okla/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Vice/NNP/O Chairman/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Cohen/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O R./NNP/O ,/,/O Maine/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O part/NN/O ,/,/O angrily/RB/O accused/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O selectively/RB/O leaking/VBG/O classified/VBN/O documents/NNS/O and/CC/O trying/VBG/O unfairly/RB/O to/TO/O shift/VB/O the/DT/O blame/NN/O to/TO/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O the/DT/O bungled/VBN/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O topple/VB/O Gen./NNP/O Noriega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG got/VBD/O the/DT/O better/JJR/O of/IN/O the/DT/O exchange/NN/O but/CC/O took/VBD/O care/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O press/VB/O its/PRP$/O advantage/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O constitutional/JJ/O confrontation/NN/O sought/VBN/O by/IN/O conservative/JJ/O Republicans/NNPS/O who/WP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O any/DT/O congressional/JJ/O oversight/NN/O of/IN/O intelligence/NN/O activities/NNS/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O aides/NNS/O made/VBD/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O they/PRP/O respected/VBD/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O role/NN/O and/CC/O felt/VBD/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O work/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O Mr./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O moderate/JJ/O Mr./NNP/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O iron/VB/O out/RP/O their/PRP$/O differences/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O senators/NNS/O responded/VBD/O in/IN/O kind/NN/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON happily/RB/O told/VBD/O reporters/NNS/O that/IN/O there/EX/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O meeting/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O minds/NNS/O ''/''/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O had/VBD/O given/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O a/DT/O clean/JJ/O slate/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O free/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O impediments/NNS/O imposed/VBN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON years/NNS/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O relationship/NN/O has/VBZ/O reverted/VBN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O pre-Reagan/JJ/B-PERSON character/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O some/DT/O details/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O nailed/VBN/O down/IN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O reserving/VBG/O the/DT/O right/NN/O in/IN/O ``/``/O rare/JJ/O ''/''/O instances/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O dark/NN/O ,/,/O asserting/VBG/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O prerogative/NN/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O recognize/VB/O ././O
And/CC/O a/DT/O pending/VBG/O Justice/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG interpretation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O assassination/NN/O ban/NN/O could/MD/O raise/VB/O questions/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O settled/VBN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O both/DT/O sides/NNS/O may/MD/O face/VB/O political/JJ/O critics/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O conservatives/NNS/O will/MD/O accuse/VB/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O promising/JJ/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG too/RB/O much/RB/O ././O
And/CC/O they/PRP/O continue/VBP/O anonymously/RB/O attacking/VBG/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG Director/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Webster/NNP/I-PERSON for/IN/O being/VBG/O too/RB/O accommodating/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O some/DT/O congressional/JJ/O liberals/NNS/O will/MD/O accuse/VB/O Sens./NNP/O Boren/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Cohen/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O wimping/VBG/O out/IN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O warn/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O lawmakers/NNS/O '/POS/O concessions/NNS/O raise/VBP/O the/DT/O specter/NN/O of/IN/O more/RBR/O internationally/RB/O embarrassing/JJ/O covert/JJ/O operations/NNS/O like/IN/O the/DT/O mining/NN/O of/IN/O Nicaraguan/JJ/O harbors/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE arms/NNS/O sales/NNS/O ././O
