Federal/NNP/B-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG critics/NNS/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O complain/VB/O of/IN/O ``/``/O stop/VB/O and/CC/O go/VB/O ''/''/O monetary/JJ/O policies/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O claimed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O first/RB/O give/VB/O a/DT/O green/JJ/O light/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O by/IN/O making/VBG/O credit/NN/O readily/RB/O available/JJ/O and/CC/O then/RB/O turn/VB/O on/RP/O the/DT/O red/JJ/O and/CC/O bring/VB/O growth/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O screeching/JJ/O halt/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O under/IN/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON Greenspan/NNP/I-PERSON that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O changed/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O supremely/RB/O cautious/JJ/O man/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O is/VBZ/O forever/RB/O blinking/RB/O yellow/JJ/O ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O caution/NN/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O legendary/JJ/O within/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O fusses/VBZ/O endlessly/RB/O over/IN/O economic/JJ/O statistics/NNS/O ,/,/O dissecting/VBG/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O ways/NNS/O ,/,/O probing/VBG/O for/IN/O hours/NNS/O in/IN/O search/NN/O of/IN/O potential/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O thoroughly/RB/O digesting/VBG/O reams/NNS/O of/IN/O information/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O often/RB/O concludes/VBZ/O that/IN/O more/JJR/O data/NNS/O are/VBP/O needed/VBN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O finally/RB/O decides/VBZ/O to/TO/O act/VB/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O movements/NNS/O sometimes/RB/O seem/VBP/O excrutiatingly/RB/O small/JJ/O ././O
Some/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O urged/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O make/VB/O an/DT/O immediate/JJ/O public/JJ/O announcement/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O ample/JJ/O credit/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O refused/VBD/O ,/,/O claiming/VBG/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O see/VB/O what/WP/O happened/VBD/O Monday/NNP/O morning/NN/O before/IN/O making/VBG/O any/DT/O public/JJ/O statement/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O ``/``/O senior/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O ''/''/O spoke/VBD/O on/IN/O Saturday/NNP/O after/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O swoon/NN/O to/TO/O both/PDT/O the/DT/B-ORG Washington/NNP/I-ORG Post/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O saying/VBG/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O prepared/VBN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O as/IN/O much/JJ/O credit/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O needed/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O statement/NN/O angered/VBD/O Chairman/NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O greeted/VBN/O with/IN/O applause/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O mutinous/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG member/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O gone/VBN/O public/JJ/O ,/,/O some/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG governors/NNS/O ,/,/O most/RBS/O notably/RB/O Vice/NNP/O Chairman/NNP/O Manuel/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O are/VBP/O known/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O disagreed/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O 's/POS/O decision/NN/O to/TO/O remain/VB/O silent/JJ/O ././O
Ironically/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O anonymous/JJ/O official/NN/O 's/POS/O comments/NNS/O have/VBP/O earned/VBN/O some/DT/O plaudits/NNS/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O mistakenly/RB/O seen/VBN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O source/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O a/DT/O hearing/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Democratic/JJ/O Sen./NNP/O Chris/NNP/B-PERSON Dodd/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Connecticut/NNP/B-GPE told/VBD/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Nicholas/NNP/B-PERSON Brady/NNP/I-PERSON that/IN/O ``/``/O Chairman/NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ''/''/O announcement/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O Oct./NNP/O 13/CD/O weekend/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O very/RB/O important/JJ/O statement/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Brady/NNP/B-PERSON hesitantly/RB/O replied/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O sure/JJ/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON ``/``/O made/VBD/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O himself/PRP/O ,/,/O or/CC/O whether/IN/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O newspaper/NN/O report/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O 's/POS/O caution/NN/O was/VBD/O apparent/JJ/O again/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Monday/NNP/O morning/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O plunge/NN/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O bank/NN/O took/VBD/O only/RB/O modest/JJ/O steps/NNS/O to/TO/O aid/VB/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O surprisingly/RB/O small/JJ/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O reserves/NNS/O was/VBD/O added/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O banking/NN/O system/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O ,/,/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O that/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O key/JJ/O federal/JJ/O funds/NNS/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O largely/RB/O controlled/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O settled/VBN/O at/IN/O 8.75/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O barely/RB/O changed/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O level/NN/O of/IN/O just/RB/O under/IN/O 9/CD/O %/NN/O that/WDT/O prevailed/VBD/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O appear/VBP/O increasingly/RB/O concerned/VBN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O cautious/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O fault/NN/O ././O
Signs/NNS/O of/IN/O growing/VBG/O weakness/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O ,/,/O paired/VBN/O with/IN/O indications/NNS/O that/IN/O inflation/NN/O is/VBZ/O staying/VBG/O well/RB/O under/IN/O control/NN/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O caused/VBN/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O wonder/VB/O why/WRB/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG chairman/NN/O is/VBZ/O so/RB/O grudging/JJ/O in/IN/O reducing/VBG/O rates/NNS/O ././O
Those/DT/O concerns/NNS/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O expressed/VBN/O in/IN/O public/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O split/NN/O is/VBZ/O there/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O concerns/NNS/O are/VBP/O understandable/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O economy/NN/O is/VBZ/O showing/VBG/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O weakness/NN/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O among/IN/O manufacturers/NNS/O ././O
Exports/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O played/VBD/O a/DT/O key/JJ/O role/NN/O in/IN/O fueling/VBG/O growth/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O seem/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O stalled/VBN/O ././O
Factory/NN/O payrolls/NNS/O and/CC/O production/NN/O fell/VBD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O auto/NN/O industry/NN/O and/CC/O housing/NN/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O a/DT/O severe/JJ/O crunch/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O reluctant/JJ/O to/TO/O loosen/VB/O policy/NN/O ,/,/O partly/RB/O because/IN/O he/PRP/O faces/VBZ/O a/DT/O phalanx/NN/O of/IN/O presidents/NNS/O of/IN/O regional/JJ/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG banks/NNS/O who/WP/O oppose/VBP/O credit/NN/O easing/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O chairman/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O wary/JJ/O eye/NN/O aimed/VBN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O or/CC/O two/CD/O down/IN/O the/DT/O road/NN/O ././O
Inflation/NN/O may/MD/O be/VB/O stable/JJ/O at/IN/O the/DT/O moment/NN/O ,/,/O running/VBG/O at/IN/O about/IN/O 4.5/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O if/IN/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG eases/VBZ/O too/RB/O soon/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON fears/VBZ/O ,/,/O prices/NNS/O may/MD/O begin/VB/O to/TO/O accelerate/VB/O again/RB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
So/IN/O far/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O cautious/JJ/O approach/NN/O to/TO/O policy/NN/O has/VBZ/O served/VBN/O both/DT/O him/PRP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O well/RB/O ././O
His/PRP$/O hand/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O monetary/JJ/O tiller/NN/O seems/VBZ/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O why/WRB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O next/JJ/O month/NN/O seems/VBZ/O highly/RB/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O an/DT/O unprecedented/JJ/O eighth/JJ/O year/NN/O of/IN/O peacetime/NN/O growth/NN/O without/IN/O a/DT/O recession/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O gotten/VBN/O through/IN/O two/CD/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O crashes/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O gone/VBN/O through/IN/O an/DT/O election/NN/O without/IN/O any/DT/O major/JJ/O problems/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Hale/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O economist/NN/O of/IN/O Kemper/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O give/VB/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O good/JJ/O rating/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O such/JJ/O caution/NN/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O guarantee/NN/O against/IN/O mistakes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O reluctance/NN/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O credit/NN/O now/RB/O could/MD/O be/VB/O laying/VBG/O the/DT/O groundwork/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O recession/NN/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O starting/VBG/O early/JJ/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O that/DT/O happens/VBZ/O ,/,/O Chairman/NNP/O Greenspan/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O well/RB/O become/VB/O an/DT/O open/JJ/O target/NN/O ././O
Already/RB/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O toying/VBG/O with/IN/O legislation/NN/O to/TO/O curb/VB/O the/DT/O Fed/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O independence/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O turns/VBZ/O down/RB/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O proposals/NNS/O could/MD/O gain/VB/O strong/JJ/O momentum/NN/O ././O
