After/IN/O days/NNS/O of/IN/O intense/JJ/O but/CC/O fruitless/JJ/O negotiations/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O judge/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O threatened/VBD/O to/TO/O convert/VB/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Herbert/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O personal/JJ/O bankruptcy/NN/O case/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O Chapter/NN/O 7/CD/O liquidation/NN/O ././O
Judge/NNP/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON C./NNP/I-PERSON Abramson/NNP/I-PERSON raised/VBD/O the/DT/O possibility/NN/O after/IN/O talks/NNS/O to/TO/O end/VB/O a/DT/O feud/NN/O between/IN/O two/CD/O major/JJ/O creditors/NNS/O failed/VBD/O and/CC/O all/DT/O three/CD/O reorganization/NN/O plans/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O ran/VBD/O into/IN/O roadblocks/NNS/O ././O
Hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O smaller/JJR/O creditors/NNS/O could/MD/O get/VB/O nothing/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O attorneys/NNS/O involved/VBN/O ././O
While/IN/O admitting/VBG/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O move/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O devastating/VBG/O ''/''/O to/TO/O most/JJS/O creditors/NNS/O ,/,/O Judge/NNP/O Abramson/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O a/DT/O courtroom/NN/O filled/VBN/O with/IN/O nearly/RB/O two/CD/O dozen/NN/O attorneys/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O concerned/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O toll/NN/O mounting/VBG/O legal/JJ/O bills/NNS/O will/MD/O take/VB/O on/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O shrinking/VBG/O estate/NN/O and/CC/O about/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O ,/,/O following/VBG/O voting/NN/O by/IN/O creditors/NNS/O ,/,/O none/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plans/NNS/O appeared/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O viable/JJ/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O present/JJ/O form/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O shame/NN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O Chapter/NN/O 7/CD/O after/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O progress/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O case/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Judge/NNP/O Abramson/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Under/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Federal/NNP/O Bankruptcy/NNP/O Code/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O company/NN/O continues/VBZ/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O under/IN/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O '/POS/O lawsuits/NNS/O while/IN/O it/PRP/O works/VBZ/O out/RP/O a/DT/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O its/PRP$/O debts/NNS/O ././O
Under/IN/O Chapter/NN/O 7/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O company/NN/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O off/RP/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O creditors/NNS/O ././O
Despite/IN/O his/PRP$/O reluctance/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O latter/JJ/O step/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O indicated/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O move/VB/O quickly/RB/O after/IN/O hearing/VBG/O testimony/NN/O later/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bitter/JJ/O dispute/NN/O between/IN/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O minerals/NNS/O concern/NN/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Peruvian/JJ/O governmemt/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O seeking/VBG/O repayment/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 36/CD/O million/CD/O loan/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O asked/VBN/O the/DT/O court/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O its/PRP$/O claim/NN/O priority/NN/O over/IN/O that/DT/O of/IN/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O won/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 132/CD/O million/CD/O judgment/NN/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O brother/NN/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Bunker/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O defendants/NNS/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O case/NN/O stemming/VBG/O from/IN/O their/PRP$/O alleged/VBN/O attempts/NNS/O to/TO/O corner/VB/O the/DT/O silver/JJ/O market/NN/O in/IN/O
While/IN/O claiming/VBG/O that/IN/O penalties/NNS/O ,/,/O legal/JJ/O fees/NNS/O and/CC/O interest/NN/O have/VBP/O driven/VBN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O claim/NN/O to/TO/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 250/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O settle/VB/O for/IN/O an/DT/O allowed/JJ/O claim/NN/O of/IN/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 65.7/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Under/IN/O prodding/VBG/O from/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Abramson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O flew/VBD/O in/IN/O from/IN/O Peru/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O week/NN/O to/TO/O talk/VB/O directly/RB/O with/IN/O executives/NNS/O from/IN/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O long/JJ/O private/JJ/O sessions/NNS/O in/IN/O both/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O ended/VBD/O the/DT/O week/NN/O ``/``/O 6,000/CD/O miles/NNS/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O apart/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O attorney/NN/O Hugh/NNP/B-PERSON Ray/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O represents/VBZ/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O inside/IN/O the/DT/O courtroom/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O fine/VB/O attorneys/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O creditors/NNS/O $/$/O 50/CD/O every/DT/O time/NN/O they/PRP/O referred/VBD/O to/TO/O each/DT/O other/JJ/O with/IN/O terms/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O ``/``/O liar/NN/O ''/''/O or/CC/O ``/``/O slime/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
All/DT/O three/CD/O major/JJ/O creditors/NNS/O --/:/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O voted/VBD/O against/IN/O and/CC/O effectively/RB/O doomed/VBD/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O proposed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
A/DT/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O proposed/VBN/O jointly/RB/O by/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O stalled/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O negative/JJ/O vote/NN/O from/IN/O Minpeco/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O mineral/NN/O concern/NN/O 's/POS/O own/JJ/O reorganization/NN/O plan/NN/O met/VBD/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O fate/NN/O after/IN/O opposition/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Manufacturers/NNPS/B-ORG Hanover/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O settlement/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O continue/VBP/O between/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Hunt/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O already/RB/O reached/VBN/O a/DT/O tentative/JJ/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O Nelson/NNP/B-PERSON Bunker/NNP/I-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O far/RB/O apart/RB/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O Herbert/NNP/B-PERSON Hunt/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O owe/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O after/IN/O his/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O ././O
