CRA/NNP/B-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O a/DT/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O Howick/NNP/B-GPE coal/NN/O mine/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE South/NNP/I-GPE Wales/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O Mitsubishi/NNP/B-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Pty./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O price/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O agreement/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O government/NN/O approval/NN/O ././O
RA/NNP/B-ORG acquired/VBD/O the/DT/O Howick/NNP/B-GPE coal/NN/O mine/NN/O Oct./NNP/O 20/CD/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O bought/VBD/O British/NNP/B-ORG Petroleum/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Australian/JJ/O coal/NN/O interests/NNS/O for/IN/O $/$/O 275/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
CRA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O then/RB/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O a/DT/O partner/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O mine/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O produces/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O three/CD/O million/CD/O metric/JJ/O tons/NNS/O of/IN/O coal/NN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
