The/DT/O buyer/NN/O was/VBD/O GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Railcar/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O owner/NN/O of/IN/O railway/NN/O equipment/NN/O and/CC/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O GE/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG operations/NNS/O ././O
Leucadia/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O estimated/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O pre-tax/JJ/O gain/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 57/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O its/PRP$/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Brae/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O gain/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O estimated/VBN/O gain/NN/O for/IN/O Brae/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O $/$/O 15/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O tax/NN/O credit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 7/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O sellers/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O credit/NN/O for/IN/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O having/VBG/O provided/VBN/O deferred/JJ/O income/NN/O taxes/NNS/O applicable/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O sold/VBN/O assets/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O higher/JJR/O income/NN/O tax/NN/O rates/NNS/O in/IN/O effect/NN/O in/IN/O prior/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O sellers/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
