E.W./NNP/B-ORG Scripps/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O acquired/VBN/O a/DT/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE cable/NN/O television/NN/O company/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O Massachusetts/NNP/B-GPE publishing/NN/O firm/NN/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O on/IN/O both/DT/O deals/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O media/NNS/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O purchased/VBD/O Cable/NNP/B-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O privately/RB/O held/VBN/O cable/NN/O television/NN/O system/NN/O in/IN/O Carroll/NNP/B-GPE County/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Ga./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O suburb/NN/O of/IN/O Atlanta/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O system/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O under/IN/O construction/NN/O and/CC/O will/MD/O serve/VB/O a/DT/O market/NN/O of/IN/O 7,600/CD/O homes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O acquired/VBN/O Sundance/NNP/B-ORG Publishers/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Distributors/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O family/NN/O owned/VBN/O producer/NN/O and/CC/O distributor/NN/O of/IN/O educational/JJ/O materials/NNS/O in/IN/O Littleton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass/NNP/B-GPE ././O
