Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/RBS/O famous/JJ/O raider/NN/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O one/CD/O ././O
Werner/NNP/B-PERSON K./NNP/I-PERSON Rey/NNP/I-PERSON believes/VBZ/O fortunes/NNS/O are/VBP/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O being/VBG/O friendly/JJ/O ././O
He/PRP/O achieved/VBD/O this/DT/O in/IN/O part/NN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O uncanny/JJ/O talent/NN/O for/IN/O getting/VBG/O his/PRP$/O foot/NN/O peacefully/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O door/NN/O of/IN/O established/VBN/O European/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ././O
Shareholders/NNS/O must/MD/O approve/VB/O the/DT/O merger/NN/O at/IN/O general/JJ/O meetings/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O companies/NNS/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O November/NNP/O ././O
But/CC/O approval/NN/O is/VBZ/O almost/RB/O certain/JJ/O since/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O friendly/JJ/O Adia/NNP/B-ORG management/NN/O are/VBP/O in/IN/O control/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON estimates/VBZ/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O his/PRP$/O Omni/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O about/IN/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O his/PRP$/O return/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O original/JJ/O investment/NN/O of/IN/O between/IN/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O and/CC/O 80/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O like/VBP/O to/TO/O succeed/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON during/IN/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O morning/NN/O of/IN/O working/VBG/O at/IN/O home/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O he/PRP/O also/RB/O likes/VBZ/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O corner/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O reception/NN/O room/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O delicate/JJ/O antique/NN/O desk/NN/O piled/VBN/O high/RB/O with/IN/O dossiers/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O Renoir/NNP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O wall/NN/O ././O
Writes/VBZ/O Bilanz/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O No/DT/O one/NN/O in/IN/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE ever/RB/O came/VBD/O so/RB/O far/RB/O so/RB/O fast/RB/O .../:/O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O simply/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O in/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O to/TO/O realize/VB/O that/IN/O treasures/NNS/O were/VBD/O just/RB/O lying/VBG/O around/RB/O waiting/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O picked/VBN/O up/IN/O ././O
In/IN/O short/JJ/O :/:/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON found/VBD/O companies/NNS/O with/IN/O weak/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O but/CC/O rich/JJ/O assets/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Swiss/JJ/O financial/JJ/O press/NN/O in/IN/O general/JJ/O ,/,/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O many/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O had/VBN/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O time/NN/O making/VBG/O up/RP/O their/PRP$/O minds/NNS/O about/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O un-Swiss/JJ/O ways/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O most/JJS/O prestigious/JJ/O newspaper/NN/O ,/,/O Neue/NNP/B-ORG Zuercher/NNP/I-ORG Zeitung/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O destined/VBN/O to/TO/O remain/VB/O the/DT/O ``/``/O former/JJ/O Bally/NNP/B-ORG raider/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O an/DT/O image/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O proved/VBN/O hard/RB/O to/TO/O overcome/VB/O ././O
Sitting/VBG/O beside/IN/O a/DT/O banker/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O luncheon/NN/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O working/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O consultant/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O learned/VBD/O that/IN/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O packet/NN/O of/IN/O Bally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O shares/NNS/O was/VBD/O up/IN/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O ././O
Investing/VBG/O four/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O earned/VBN/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O financial/JJ/O transactions/NNS/O and/CC/O two/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O from/IN/O his/PRP$/O parents/NNS/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON acquired/VBD/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Bally/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG shares/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O such/JJ/O tactics/NNS/O were/VBD/O alien/JJ/O to/TO/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O 1976/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O common/JJ/O because/IN/O of/IN/O share/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O that/IN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O Swiss/JJ/O francs/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Bally/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O not/RB/O an/DT/O unfriendly/JJ/O takeover/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O insists/VBZ/O ././O
Buying/VBG/O from/IN/O willing/JJ/O shareholders/NNS/O makes/VBZ/O an/DT/O unfriendly/JJ/O takeover/NN/O impossible/JJ/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON contends/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O bought/VBD/O from/IN/O willing/JJ/O shareholders/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Nevertheless/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O very/RB/O careful/JJ/O since/IN/O then/RB/O to/TO/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O his/PRP$/O moves/NNS/O are/VBP/O welcome/JJ/O ././O
And/CC/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O worked/VBN/O to/TO/O shed/VB/O his/PRP$/O raider/NN/O image/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O 1979/CD/O ,/,/O his/PRP$/O career/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O industrialist/NN/O began/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Swiss/JJ/O metals/NNS/O works/NNS/O Selve/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Thun/NNP/B-GPE ././O
With/IN/O the/DT/O nonferrous/JJ/O metals/NNS/O business/NN/O undermined/VBN/O in/IN/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE by/IN/O tough/JJ/O foreign/JJ/O competition/NN/O and/CC/O high/JJ/O domestic/JJ/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O this/DT/O looked/VBD/O like/IN/O a/DT/O dull/JJ/O undertaking/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON brought/VBD/O about/RP/O a/DT/O merger/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O years/NNS/O between/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O major/JJ/O producers/NNS/O ;/:/O the/DT/O increased/VBN/O efficiency/NN/O has/VBZ/O perked/VBN/O up/RP/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O years/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O machinery/NN/O producer/NN/O Ateliers/NNP/B-ORG de/NNP/I-ORG Constructions/NNP/I-ORG Mecaniques/NNP/I-ORG de/NNP/I-ORG Vevey/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O to/TO/O become/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON empire/NN/O ././O
Once/RB/O again/RB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O future/NN/O looked/VBD/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O rosy/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O after/IN/O restructuring/VBG/O under/IN/O new/JJ/O management/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O profits/NNS/O began/VBD/O rolling/VBG/O in/IN/O ././O
A/DT/O major/JJ/O boost/NN/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O respectability/NN/O among/IN/O the/DT/O Swiss/NNPS/O came/VBD/O in/IN/O 1986/CD/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O sold/VBD/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O Phibro/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O the/DT/O conservative/JJ/O Swiss/JJ/O cantonal/JJ/O banks/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O renamed/VBD/O it/PRP/O Swiss/NNP/B-ORG Cantobank/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O are/VBP/O using/VBG/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O abroad/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON bested/VBD/O leading/VBG/O publishing/VBG/O houses/NNS/O to/TO/O take/VB/O over/RP/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Jean/NNP/B-ORG Frey/NNP/I-ORG AG/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O magazines/NNS/O and/CC/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O
Sulzer/NNP/B-ORG preferred/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O financier/NN/O Tito/NNP/B-PERSON Tettamanti/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O secretive/JJ/O raid/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O stock/NN/O had/VBD/O led/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O bitter/JJ/O battle/NN/O ././O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O branch/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O empire/NN/O runs/VBZ/O under/IN/O the/DT/O name/NN/O Omnicorp/NNP/B-ORG Offering/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O handles/VBZ/O mergers/NNS/O and/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O ,/,/O placement/NN/O of/IN/O securities/NNS/O and/CC/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O financial/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O ,/,/O reading/VBG/O Omni/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O accounts/NNS/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O challenge/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Companies/NNS/O move/VBP/O in/IN/O and/CC/O out/IN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Helga/NNP/B-PERSON Kern/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O KK/NNP/B-ORG Swiss/NNP/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Rey/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O yet/RB/O another/DT/O example/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O conservatism/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O explains/VBZ/O that/IN/O companies/NNS/O with/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O give/VBP/O ``/``/O security/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O points/VBZ/O out/RP/O ,/,/O as/IN/O guarantees/NNS/O for/IN/O bank/NN/O loans/NNS/O for/IN/O corporate/JJ/O development/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O ``/``/O influence/VB/O ''/''/O but/CC/O not/RB/O ``/``/O manage/VB/O ''/''/O companies/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O like/IN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O financier/NN/O Alan/NNP/B-PERSON -RCB-/-RRB-/I-PERSON Bond/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O Australians/NNPS/O ././O
I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O companies/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O built/VBN/O around/IN/O me/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O person/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O want/VBP/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O stand/VB/O alone/RB/O ././O
