The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O been/VBN/O under/IN/O pressure/NN/O from/IN/O several/JJ/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O ,/,/O especially/RB/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O to/TO/O ease/VB/O restrictions/NNS/O on/IN/O some/DT/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O machine/NN/O tools/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O those/DT/O countries/NNS/O argued/VBD/O were/VBD/O now/RB/O widely/RB/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O East/NNP/B-LOC Bloc/NNP/I-LOC countries/NNS/O from/IN/O non-Cocom/JJ/B-ORG members/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O countries/NNS/O also/RB/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O pressing/VBG/O for/IN/O special/JJ/O treatment/NN/O for/IN/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O they/PRP/O move/VBP/O toward/IN/O more/RBR/O democratic/JJ/O rule/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O as/IN/O special/JJ/O treatment/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O agreed/VBN/O on/IN/O for/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O officials/NNS/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O treating/VBG/O China/NNP/B-GPE as/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O case/NN/O ,/,/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O repression/NN/O of/IN/O dissent/NN/O there/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O no/DT/O further/JJ/O concessions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O rapid/JJ/O changes/NNS/O under/IN/O way/NN/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O agreed/VBD/O on/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O continuing/VBG/O need/NN/O for/IN/O this/DT/O organization/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O founded/VBN/O 40/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/IN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O start/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Cold/NNP/O War/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O meeting/NN/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O working/VBG/O toward/IN/O ``/``/O streamlining/VBG/O ''/''/O Cocom/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O restricted/VBN/O products/NNS/O list/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O procedures/NNS/O for/IN/O punishing/VBG/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O comply/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O export/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O this/DT/O meeting/NN/O ``/``/O put/VBD/O in/IN/O motion/NN/O ''/''/O procedural/JJ/O steps/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O speed/VB/O up/IN/O both/DT/O of/IN/O these/DT/O functions/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O no/DT/O specific/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O were/VBD/O taken/VBN/O on/IN/O either/DT/O matter/NN/O ././O
