Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON made/VBD/O his/PRP$/O comments/NNS/O during/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O detailing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O plans/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O to/TO/O know/VB/O clients/NNS/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O closer/JJR/O to/TO/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Lever/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O are/VBP/O planning/VBG/O joint/JJ/O visits/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O clients/NNS/O to/TO/O attempt/VB/O to/TO/O smoothly/RB/O hand/VB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O reins/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O finally/RB/O implement/VB/O a/DT/O reorganization/NN/O announced/VBN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O but/CC/O put/VBN/O on/IN/O hold/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O WPP/NNP/B-ORG takeover/NN/O ././O
Industry/NN/O executives/NNS/O and/CC/O analysts/NNS/O are/VBP/O divided/VBN/O on/IN/O whether/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O up/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O task/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O one/CD/O thing/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON clearly/RB/O does/VBZ/O have/VB/O going/VBG/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O is/VBZ/O continuity/NN/O ,/,/O although/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O certain/JJ/O if/IN/O that/DT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O enough/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Roman/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O indeed/RB/O quite/RB/O similar/JJ/O in/IN/O substance/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O not/RB/O in/IN/O style/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Phillips/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O expected/VBN/O margin/NN/O improvement/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O all/DT/O but/CC/O inevitable/JJ/O ,/,/O given/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O profitability/NN/O was/VBD/O dragged/VBN/O down/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O expensive/JJ/O move/NN/O to/TO/O luxurious/JJ/O ,/,/O oversized/JJ/O new/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE headquarters/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O ,/,/O budgeted/VBN/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 7/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O actually/RB/O came/VBD/O in/IN/O at/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Ogilvy/NNP/B-ORG eliminated/VBD/O the/DT/O mail/NN/O room/NN/O staff/NN/O ,/,/O closed/VBD/O the/DT/O executive/NN/O dining/NN/O room/NN/O and/CC/O ,/,/O after/IN/O the/DT/O takeover/NN/O ,/,/O let/VBD/O go/VB/O half/PDT/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O financial/JJ/O executives/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O will/MD/O now/RB/O be/VB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE company/NN/O ,/,/O under/IN/O British/JJ/O accounting/NN/O rules/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O also/RB/O make/VB/O the/DT/O profit/NN/O picture/NN/O look/VB/O better/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Klein/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O work/VB/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Kroll/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O activities/NNS/O and/CC/O acquisitions/NNS/O while/IN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O is/VBZ/O pending/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 35/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O billings/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O dissolved/VBN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O staffers/NNS/O absorbed/VBN/O by/IN/O WCRS/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Della/NNP/B-ORG Femina/NNP/I-ORG McNamee/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O in/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ms./NNP/O Heller/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O too/RB/O early/JJ/O to/TO/O say/VB/O what/WP/O would/MD/O happen/VB/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O clients/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Reebok/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Apple/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Wells/NNP/B-ORG Rich/NNP/I-ORG declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O status/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O account/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O did/VBD/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O ././O
