APARTHEID/NNP/O FOES/NNS/O STAGED/VBD/O a/DT/O massive/JJ/O anti-government/JJ/O rally/NN/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O considered/VBN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE largest/JJS/O opposition/NN/O rally/NN/O ././O
Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Sisulu/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O former/JJ/O secretary/NN/O general/NN/O who/WP/O served/VBD/O 26/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O before/IN/O being/VBG/O released/VBN/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/IN/O ,/,/O urged/VBD/O peace/NN/O ,/,/O negotiation/NN/O and/CC/O discipline/NN/O ././O
President/NNP/O de/NNP/B-PERSON Klerk/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/O government/NN/O permitted/VBD/O the/DT/O rally/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O security/NN/O forces/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O interfere/VB/O ././O
Pretoria/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O approval/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O demonstration/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O ANC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O conciliatory/JJ/O tone/NN/O appeared/VBD/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O setting/VBG/O up/IN/O negotiations/NNS/O to/TO/O give/VB/O blacks/NNS/O political/JJ/O rights/NNS/O ././O
CONGRESSIONAL/JJ/B-ORG LEADERS/NNS/O BACKED/VBD/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O criticism/NN/O of/IN/O Nicaragua/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Ortega/NNP/B-PERSON cited/VBD/O renewed/VBN/O attacks/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S.backed/JJ/B-GPE rebels/NNS/O ././O
Spain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Socialist/NNP/B-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG claimed/VBD/O victory/NN/O in/IN/O nationwide/JJ/O elections/NNS/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O retained/VBN/O its/PRP$/O parliamentary/JJ/O majority/NN/O by/IN/O one/CD/O seat/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Socialists/NNPS/O held/VBD/O 184/CD/O seats/NNS/O going/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O balloting/NN/O ././O
Thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O East/NNP/O Germans/NNPS/O attended/VBD/O public/JJ/O rallies/NNS/O organized/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Communist/NNP/O leadership/NN/O and/CC/O demanded/VBD/O free/JJ/O speech/NN/O ,/,/O controls/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O security/NN/O forces/NNS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O end/NN/O to/TO/O official/JJ/O privileges/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O gatherings/NNS/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O elsewhere/RB/O were/VBD/O viewed/VBN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O government/NN/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O activists/NNS/O from/IN/O staging/VBG/O protests/NNS/O to/TO/O press/VB/O their/PRP$/O demands/NNS/O ././O
Dissidents/NNS/O in/IN/O Czechoslovakia/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O pro-democracy/JJ/O movement/NN/O was/VBD/O growing/VBG/O despite/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O move/NN/O to/TO/O crush/VB/O a/DT/O protest/NN/O Saturday/NNP/O in/IN/O Prague/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Wenceslas/NNP/B-FAC Square/NNP/I-FAC ././O
Police/NNS/O detained/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 350/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
Federal/NNP/O investigators/NNS/O have/VBP/O determined/VBN/O a/DT/O metallurgical/JJ/O flaw/NN/O that/WDT/O developed/VBD/O during/IN/O the/DT/O making/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O engine/NN/O disk/NN/O led/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O July/NNP/O crash/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG jetliner/NN/O in/IN/O Sioux/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Iowa/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O killing/VBG/O 112/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG sent/VBD/O to/TO/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON an/DT/O $/$/O 8.5/CD/O billion/CD/O military/JJ/O construction/NN/O bill/NN/O that/WDT/O cuts/VBZ/O spending/NN/O for/IN/O new/JJ/O installations/NNS/O by/IN/O 16/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O talks/NNS/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE are/VBP/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O since/IN/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Soviet/JJ/O Foreign/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Shevardnadze/NNP/B-PERSON unveiled/VBD/O proposals/NNS/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O to/TO/O scrap/VB/O existing/VBG/O weapons/NNS/O ././O
Afghan/NNP/O guerrillas/NNS/O bombarded/VBD/O Kabul/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O a/DT/O weekend/NN/O assault/NN/O that/IN/O Western/JJ/O diplomats/NNS/O called/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O offensives/NNS/O since/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE completed/VBD/O a/DT/O troop/NN/O withdrawal/NN/O in/IN/O February/NNP/O ././O
Gen./NNP/O Michel/NNP/B-PERSON Aoun/NNP/I-PERSON rejected/VBD/O the/DT/O pact/NN/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O fails/VBZ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O a/DT/O timetable/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O Syrian/JJ/O troop/NN/O pullout/NN/O from/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Authorities/NNS/O in/IN/O Hawaii/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O the/DT/O wreckage/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O missing/VBG/O commuter/NN/O plane/NN/O with/IN/O 20/CD/O people/NNS/O aboard/IN/O was/VBD/O spotted/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O remote/JJ/O valley/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O island/NN/O of/IN/O Molokai/NNP/B-LOC ././O
There/EX/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O any/DT/O evidence/NN/O of/IN/O survivors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O plane/NN/O failed/VBD/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O Molokai/NNP/B-LOC 's/POS/O airport/NN/O Saturday/NNP/O while/IN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O flight/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O neighboring/VBG/O island/NN/O of/IN/O Maui/NNP/B-LOC ././O
