What/WP/O shook/VBD/O America/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O not/RB/O a/DT/O battle/NN/O for/IN/O justice/NN/O but/CC/O for/IN/O naked/JJ/O power/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O an/DT/O army/NN/O of/IN/O judicial/JJ/O activists/NNS/O rolled/VBD/O over/IN/O a/DT/O judge/NN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O demonized/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bronner/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O believe/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O hearings/NNS/O could/MD/O have/VB/O gone/VBN/O either/DT/O way/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O doubt/VBP/O that/DT/O ././O
Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Neas/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/O organizing/NN/O genius/NN/O ,/,/O whipping/VBG/O a/DT/O conglomerate/NN/O of/IN/O pressure/NN/O groups/NNS/O into/IN/O an/DT/O irresistible/JJ/O attacking/NN/O force/NN/O ././O
Harvard/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Laurence/NNP/B-ORG Tribe/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O the/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O heavy/NN/O ,/,/O laying/VBG/O out/RP/O legal/JJ/O strategies/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O and/CC/O witnesses/NNS/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Kennedy/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O never/RB/O mind/VB/O his/PRP$/O dubious/JJ/O credentials/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O moral/JJ/O high/JJ/O ground/NN/O ,/,/O emoted/VBD/O brilliantly/RB/O ././O
I/PRP/O add/VBP/O two/CD/O others/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O ``/``/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O mainstream/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O legal/JJ/O thought/NN/O gravely/RB/O undercut/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O scholarly/JJ/O standing/NN/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O him/PRP/O bleeding/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O platform/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O nomination/NN/O still/RB/O might/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O salvaged/VBN/O if/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O moderates/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Southwest/NNP/B-LOC had/VBD/O broken/VBN/O party/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
Demographics/NNS/O converged/VBD/O with/IN/O ``/``/O mainstream/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O demonizing/NN/O to/TO/O seal/VB/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Bork/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON fate/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O upshot/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O chilling/JJ/O message/NN/O the/DT/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON hearings/NNS/O sent/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O judicial/JJ/O culture/NN/O from/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG draws/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O talent/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O word/NN/O went/VBD/O forth/RB/O to/TO/O every/DT/O law/NN/O school/NN/O that/IN/O those/DT/O with/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O ambitions/NNS/O must/MD/O travel/VB/O a/DT/O safe/JJ/O constitutional/JJ/O journey/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O no/DT/O paper/NN/O trail/NN/O and/CC/O no/DT/O bite/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O tongue/NN/O or/CC/O pen/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O too/RB/O readily/RB/O swallowed/VBN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O activist/JJ/O law/NN/O school/NN/O culture/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O would/MD/O discover/VB/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O in/IN/O Alexander/NNP/B-PERSON Bickel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O subtle/JJ/O constitutional/JJ/O scholar/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O closest/JJS/O friend/NN/O at/IN/O Yale/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O influence/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O goes/VBZ/O well/RB/O beyond/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bronner/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O reporting/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O strength/NN/O lies/VBZ/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O majoritarian/JJ/O doctrine/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O keeps/VBZ/O the/DT/O Court/NNP/B-ORG clear/JJ/O of/IN/O transient/JJ/O group/NN/O pressures/NNS/O and/CC/O leaves/VBZ/O most/JJS/O decisions/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O democracy/NN/O to/TO/O elected/JJ/O legislatures/NNS/O and/CC/O executives/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O segregated/JJ/O schools/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Brown/NNP/B-PERSON vs./IN/O Board/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Education/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O such/PDT/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
One/PRP/O can/MD/O understand/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O fear/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O right/NN/O to/TO/O privacy/NN/O will/MD/O become/VB/O intolerably/RB/O stretched/VBN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O a/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG composed/VBN/O of/IN/O men/NNS/O and/CC/O women/NNS/O with/IN/O realism/NN/O ,/,/O guts/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O limits/NNS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O manage/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
What/WP/O is/VBZ/O certain/JJ/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O allow/VBP/O another/DT/O happening/NN/O like/IN/O the/DT/O degrading/JJ/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON confirmation/NN/O circus/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O at/IN/O their/PRP$/O peril/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lerner/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O writer/NN/O and/CC/O historian/NN/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
