StatesWest/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O submitted/VBD/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O directors/NNS/O of/IN/O Mesa/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O Farmington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.M./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O carrier/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O asked/VBD/O Mesa/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O proposal/NN/O confidential/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O Mesa/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O confirmed/VBD/O receipt/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O directors/NNS/O would/MD/O meet/VB/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Mesa/NNP/B-ORG rejected/VBD/O a/DT/O proposal/NN/O by/IN/O StatesWest/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O acquire/VB/O it/PRP/O or/CC/O merge/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O carrier/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O yet/RB/O turned/VBN/O a/DT/O profit/NN/O ././O
