I/PRP/O approached/VBD/O ``/``/O Mastergate/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Larry/NNP/B-PERSON Gelbart/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON new/JJ/O comedy/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Criterion/NNP/I-FAC Center/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O with/IN/O considerable/JJ/O trepidation/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O had/VBD/O underestimated/VBN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O both/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O wit/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O persistence/NN/O of/IN/O scandal/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O one/CD/O point/NN/O Merry/NNP/B-PERSON Chase/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Melinda/NNP/B-PERSON Mullins/NNP/I-PERSON -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O a/DT/O cool/JJ/O ,/,/O carefully/RB/O coiffed/JJ/O television/NN/O announcer/NN/O ,/,/O recites/VBZ/O a/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O scandals/NNS/O of/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O concluding/VBG/O with/IN/O those/DT/O affecting/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Housing/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Urban/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O savings/NNS/O and/CC/O loan/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
Onstage/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O hearing/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O progress/NN/O ,/,/O complete/JJ/O with/IN/O elegant/JJ/O crystal/NN/O chandelier/NN/O overhead/RB/O and/CC/O a/DT/O lifesize/JJ/O reproduction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O signing/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Constitution/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O background/NN/O ././O
Not/RB/O only/RB/O are/VBP/O there/RB/O camera/NN/O operators/NNS/O on/IN/O all/DT/O sides/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O proceedings/NNS/O are/VBP/O shown/VBN/O on/IN/O monitors/NNS/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O theater/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O metaphor/NN/O of/IN/O theater/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O entirely/RB/O coincidental/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON clearly/RB/O feels/VBZ/O that/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O participants/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O hearing/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O witnesses/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O interrogators/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O news/NN/O media/NNS/O --/:/O are/VBP/O performers/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O story/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Mastergate/NNP/O ''/''/O unfolds/VBZ/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O learn/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Internal/NNP/I-ORG Revenue/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG confiscated/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O properties/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O foreign/JJ/O financier/NN/O who/WP/O owes/VBZ/O the/DT/O government/NN/O millions/NNS/O in/IN/O taxes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O man/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O Lichtenstein/NNP/B-GPE corporation/NN/O ,/,/O licensed/VBN/O in/IN/O Libya/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O sheltered/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Bahamas/NNPS/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O himself/PRP/O lives/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O consecutive/JJ/O series/NN/O of/IN/O unnumbered/JJ/O houses/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O town/NN/O in/IN/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O property/NN/O seized/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE film/NN/O studio/NN/O ,/,/O Master/NNP/B-ORG Pictures/NNP/I-ORG Incorporated/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O MPI/NNP/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Supposedly/NNP/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O sell/VB/O off/RP/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O MPI/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O lowly/JJ/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG agent/NN/O is/VBZ/O called/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O hospital/NN/O room/NN/O of/IN/O Wylie/NNP/B-PERSON Slaughter/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O dying/VBG/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O lowly/JJ/O agent/NN/O ,/,/O Abel/NNP/B-PERSON Lamb/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O as/IN/O you/PRP/O might/MD/O guess/VB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O led/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O slaughter/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ordered/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O over/RP/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O ././O
Soon/RB/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O is/VBZ/O producing/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O picture/NN/O called/VBN/O ``/``/O Tet/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Motion/NNP/O Picture/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O to/TO/O distinguish/VB/O it/PRP/O from/IN/O ``/``/O Tet/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Offensive/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O ``/``/O Tet/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Book/NNP/O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Tet/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Album/NNP/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O picture/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Central/JJ/O American/JJ/O country/NN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Elvador/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O cover/NN/O for/IN/O sending/VBG/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O arms/NNS/O to/TO/O Los/NNP/B-ORG Otros/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O rebel/JJ/O group/NN/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O regain/VB/O neighboring/JJ/O Ambigua/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O taken/VBN/O over/RP/O by/IN/O the/DT/O leftist/JJ/O dictator/NN/O Dr./NNP/O Overtega/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O podiatrist/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O leads/VBZ/O a/DT/O revolutionary/JJ/O band/NN/O of/IN/O foot/NN/O soldiers/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O one/CD/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O pregnant/JJ/O ,/,/O with/IN/O Major/NNP/O Battle/NNP/B-PERSON she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O knitting/VBG/O an/DT/O American/JJ/O flag/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O as/IN/O the/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O 's/POS/O wife/NN/O she/PRP/O rushes/VBZ/O in/RB/O with/IN/O white/JJ/O hair/NN/O ,/,/O wearing/VBG/O a/DT/O tailored/JJ/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O pearls/NNS/O ,/,/O imitating/VBG/O Barbara/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON gestures/NNS/O down/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O detail/NN/O ././O
Though/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sympathies/NNS/O do/VBP/O not/RB/O lie/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O far/RB/O right/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O also/RB/O true/JJ/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O evenhanded/JJ/O in/IN/O dispensing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O satirical/JJ/O jabs/NNS/O ,/,/O taking/VBG/O sharp/JJ/O aim/NN/O at/IN/O senators/NNS/O and/CC/O congressmen/NNS/O of/IN/O all/DT/O stripes/NNS/O and/CC/O particularly/RB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O has/VBZ/O fun/NN/O with/IN/O language/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Mastergate/NNP/O ''/''/O is/VBZ/O subtitled/VBN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O play/NN/O on/IN/O words/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON plays/VBZ/O that/DT/O game/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O anyone/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O describes/VBZ/O a/DT/O Mastergate/NNP/O flunky/NN/O as/IN/O one/NN/O who/WP/O experienced/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O meteoric/JJ/O disappearance/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O found/VBD/O himself/PRP/O ``/``/O handling/VBG/O blanket/NN/O appeals/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Indian/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNP/I-ORG ././O ''/''/O
This/DT/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O words/NNS/O goes/VBZ/O beyond/IN/O puns/NNS/O and/CC/O playfulness/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON deplores/VBZ/O the/DT/O obfuscation/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O circumlocution/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O debasement/NN/O of/IN/O language/NN/O he/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O on/IN/O all/DT/O sides/NNS/O ././O
At/IN/O another/DT/O point/NN/O he/PRP/O intones/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O Publicity/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O price/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O secrecy/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O evening/NN/O is/VBZ/O short/JJ/O --/:/O 95/CD/O minutes/NNS/O without/IN/O an/DT/O intermission/NN/O --/:/O but/CC/O even/RB/O so/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O play/NN/O progresses/VBZ/O the/DT/O thrust/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O satire/NN/O loses/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O sharpness/NN/O as/IN/O his/PRP$/O targets/NNS/O pop/VBP/O up/RP/O ever/RB/O more/RBR/O predictably/RB/O ././O
Most/RBS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O evening/NN/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O filled/VBN/O with/IN/O rare/JJ/O and/CC/O welcome/JJ/O wit/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O ``/``/O Mastergate/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O provided/VBN/O us/PRP/O not/RB/O just/RB/O one/CD/O but/CC/O two/CD/O commodities/NNS/O that/WDT/O have/VBP/O all/RB/O but/RB/O disappeared/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Broadway/NNP/B-FAC theater/NN/O :/:/O sharp/JJ/O political/JJ/O satire/NN/O and/CC/O an/DT/O even/RB/O sharper/JJR/O appreciation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O language/NN/O ././O
