Ethan/NNP/B-PERSON Bronner/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O Battle/NN/O for/IN/O Justice/NN/O :/:/O How/WRB/O the/DT/O Bork/NNP/O Nomination/NN/O Shook/VBD/O America/NNP/O ''/''/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O Norton/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O 399/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 22.50/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O spirited/JJ/O narrative/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nastiest/JJS/O of/IN/O these/DT/O hearings/NNS/O ,/,/O done/VBN/O with/IN/O journalistic/JJ/O verve/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O with/IN/O a/DT/O flawed/JJ/O legal/JJ/O philosophy/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O book/NN/O amply/RB/O justifies/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O subtitle/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O title/NN/O itself/PRP/O is/VBZ/O dubious/JJ/O ././O
What/WP/O shook/VBD/O America/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O not/RB/O a/DT/O battle/NN/O for/IN/O justice/NN/O but/CC/O for/IN/O naked/JJ/O power/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O an/DT/O army/NN/O of/IN/O judicial/JJ/O activists/NNS/O rolled/VBD/O over/RB/O a/DT/O judge/NN/O they/PRP/O had/VBD/O demonized/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bronner/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O believe/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O hearings/NNS/O could/MD/O have/VB/O gone/VBN/O either/DT/O way/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O doubt/VBP/O that/DT/O ././O
Given/VBN/O Democratic/JJ/O frustration/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Reagan/NNP/B-PERSON victories/NNS/O and/CC/O Court/NNP/B-ORG appointments/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O contingency/NN/O plans/NNS/O in/IN/O place/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O paper/NN/O trail/NN/O of/IN/O vulnerable/JJ/O writings/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O pretty/RB/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O Judge/NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON never/RB/O stood/VBD/O much/JJ/O chance/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O confirmed/VBN/O ././O
As/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bronner/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O smell/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O raw/JJ/O meat/NN/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O won/VBD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O attackers/NNS/O come/VBD/O through/RP/O more/RBR/O vividly/RB/O than/IN/O his/PRP$/O defenders/NNS/O ././O
Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Neas/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/O organizing/NN/O genius/NN/O ,/,/O whipping/VBG/O a/DT/O conglomerate/NN/O of/IN/O pressure/NN/O groups/NNS/O into/IN/O an/DT/O irresistible/JJ/O attacking/NN/O force/NN/O ././O
Harvard/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Laurence/NNP/B-ORG Tribe/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O the/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O heavy/NN/O ,/,/O laying/VBG/O out/RP/O legal/JJ/O strategies/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O senators/NNS/O and/CC/O witnesses/NNS/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O Ted/NNP/B-PERSON Kennedy/NNP/I-PERSON who/WP/O scored/VBD/O most/RBS/O effectively/RB/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O searing/JJ/O portrayal/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Robert/NNP/O Bork/NNP/O 's/POS/O America/NNP/O ''/''/O --/:/O the/DT/O parade/NN/O of/IN/O imaginary/JJ/O horribles/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O follow/VB/O logically/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O claimed/VBD/O ,/,/O from/IN/O the/DT/O positions/NNS/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O taken/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O space/NN/O of/IN/O two/CD/O decades/NNS/O ././O
Sen./NNP/O Kennedy/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O never/RB/O mind/VB/O his/PRP$/O dubious/JJ/O credentials/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O moral/JJ/O high/JJ/O ground/NN/O ,/,/O emoted/VBD/O brilliantly/RB/O ././O
I/PRP/O add/VBP/O two/CD/O others/NNS/O ././O
Republican/NNP/O Sen./NNP/O Arlen/NNP/B-PERSON Specter/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE engaged/VBD/O the/DT/O nominee/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O verbal/JJ/O contest/NN/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O showing/VBG/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O stretch/VB/O the/DT/O Constitution/NNP/O in/IN/O one/CD/O area/NN/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O free/JJ/O speech/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O while/IN/O remaining/VBG/O rigid/JJ/O in/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O others/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O achieved/VBD/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O media/NN/O play/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O enabled/VBD/O Sen./NNP/O Specter/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O others/NNS/O to/TO/O vote/VB/O against/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON out/IN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O conscience/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Further/JJ/O ammunition/NN/O came/VBD/O from/IN/O left/JJ/O legal/JJ/O theorist/NN/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Dworkin/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Review/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Books/NNP/I-ORG painted/VBD/O a/DT/O picture/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O constitutional/JJ/O zombie/NN/O willfully/RB/O reading/VBG/O his/PRP$/O personal/JJ/O prejudices/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O Constitution/NNP/O ,/,/O particularly/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O original/JJ/O intent/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O being/VBG/O ``/``/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O mainstream/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O legal/JJ/O thought/NN/O gravely/RB/O undercut/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O scholarly/JJ/O standing/NN/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O him/PRP/O bleeding/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O platform/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O nomination/NN/O still/RB/O might/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O salvaged/VBN/O if/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O Democratic/JJ/O moderates/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O South/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Southwest/NNP/B-LOC had/VBD/O broken/VBN/O party/NN/O lines/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Democratic/NNP/O Sen./NNP/O Bennett/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Louisiana/NNP/B-GPE reminded/VBD/O the/DT/O little/JJ/O band/NN/O that/IN/O anti-Bork/JJ/B-PERSON blacks/NNS/O and/CC/O women/NNS/O could/MD/O furnish/VB/O the/DT/O margin/NN/O to/TO/O punish/VB/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O next/JJ/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG elections/NNS/O ././O
Demographics/NNS/O converged/VBD/O with/IN/O ``/``/O mainstream/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O demonizing/NN/O to/TO/O seal/VB/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Bork/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON fate/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O upshot/NN/O ?/./O
Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O opponents/NNS/O chose/VBD/O the/DT/O battlefield/NN/O ,/,/O held/VBD/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O kept/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O
Yet/CC/O with/IN/O the/DT/O smooth/JJ/O confirmation/NN/O of/IN/O Anthony/NNP/B-PERSON Kennedy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O ``/``/O 80/CD/O percenter/NN/O ''/''/O only/RB/O slightly/RB/O less/RBR/O supportive/JJ/O of/IN/O judicial/JJ/O restraint/NN/O than/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Democrats/NNPS/O may/MD/O have/VB/O won/VBN/O the/DT/O battle/NN/O but/CC/O lost/VBN/O the/DT/O war/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O upshot/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O chilling/JJ/O message/NN/O the/DT/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON hearings/NNS/O sent/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O judicial/JJ/O culture/NN/O from/IN/O which/WDT/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG draws/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O talent/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O word/NN/O went/VBD/O forth/RB/O to/TO/O every/DT/O law/NN/O school/NN/O that/IN/O those/DT/O with/IN/O federal/JJ/O court/NN/O ambitions/NNS/O must/MD/O travel/VB/O a/DT/O safe/JJ/O constitutional/JJ/O journey/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O no/DT/O paper/NN/O trail/NN/O and/CC/O no/DT/O bite/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O tongue/NN/O or/CC/O pen/NN/O ././O
Unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O author/NN/O simply/RB/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O supply/VB/O the/DT/O philosophical/JJ/O frame/NN/O to/TO/O sustain/VB/O his/PRP$/O reportorial/JJ/O talents/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O too/RB/O readily/RB/O swallowed/VBN/O the/DT/O case/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O activist/JJ/O law/NN/O school/NN/O culture/NN/O ././O
Probing/VBG/O more/RBR/O deeply/RB/O into/IN/O the/DT/O doctrine/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O judicial/JJ/O restraint/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O found/VBN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O history/NN/O going/VBG/O back/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O great/JJ/O decisions/NNS/O of/IN/O Justice/NNP/O Holmes/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O would/MD/O discover/VB/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O in/IN/O Alexander/NNP/B-PERSON Bickel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O subtle/JJ/O constitutional/JJ/O scholar/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O closest/JJS/O friend/NN/O at/IN/O Yale/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O influence/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O judge/NN/O goes/VBZ/O well/RB/O beyond/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bronner/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O reporting/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O view/NN/O of/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Bork/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O constitutional/JJ/O thinker/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O spotty/JJ/O one/CD/O ././O
His/PRP$/O strength/NN/O lies/VBZ/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O majoritarian/JJ/O doctrine/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O keeps/VBZ/O the/DT/O Court/NNP/B-ORG clear/JJ/O of/IN/O transient/JJ/O group/NN/O pressures/NNS/O and/CC/O leaves/VBZ/O most/JJS/O decisions/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O democracy/NN/O to/TO/O elected/JJ/O legislatures/NNS/O and/CC/O executives/NNS/O ././O
Unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON failed/VBD/O to/TO/O distinguish/VB/O between/IN/O such/JJ/O pressures/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O emergence/NN/O of/IN/O great/JJ/O issues/NNS/O critical/JJ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O society/NN/O that/WDT/O must/MD/O be/VB/O settled/VBN/O judicially/RB/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O cohere/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O question/NN/O of/IN/O segregated/JJ/O schools/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Brown/NNP/B-PERSON vs./IN/O Board/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Education/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O such/PDT/O an/DT/O issue/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O our/PRP$/O time/NN/O abortion/NN/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O another/DT/O ,/,/O best/RBS/O left/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O line/NN/O of/IN/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG decisions/NNS/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O chaos/NN/O of/IN/O 50/CD/O state/NN/O legislatures/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O reflective/JJ/O and/CC/O growing/JJ/O consensus/NN/O of/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O clearly/RB/O wishes/VBZ/O to/TO/O apply/VB/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O privacy/NN/O in/IN/O contraceptive/JJ/O matters/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O decided/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Griswold/NNP/B-PERSON case/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O to/TO/O abortion/NN/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
One/PRP/O can/MD/O understand/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O fear/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O right/NN/O to/TO/O privacy/NN/O will/MD/O become/VB/O intolerably/RB/O stretched/VBN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O a/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG composed/VBN/O of/IN/O men/NNS/O and/CC/O women/NNS/O with/IN/O realism/NN/O ,/,/O guts/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O limits/NNS/O should/MD/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O manage/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
What/WP/O is/VBZ/O certain/JJ/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O Americans/NNPS/O allow/VBP/O another/DT/O happening/NN/O like/IN/O the/DT/O degrading/JJ/O Bork/NNP/B-PERSON confirmation/NN/O circus/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O at/IN/O their/PRP$/O peril/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lerner/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O writer/NN/O and/CC/O historian/NN/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
