Canada/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O preparing/VBG/O to/TO/O speed/VB/O up/RP/O tariff/NN/O cuts/NNS/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O recorded/VBD/O a/DT/O 47/CD/O %/NN/O narrowing/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O Statistics/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O reported/VBD/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE exports/NNS/O to/TO/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE jumped/VBD/O 11.2/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O from/IN/O July/NNP/O while/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE imports/NNS/O from/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE rose/VBD/O only/RB/O 2.7/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE narrowed/VBD/O to/TO/O C$/$/O 656.5/CD/O million/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 558/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O from/IN/O C$/$/O 1.23/CD/O billion/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 1.04/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE exports/NNS/O benefited/VBD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O from/IN/O heavy/JJ/O Canadian/JJ/O spending/NN/O on/IN/O new/JJ/O plant/NN/O and/CC/O equipment/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O pickup/NN/O in/IN/O Canadian/JJ/O auto/NN/O demand/NN/O ,/,/O Canadian/JJ/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Industries/NNS/O in/IN/O both/DT/O countries/NNS/O have/VBP/O requested/VBN/O a/DT/O speedup/NN/O of/IN/O tariff/NN/O cuts/NNS/O on/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O products/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O tariffs/NNS/O were/VBD/O eliminated/VBN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O pact/NN/O took/VBD/O effect/NN/O Jan./NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O remainder/NN/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O phased/VBN/O out/RP/O in/IN/O five/CD/O or/CC/O 10/CD/O annual/JJ/O installments/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O all/DT/O tariffs/NNS/O eliminated/VBN/O by/IN/O January/NNP/O 1998/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O two/CD/O countries/NNS/O aim/VBP/O to/TO/O reach/VB/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O by/IN/O early/JJ/O December/NNP/O on/IN/O a/DT/O package/NN/O of/IN/O accelerated/JJ/O tariff/NN/O cuts/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O take/VB/O effect/VB/O early/RB/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Canadian/JJ/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O pact/NN/O has/VBZ/O kindled/VBN/O an/DT/O export/NN/O interest/NN/O among/IN/O many/JJ/O small/JJ/O Canadian/JJ/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O previously/RB/O had/VBD/O little/JJ/O or/CC/O no/RB/O foreign/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O such/JJ/O businessmen/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O organizing/VBG/O 55/CD/O missions/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O to/TO/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE states/NNS/O bordering/VBG/O on/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O businessmen/NNS/O are/VBP/O introduced/VBN/O to/TO/O potential/JJ/O agents/NNS/O and/CC/O distributors/NNS/O and/CC/O instructed/VBN/O in/IN/O trade/NN/O procedures/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG U.S./NNP/I-ORG Commerce/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O planning/VBG/O to/TO/O try/VB/O out/RP/O similar/JJ/O trips/NNS/O on/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE businessmen/NNS/O in/IN/O coming/JJ/O months/NNS/O under/IN/O its/PRP$/O Canada/NNP/O First/NNP/O !/./O Outreach/NNP/O Program/NNP/O ././O
Participants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE missions/NNS/O to/TO/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O assisted/VBN/O by/IN/O members/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Corps/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Retired/NNP/I-ORG Executives/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O volunteer/NN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O their/PRP$/O export/NN/O challenges/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O government/NN/O also/RB/O has/VBZ/O recently/RB/O opened/VBN/O new/JJ/O trade/NN/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O San/NNP/B-GPE Juan/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ;/:/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Princeton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O bringing/VBG/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O Canadian/JJ/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O 27/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O six/CD/O trade/NN/O promotion/NN/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O export/NN/O effort/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O blunted/VBN/O by/IN/O robust/JJ/O home/NN/O market/NN/O demand/NN/O and/CC/O by/IN/O an/DT/O 18/CD/O %/NN/O appreciation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O dollar/NN/O against/IN/O its/PRP$/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE counterpart/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O Canadian/JJ/O goods/NNS/O more/RBR/O costly/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
Canada/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O with/IN/O all/DT/O countries/NNS/O narrowed/VBD/O to/TO/O C$/$/O 203.5/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O from/IN/O C$/$/O 528.3/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O Statistics/NNP/B-ORG Canada/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
