Wall/NNP/B-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG reporters/NNS/O called/VBD/O companies/NNS/O with/IN/O headquarters/NNS/O or/CC/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC in/IN/O a/DT/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O assess/VB/O the/DT/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O operations/NNS/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O calls/NNS/O reached/VBD/O many/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O certainly/RB/O not/RB/O all/DT/O ,/,/O of/IN/O the/DT/O publicly/RB/O held/VBN/O companies/NNS/O with/IN/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O most/JJS/O cases/NNS/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O company/NN/O facilities/NNS/O and/CC/O operations/NNS/O was/VBD/O minimal/JJ/O ././O
ADIA/NNP/B-ORG SERVICES/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Menlo/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O temporary/JJ/O personnel/NNS/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 504/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O all/DT/O 30/CD/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O Bay/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/I-LOC were/VBD/O working/VBG/O ,/,/O but/CC/O in/IN/O various/JJ/O states/NNS/O of/IN/O disarray/NN/O ././O
Business/NN/O was/VBD/O slow/JJ/O because/IN/O many/JJ/O companies/NNS/O were/VBD/O closed/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
ADVANCED/NNP/B-ORG MICRO/NNP/I-ORG DEVICES/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O integrated/JJ/O circuit/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.12/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O only/JJ/O minor/JJ/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O ././O
Most/JJS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 4,500/CD/O workers/NNS/O were/VBD/O at/IN/O work/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O no/DT/O production/NN/O slowdown/NN/O was/VBD/O anticipated/VBN/O as/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O electricity/NN/O remains/VBZ/O available/JJ/O ././O
AMDAHL/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O computer/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.8/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O closed/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O and/CC/O no/DT/O damage/NN/O estimates/NNS/O were/VBD/O available/JJ/O ././O
AMERICAN/NNP/B-ORG BUILDING/NNP/I-ORG MAINTENANCE/NNP/I-ORG INDUSTRIES/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O provider/NN/O of/IN/O maintenance/NN/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 582/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O some/DT/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O headquarters/NN/O and/CC/O lost/VBD/O phone/NN/O service/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O operations/NNS/O were/VBD/O moved/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O branch/NN/O office/NN/O and/CC/O are/VBP/O running/VBG/O smoothly/RB/O thanks/NNS/O to/TO/O a/DT/O decentralized/JJ/O computer/NN/O system/NN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O had/VBD/O developed/VBN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O work/VB/O a/DT/O ship/NN/O due/JJ/O in/IN/O today/NN/O with/IN/O minimal/JJ/O delays/NNS/O ,/,/O despite/IN/O sporadic/JJ/O power/NN/O ././O
ANACOMP/NNP/B-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Indianapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O Xidex/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE maker/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O disks/NNS/O and/CC/O microfilm/NN/O with/IN/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 637/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O only/JJ/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O ././O
ANTHEM/NNP/B-ORG ELECTRONICS/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O distributor/NN/O of/IN/O electronic/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O sustained/VBD/O very/RB/O little/JJ/O damage/NN/O ,/,/O anticipated/VBN/O being/VBG/O ``/``/O in/IN/O 100/CD/O %/NN/O operating/NN/O condition/NN/O ''/''/O by/IN/O midday/NN/O ././O
APPLE/NNP/B-ORG COMPUTER/NNP/I-ORG CO./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Cupertino/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O computer/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 4.07/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O sustained/VBD/O some/DT/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O ././O
Offices/NNS/O were/VBD/O closed/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Company/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O 1,750/CD/O workers/NNS/O in/IN/O area/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O fully/RB/O functional/JJ/O ././O
ATARI/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O and/CC/O software/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 700/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O by/IN/O tomorrow/NN/O ././O
BANKAMERICA/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O bank/NN/O holding/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 10.2/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O yesterday/NN/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O power/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NNS/O ,/,/O 80/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 433/CD/O Northern/NNP/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC branches/NNS/O were/VBD/O closed/JJ/O and/CC/O 250/CD/O of/IN/O 750/CD/O automatic/JJ/O teller/NN/O machines/NNS/O were/VBD/O closed/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O ././O
Securities/NNS/O trading/NN/O was/VBD/O conducted/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O backup/JJ/O facility/NN/O in/IN/O Concord/NNP/B-GPE ././O
BECHTEL/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O engineering/NN/O and/CC/O construction/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O only/RB/O minor/JJ/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O three/CD/O buildings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O computers/NNS/O were/VBD/O knocked/VBN/O out/RP/O ././O
Workers/NNS/O ,/,/O except/IN/O for/IN/O senior/JJ/O management/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O asked/VBN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O report/VB/O for/IN/O work/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
BORLAND/NNP/B-ORG INTERNATIONAL/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Scotts/NNP/B-GPE Valley/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O personal/JJ/O computer/NN/O and/CC/O software/NN/O designer/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 72/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O heavy/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O conducting/VBG/O business/NN/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O parking/NN/O lot/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O any/DT/O shipping/NN/O delays/NNS/O ././O
BUSINESSLAND/NNP/B-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O computer/NN/O retail/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O all/DT/O 16/CD/O corporate/JJ/O office/NN/O and/CC/O stores/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O were/VBD/O open/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O exception/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O retail/JJ/O center/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE business/NN/O district/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O facility/NN/O should/MD/O reopen/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
CARTER/NNP/B-ORG HAWLEY/NNP/I-ORG HALE/NNP/I-ORG STORES/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O retailer/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.79/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O nine/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 22/CD/O Emporium/NNP/B-ORG stores/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O were/VBD/O closed/JJ/O because/IN/O of/IN/O water/NN/O damage/NN/O ,/,/O broken/JJ/O windows/NNS/O and/CC/O fallen/JJ/O displays/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O sales/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O hurt/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O losses/NNS/O are/VBP/O covered/VBN/O by/IN/O insurance/NN/O ././O
CHEVRON/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O oil/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 25.2/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O downtown/JJ/O headquarters/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O closed/VBD/O two/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O seven/CD/O buildings/NNS/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Ramone/NNP/I-GPE industrial/JJ/O park/NN/O ././O
Company/NN/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
CLOROX/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O consumer/NN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.36/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O closed/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O but/CC/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O reopen/VB/O today/NN/O or/CC/O tomorrow/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O orders/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O routed/VBN/O through/IN/O Kingsford/NNP/B-ORG Products/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O in/IN/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ky./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O but/CC/O computer/NN/O problems/NNS/O mean/VBP/O they/PRP/O must/MD/O be/VB/O processed/VBN/O manually/RB/O ././O
Expects/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O early/RB/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
COHERENT/NNP/B-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O laser/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 159/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O closed/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O but/CC/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O reopen/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
CONSOLIDATED/NNP/B-ORG FREIGHTWAYS/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Menlo/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O trucking/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O $/$/O 2.69/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O CF/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Freight/NNP/I-ORG subsidiary/NN/O 's/POS/O office/NN/O in/IN/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O no/DT/O damage/NN/O in/IN/O Menlo/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ././O
COOPER/NNP/B-ORG COMPANIES/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O medical/JJ/O products/NNS/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 628/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O little/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O full/JJ/O operation/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O reopen/VB/O three/CD/O Target/NNP/B-ORG stores/NNS/O and/CC/O all/DT/O but/IN/O two/CD/O Mervyn/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O today/NN/O or/CC/O tomorrow/NN/O ././O
DIASONICS/NNP/B-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE San/NNP/I-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O magnetic/JJ/O resonance/NN/O imaging/NN/O equipment/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 281/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O Amex/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O ,/,/O mostly/RB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O stockroom/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O today/NN/O ././O
DIGITAL/NNP/B-ORG EQUIPMENT/NNP/I-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Maynard/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O computer/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 12.7/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE sales/NNS/O office/NN/O but/CC/O no/DT/O appreciable/JJ/O damage/NN/O elsewhere/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O its/PRP$/O Cupertino/NNP/B-GPE plant/NN/O ././O
DREYER'S/NNP/B-ORG GRAND/NNP/I-ORG ICE/NNP/I-ORG CREAM/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ice/NN/O cream/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 225/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O delivering/VBG/O ice/NN/O cream/NN/O wherever/WRB/O roads/NNS/O are/VBP/O passable/JJ/O ././O
EVEREX/NNP/B-ORG SYSTEMS/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Fremont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O and/CC/O peripherals/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 377/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O almost/RB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
EXXON/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O oil/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O refinery/NN/O northeast/RB/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE was/VBD/O operating/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O slightly/RB/O reduced/VBN/O rate/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O precaution/NN/O in/IN/O case/NN/O of/IN/O aftershocks/NNS/O ././O
GENENTECH/NNP/B-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O South/NNP/B-GPE San/NNP/I-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O biotechnology/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 334.8/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O sustained/VBD/O no/DT/O major/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O today/NN/O ././O
Business/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disrupted/VBD/O ././O
GENERAL/NNP/B-ORG MOTORS/NNP/I-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Detroit/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 123.6/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O sustained/VBD/O about/RB/O 10/CD/O injuries/NNS/O to/TO/O workers/NNS/O and/CC/O some/DT/O ruptured/JJ/O water/NN/O mains/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O New/NNP/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Manufacturing/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG facility/NN/O in/IN/O Fremont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O with/IN/O Toyota/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Plant/NN/O officials/NNS/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O assessing/VBG/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O parts/NNS/O suppliers/NNS/O and/CC/O Port/NNP/B-FAC of/IN/I-FAC Oakland/NNP/I-FAC facilities/NNS/O that/WDT/O handle/VBP/O shipments/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O ././O
GOLDEN/NNP/B-ORG WEST/NNP/I-ORG FINANCIAL/NNP/I-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O savings/NNS/O and/CC/O loan/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.4/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O only/JJ/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O branches/NNS/O and/CC/O no/DT/O injured/JJ/O employees/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O computer/NN/O system/NN/O was/VBD/O operating/VBG/O ,/,/O so/IN/O orders/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O has/VBZ/O 18,000/CD/O employees/NNS/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 70/CD/O buildings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ././O
One/CD/O building/NN/O in/IN/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE may/MD/O be/VB/O damaged/JJ/O beyond/IN/O repair/NN/O ././O
Others/NNS/O had/VBD/O lesser/JJR/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O there/EX/O were/VBD/O no/DT/O injuries/NNS/O among/IN/O workers/NNS/O ././O
Damage/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O ``/``/O easily/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O millions/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
HEXCEL/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Dublin/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O manufacturer/NN/O of/IN/O engineered/JJ/O parts/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 399/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O little/JJ/O damage/NN/O beyond/IN/O some/DT/O phone/NN/O trouble/NN/O ././O
HOMESTAKE/NNP/B-ORG MINING/NNP/I-ORG CO./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O gold/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O miner/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 432.6/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O was/VBD/O closed/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O power/NN/O failures/NNS/O and/CC/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O water/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O may/MD/O reopen/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O any/DT/O impact/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O business/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O slight/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O expects/VBZ/O all/DT/O branches/NNS/O to/TO/O reopen/VB/O today/NN/O ././O
INMAC/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Clara/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O accessories/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 250/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O telephones/NNS/O were/VBD/O out/RB/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O headquarters/NN/O but/CC/O service/NN/O should/MD/O be/VB/O restored/VBN/O by/IN/O today/NN/O ././O
INTEL/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Clara/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O semiconductor/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.87/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O some/DT/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O few/JJ/O people/NNS/O were/VBD/O at/IN/O work/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O plant/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O 8,500/CD/O employees/NNS/O gradually/RB/O will/MD/O resume/VB/O operations/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O several/JJ/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O closing/NN/O ,/,/O affecting/VBG/O 266/CD/O employees/NNS/O ,/,/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O until/IN/O roads/NNS/O are/VBP/O cleared/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O known/VBN/O to/TO/O what/WP/O extent/NN/O ,/,/O if/IN/O any/DT/O ,/,/O the/DT/O facility/NN/O was/VBD/O damaged/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O division/NN/O had/VBD/O only/RB/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O Sunnyvale/NNP/B-GPE headquarters/NN/O and/CC/O plant/NN/O in/IN/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Altos/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O no/DT/O delays/NNS/O in/IN/O deliveries/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O ././O
All/DT/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O reopen/VB/O soon/RB/O ././O
LSI/NNP/B-ORG LOGIC/NNP/I-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Milpitas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O customized/JJ/O integrated/JJ/O circuits/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 550/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O halted/VBN/O manufacturing/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O three/CD/O plants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O while/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O inspected/VBN/O for/IN/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O full/JJ/O operations/NNS/O by/IN/O today/NN/O ././O
MEASUREX/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Cupertino/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O integrated/JJ/O manufacturing/NN/O processes/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 265/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O had/VBD/O only/RB/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O but/CC/O workers/NNS/O spent/VBD/O most/RBS/O of/IN/O yesterday/NN/O cleaning/VBG/O up/RP/O ././O
Production/NN/O resumed/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
ORACLE/NNP/B-ORG SYSTEMS/NNP/I-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Belmont/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O provider/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O programming/NN/O and/CC/O software/NN/O services/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O $/$/O 584/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O four/CD/O of/IN/O 12/CD/O offices/NNS/O and/CC/O buildings/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Belmont/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O San/NNP/B-GPE Mateo/NNP/I-GPE areas/NNS/O were/VBD/O closed/JJ/O ,/,/O 95/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O and/CC/O telephone/NN/O systems/NNS/O are/VBP/O operating/VBG/O ,/,/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O back/RB/O to/TO/O full/JJ/O operation/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
PACIFIC/NNP/B-ORG TELESIS/NNP/I-ORG GROUP/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O telecommunications/NNS/O holding/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 9.5/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O no/DT/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O headquarters/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O no/DT/O power/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O power/NN/O failure/NN/O has/VBZ/O caused/VBN/O a/DT/O delay/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O release/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O earnings/NNS/O report/NN/O ,/,/O major/JJ/O concern/NN/O is/VBZ/O subsidiaries/NNS/O ,/,/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Bell/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Pacific/NNP/B-ORG Telesis/NNP/I-ORG Cellular/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O both/DT/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O sustained/VBD/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O buildings/NNS/O ,/,/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O several/JJ/O cellular/JJ/O sites/NNS/O in/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Cruz/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O volume/NN/O of/IN/O calls/NNS/O on/IN/O cellular/JJ/O phones/NNS/O 10/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O usual/JJ/O ,/,/O causing/VBG/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O slowdown/NN/O ././O
QUANTUM/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Milpitas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O manufactures/VBZ/O rigid/JJ/O disc/NN/O drives/NNS/O for/IN/O small/JJ/O business/NN/O computers/NNS/O ,/,/O word/NN/O processors/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O $/$/O 120.8/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O open/JJ/O for/IN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O minor/JJ/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O ././O
RAYCHEM/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Menlo/NNP/B-GPE Park/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O plastics/NNS/O manufacturer/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O no/DT/O major/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O no/DT/O production/NN/O slowdown/NN/O is/VBZ/O anticipated/VBN/O ././O
ROSS/NNP/B-ORG STORES/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Newark/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O discount/NN/O apparel/NN/O chain/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O $/$/O 576/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O two/CD/O of/IN/O 28/CD/O stores/NNS/O in/IN/O Bay/NNP/B-LOC Area/NNP/I-LOC closed/JJ/O ,/,/O both/DT/O could/MD/O open/VB/O as/RB/O early/RB/O as/IN/O today/NN/O ././O
SAFEWAY/NNP/B-ORG STORES/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O retail/JJ/O food/NN/O chain/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 13.6/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O some/DT/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O headquarters/NN/O and/CC/O no/DT/O power/NN/O ;/:/O major/JJ/O problems/NNS/O transporting/VBG/O products/NNS/O to/TO/O those/DT/O stores/NNS/O that/WDT/O remained/VBD/O open/JJ/O ;/:/O no/DT/O numbers/NNS/O on/IN/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O stores/NNS/O closed/VBD/O ././O
Office/NN/O closed/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O at/IN/O 4:30/CD/O p.m./NN/O EDT/NNP/O ././O
SEAGATE/NNP/B-ORG TECHNOLOGY/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Scotts/NNP/B-GPE Valley/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O hard/JJ/O disk/NN/O drives/NNS/O for/IN/O computers/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.37/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O closed/VBD/O to/TO/O assess/VB/O what/WP/O appeared/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O some/DT/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 20/CD/O buildings/NNS/O ././O
SOUTHERN/NNP/B-ORG PACIFIC/NNP/I-ORG TRANSPORTATION/NNP/I-ORG CO./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O railroad/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 2.41/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O only/RB/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O headquarters/NN/O and/CC/O tracks/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O expects/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O tomorrow/NN/O ././O
St./NNP/B-ORG Louis/NNP/I-ORG Southwestern/NNP/I-ORG Railway/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O halted/VBD/O all/DT/O service/NN/O Tuesday/NNP/O night/NN/O but/CC/O has/VBZ/O since/IN/O restored/VBN/O some/DT/O freight/NN/O lines/NNS/O and/CC/O limited/JJ/O commuter/NN/O service/NN/O between/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ././O
SUN/NNP/B-ORG MICROSYSTEMS/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Mountain/NNP/B-GPE View/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O desktop/JJ/O computers/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O $/$/O 1.77/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O no/DT/O injured/JJ/O employees/NNS/O and/CC/O very/RB/O little/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O buildings/NNS/O ././O
Closed/VBN/O yesterday/RB/O due/JJ/O to/TO/O power/NN/O difficulties/NNS/O ././O
TANDEM/NNP/B-ORG COMPUTERS/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Cupertino/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O computer/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.6/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O NYSE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O significant/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O should/MD/O be/VB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O within/IN/O a/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O employees/NNS/O stayed/VBD/O home/RB/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O customer/NN/O service/NN/O was/VBD/O being/VBG/O maintained/VBN/O ././O
VARIAN/NNP/B-ORG ASSOCIATES/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Palo/NNP/B-GPE Alto/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O instrumentation/NN/O and/CC/O semiconductor/NN/O equipment/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 1.3/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O had/VBD/O only/RB/O minor/JJ/O damage/NN/O and/CC/O no/DT/O slowdowns/NNS/O were/VBD/O anticipated/VBN/O ././O
VLSI/NNP/B-ORG TECHNOLOGY/NNP/I-ORG INC./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O semiconductor/NN/O products/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O $/$/O 171.9/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O minimal/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O facilities/NNS/O ,/,/O no/DT/O injuries/NNS/O ,/,/O expected/VBN/O operations/NNS/O to/TO/O return/VB/O to/TO/O normal/JJ/O late/RB/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
3COM/NNP/B-ORG CORP./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Clara/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O computer/NN/O communications/NNS/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 386/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O OTC/NNP/O ,/,/O slight/JJ/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O headquarters/NNS/O ,/,/O communications/NNS/O systems/NNS/O already/RB/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O ././O
