Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Craven/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O group/NN/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O over/RB/O the/DT/O chairmanship/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O merchant/NN/O banking/VBG/O group/NN/O from/IN/O Sir/NNP/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Carey/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O retiring/VBG/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Carey/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O remain/VB/O a/DT/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O merchant/NN/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O board/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Craven/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O widely/RB/O credited/VBN/O with/IN/O refocusing/NN/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG energies/NNS/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O core/NN/O corporate/JJ/O finance/NN/O ,/,/O fund/NN/O management/NN/O and/CC/O banking/VBG/O activities/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG shut/VBD/O down/RB/O its/PRP$/O ailing/VBG/O U.K./NN/B-GPE securities/NNS/O operations/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Craven/NNP/B-PERSON joined/VBD/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O group/NN/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O in/IN/O May/NNP/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O after/IN/O the/DT/O resignations/NNS/O of/IN/O former/JJ/O Chief/NNP/O Executive/NNP/O Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Reeves/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O top/JJ/O officials/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O merchant/NN/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O role/NN/O in/IN/O Guinness/NNP/B-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG controversial/JJ/O takeover/NN/O of/IN/O Distiller/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Co./NN/I-ORG in/IN/O 1986/CD/O ././O
Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O advised/VBN/O Guinness/NNP/B-ORG on/IN/O the/DT/O bid/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O was/VBD/O surrounded/VBN/O by/IN/O allegations/NNS/O that/IN/O Guinness/NNP/B-ORG used/VBD/O artificial/NN/O means/NNS/O to/TO/O support/VB/O the/DT/O bid/NN/O 's/POS/O value/NN/O ././O
Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Dobson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O currently/RB/O group/NN/O deputy/NN/O chief/NN/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O assume/VB/O the/DT/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O position/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O merchant/NN/O bank/NN/O also/RB/O announced/VBD/O that/IN/O finance/NN/O director/NN/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Eward/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O early/JJ/O retirement/NN/O for/IN/O personal/NN/O reasons/NNS/O ././O
News/NNP/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Eward/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O retirement/NN/O comes/VBZ/O one/CD/O day/NN/O after/IN/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O Christopher/NNP/B-PERSON Whittington/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O banking/VBG/O subsidiary/NN/O to/TO/O join/VB/O a/DT/O financial/JJ/O services/NNS/O firm/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Craven/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O both/DT/O Messrs./NNP/O Eward/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Whittington/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O planned/VBN/O to/TO/O leave/VB/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O earlier/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Craven/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O persuaded/VBN/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O remain/VB/O until/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O healthy/JJ/O position/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O any/DT/O coincidence/NN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O departures/NNS/O it/PRP/O 's/POS/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O leaving/VBG/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O reasonably/RB/O good/JJ/O shape/NN/O and/CC/O going/VBG/O forward/RB/O very/RB/O well/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O Morgan/NNP/B-ORG Grenfell/NNP/I-ORG announced/VBD/O its/PRP$/O pretax/NN/O profit/NN/O rose/VBD/O 49.6/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O #/#/O 32.8/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O half/NN/O ,/,/O boosted/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O healthy/JJ/O growth/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O domestic/JJ/O and/CC/O international/JJ/O corporate/JJ/O finance/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
