Crown/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O reached/VBD/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O the/DT/O Gold/NNP/B-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O it/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O already/RB/O own/JJ/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O Gold/NNP/B-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG holders/NNS/O will/MD/O receive/VB/O 1.43/CD/O Crown/NNP/B-ORG shares/NNS/O for/IN/O each/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 1.1/CD/O million/CD/O Gold/NNP/B-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG shares/NNS/O not/RB/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O Crown/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O already/RB/O owns/VBZ/O 65/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O arrangement/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Supreme/NNP/I-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE province/NN/O ,/,/O Crown/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Gold/NNP/B-ORG Texas/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Vancouver/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Crown/NNP/B-ORG Resources/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Both/DT/O are/VBP/O mining/NN/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
