Great/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O board/NN/O approved/VBD/O the/DT/O formation/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O holding/NN/O company/NN/O enabling/VBG/O the/DT/O savings/NNS/O bank/NN/O to/TO/O pursue/VB/O nontraditional/JJ/O banking/NN/O activities/NNS/O under/IN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O federal/JJ/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O proposed/JJ/O holding/NN/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O primary/JJ/O purpose/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O Great/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O continue/VB/O engaging/JJ/O in/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O development/NN/O activities/NNS/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Those/DT/O activities/NNS/O generated/VBD/O $/$/O 26.1/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O Great/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O such/JJ/O profits/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O count/VB/O toward/IN/O meeting/VBG/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE savings/NNS/O bank/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O capitalization/NN/O requirements/NNS/O under/IN/O 1989/CD/O federal/JJ/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O unit/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O capital/NN/O structure/NN/O to/TO/O comply/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O law/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O proposed/JJ/O holding/NN/O company/NN/O would/MD/O also/RB/O consolidate/VB/O Great/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O its/PRP$/O Tucson/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ariz./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O savings/NNS/O bank/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O ,/,/O federally/RB/O chartered/JJ/O institution/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Diego/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O consolidation/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O save/VB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O in/IN/O administrative/JJ/O costs/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Great/NNP/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
