Loral/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O received/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 325/CD/O million/CD/O order/NN/O from/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Ministry/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O contract/NN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ever/RB/O has/VBZ/O received/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O defense/NN/O electronics/NNS/O maker/NN/O said/VBD/O delivery/NN/O will/MD/O begin/VB/O in/IN/O October/NNP/O 1991/CD/O and/CC/O run/VB/O through/IN/O mid-1995/NN/O ././O
Loral/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O with/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O provide/VB/O opportunities/NNS/O for/IN/O Loral/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O supply/VB/O that/DT/O country/NN/O with/IN/O other/JJ/O defense/NN/O systems/NNS/O ././O
