Times/NNP/B-ORG may/MD/O be/VB/O tough/JJ/O on/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O for/IN/O some/DT/O ,/,/O but/CC/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O bosses/NNS/O are/VBP/O making/VBG/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O ever/RB/O --/:/O or/CC/O more/JJR/O ././O
The/DT/O figures/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O include/VB/O substantial/JJ/O dividends/NNS/O on/IN/O holdings/NNS/O of/IN/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG stock/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Greenberg/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O was/VBD/O paid/VBN/O $/$/O 4.5/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O before/IN/O an/DT/O estimated/JJ/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O dividends/NNS/O ,/,/O up/RB/O from/IN/O $/$/O 2.4/CD/O million/CD/O the/DT/O year/NN/O before/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O increase/NN/O is/VBZ/O noted/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O brokerage/NN/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O latest/JJS/O proxy/JJ/O statement/NN/O filed/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Securities/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Because/IN/O it/PRP/O operates/VBZ/O on/IN/O a/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG yearly/JJ/O filings/NNS/O are/VBP/O available/JJ/O much/RB/O earlier/RBR/O than/IN/O those/DT/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O firms/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O latest/JJS/O period/NN/O includes/VBZ/O 14/CD/O months/NNS/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O 12/CD/O because/IN/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG changed/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ending/VBG/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O April/NNP/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG 650/CD/O stock/NN/O and/CC/O bond/NN/O salesmen/NNS/O saw/VBD/O thinner/JJR/O paychecks/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O year/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O the/DT/O company/NN/O says/VBZ/O reflected/VBD/O lower/JJR/O commission/NN/O revenue/NN/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O decline/NN/O in/IN/O investor/NN/O activity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O markets/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG on/IN/O Monday/NNP/O reported/VBD/O improved/JJ/O earnings/NNS/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O ended/VBN/O Sept./NNP/O 29/CD/O ,/,/O partly/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O 31/CD/O %/NN/O increase/NN/O in/IN/O commissions/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O quarter/NN/O ././O
William/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Montgoris/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/JJ/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O defended/VBD/O the/DT/O lofty/JJ/O salaries/NNS/O at/IN/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O All/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O are/VBP/O on/IN/O a/DT/O base/JJ/O salary/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O if/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O makes/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O pretty/RB/O low/JJ/O as/RB/O far/RB/O as/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O goes/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Montgoris/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O never/RB/O had/VBD/O an/DT/O unprofitable/JJ/O year/NN/O since/IN/O its/PRP$/O founding/NN/O 65/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O proxy/JJ/O statement/NN/O ,/,/O James/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Cayne/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 55/CD/O ,/,/O Bear/NNP/B-ORG Stearns/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG president/NN/O ,/,/O made/VBD/O $/$/O 3.9/CD/O million/CD/O ;/:/O an/DT/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Tarnopol/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 53/CD/O ,/,/O made/VBD/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 3.4/CD/O million/CD/O ;/:/O and/CC/O two/CD/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O presidents/NNS/O ,/,/O Vincent/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Mattone/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 44/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O William/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Michaelcheck/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O 42/CD/O ,/,/O made/VBN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 3.3/CD/O million/CD/O each/DT/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Montgoris/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O ``/``/O straight/JJ/O mathematical/JJ/O formula/NN/O ''/''/O for/IN/O determining/VBG/O compensation/NN/O ,/,/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O earnings/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Just/RB/O because/IN/O a/DT/O particular/JJ/O element/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O is/VBZ/O down/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O stockbrokerage/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O mean/VB/O the/DT/O executive/JJ/O committee/NN/O should/MD/O be/VB/O paid/VBN/O less/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
