Egon/NNP/B-PERSON Krenz/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O man/NN/O tapped/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O to/TO/O become/VB/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE new/JJ/O leader/NN/O ,/,/O faces/VBZ/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O task/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O fallen/VBN/O to/TO/O neighboring/VBG/O socialist/JJ/O colleagues/NNS/O :/:/O reforming/VBG/O a/DT/O country/NN/O in/IN/O crisis/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O unlike/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O new/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC Bloc/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O face/VB/O an/DT/O immediate/JJ/O threat/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O very/JJ/O existence/NN/O :/:/O German/JJ/O reunification/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O change/VB/O his/PRP$/O stripes/NNS/O and/CC/O become/VB/O another/DT/B-PERSON Milton/NNP/I-PERSON Friedman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O still/RB/O stand/VB/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O chance/NN/O of/IN/O losing/VBG/O a/DT/O country/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON almost/RB/O certainly/RB/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O younger/JJR/O version/NN/O of/IN/O Erich/NNP/B-PERSON Honecker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O rigid/JJ/O predecessor/NN/O as/IN/O dictator/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O followed/VBN/O much/RB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O career/NN/O path/NN/O as/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O Both/DT/O spent/VBD/O years/NNS/O overseeing/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Freie/NNP/I-ORG Deutsche/NNP/I-ORG Jugend/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O youth/NN/O group/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O communist/JJ/O regime/NN/O 's/POS/O principal/JJ/O tool/NN/O for/IN/O stamping/VBG/O young/JJ/O Germans/NNPS/O into/IN/O socialist/JJ/O citizens/NNS/O ././O
More/RBR/O recently/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O security/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O youngest/JJS/O member/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ruling/VBG/O Politburo/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Faced/VBN/O with/IN/O another/DT/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O so/RB/O many/JJ/O despairing/JJ/O East/NNP/O Germans/NNPS/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O flee/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O German/JJ/O peoples/NNS/O will/MD/O get/VB/O their/PRP$/O reunification/NN/O ,/,/O de/FW/O facto/FW/O ,/,/O on/IN/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O ground/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O if/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE arthritic/JJ/O Politburo/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O loosen/VB/O up/RP/O enough/RB/O to/TO/O permit/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O make/VB/O serious/JJ/O efforts/NNS/O at/IN/O reform/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O face/VB/O a/DT/O challenge/NN/O just/RB/O as/IN/O fundamental/JJ/O ././O
Abandoning/VBG/O socialism/NN/O means/NNS/O abandoning/VBG/O the/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O state/NN/O 's/POS/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O existence/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O with/IN/O it/PRP/O the/DT/O justification/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O watchdogs/NNS/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O Wall/NNP/B-FAC ././O
In/IN/O this/DT/O scenario/NN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O imagine/VB/O that/IN/O a/DT/O pale/JJ/O imitation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Republic/NNP/I-ORG could/MD/O avoid/VB/O being/VBG/O pulled/VBD/O into/IN/O some/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O tie/NN/O --/:/O economic/JJ/O ,/,/O federal/JJ/O or/CC/O stronger/JJR/O --/:/O with/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O need/VB/O a/DT/O bit/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O to/TO/O consolidate/VB/O his/PRP$/O empire/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O do/VB/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O to/TO/O promote/VB/O Reunification/NNP/O Scenario/NNP/O One/CD/O ././O
Cartoonists/NNP/O in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE have/VBP/O already/RB/O mocked/VBN/O the/DT/O exodus/NN/O by/IN/O imagining/VBG/O an/DT/O advertisement/NN/O placed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O ``/``/O Wanted/VBN/O :/:/O one/CD/O people/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O embassies/NNS/O in/IN/O Prague/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Budapest/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE are/VBP/O continuing/VBG/O to/TO/O find/VB/O refugees/NNS/O at/IN/O their/PRP$/O gates/NNS/O ././O
Of/IN/O course/NN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O true/JJ/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O tradition/NN/O ,/,/O could/MD/O tighten/VB/O its/PRP$/O borders/NNS/O yet/CC/O further/RBR/O ././O
Two/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O gestures/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON regime/NN/O were/VBD/O to/TO/O close/VB/O the/DT/O border/NN/O to/TO/O Czechoslovakia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O install/VB/O halogen/NN/O lights/NNS/O in/IN/O some/DT/O spots/NNS/O along/IN/O the/DT/O frontier/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O some/DT/O reports/NNS/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O moving/VBG/O to/TO/O ``/``/O soften/VB/O ''/''/O his/PRP$/O reputation/NN/O ,/,/O notably/RB/O rumors/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O he/PRP/O who/WP/O kept/VBD/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE state/NN/O police/NN/O off/IN/O protesters/NNS/O '/POS/O backs/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O dismal/JJ/O 40th/JJ/O anniversary/NN/O celebrations/NNS/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
Czech/JJ/O reformers/NNS/O can/MD/O recall/VB/O the/DT/O Wilsonian/JJ/O ideals/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O period/NN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O country/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O the/DT/O Soviet/NNP/B-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON the/DT/I-PERSON Great/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O rediscover/VB/O ,/,/O should/MD/O it/PRP/O choose/VB/O to/TO/O ././O
But/CC/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O merely/RB/O ``/``/O the/DT/O land/NN/O of/IN/O truly/RB/O existing/VBG/O socialism/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Beyond/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O with/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE for/IN/O a/DT/O claim/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O German/JJ/O identity/NN/O ././O
Up/IN/O to/TO/O now/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O weapon/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O worker/NN/O and/CC/O peasant/NN/O state/NN/O ''/''/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O ideology/NN/O of/IN/O socialism/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O talk/NN/O today/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O economic/JJ/O miracle/NN/O in/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE no/RB/O longer/RBR/O can/MD/O content/VB/O itself/PRP/O with/IN/O being/VBG/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O star/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O loser/JJ/O league/NN/O ././O
Without/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O military/NN/O and/CC/O party/NN/O behind/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE runs/VBZ/O the/DT/O risk/NN/O of/IN/O disintegrating/VBG/O ././O
There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O certain/JJ/O cruel/JJ/O logic/NN/O at/IN/O work/NN/O here/RB/O :/:/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O particularly/RB/O appropriate/JJ/O --/:/O and/CC/O tragic/JJ/O --/:/O that/IN/O the/DT/O land/NN/O that/WDT/O produced/VBD/O Karl/NNP/B-PERSON Marx/NNP/I-PERSON should/MD/O prove/VB/O socialism/NN/O 's/POS/O failure/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O experiment/NN/O that/WDT/O uses/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O people/NNS/O as/IN/O controls/NNS/O ././O
There/EX/O may/MD/O be/VB/O forces/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O delay/VB/O this/DT/O scenario/NN/O ././O
Ideologues/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O to/TO/O surrender/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Germans/NNPS/O are/VBP/O an/DT/O ideological/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O protesters/NNS/O who/WP/O greeted/VBD/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON at/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE airport/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O month/NN/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O shouting/VBG/O ``/``/O Go/VB/O U.S.A/NNP/B-GPE ''/''/O --/:/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O chanting/VBG/O ``/``/O Gorby/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Help/VB/O Us/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Ideologues/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O border/NN/O can/MD/O also/RB/O slow/VB/O the/DT/O process/NN/O ././O
Helmut/NNP/B-PERSON Kohl/NNP/I-PERSON 's/VBZ/I-PERSON governing/VBG/O conservative/JJ/O coalition/NN/O is/VBZ/O proving/VBG/O admirably/RB/O true/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O constitution/NN/O by/IN/O making/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 500,000/CD/O people/NNS/O of/IN/O German/JJ/O descent/NN/O automatic/JJ/O citizens/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O alone/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O within/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O and/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O think/VB/O tanks/NNS/O outside/IN/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O West/NNP/O Germans/NNPS/O maintain/VBP/O that/IN/O they/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O immediate/JJ/O reunification/NN/O ././O
Politically/RB/O ,/,/O this/DT/O currently/RB/O is/VBZ/O wisdom/NN/O --/:/O particularly/RB/O given/VBN/O a/DT/O nervous/JJ/O neighboring/JJ/O France/NNP/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O ironic/JJ/O if/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O reunification/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O like/IN/O its/PRP$/O division/NN/O ,/,/O eventually/RB/O were/VBD/O the/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O actions/NNS/O in/IN/O centers/NNS/O of/IN/O power/NN/O other/JJ/O than/IN/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Berlin/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O as/RB/O close/JJ/O as/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE gets/VBZ/O to/TO/O practicing/VBG/O ``/``/O glasnost/NN/O ''/''/O ,/,/O Otto/NNP/B-PERSON Reinhold/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O party/NN/O theorist/NN/O ,/,/O actually/RB/O acknowledged/VBD/O the/DT/O reunification/NN/O dilemma/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O main/JJ/O problem/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Reinhold/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O radio/NN/O interview/NN/O monitored/VBN/O by/IN/O Radio/NNP/B-ORG Free/NNP/I-ORG Europe/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Munich/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O stems/VBZ/O from/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O GDR/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O different/JJ/O ''/''/O from/IN/O other/JJ/O East/JJ/O European/JJ/O states/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O What/WDT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O right/NN/O to/TO/O exist/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O asked/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O would/MD/O a/DT/O capitalist/JJ/O German/NNP/B-GPE Democratic/NNP/I-GPE Republic/NNP/I-GPE have/VBP/O alongside/IN/O a/DT/O capitalist/JJ/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Republic/NNP/I-ORG ?/./O ''/''/O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O question/NN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ca/MD/O n't/RB/O answer/VB/O easily/RB/O ,/,/O no/DT/O matter/NN/O what/WP/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O leader/NN/O does/VBZ/O ././O
