His/PRP$/O comments/NNS/O ,/,/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O response/NN/O to/TO/O reporters/NNS/O '/POS/O questions/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG Club/NNP/I-ORG here/RB/O ,/,/O signaled/VBD/O that/IN/O Seoul/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O resisting/VBG/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE pressure/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O further/JJR/O rise/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O currency/NN/O 's/POS/O value/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE wants/VBZ/O a/DT/O higher/JJR/O won/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE exports/NNS/O more/RBR/O expensive/JJ/O and/CC/O help/VB/O trim/VB/O Seoul/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O trade/NN/O surplus/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O South/JJ/O Korean/JJ/O business/NN/O people/NNS/O want/VBP/O a/DT/O devaluation/NN/O instead/RB/O ,/,/O arguing/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O won/VBN/O 's/POS/O recent/JJ/O gains/NNS/O already/RB/O have/VBP/O weakened/VBN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O export/NN/O performance/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roh/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O said/VBD/O South/NNP/B-GPE Korea/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O steps/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O free/VB/O the/DT/O won/NN/O to/TO/O respond/VB/O to/TO/O market/NN/O forces/NNS/O ././O
Seoul/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O pointed/VBN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O foreign/JJ/O exchange/NN/O market/NN/O as/IN/O one/CD/O reason/NN/O the/DT/O won/NN/O 's/POS/O value/NN/O remains/VBZ/O heavily/RB/O controlled/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Roh/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE demand/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O removal/NN/O of/IN/O South/JJ/O Korean/JJ/O import/NN/O quotas/NNS/O on/IN/O beef/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O resolved/VBN/O ``/``/O satisfactorily/RB/O ''/''/O but/CC/O gave/VBD/O no/DT/O hint/NN/O when/WRB/O that/DT/O will/MD/O happen/VB/O ././O
