The/DT/O former/JJ/O president/NN/O of/IN/O FirstSouth/NNP/B-ORG F.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O defunct/JJ/O Arkansas/NNP/B-GPE thrift/NN/O ,/,/O pleaded/VBD/O guilty/JJ/O to/TO/O conspiring/VBG/O to/TO/O inflate/VB/O the/DT/O institution/NN/O 's/POS/O earnings/NNS/O by/IN/O concealing/VBG/O worthless/JJ/O loan/NN/O guarantees/NNS/O ././O
Roderick/NNP/B-PERSON D./NNP/I-PERSON Reed/NNP/I-PERSON III/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O was/VBD/O also/RB/O chief/JJ/O operating/NN/O officer/NN/O of/IN/O FirstSouth/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O could/MD/O receive/VB/O a/DT/O maximum/JJ/O sentence/NN/O of/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O fine/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O sentencing/NN/O date/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O been/VBN/O set/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O conspiracy/NN/O was/VBD/O part/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Reed/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O hide/VB/O FirstSouth/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O shaky/JJ/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O from/IN/O federal/JJ/O regulators/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O federal/JJ/O prosecutors/NNS/O and/CC/O regulators/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O $/$/O 1.68/CD/O billion/CD/O thrift/NN/O was/VBD/O declared/VBN/O insolvent/JJ/O and/CC/O closed/VBN|VBD/O in/IN/O December/NNP/O 1986/CD/O ././O
FirstSouth/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O former/JJ/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O Howard/NNP/B-PERSON Weichern/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O conspiring/VBG/O to/TO/O conceal/VB/O the/DT/O agreements/NNS/O with/IN/O Messrs./NNPS/O Watson/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Taylor/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Weichern/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O for/IN/O trial/NN/O Jan./NNP/O 3/CD/O before/IN/O federal/JJ/O Judge/NNP/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Reasoner/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Little/NNP/B-GPE Rock/NNP/I-GPE ././O
