Par/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceutical/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O named/VBD/O its/PRP$/O interim/JJ/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON I./NNP/I-PERSON Sawyer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O to/TO/O those/DT/O posts/NNS/O permanently/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O elected/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O the/DT/O board/NN/O ././O
Par/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O advised/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE attorney/NN/O for/IN/O Maryland/NN/B-GPE that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O companies/NNS/O being/VBG/O investigated/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O grand/JJ/O jury/NN/B-ORG for/IN/O alleged/JJ/O violations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O Food/NNP/O ,/,/O Drug/NNP/O and/CC/O Cosmetic/NNP/O Act/NNP/O ././O
A/DT/O Par/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O understood/VBD/O the/DT/O criminal/JJ/O investigation/NN/O in/IN/O Maryland/NNP/B-GPE relates/VBZ/O to/TO/O matters/NNS/O Par/NNP/B-ORG disclosed/VBD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O Par/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O filed/VBD/O false/JJ/O drug/NN/O information/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O book/NN/O noted/VBD/O changes/NNS/O made/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O manufacturing/NN/O level/NN/O that/WDT/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Par/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O cooperating/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O investigation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Patel/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O was/VBD/O placed/VBN/O on/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O '/POS/O probation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Patel/NNP/B-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Par/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O April/NNP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sawyer/NNP/B-PERSON began/VBD/O running/VBG/O the/DT/O company/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O interim/JJ/O basis/NN/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O September/NNP/O ././O
Par/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O selected/VBD/O him/PRP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O posts/NNS/O of/IN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O permanent/JJ/O basis/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O experience/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O performance/NN/O at/IN/O Par/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Perry/NNP/B-PERSON Levine/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Sawyer/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O ``/``/O taken/VBN/O significant/JJ/O steps/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O restore/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O credibility/NN/O and/CC/O sense/NN/O of/IN/O professionalism/NN/O and/CC/O integrity/NN/O ././O
