I/PRP/O approached/VBD/O ``/``/O Mastergate/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Larry/NNP/B-PERSON Gelbart/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON new/JJ/O comedy/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Criterion/NNP/I-FAC Center/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O with/IN/O considerable/JJ/O trepidation/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O had/VBD/O underestimated/VBN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O both/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O wit/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O persistence/NN/O of/IN/O scandal/NN/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Onstage/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O hearing/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O progress/NN/O ,/,/O complete/JJ/O with/IN/O elegant/JJ/O crystal/NN/O chandelier/NN/O overhead/RB/O and/CC/O a/DT/O lifesize/JJ/O reproduction/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O signing/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Constitution/NNP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O background/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O metaphor/NN/O of/IN/O theater/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O entirely/RB/O coincidental/JJ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON clearly/RB/O feels/VBZ/O that/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O participants/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O hearing/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O witnesses/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lawyers/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O interrogators/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O news/NN/O media/NNS/O --/:/O are/VBP/O performers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O man/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O Lichtenstein/NNP/B-GPE corporation/NN/O ,/,/O licensed/VBN/O in/IN/O Libya/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O sheltered/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Bahamas/NNPS/B-GPE ././O
Supposedly/NNP/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O sell/VB/O off/RP/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O MPI/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O before/IN/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O ,/,/O a/DT/O lowly/JJ/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG agent/NN/O is/VBZ/O called/VBN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O hospital/NN/O room/NN/O of/IN/O Wylie/NNP/B-PERSON Slaughter/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O dying/VBG/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Central/NNP/I-ORG Intelligence/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O lowly/JJ/O agent/NN/O ,/,/O Abel/NNP/B-PERSON Lamb/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O as/IN/O you/PRP/O might/MD/O guess/VB/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O led/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O slaughter/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O ordered/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O over/RP/O the/DT/O studio/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O picture/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O made/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Central/JJ/O American/JJ/O country/NN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Elvador/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O cover/NN/O for/IN/O sending/VBG/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O arms/NNS/O to/TO/O Los/NNP/B-ORG Otros/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O rebel/JJ/O group/NN/O attempting/VBG/O to/TO/O regain/VB/O neighboring/JJ/O Ambigua/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O taken/VBN/O over/RP/O by/IN/O the/DT/O leftist/JJ/O dictator/NN/O Dr./NNP/O Overtega/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O podiatrist/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O leads/VBZ/O a/DT/O revolutionary/JJ/O band/NN/O of/IN/O foot/NN/O soldiers/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O has/VBZ/O fun/NN/O with/IN/O language/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O words/NNS/O goes/VBZ/O beyond/IN/O puns/NNS/O and/CC/O playfulness/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON deplores/VBZ/O the/DT/O obfuscation/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O circumlocution/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O debasement/NN/O of/IN/O language/NN/O he/PRP/O sees/VBZ/O on/IN/O all/DT/O sides/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O evening/NN/O is/VBZ/O short/JJ/O --/:/O 95/CD/O minutes/NNS/O without/IN/O an/DT/O intermission/NN/O --/:/O but/CC/O even/RB/O so/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O play/NN/O progresses/VBZ/O the/DT/O thrust/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Gelbart/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O satire/NN/O loses/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O sharpness/NN/O as/IN/O his/PRP$/O targets/NNS/O pop/VBP/O up/RP/O ever/RB/O more/RBR/O predictably/RB/O ././O
