He/PRP/O succeeds/VBZ/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Kohut/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Barkley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O marketing/NN/O executive/NN/O with/IN/O FMC/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O appointed/VBN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Continental/NNP/B-ORG Container/NNP/I-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O can/NN/O closing/VBG/O machinery/NN/O that/IN/O Figgie/NNP/B-ORG acquired/VBD/O late/RB/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Figgie/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O fire/NN/O protection/NN/O ,/,/O electronics/NN/O and/CC/O industrial/JJ/O products/NNS/O concern/NN/O ././O
