Prospect/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O recent/JJ/O hostile/JJ/O tender/NN/O offer/NN/O for/IN/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG failed/VBD/O for/IN/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O financing/NN/O ,/,/O apparently/RB/O has/VBZ/O gained/VBN/O a/DT/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O control/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O troubled/JJ/O company/NN/O anyway/RB/O ././O
As/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O a/DT/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O termed/VBD/O an/DT/O ``/``/O amiable/JJ/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O wind/VB/O up/RP/O with/IN/O control/NN/O of/IN/O top/JJ/O management/NN/O posts/NNS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O increased/JJ/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O data/NNS/O management/NN/O equipment/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O management/NN/O restructuring/NN/O ,/,/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON L./NNP/I-PERSON Ringer/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Israel/NNP/B-PERSON Sheinberg/NNP/I-PERSON resigned/VBD/O as/IN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sheinberg/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O as/IN/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Hurley/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Vanourek/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O designated/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O over/RP/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O top/JJ/O spots/NNS/O had/VBD/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O tender/NN/O offer/NN/O succeeded/VBN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O named/VBN/O co-chief/JJ/O executives/NNS/O and/CC/O directors/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hurley/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O formerly/RB/O a/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG division/NN/O ;/:/O Mr./NNP/O Vanourek/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O group/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Pitney/NNP/B-ORG Bowes/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O calls/VBZ/O for/IN/O Gilbert/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Lamphere/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG executive/JJ/O committee/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O be/VB/O named/VBN/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O restructured/VBN/O board/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O include/VB/O four/CD/O new/JJ/O independent/JJ/O directors/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O named/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O revised/JJ/O board/NN/O was/VBD/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Loose/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O counsel/NN/O ././O
Under/IN/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O ,/,/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O permitted/VBN/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Beyond/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O offer/VB/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O additional/JJ/O shares/NNS/O for/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 11.25/CD/O a/DT/O share/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O or/CC/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 14.06/CD/O a/DT/O share/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O subsequent/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O certain/JJ/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O debt/NN/O agreements/NNS/O with/IN/O bank/NN/O lenders/NNS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 3.9/CD/O million/CD/O loss/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ended/VBN/O July/NNP/O 31/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O attributed/VBD/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O to/TO/O declining/VBG/O revenue/NN/O and/CC/O litigation/NN/O costs/NNS/O relating/VBG/O to/TO/O criminal/JJ/O charges/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O two/CD/O former/JJ/O executives/NNS/O ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Moore/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Reedy/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O former/JJ/O executives/NNS/O were/VBD/O indicted/VBN/O last/JJ/O October/NNP/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O ,/,/O theft/NN/O and/CC/O conspiracy/NN/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O efforts/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O Postal/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG contracts/NNS/O ././O
Recognition/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O expected/VBD/O to/TO/O put/VB/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O stockholders/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
In/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG composite/JJ/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG rose/VBD/O 87.5/CD/O cents/NNS/O to/TO/O $/$/O 6.625/CD/O ././O
