Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O managing/NN/O director/NN/O at/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG since/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O before/IN/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Public/NNP/B-ORG Strategies/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE consulting/NN/O firm/NN/O ././O
Fannie/NNP/B-ORG Mae/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O James/NNP/B-PERSON A./NNP/I-PERSON Aliber/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Michigan/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O a/DT/O director/NN/O since/IN/O 1985/CD/O ,/,/O moved/VBD/O up/RP/O the/DT/O date/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O retirement/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O board/NN/O to/TO/O accommodate/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O election/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O director/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O board/NN/O has/VBZ/O 13/CD/O members/NNS/O elected/VBN/O by/IN/O holders/NNS/O and/CC/O five/CD/O presidential/JJ/O appointees/NNS/O ././O
