A/DT/O new/JJ/O drug/NN/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O the/DT/O rejection/NN/O of/IN/O transplanted/JJ/O organs/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O successfully/RB/O used/VBN/O on/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 100/CD/O patients/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Pittsburgh/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O researchers/NNS/O ././O
Researchers/NNS/O began/VBD/O using/VBG/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O in/IN/O February/NNP/O on/IN/O patients/NNS/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O received/VBN/O kidney/NN/O ,/,/O liver/NN/O ,/,/O heart/NN/O and/CC/O pancreas/NN/O transplants/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O drug/NN/O ,/,/O discovered/VBN/O in/IN/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O metabolized/VBN/O from/IN/O soil/NN/O fungus/NN/O found/VBN/O in/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Pittsburgh/NNP/B-GPE patients/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O humans/NNS/O to/TO/O be/VB/O given/VBN/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O Fujisawa/NNP/B-ORG Pharmaceutical/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
There/EX/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O firm/JJ/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O the/DT/O experimental/JJ/O program/NN/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Pittsburgh/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O hospital/NN/O performs/VBZ/O the/DT/O most/JJS/O transplants/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Starzl/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O research/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O largely/RB/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O by/IN/O university/NN/O funds/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Fujisawa/NNP/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O give/VB/O the/DT/O hospital/NN/O any/DT/O grants/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O research/NN/O team/NN/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O financial/JJ/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O ././O
