The/DT/O lethal/JJ/O shudders/NNS/O that/WDT/O wracked/VBD/O the/DT/B-LOC San/NNP/I-LOC Francisco/NNP/I-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC Area/NNP/I-LOC --/:/O rated/VBN/O a/DT/O 6.9/CD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Richter/JJR/O scale/NN/O --/:/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O match/VB/O the/DT/O great/JJ/O earthquake/NN/O of/IN/O 1906/CD/O ,/,/O rated/VBN/O at/IN/O 8.25/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O difference/NN/O of/IN/O just/RB/O 1.35/CD/O points/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O scale/NN/O ,/,/O designed/VBN/O by/IN/O Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Richter/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O CalTech/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O 1930s/NNS/O ,/,/O means/VBZ/O the/DT/O older/JJR/O quake/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O 10/CD/O to/TO/O 20/CD/O times/NNS/O stronger/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Lane/NNP/B-PERSON Johnson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG California/NNP/I-ORG Berkeley/NNP/I-ORG Seismographic/NNP/I-ORG Station/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O 1906/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O rupture/NN/O was/VBD/O 300/CD/O miles/NNS/O long/JJ/O and/CC/O a/DT/O couple/NN/O feet/NNS/O wide/JJ/O ././O
Though/IN/O the/DT/O epicenter/NN/O of/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O temblor/NN/O was/VBD/O located/VBN/O 10/CD/O miles/NNS/O north/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O town/NN/O of/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Cruz/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O 50/CD/O miles/NNS/O south/RB/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O its/PRP$/O havoc/NN/O hopscotched/VBD/O up/IN/O the/DT/O coast/NN/O in/IN/O seemingly/RB/O random/JJ/O fashion/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O greatest/JJS/O damage/NN/O was/VBD/O visited/VBN/O on/IN/O buildings/NNS/O and/CC/O roadways/NNS/O perched/VBN/O upon/IN/O landfill/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O were/VBD/O the/DT/B-LOC Marina/NNP/I-LOC District/NNP/I-LOC of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-FAC Bay/NNP/I-FAC Bridge/NNP/I-FAC --/:/O two/CD/O areas/NNS/O of/IN/O maximum/JJ/O devastation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Landfill/NN/O --/:/O loose/JJ/O and/CC/O unconsolidated/JJ/O earth/NN/O --/:/O may/MD/O feel/VB/O like/IN/O rock/NN/O but/CC/O it/PRP/O behaves/VBZ/O like/IN/O liquid/NN/O when/WRB/O you/PRP/O shake/VBP/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Segar/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O professor/NN/O of/IN/O geosciences/NNS/O at/IN/O San/NNP/B-ORG Francisco/NNP/I-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG University/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O televised/JJ/O interview/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O liquefies/VBZ/O in/IN/O a/DT/O patchwork/JJ/O quilt/NN/O pattern/NN/O ././O
Our/PRP$/O quake/NN/O behaved/VBD/O much/RB/O like/IN/O the/DT/O Mexico/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O great/JJ/O damage/NN/O was/VBD/O miles/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O epicenter/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Berkeley/NNP/B-GPE seismographic/JJ/O station/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O Landfill/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O done/VBN/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O properly/RB/O compacted/VBN/O ././O
You/PRP/O can/MD/O drive/VB/O piles/NNS/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O build/VB/O on/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O cited/VBD/O the/DT/O example/NN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE financial/JJ/O district/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O many/JJ/O new/JJ/O glass/NN/O towers/NNS/O survived/VBD/O almost/RB/O unscathed/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O policy/NN/O issues/NNS/O raised/VBN/O by/IN/O earthquake/NN/O damage/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O difficult/JJ/O to/TO/O address/VB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON predicted/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O attention/NN/O span/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O public/NN/O is/VBZ/O short/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O known/VBN/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O years/NNS/O we/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBD/O lots/NNS/O of/IN/O old/JJ/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O pre-1950s/JJ/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O unreinforced/JJ/O brick/NN/O and/CC/O masonry/NN/O buildings/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Reinforcing/VBG/O such/JJ/O old/JJ/O building/NN/O stock/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O comes/VBZ/O down/RB/O to/TO/O money/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O danger/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O know/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O there/RB/O ././O
And/CC/O sooner/RB/O or/CC/O later/RB/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O something/NN/O about/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O The/DT/O big/JJ/O one/CD/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O due/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Johnson/NNP/B-PERSON predicted/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC Area/NNP/I-LOC has/VBZ/O three/CD/O very/RB/O dangerous/JJ/O faults/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-LOC San/NNP/I-LOC Andreas/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O the/DT/O Hayward/NNP/B-LOC fault/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Calaveras/NNS/B-LOC fault/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O quake/NN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O solved/VBD/O our/PRP$/O problem/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O reality/NN/O ././O
