Democrat/NNP/O Gene/NNP/B-PERSON Taylor/NNP/I-PERSON won/VBD/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O election/NN/O to/TO/O fill/VB/O the/DT/O congressional/JJ/O seat/NN/O vacated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O death/NN/O of/IN/O Republican/NNP/O Larkin/NNP/B-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O taking/VBG/O back/RP/O the/DT/O GOP/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O lone/JJ/O redoubt/NN/O in/IN/O Mississippi/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O House/NNP/B-ORG delegation/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Taylor/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O overwhelming/JJ/O victory/NN/O against/IN/O Republican/NNP/O Tom/NNP/B-PERSON Anderson/NNP/I-PERSON reclaims/VBZ/O a/DT/O seat/NN/O the/DT/O Republicans/NNPS/O had/VBD/O held/VBN/O for/IN/O 17/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O gives/VBZ/O the/DT/O Democrats/NNPS/O their/PRP$/O fifth/JJ/O victory/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O seven/CD/O special/JJ/O House/NNP/B-ORG elections/NNS/O held/VBN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Taylor/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O victory/NN/O was/VBD/O an/DT/O embarrassment/NN/O for/IN/O both/DT/O state/NN/O and/CC/O national/JJ/O Republicans/NNPS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Anderson/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Lott/NNP/B-PERSON aide/NN/O ,/,/O received/VBD/O campaign/NN/O assistance/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O senator/NN/O and/CC/O from/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O visited/VBD/O the/DT/O district/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON died/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O plane/NN/O crash/NN/O on/IN/O Aug./NNP/O 13/CD/O ././O
