According/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O ``/``/O screaming/VBG/O ''/''/O for/IN/O price/NN/O controls/NNS/O occurs/VBZ/O when/WRB/O income/NN/O redistribution/NN/O ``/``/O threatens/VBZ/O to/TO/O hit/VB/O home/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
To/TO/O be/VB/O sure/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O threat/NN/O has/VBZ/O hit/VBN/O home/NN/O down/IN/O here/RB/O ././O
Allowing/VBG/O uncontrolled/JJ/O prices/NNS/O for/IN/O necessities/NNS/O would/MD/O indeed/RB/O shorten/VB/O the/DT/O lines/NNS/O at/IN/O stores/NNS/O ,/,/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O contends/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O not/RB/O because/IN/O resources/NNS/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O most/RBS/O efficient/JJ/O use/NN/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O scarce/JJ/O goods/NNS/O ``/``/O allocated/VBN/O to/TO/O those/DT/O buyers/NNS/O who/WP/O place/VBP/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O value/NN/O on/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O ''/''/O
Rather/RB/O ,/,/O lines/NNS/O would/MD/O diminish/VB/O because/RB/O at/IN/O higher/JJR/O prices/NNS/O many/JJ/O victims/NNS/O could/MD/O not/RB/O afford/VB/O necessities/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O food/NN/O and/CC/O medical/JJ/O supplies/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O inhumane/JJ/O to/TO/O imply/VB/O that/IN/O a/DT/O poor/JJ/O ,/,/O unemployed/JJ/O woman/NN/O can/MD/O not/RB/O receive/VB/O immediate/JJ/O relief/NN/O for/IN/O her/PRP$/O family/NN/O at/IN/O fair/JJ/O prices/NNS/O because/IN/O she/PRP/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O have/VB/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O to/TO/O protect/VB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O rich/JJ/O family/NN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O essential/JJ/O relief/NN/O supplies/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O ice/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O distributed/VBN/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O population/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O potential/JJ/O health/NN/O problems/NNS/O from/IN/O spoiled/JJ/O food/NN/O and/CC/O possible/JJ/O outbreak/NN/O of/IN/O disease/NN/O ././O
Such/JJ/O spillover/NN/O effects/NNS/O give/VBP/O the/DT/O state/NN/O a/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O intervene/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O marketplace/NN/O and/CC/O temporarily/RB/O coordinate/VB/O allocation/NN/O of/IN/O resources/NNS/O ././O
Why/WRB/O should/MD/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O co-exist/VB/O with/IN/O opportunists/NNS/O rushing/VBG/O in/RB/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O a/DT/O quick/JJ/O profit/NN/O ?/./O
South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE deserves/VBZ/O an/DT/O A/NN/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O quick/JJ/O and/CC/O timely/JJ/O relief/NN/O efforts/NNS/O ././O
Give/VB/O him/PRP/O an/DT/O F/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O failure/NN/O to/TO/O understand/VB/O the/DT/O ethics/NNS/O of/IN/O economic/JJ/O equity/NN/O ././O
Signed/VBN/O by/IN/O 25/CD/O students/NNS/O
Of/IN/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Woodward/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Honors/NNP/B-ORG Economics/NNP/I-ORG Class/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O
University/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG South/NNP/I-ORG Carolina/NNP/I-ORG
Columbia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O S.C/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON gives/VBZ/O us/PRP/O an/DT/O idea/NN/O why/WRB/O economists/NNS/O '/POS/O predictions/NNS/O are/VBP/O usually/RB/O wrong/JJ/O ././O
They/PRP/O set/VBP/O up/RP/O absurd/JJ/O situations/NNS/O ,/,/O detached/VBN/O from/IN/O reality/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O then/RB/O try/VB/O to/TO/O reason/VB/O from/IN/O them/PRP/O ././O
I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O surprised/JJ/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O advocate/NN/O letting/VBG/O people/NNS/O loot/VB/O ,/,/O since/IN/O that/DT/O behavior/NN/O can/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O foreseen/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O disaster/NN/O and/CC/O ``/``/O every/DT/O individual/NN/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O incentive/NN/O to/TO/O alter/VB/O the/DT/O distribution/NN/O of/IN/O income/NN/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O favor/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Price/NN/O controls/NNS/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O so/RB/O fervently/RB/O embraced/VBN/O by/IN/O Charleston/NNP/B-GPE ''/''/O because/IN/O price/NN/O gouging/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O situation/NN/O is/VBZ/O equivalent/JJ/O to/TO/O looting/VBG/O ././O
Suzanne/NNP/B-PERSON Foster/NNP/I-PERSON
Galax/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Va/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON described/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O more/RBR/O insidious/JJ/O threats/NNS/O we/PRP/O face/VBP/O when/WRB/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O disasters/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Hugo/NNP/O --/:/O anti-profiteering/JJ/O ordinances/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O that/DT/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Charleston/NNP/I-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG as/IN/O it/PRP/O thrashed/VBD/O about/RB/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O Do/VB/O Something/NN/O ././O
Since/IN/O he/PRP/O concentrated/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O folly/NN/O of/IN/O such/JJ/O ordinances/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O certain/JJ/O other/JJ/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O effects/NNS/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O increase/VB/O supplies/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O reduce/VBP/O them/PRP/O and/CC/O encourage/VBP/O hoarding/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O they/PRP/O ,/,/O or/CC/O even/RB/O the/DT/O prospect/NN/O of/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O discourage/VBP/O disaster/NN/O preparedness/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O form/NN/O of/IN/O speculative/JJ/O advance/NN/O stocking/NN/O of/IN/O supplies/NNS/O by/IN/O merchants/NNS/O ././O
N./NNP/B-PERSON Joseph/NNP/I-PERSON Potts/NNP/I-PERSON
Miami/NNP/B-GPE Lakes/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Fla/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Would/MD/O Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O suggest/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Salvation/NNP/B-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O military/JJ/O units/NNS/B-ORG ,/,/O police/NNS/B-ORG ,/,/O fire/NN/O departments/NNS/B-ORG ,/,/O rescue/NN/O units/NNS/B-ORG and/CC/O individual/JJ/O citizens/NNS/O cease/VB/O their/PRP$/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O assist/VB/O Hugo/NNP/O 's/POS/O victims/NNS/O because/IN/O they/PRP/O interfere/VBP/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O concept/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O free/JJ/O market/NN/O ''/''/O ?/./O
What/WP/O about/IN/O those/DT/O caring/JJ/O people/NNS/O all/RB/O over/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O who/WP/O are/VBP/O donating/VBG/O food/NN/O ,/,/O water/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O necessities/NNS/O of/IN/O life/NN/O to/TO/O these/DT/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O could/MD/O be/VB/O any/DT/O of/IN/O us/PRP/O ?/./O
Should/MD/O they/PRP/O ,/,/O too/RB/O ,/,/O stop/VB/O ``/``/O messing/VBG/O with/IN/O ''/''/O his/PRP$/O free/JJ/O market/NN/O ?/./O
Maybe/RB/O he/PRP/O thinks/VBZ/O they/PRP/O should/MD/O also/RB/O sell/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O bidder/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O what/WP/O about/IN/O insurance/NN/O firms/NNS/O ?/./O
Should/MD/O they/PRP/O be/VB/O required/VBN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O claims/NNS/O based/VBN/O on/IN/O exorbitant/JJ/O costs/NNS/O for/IN/O labor/NN/O and/CC/O materials/NNS/O ?/./O
Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON should/MD/O beware/VB/O ,/,/O since/IN/O he/PRP/O lives/VBZ/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Rush/NNP/I-PERSON
Marietta/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ga/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Having/VBG/O been/VBN/O through/IN/O several/JJ/O tornadoes/NNS/O and/CC/O hurricanes/NNS/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O perspective/NN/O ././O
Mine/PRP/O comes/VBZ/O from/IN/O seeing/VBG/O thriving/JJ/O communities/NNS/O devastated/VBN/O --/:/O but/CC/O only/RB/O temporarily/RB/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O recovery/NN/O came/VBD/O surprisingly/RB/O fast/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O always/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O help/NN/O of/IN/O neighbors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O shock/NN/O of/IN/O seeing/VBG/O homes/NNS/O destroyed/VBN/O and/CC/O city/NN/O services/NNS/O disrupted/VBN/O may/MD/O cause/VB/O some/DT/O to/TO/O confuse/VB/O priorities/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O true/JJ/O economic/JJ/O value/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O freezer/NN/O full/JJ/O of/IN/O meat/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE after/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Alicia/NNP/O ,/,/O major/JJ/O grocery/NN/O chains/NNS/O used/VBD/O their/PRP$/O truck/NN/O fleets/NNS/O to/TO/O ship/VB/O essential/JJ/O goods/NNS/O to/TO/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O no/DT/O gouging/NN/O ,/,/O just/RB/O good/JJ/O will/NN/O ././O
Tom/NNP/B-PERSON Mongan/NNP/I-PERSON
Victoria/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE
We/PRP/O here/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O affected/JJ/O areas/NNS/O were/VBD/O dazzled/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O analysis/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O values/NNS/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O comparisons/NNS/O of/IN/O effectiveness/NN/O concerning/VBG/O research/NN/O and/CC/O development/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O theoretical/JJ/O approach/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O publication/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O venerable/JJ/O paper/NN/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O doubt/NN/O a/DT/O noteworthy/JJ/O accomplishment/NN/O for/IN/O him/PRP/O ././O
Too/RB/O bad/JJ/O theory/NN/O fails/VBZ/O in/IN/O practice/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O consumers/NNS/O tend/VBP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O long/JJ/O memories/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O businesses/NNS/O subscribing/VBG/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O effective/JJ/O price/NN/O system/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O remembered/VBN/O when/WRB/O normalcy/NN/O returns/VBZ/O ././O
Perhaps/RB/O ,/,/O considering/VBG/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O our/PRP$/O time/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O patronize/VB/O their/PRP$/O establishments/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O post-Hugo/JJ/O era/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O question/NN/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Laband/NNP/B-PERSON :/:/O How/WRB/O do/VB/O I/PRP/O explain/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O single/JJ/O mother/NN/O of/IN/O three/CD/O standing/NN/O in/IN/O line/NN/O next/JJ/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O three/CD/O hours/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O bags/NNS/O of/IN/O ice/NN/O she/PRP/O needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O her/PRP$/O children/NNS/O 's/POS/O food/NN/O edible/JJ/O will/MD/O take/VB/O her/PRP/O last/JJ/O $/$/O 20/CD/O ?/./O
I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O sure/JJ/O she/PRP/O 'll/MD/O appreciate/VB/O what/WP/O an/DT/O efficient/JJ/O reaction/NN/O to/TO/O her/PRP$/O problems/NNS/O the/DT/O price/NN/O system/NN/O has/VBZ/O created/VBN/O ././O
Chris/NNP/B-PERSON Edgar/NNP/I-PERSON
Myrtle/NNP/B-GPE Beach/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O S.C/NNP/B-GPE ././O
