In/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O soon/RB/O after/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG Laboratories/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O a/DT/O staggering/JJ/O $/$/O 424.3/CD/O million/CD/O loss/NN/O and/CC/O replaced/VBD/O its/PRP$/O president/NN/O ,/,/O two/CD/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE sales/NNS/O representatives/NNS/O sent/VBD/O customers/NNS/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O saying/VBG/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O fully/RB/O expect/VBP/O that/IN/O you/PRP/O will/MD/O soon/RB/O be/VB/O reading/VBG/O stories/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O press/NN/O reporting/VBG/O the/DT/O `/``/O Amazing/NNP/O Comeback/NNP/O at/IN/O Wang/NNP/O ././O '/''/O ''/''/O
How/WRB/O soon/RB/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O stage/VB/O a/DT/O comeback/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O at/IN/O all/DT/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O still/RB/O matters/NNS/O of/IN/O debate/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG salespeople/NN/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O cope/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O biggest/JJS/O challenge/NN/O any/DT/O marketer/NN/O can/MD/O face/VB/O :/:/O selling/VBG/O the/DT/O products/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O company/NN/O that/WDT/O is/VBZ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O ropes/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O your/PRP$/O prospect/NN/O is/VBZ/O feeling/VBG/O risk/VB/O the/DT/O whole/JJ/O time/NN/O and/CC/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O feeling/VBG/O as/IN/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O backed/VBN/O up/RP/O by/IN/O a/DT/O stable/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O 've/VBP/O lost/VBN/O it/PRP/O before/IN/O you/PRP/O 've/VBP/O begun/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Ann/NNP/I-PERSON Cluggish/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Wellesley/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O sales/NNS/O trainer/NN/O and/CC/O consultant/NN/O who/WP/O works/VBZ/O with/IN/O high/JJ/O technology/NN/O companies/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O can/MD/O happen/VB/O in/IN/O any/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Consider/VB/O the/DT/O difficulties/NNS/O faced/VBN/O by/IN/O Audi/NNP/B-ORG salespeople/NN/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O car/NN/O was/VBD/O tainted/VBN/O by/IN/O false/JJ/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O sudden/JJ/O acceleration/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG dealers/NNS/O '/POS/O problems/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O wake/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Valdez/NNP/O oil/NN/O spill/NN/O ././O
Like/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O salespeople/NN/O before/IN/O them/PRP/O ,/,/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O are/VBP/O finding/VBG/O ways/NNS/O to/TO/O combat/VB/O the/DT/O bad/JJ/O news/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O important/JJ/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O exude/VBP/O confidence/NN/O ,/,/O even/RB/O though/IN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O family/NN/O we/PRP/O know/VBP/O there/EX/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O lot/NN/O of/IN/O hard/JJ/O work/NN/O ahead/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Miller/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Lowell/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O computer/NN/O concern/NN/O 's/POS/O new/JJ/O president/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O video/JJ/O message/NN/O to/TO/O salespeople/NNS/O a/DT/O month/NN/O after/IN/O he/PRP/O took/VBD/O over/RP/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG got/VBD/O into/IN/O financial/JJ/O trouble/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O bloated/JJ/O overhead/NN/O and/CC/O overly/RB/O optimistic/JJ/O sales/NNS/O forecasts/NNS/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O mainline/JJ/O minicomputers/NNS/O and/CC/O word/NN/O processors/NNS/O have/VBP/O lost/VBN/O ground/NN/O to/TO/O cheaper/JJR/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O it/PRP/O funded/VBD/O its/PRP$/O high/JJ/O employment/NN/O by/IN/O heavy/JJ/O borrowing/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O suffered/VBD/O huge/JJ/O losses/NNS/O when/WRB/O sales/NNS/O turned/VBD/O down/RB/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O rising/VBG/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O reported/VBD/O red/JJ/O ink/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O marketing/NN/O department/NN/O provided/VBD/O the/DT/O sales/NNS/O force/NN/O answers/NNS/O to/TO/O questions/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O ``/``/O How/WRB/O could/MD/O you/PRP/O not/RB/O have/VB/O known/VBN/O you/PRP/O were/VBD/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O lose/VB/O $/$/O 55/CD/O million/CD/O ?/./O ''/''/O and/CC/O ``/``/O Is/VBZ/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG still/RB/O a/DT/O viable/JJ/O company/NN/O ?/./O ''/''/O
Salespeople/NNS/O try/VBP/O to/TO/O push/VB/O their/PRP$/O products/NNS/O and/CC/O avoid/VB/O discussions/NNS/O of/IN/O finances/NNS/O ././O
Responding/VBG/O to/TO/O such/JJ/O questions/NNS/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O defensive/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Kenneth/NNP/B-PERSON Olissa/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O marketing/NN/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O antithetical/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O art/NN/O of/IN/O selling/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O notes/VBZ/O that/IN/O analyzing/VBG/O financial/JJ/O results/NNS/O ``/``/O poses/VBZ/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O salesman/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O particularly/RB/O familiar/JJ/O with/IN/O a/DT/O balance/NN/O sheet/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
At/IN/O one/CD/O sales/NNS/O strategy/NN/O meeting/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O executive/NN/O suggested/VBD/O ordering/VBG/O salespeople/NNS/O to/TO/O become/VB/O experts/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O annual/JJ/O report/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON vetoed/VBD/O that/DT/O :/:/O ``/``/O Even/RB/O I/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O understand/VB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O footnotes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O if/IN/O the/DT/O salespeople/NNS/O can/MD/O get/VB/O the/DT/O customers/NNS/O to/TO/O consider/VB/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O products/NNS/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O merits/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O or/CC/O a/DT/O top/JJ/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O will/MD/O try/VB/O to/TO/O assuage/VB/O the/DT/O fears/NNS/O about/IN/O finances/NNS/O ././O
Mike/NNP/B-PERSON Metschan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O salesman/NN/O in/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Austin/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O office/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O breezier/JJR/O method/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O tell/VBP/O them/PRP/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O companies/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O go/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O tell/VBP/O them/PRP/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O having/VBG/O financial/JJ/O difficulties/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Numerous/JJ/O computer/NN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O having/VBG/O sales/NNS/O slumps/NNS/O and/CC/O earnings/NNS/O declines/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O very/RB/O few/JJ/O have/VBP/O had/VBN/O losses/NNS/O comparable/JJ/O to/TO/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O or/CC/O are/VBP/O carrying/VBG/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O debt/NN/O load/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/IN/O after/IN/O a/DT/O sharp/JJ/O sales/NNS/O slump/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O and/CC/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O sales/NNS/O stabilized/VBD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ././O
Although/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O report/VB/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ended/VBN/O Sept./NNP/O 30/CD/O and/CC/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O expects/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O will/MD/O return/VB/O to/TO/O profitability/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ././O
Experts/NNS/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O technique/NN/O say/VBP/O anyone/NN/O representing/VBG/O a/DT/O troubled/JJ/O company/NN/O must/MD/O walk/VB/O a/DT/O fine/JJ/O line/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O a/DT/O salesman/NN/O jeopardizes/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O credibility/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O time/NN/O of/IN/O trouble/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O long/JJ/O run/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Palmatier/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Minden/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Nev./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O sales/NNS/O consultant/NN/O and/CC/O author/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Marketing/NN/O Edge/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Sullivan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O management/NN/O recruiter/NN/O with/IN/O Daniel/NNP/B-ORG Roberts/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O held/VBN/O senior/JJ/O sales/NNS/O positions/NNS/O at/IN/O Polaroid/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Atari/NNP/B-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O customer/NN/O will/MD/O react/VB/O to/TO/O strength/NN/O ././O
Ignore/VB/O the/DT/O present/JJ/O condition/NN/O ././O
Show/VB/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O business/NN/O as/IN/O usual/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O easy/JJ/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O customers/NNS/O are/VBP/O data/NNS/O processing/NN/O managers/NNS/O who/WP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sure/JJ/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O suppliers/NNS/O are/VBP/O stable/JJ/O ,/,/O wellrun/JJ/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O around/RB/O to/TO/O fix/VB/O bugs/NNS/O and/CC/O upgrade/VB/O computers/NNS/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O university/NN/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O installing/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O system/NN/O to/TO/O store/VB/O applications/NNS/O electronically/RB/O ././O
``/``/O Before/IN/O the/DT/O really/RB/O bad/JJ/O news/NN/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O looking/VBG/O at/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG fairly/RB/O seriously/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O she/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O ``/``/O their/PRP$/O present/JJ/O financial/JJ/O condition/NN/O means/VBZ/O I/PRP/O 'd/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O hard/JJ/O time/NN/O convincing/VBG/O the/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O purchasing/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
Ms./NNP/O Conlin/NNP/B-PERSON adds/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O At/IN/O some/DT/O point/NN/O we/PRP/O 'd/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O ask/VB/O ,/,/O `/``/O How/WRB/O do/VBP/O we/PRP/O know/VB/O that/IN/O in/IN/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O you/PRP/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O in/IN/O Chapter/NNP/O 11/CD/O ?/./O '/''/O ''/''/O
During/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O developed/VBN/O new/JJ/O products/NNS/O and/CC/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O strategy/NN/O and/CC/O hired/VBN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O president/NN/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O overall/JJ/O product/NN/O line/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O still/RB/O not/RB/O as/RB/O good/JJ/O as/IN/O other/JJ/O vendors/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O come/VBN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O way/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Steven/NNP/B-PERSON Wendler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O with/IN/O market/NN/O researcher/NN/O Gartner/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O They/PRP/O were/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O road/NN/O to/TO/O recovery/NN/O in/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O customer/NN/O attitudes/NNS/O until/IN/O this/DT/O bad/JJ/O quarter/NN/O happened/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O priority/NN/O for/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O force/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O it/PRP/O holds/VBZ/O on/IN/O to/TO/O existing/JJ/O customers/NNS/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O installed/JJ/O base/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O greatest/JJS/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O those/DT/O customers/NNS/O remain/VBP/O extremely/RB/O loyal/JJ/O ././O
But/CC/O even/RB/O before/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O latest/JJS/O financial/JJ/O troubles/NNS/O surfaced/VBD/O ,/,/O some/DT/O customers/NNS/O ``/``/O were/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O wall/VB/O off/RP/O their/PRP$/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG installations/NNS/O ''/''/O so/IN/O other/JJ/O departments/NNS/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O add/VB/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Chris/NNP/B-PERSON Christiansen/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG marketer/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O a/DT/O market/NN/O analyst/NN/O with/IN/O Meta/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O market/NN/O research/NN/O firm/NN/O in/IN/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn/NNP/B-GPE ././O
One/CD/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG salesman/NN/O who/WP/O left/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O recalls/VBZ/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O products/NNS/O to/TO/O Eastman/NNP/B-ORG Kodak/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O worked/VBD/O ``/``/O to/TO/O muster/VB/O support/NN/O from/IN/O internal/JJ/O allies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O ``/``/O those/DT/O allies/NNS/O became/VBD/O skeptical/JJ/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O saw/VBD/O the/DT/O downtrend/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O more/RBR/O recent/JJ/O losses/NNS/O were/VBD/O really/RB/O devastating/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Rick/NNP/B-PERSON Lynch/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O top/JJ/O salesman/NN/O in/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE office/NN/O ,/,/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O mainstay/JJ/O computer/NN/O line/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O sell/VB/O a/DT/O VS/NNP/O to/TO/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O customer/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lynch/NNP/B-PERSON left/VBD/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG this/DT/O summer/NN/O for/IN/O Oracle/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O software/NN/O vendor/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O financial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O are/VBP/O particularly/RB/O frustrating/JJ/O for/IN/O salespeople/NNS/O pushing/VBG/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O image/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O convert/VBP/O paper/NN/O forms/NNS/O to/TO/O electronic/JJ/O documents/NNS/O ././O
Consultants/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O technology/NN/O is/VBZ/O among/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O available/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O image/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O salespeople/NNS/O often/RB/O found/VBD/O that/IN/O news/NN/O of/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O problems/NNS/O superseded/VBD/O their/PRP$/O sales/NNS/O efforts/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O making/VBG/O the/DT/O decision/NN/O ,/,/O all/DT/O hell/NN/O broke/VBD/O loose/RB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O finances/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Lilly/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O told/VBD/O him/PRP/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O take/VB/O the/DT/O risk/NN/O with/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tait/NNP/B-PERSON say/VB/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O blame/VB/O Lilly/RB/B-ORG ././O
Buyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O rely/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O supplier/NN/O ``/``/O continually/RB/O upgrading/VBG/O and/CC/O replacing/VBG/O the/DT/O product/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O When/WRB/O a/DT/O company/NN/O realizes/VBZ/O that/DT/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O hard/JJ/O to/TO/O go/VB/O with/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG ././O ''/''/O
For/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Tait/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O used/VBD/O to/TO/O earn/VB/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O as/IN/O $/$/O 150,000/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O at/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O more/JJR/O reason/NN/O to/TO/O quit/VB/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Eastate/NNP/B-ORG Homes/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O Indianapolis/NNP/B-GPE contractor/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O hard/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O salesperson/NN/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O off/RP/O feelings/NNS/O of/IN/O discouragement/NN/O ././O
Brian/NNP/B-PERSON Petre/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG salesman/NN/O in/IN/O upstate/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O pride/NN/O in/IN/O your/PRP$/O job/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O think/VBP/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O go/VB/O out/RB/O and/CC/O turn/VB/O things/NNS/O around/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O thing/NN/O when/WRB/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O reason/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O relate/VB/O to/TO/O your/PRP$/O selling/NN/O skills/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Discouragement/NN/O feeds/VBZ/O on/IN/O itself/PRP/O ././O
One/CD/O key/NN/O for/IN/O salespeople/NNS/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O morale/NN/O ././O
Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Hellman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Framingham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O management/NN/O consultant/NN/O and/CC/O author/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Ready/JJ/O ,/,/O Aim/VB/O ,/,/O You/PRP/O 're/VBP/O Hired/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O bad/JJ/O news/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O rejected/VBN/O more/RBR/O ././O
The/DT/O good/JJ/O news/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O your/PRP$/O fault/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
So/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O advises/VBZ/O ,/,/O make/VB/O goals/NNS/O achievable/JJ/O ././O
For/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O suggests/VBZ/O that/IN/O salespeople/NNS/O making/VBG/O telephone/NN/O calls/NNS/O should/MD/O say/VB/O to/TO/O themselves/PRP/O :/:/O ``/``/O All/DT/O I/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O today/NN/O is/VBZ/O get/VB/O 50/CD/O rejections/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O new/JJ/O president/NN/O ,/,/O recently/RB/O warned/VBD/O his/PRP$/O salespeople/NN/O about/IN/O negativism/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O customers/NNS/O watch/VBP/O us/PRP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O hidden/JJ/O message/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Look/VB/O a/DT/O customer/NN/O right/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O eye/NN/O and/CC/O say/VB/O ,/,/O `/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O glad/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O at/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG ././O
