The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O sure/RB/O nobody/NN/O will/MD/O accuse/VB/O it/PRP/O of/IN/O taking/VBG/O this/DT/O crisis/NN/O lightly/RB/O ././O
Some/DT/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O necessary/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O federal/JJ/O help/NN/O flowing/VBG/O to/TO/O victims/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O some/DT/O seemed/VBD/O designed/VBN/O mostly/RB/O to/TO/O project/VB/O an/DT/O image/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O action/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O aides/NNS/O were/VBD/O accused/VBN/O of/IN/O responding/VBG/O too/RB/O slowly/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O Exxon/NNP/B-ORG Valdez/NNP/I-ORG oil/NN/O tanker/NN/O split/VBD/O open/RB/O in/IN/O Alaskan/JJ/O waters/NNS/O and/CC/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O struck/VBD/O the/DT/O Carolina/NNP/B-LOC coast/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O clearly/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O a/DT/O repeat/NN/O of/IN/O those/DT/O charges/NNS/O now/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON himself/PRP/O essentially/RB/O acknowledged/VBD/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O aides/NNS/O were/VBD/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O head/VB/O off/RP/O criticism/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG already/RB/O is/VBZ/O talking/VBG/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON visiting/VBG/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE earthquake/NN/O site/NN/O this/DT/O weekend/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O visited/VBD/O the/DT/O Hugo/NNP/O devastation/NN/O but/CC/O not/RB/O until/IN/O after/IN/O local/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O urged/VBD/O him/PRP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O so/RB/O ././O
