CALIFORNIA/NNP/B-GPE STRUGGLED/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O aftermath/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Bay/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/I-LOC earthquake/NN/O ././O
Bush/NNP/B-PERSON declared/VBD/O the/DT/O region/NN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O disaster/NN/O area/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O military/NN/O was/VBD/O mobilized/VBN/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O looting/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O baseball/NN/O commissioner/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O game/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O between/IN/O the/DT/O Giants/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O Athletics/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O played/VBN/O Tuesday/NNP/O in/IN/O Candlestick/NNP/B-FAC Park/NNP/I-FAC ././O
HONECKER/NNP/B-PERSON WAS/VBD/O OUSTED/VBN/O as/IN/O leader/NN/O of/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE amid/IN/O growing/VBG/O unrest/NN/O ././O
Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O departure/NN/O came/VBD/O after/IN/O weeks/NNS/O of/IN/O street/NN/O protests/NNS/O and/CC/O an/DT/O exodus/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O West/NNP/B-LOC of/IN/O East/NNP/O Germans/NNPS/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O become/VBN/O disenchanted/JJ/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O rule/NN/O ././O
HUNGARY/NNP/B-GPE ADOPTED/VBD/O constitutional/JJ/O changes/NNS/O to/TO/O form/VB/O a/DT/O democratic/JJ/O system/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O country/NN/O was/VBD/O renamed/VBN/O the/DT/B-GPE Republic/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/I-GPE Hungary/NNP/I-GPE ././O
The/DT/O $/$/O 1.4/CD/O billion/CD/O robot/NN/O spacecraft/NN/O 's/POS/O exploratory/JJ/O mission/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O take/VB/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O shuttle/NN/O is/VBZ/O slated/VBN/O to/TO/O return/VB/O Monday/NNP/O to/TO/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O tragic/JJ/O results/NNS/O could/MD/O follow/VB/O any/DT/O ``/``/O hint/NN/O of/IN/O weakening/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE defense/NN/O commitment/NN/O to/TO/O Seoul/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Census/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O that/IN/O 13.1/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE population/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 31.9/CD/O million/CD/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O living/VBG/O in/IN/O poverty/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O figure/NN/O was/VBD/O down/RB/O from/IN/O 13.4/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O marked/VBD/O the/DT/O fifth/JJ/O consecutive/JJ/O annual/JJ/O decline/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O poverty/NN/O rate/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O accused/VBD/O Israeli/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Shamir/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O hindering/VBG/O peace/NN/O efforts/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Mideast/NNP/B-LOC with/IN/O ``/``/O unhelpful/JJ/O ''/''/O and/CC/O disappointing/JJ/O statements/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O election/NN/O was/VBD/O by/IN/O secret/JJ/O ballot/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Assembly/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE did/VBD/O n't/RB/O openly/RB/O oppose/VB/O Cuba/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O seating/NN/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Latin/JJ/O American/JJ/O council/NN/O delegate/NN/O ././O
Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON told/VBD/O a/DT/O Commonwealth/NNP/B-ORG summit/NN/O in/IN/O Kuala/NNP/B-GPE Lumpur/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O that/WDT/O sanctions/NNS/O against/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Africa/NNP/I-GPE were/VBD/O ``/``/O utterly/RB/O irresponsible/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Christian/JJ/O legislators/NNS/O are/VBP/O insisting/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O Syrian/JJ/O troop/NN/O pullout/NN/O from/IN/O Lebanon/NNP/B-GPE before/IN/O agreeing/VBG/O to/TO/O political/JJ/O changes/NNS/O giving/VBG/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O Moslems/NNPS/O a/DT/O greater/JJR/O role/NN/O in/IN/O Beirut/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O government/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O narcotics/NNS/O traffickers/NNS/O claimed/VBD/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O slaying/NN/O ././O
