This/DT/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O season/NN/O for/IN/O revivals/NNS/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Though/NNP/O the/DT/O Cubs/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O championship/NN/O season/NN/O ended/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O National/NNP/B-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG playoffs/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O revival/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Organic/NNP/I-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG production/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Bleacher/NN/O Bums/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O play/NN/O in/IN/O nine/CD/O innings/NN/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Wrigley/NNP/B-FAC Field/NNP/I-FAC bleachers/NNS/O ,/,/O continues/VBZ/O within/IN/O spitting/NN/O distance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ballpark/NN/O ././O
Revivals/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O sort/NN/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O offered/VBN/O by/IN/O our/PRP$/O two/CD/O major/JJ/O theater/NN/O troupes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Goodman/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Each/DT/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O problematic/JJ/O than/IN/O an/DT/O unexpected/JJ/O divisional/JJ/O baseball/NN/O championship/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O both/DT/O help/VBP/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O vital/JJ/O center/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O regional/JJ/O theater/NN/O movement/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Goodman/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O offering/VBG/O a/DT/O modernized/JJ/O version/NN/O of/IN/O Moliere/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Misanthrope/NN/O ''/''/O through/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 4/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O original/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O comedy/NN/O about/IN/O Alceste/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O sees/VBZ/O falseness/NN/O and/CC/O vanity/NN/O in/IN/O everyone/NN/O except/IN/O himself/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O jealous/JJ/O friend/NN/O of/IN/O Philinte/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O jealous/JJ/O lover/NN/O of/IN/O Celimene/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O play/NN/O is/VBZ/O filled/VBN/O with/IN/O intrigue/NN/O ,/,/O dishonesty/NN/O and/CC/O injustice/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Wilbur/NNP/B-PERSON translation/NN/O is/VBZ/O remarkable/JJ/O --/:/O well/RB/O worth/JJ/O a/DT/O read/VBN/O and/CC/O even/RB/O better/RBR/O seen/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O theater/NN/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O ever/RB/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Falls/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Goodman/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O artistic/JJ/O director/NN/O ,/,/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O adaptation/NN/O by/IN/O Neil/NNP/B-PERSON Bartlett/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O significantly/RB/O adapted/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bartlett/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O slimmed/VBN/O Moliere/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O cast/NN/O of/IN/O characters/NNS/O to/TO/O six/CD/O and/CC/O set/VBN/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE media/NN/O world/NN/O of/IN/O Thatcherite/JJ/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Falls/NNP/B-PERSON transfers/VBZ/O the/DT/O setting/NN/O to/TO/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O transforms/VBZ/O the/DT/O characters/NNS/O into/IN/O what/WP/O passes/VBZ/O for/IN/O aristocracy/NN/O there/RB/O --/:/O agents/NNS/O ,/,/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O actors/NNS/O ,/,/O writers/NNS/O and/CC/O sycophants/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O works/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bartlett/NNP/B-PERSON managed/VBD/O to/TO/O more/RBR/O or/CC/O less/RBR/O maintain/VB/O Moliere/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Alexandrine/JJ/O verse/NN/O form/NN/O ,/,/O 12/CD/O syllable/NN/O lines/NNS/O in/IN/O rhyming/VBG/O couplets/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Falls/NNP/B-PERSON kept/VBD/O the/DT/O form/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Americanized/VBD/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bartlett/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O further/JJ/O help/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Steppenwolf/NNP/I-ORG Theatre/NNP/I-ORG Company/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O back/RB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O critical/JJ/O and/CC/O box/NN/O office/NN/O success/NN/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O its/PRP$/O adaptation/NN/O of/IN/O Steinbeck/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Grapes/NNS/O of/IN/O Wrath/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O opened/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O season/NN/O with/IN/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON Pinter/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O The/DT/O Homecoming/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O first/RB/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Royal/NNP/I-ORG Shakespeare/NNP/I-ORG Company/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1965/CD/O ././O
Silences/NNS/O were/VBD/O lengthy/JJ/O --/:/O nobody/NN/O moved/VBD/O or/CC/O gestured/VBD/O ././O
Nobody/NN/O smiled/VBD/O onstage/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O nobody/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O audience/NN/O was/VBD/O encouraged/VBN/O to/TO/O laugh/VB/O ././O
This/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O theater/NN/O was/VBD/O new/JJ/O to/TO/O us/PRP/O ././O
Three/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O family/NN/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O two/CD/O sons/NNS/O ,/,/O Lenny/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Joey/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O live/VBP/O off/IN/O the/DT/O flesh/NN/O :/:/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O retired/JJ/O butcher/NN/O ,/,/O Lenny/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O pimp/NN/O and/CC/O Joey/NNP/B-PERSON an/DT/O aspiring/JJ/O boxer/NN/O ././O
Sam/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O brother/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O escaped/VBN/O the/DT/O flesh/NN/O by/IN/O working/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O liveried/JJ/O chauffeur/NN/O and/CC/O never/RB/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O wife/NN/O ././O
Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O eldest/JJS/O of/IN/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sons/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O dramatic/JJ/O escape/NN/O by/IN/O becoming/VBG/O a/DT/O professor/NN/O of/IN/O philosophy/NN/O at/IN/O an/DT/O American/JJ/O university/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O play/NN/O concerns/VBZ/O Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O homecoming/NN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O of/IN/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Ruth/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Curiously/NNP/O ,/,/O Randall/NNP/B-PERSON Arney/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O cast/NN/O member/NN/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O zombie/NN/O approach/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Pinter/NNP/B-PERSON character/NN/O ././O
Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O the/DT/O extra/JJ/O seats/NNS/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O fly/NN/O space/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O currently/RB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O away/RP/O many/JJ/O potential/JJ/O subscribers/NNS/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O 13,000/CD/O who/WP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O accommodated/VBN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O present/JJ/O digs/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O confident/JJ/O ,/,/O can/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O board/NN/O members/NNS/O alone/RB/O have/VBP/O pledged/VBN/O $/$/O 800,000/CD/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O massage/VB/O local/JJ/O foundations/NNS/O and/CC/O corporations/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sagan/NNP/B-PERSON compares/VBZ/O the/DT/O importance/NN/O of/IN/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O Orson/NNP/B-PERSON Welles/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Mercury/NNP/B-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O '30s/NNS/O ././O
