Prospect/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O recent/JJ/O hostile/JJ/O tender/NN/O offer/NN/O for/IN/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG failed/VBD/O for/IN/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O financing/NN/O ,/,/O apparently/RB/O has/VBZ/O gained/VBN/O a/DT/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O control/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O troubled/JJ/O company/NN/O anyway/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sheinberg/NNP/B-PERSON remains/VBZ/O as/IN/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Hurley/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON A./NN/I-PERSON Vanourek/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O designated/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O over/RP/O Recognition/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O top/JJ/O spots/NNS/O had/VBD/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O tender/NN/O offer/NN/O succeeded/VBN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O named/VBN/O co-chief/JJ/O executives/NNS/O and/CC/O directors/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hurley/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O formerly/RB/O a/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O and/CC/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O Avery/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG division/NN/O ;/:/O Mr./NNP/O Vanourek/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O group/NN/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Pitney/NNP/B-ORG Bowes/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O attributed/VBD/O the/DT/O loss/NN/O to/TO/O declining/VBG/O revenue/NN/O and/CC/O litigation/NN/O costs/NNS/O relating/VBG/O to/TO/O criminal/JJ/O charges/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O and/CC/O two/CD/O former/JJ/O executives/NNS/O ,/,/O William/NNP/B-PERSON G./NNP/I-PERSON Moore/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON W./NNP/I-PERSON Reedy/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O former/JJ/O executives/NNS/O were/VBD/O indicted/VBN/O last/JJ/O October/NNP/O on/IN/O charges/NNS/O of/IN/O fraud/NN/O ,/,/O theft/NN/O and/CC/O conspiracy/NN/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O efforts/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O Postal/NNP/B-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG contracts/NNS/O ././O
Recognition/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O expected/VBD/O to/TO/O put/VB/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O with/IN/O Prospect/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O stockholders/NNS/O at/IN/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O ././O
