Economist/O David/B-PERSON N./I-PERSON Laband/I-PERSON 's/O Sept./O 27/O editorial/O -/O page/O article/O ,/O ``/O In/O Hugo/O 's/O Path/O ,/O a/O Man/O -/O Made/O Disaster/O ,/O ''/O decries/O the/O control/O of/O price/O gouging/O ,/O swiftly/O ordered/O by/O South/B-GPE Carolina/I-GPE 's/I-GPE governor/O after/O Hurricane/O Hugo/O ./O
Rather/O ,/O lines/O would/O diminish/O because/O at/O higher/O prices/O many/O victims/O could/O not/O afford/O necessities/O such/O as/O food/O and/O medical/O supplies/O ./O
Moreover/O ,/O essential/O relief/O supplies/O such/O as/O ice/O must/O be/O distributed/O throughout/O the/O population/O because/O of/O potential/O health/O problems/O from/O spoiled/O food/O and/O possible/O outbreak/O of/O disease/O ./O
Fortunately/O ,/O volunteers/O and/O charities/O are/O not/O motivated/O by/O self/O -/O interest/O ,/O but/O by/O altruism/O ./O
Why/O should/O they/O have/O to/O co-exist/O with/O opportunists/O rushing/O in/O to/O turn/O a/O quick/O profit/O ?/O
These/O latter/O -/O day/O scalawags/O would/O be/O ill/O -/O advised/O to/O take/O advantage/O of/O the/O situation/O ,/O if/O they/O ever/O expect/O to/O face/O the/O people/O of/O South/B-GPE Carolina/I-GPE again/O ./O
Give/O him/O an/O F/O for/O his/O failure/O to/O understand/O the/O ethics/O of/O economic/O equity/O ./O
Signed/O by/O 25/O students/O
Of/O Douglas/B-PERSON Woodward/I-PERSON 's/I-PERSON Honors/B-ORG Economics/I-ORG Class/I-ORG ,/O
Columbia/B-GPE ,/O S.C/B-GPE ./O
Mr./O Laband/B-PERSON gives/O us/O an/O idea/O why/O economists/O '/O predictions/O are/O usually/O wrong/O ./O
Suzanne/B-PERSON Foster/I-PERSON
Galax/B-GPE ,/O Va/B-GPE ./O
Mr./O Laband/B-PERSON described/O one/O of/O the/O more/O insidious/O threats/O we/O face/O when/O dealing/O with/O disasters/O such/O as/O Hugo/O --/O anti-profiteering/O ordinances/O such/O as/O that/O by/O the/B-ORG Charleston/I-ORG City/I-ORG Council/I-ORG as/O it/O thrashed/O about/O trying/O to/O Do/O Something/O ./O
They/O divert/O law/O -/O enforcement/O resources/O at/O a/O time/O they/O are/O most/O needed/O for/O protecting/O lives/O and/O property/O ./O
Also/O ,/O rather/O than/O increase/O supplies/O ,/O they/O reduce/O them/O and/O encourage/O hoarding/O ./O
What/O about/O those/O caring/O people/O all/O over/O the/O country/O who/O are/O donating/O food/O ,/O water/O and/O other/O necessities/O of/O life/O to/O these/O people/O who/O could/O be/O any/O of/O us/O ?/O
Maybe/O he/O thinks/O they/O should/O also/O sell/O to/O the/O highest/O bidder/O ./O
And/O what/O about/O insurance/O firms/O ?/O
Should/O they/O be/O required/O to/O pay/O claims/O based/O on/O exorbitant/O costs/O for/O labor/O and/O materials/O ?/O
Mr./O Laband/B-PERSON should/O beware/O ,/O since/O he/O lives/O in/O South/B-GPE Carolina/I-GPE ./O
In/O a/O free/O market/O ,/O his/O insurance/O rates/O can/O be/O raised/O to/O recover/O insurance/O -/O company/O losses/O ./O
John/B-PERSON W./I-PERSON Rush/I-PERSON
Marietta/B-GPE ,/O Ga/B-GPE ./O
Having/O been/O through/O several/O tornadoes/O and/O hurricanes/O ,/O I/O have/O a/O different/O perspective/O ./O
In/O Texas/B-GPE after/O Hurricane/O Alicia/O ,/O major/O grocery/O chains/O used/O their/O truck/O fleets/O to/O ship/O essential/O goods/O to/O Houston/B-GPE ,/O no/O gouging/O ,/O just/O good/O will/O ./O
Tom/B-PERSON Mongan/I-PERSON
Victoria/B-GPE ,/O Texas/B-GPE
His/O theoretical/O approach/O and/O its/O publication/O in/O this/O venerable/O paper/O are/O no/O doubt/O a/O noteworthy/O accomplishment/O for/O him/O ./O
Too/O bad/O theory/O fails/O in/O practice/O ./O
We/O consumers/O tend/O to/O have/O long/O memories/O ./O
The/O businesses/O subscribing/O to/O Mr./O Laband/B-PERSON 's/O effective/O price/O system/O will/O be/O remembered/O when/O normalcy/O returns/O ./O
Perhaps/O ,/O considering/O the/O value/O of/O our/O time/O ,/O we/O will/O be/O unable/O to/O patronize/O their/O establishments/O in/O the/O post-Hugo/O era/O ./O
I/O have/O a/O question/O for/O Mr./O Laband/B-PERSON :/O How/O do/O I/O explain/O to/O the/O single/O mother/O of/O three/O standing/O in/O line/O next/O to/O me/O for/O the/O past/O three/O hours/O that/O the/O two/O bags/O of/O ice/O she/O needs/O to/O keep/O her/O children/O 's/O food/O edible/O will/O take/O her/O last/O $/O 20/O ?/O
Chris/B-PERSON Edgar/I-PERSON
Myrtle/B-GPE Beach/I-GPE ,/O S.C/B-GPE ./O
