``/``/O Many/JJ/O members/NNS/O feel/VBP/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O important/JJ/O features/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG bill/NN/O that/WDT/O should/MD/O be/VB/O enacted/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Speaker/NNP/O Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Foley/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Wash/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O any/DT/O support/NN/O for/IN/O reducing/VBG/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O conditioned/VBN/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O desire/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O them/PRP/O passed/VBN/O in/IN/O another/DT/O form/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
``/``/O You/PRP/O 've/VBP/O got/VBN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O these/DT/O chairmen/NNS/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O can/MD/O work/VB/O things/NNS/O out/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O House/NNP/B-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Leon/NNP/B-PERSON Panetta/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Senate/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O had/VBD/O hoped/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O send/VB/O a/DT/O compromise/NN/O version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O to/TO/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O week/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Speaker/NNP/O Foley/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O likely/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O enacted/VBN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O cuts/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O restored/VBN/O ././O
