The/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Ethics/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG officially/RB/O cited/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Bates/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O for/IN/O sexually/RB/O harassing/VBG/O two/CD/O female/JJ/O employees/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O recommend/VB/O formal/JJ/O disciplinary/JJ/O action/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Bates/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O accepted/VBD/O the/DT/O finding/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O victims/NNS/O ,/,/O Dorena/NNP/B-PERSON Bertussi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O denounced/VBD/O the/DT/O ethics/NNS/O panel/NN/O 's/POS/O action/NN/O as/IN/O ``/``/O absurd/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Acting/VBG/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O after/IN/O Ms./NNP/O Bertussi/NNP/B-PERSON filed/VBD/O a/DT/O complaint/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O issued/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O letter/NN/O of/IN/O reproval/NN/O ''/''/O saying/VBG/O Rep./NNP/O Bates/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O admitted/VBN/O conduct/NN/O that/WDT/O violated/VBD/O a/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG rule/NN/O forbidding/VBG/O discrimination/NN/O against/IN/O employees/NNS/O on/IN/O account/NN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O sex/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O ordered/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Bates/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O write/VB/O letters/NNS/O of/IN/O apology/NN/O to/TO/O Ms./NNP/O Bertussi/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O to/TO/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O complainant/NN/O ,/,/O Karen/NNP/B-PERSON Dryden/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Rep./NNP/O Bates/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O write/VB/O the/DT/O letters/NNS/O as/IN/O ordered/VBN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O accept/VBP/O the/DT/O resolution/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O matter/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ethics/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O panel/NN/O also/RB/O warned/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O Bates/NNP/B-PERSON that/IN/O any/DT/O further/JJ/O violations/NNS/O ``/``/O may/MD/O result/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O recommendation/NN/O that/IN/O disciplinary/JJ/O action/NN/O be/VB/O considered/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O Ms./NNP/O Bertussi/NNP/B-PERSON asked/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Who/WP/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O right/JJ/O mind/NN/O is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O file/VB/O another/DT/O complaint/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Ethics/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG ?/./O ''/''/O
Rep./NNP/O Bates/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O publicly/RB/O begged/VBN/O for/IN/O forgiveness/NN/O from/IN/O voters/NNS/O and/CC/O was/VBD/O re-elected/VBN/O with/IN/O 60/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O vote/NN/O last/JJ/O November/NNP/O ././O
