The/DT/B-ORG Tennessee/NNP/I-ORG Valley/NNP/I-ORG Authority/NNP/I-ORG issued/VBD/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O bonds/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O utility/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O public/JJ/O debt/NN/O offering/NN/O in/IN/O 15/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Proceeds/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O coupon/NN/O rates/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O range/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O replace/VB/O bonds/NNS/O with/IN/O an/DT/O average/JJ/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O 13.1/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O refinancing/VBG/O should/MD/O save/VB/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O a/DT/O year/NN/O in/IN/O interest/NN/O payments/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O refinancing/NN/O is/VBZ/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strategy/NN/O of/IN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O what/WP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O an/DT/O intractable/JJ/O problem/NN/O :/:/O its/PRP$/O staggering/JJ/O $/$/O 18.5/CD/O billion/CD/O debt/NN/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O owed/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG Treasury/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Federal/NNP/B-ORG Financing/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O bond/NN/O issue/NN/O also/RB/O will/MD/O help/VB/O the/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG meet/VB/O its/PRP$/O goal/NN/O of/IN/O not/RB/O raising/VBG/O rates/NNS/O for/IN/O another/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O William/NNP/B-PERSON F./NNP/I-PERSON Malec/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O financial/JJ/O officer/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bond/NN/O issue/NN/O is/VBZ/O TVA/NNP/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O public/JJ/O offering/NN/O since/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Financing/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O 1974/CD/O ,/,/O primarily/RB/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O the/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O offering/NN/O almost/RB/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O happen/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O decided/VBD/O to/TO/O proceed/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O bond/NN/O offering/NN/O following/VBG/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Financing/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O allows/VBZ/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O keep/VB/O borrowing/VBG/O short/JJ/O term/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O bank/NN/O for/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O after/IN/O it/PRP/O goes/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG contended/VBD/O that/IN/O TVA/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O n't/RB/O borrow/VB/O from/IN/O both/DT/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O debt/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
