Dale/NNP/B-PERSON Lang/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O this/DT/O week/NN/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O publisher/NN/O of/IN/O Ms./NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O is/VBZ/O candid/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O challenge/NN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O taking/VBG/O on/RP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON admits/VBZ/O that/DT/O Ms./NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O ``/``/O in/IN/O dire/JJ/O straits/NNS/O ''/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O big/JJ/O promotional/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O it/PRP/O alive/JJ/O ././O
Last/JJ/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O staff/NN/O of/IN/O Ms./NNP/B-ORG that/IN/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O would/MD/O begin/VB/O publishing/VBG/O without/IN/O advertising/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O publish/VB/O one/NN/O that/WDT/O succeeds/VBZ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O For/IN/O Ms./NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O time/NN/O to/TO/O publish/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O reader/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O the/DT/O advertiser/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O for/IN/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O competes/VBZ/O directly/RB/O with/IN/O News/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Seventeen/NNP/B-ORG magazine/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O he/PRP/O will/MD/O spend/VB/O $/$/O 6/CD/O million/CD/O promoting/VBG/O and/CC/O improving/VBG/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O reaction/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O nothing/NN/O and/CC/O ride/VB/O it/PRP/O out/RP/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O keep/VB/O its/PRP$/O irreverent/JJ/O tone/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O will/MD/O keep/VB/O a/DT/O close/JJ/O watch/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O editorial/JJ/O content/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O magazine/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Sassy/NNP/B-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O recovered/VBN/O ;/:/O circulation/NN/O has/VBZ/O quickly/RB/O passed/VBN/O the/DT/O 500,000/CD/O mark/NN/O and/CC/O advertising/NN/O pages/NNS/O have/VBP/O stabilized/VBN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O at/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 300/CD/O ././O
What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O what/WP/O all/DT/O publishers/NNS/O wish/VBP/O for/IN/O :/:/O a/DT/O bona/JJ/O fide/JJ/O niche/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Seventeen/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O written/VBN/O more/RBR/O for/IN/O mothers/NNS/O ,/,/O not/RB/O their/PRP$/O daughters/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O spirit/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O gets/VBZ/O more/JJR/O mail/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O month/NN/O than/IN/O McCall/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O got/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O from/IN/O mothers/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O feel/VBP/O about/IN/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG like/IN/O I/PRP/O did/VBD/O about/IN/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Woman/NNP/I-ORG 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON took/VBD/O on/RP/O Ms./NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O of/IN/O Matilda/NNP/B-ORG Publications/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG by/IN/O his/PRP$/O newly/RB/O formed/VBN/O Lang/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Lang/NNP/B-PERSON owns/VBZ/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Matilda/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O while/IN/O Citicorp/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O through/IN/O its/PRP$/O Citicorp/NNP/B-ORG Venture/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Partners/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O Citicorp/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON pumped/VBD/O $/$/O 800,000/CD/O into/IN/O Matilda/NNP/B-ORG just/RB/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O doors/NNS/O open/JJ/O ././O
Industry/NN/O observers/NNS/O have/VBP/O congratulated/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON on/IN/O what/WP/O some/DT/O call/VB/O his/PRP$/O ``/``/O courageous/JJ/O ''/''/O handling/NN/O of/IN/O Ms./NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O but/CC/O his/PRP$/O track/NN/O record/NN/O in/IN/O magazine/NN/O publishing/NN/O in/IN/O general/JJ/O has/VBZ/O gotten/VBN/O mixed/JJ/O reviews/NNS/O ././O
Besides/IN/O Ms./NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Sassy/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O Lang/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG includes/VBZ/O Success/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O magazine/NN/O for/IN/O entrepreneurs/NNS/O and/CC/O small/JJ/O businesses/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Woman/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Mother/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O two/CD/O monthly/JJ/O magazines/NNS/O ././O
Working/NNP/B-ORG Woman/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O circulation/NN/O near/IN/O one/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Mother/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O 625,000/CD/O circulation/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O legitimate/JJ/O magazine/NN/O success/NN/O stories/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O magazine/NN/O Success/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O lackluster/JJ/O and/CC/O unfocused/JJ/O ././O
Only/RB/O recently/RB/O has/VBZ/O it/PRP/O been/VBN/O attractively/RB/O redesigned/VBN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O editorial/JJ/O product/NN/O improved/VBN/O ././O
Success/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O recent/JJ/O folding/NN/O of/IN/O rival/JJ/O Venture/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O magazine/NN/O for/IN/O growing/VBG/O companies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O undone/VBN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O McCall/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG magazine/NN/O being/VBG/O sold/VBN/O last/JJ/O summer/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG New/NNP/I-ORG York/NNP/I-ORG Times/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Magazine/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 80/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Time/NN/B-ORG Warner/NNP/I-ORG agreeing/VBG/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O back/RP/O its/PRP$/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Woman/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Mother/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Executives/NNS/O at/IN/O Time/NNP/B-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG Magazine/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Time/NNP/O Warner/NNP/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O said/VBN/O the/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O good/JJ/O one/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON surprised/VBD/O Time/NNP/B-ORG soon/RB/O after/IN/O joining/VBG/O forces/NNS/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O negotiate/VB/O rates/NNS/O individually/RB/O with/IN/O advertisers/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O practice/NN/O common/JJ/O in/IN/O broadcasting/NN/O but/CC/O considered/VBN/O taboo/NN/O by/IN/O magazine/NN/O publishers/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O McCall/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O put/VBD/O in/RP/O a/DT/O less/RBR/O than/IN/O stellar/JJ/O performance/NN/O ././O
Until/IN/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O comeback/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O saw/VBD/O steep/JJ/O losses/NNS/O in/IN/O ad/NN/O pages/NNS/O and/CC/O circulation/NN/O ././O
Time/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O complained/VBD/O about/IN/O the/DT/O shoddy/JJ/O editorial/JJ/O quality/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O Time/NNP/B-ORG executive/NN/O who/WP/O asked/VBD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O identified/VBN/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Frankly/RB/O ,/,/O McCall/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/O joint/JJ/O venture/NN/O were/VBD/O an/DT/O embarrassment/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON feels/VBZ/O that/DT/O Time/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O priorities/NNS/O changed/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Their/PRP$/O management/NN/O changed/VBD/O right/RB/O after/IN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O venture/NN/O was/VBD/O formed/VBN/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O think/VB/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O comfortable/JJ/O getting/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O competitive/JJ/O wars/NNS/O of/IN/O women/NNS/O 's/POS/O service/NN/O magazines/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Today/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON believes/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O magazines/NNS/O will/MD/O offer/VB/O what/WP/O many/JJ/O women/NNS/O 's/POS/O magazines/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O write/VBP/O straight/RB/O for/IN/O women/NNS/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O level/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O passive/JJ/O readers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON points/VBZ/O out/RP/O that/IN/O even/RB/O Success/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O ,/,/O fits/VBZ/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O image/NN/O ,/,/O since/IN/O about/RB/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O readership/NN/O is/VBZ/O female/JJ/O ././O
She/PRP/O will/MD/O oversee/VB/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Woman/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Mother/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Success/NNP/B-ORG magazines/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O retain/VB/O her/PRP/O post/NN/O as/IN/O publisher/NN/O of/IN/O Working/NNP/B-ORG Woman/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lang/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O scouting/VBG/O new/JJ/O acquisitions/NNS/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O for/IN/O now/RB/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O go/VB/O outside/RB/O to/TO/O banks/NNS/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O money/NN/O and/CC/O I/PRP/O am/VBP/O not/RB/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O do/VB/O that/DT/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Besides/RB/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O enough/NN/O on/IN/O our/PRP$/O plate/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O is/VBZ/O plenty/NN/O of/IN/O work/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O done/VBN/O on/IN/O what/WP/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O ././O
