It/PRP/O can/MD/O happen/VB/O in/IN/O any/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG got/VBD/O into/IN/O financial/JJ/O trouble/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O bloated/JJ/O overhead/NN/O and/CC/O overly/RB/O optimistic/JJ/O sales/NNS/O forecasts/NNS/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O mainline/JJ/O minicomputers/NNS/O and/CC/O word/NN/O processors/NNS/O have/VBP/O lost/VBN/O ground/NN/O to/TO/O cheaper/JJR/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O year/NN/O it/PRP/O funded/VBD/O its/PRP$/O high/JJ/O employment/NN/O by/IN/O heavy/JJ/O borrowing/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O suffered/VBD/O huge/JJ/O losses/NNS/O when/WRB/O sales/NNS/O turned/VBD/O down/RB/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O rising/VBG/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON vetoed/VBD/O that/DT/O :/:/O ``/``/O Even/RB/O I/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O understand/VB/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O footnotes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
Mike/NNP/B-PERSON Metschan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O salesman/NN/O in/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Austin/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O office/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O breezier/JJR/O method/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O tell/VBP/O them/PRP/O $/$/O 3/CD/O billion/CD/O companies/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O go/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O ././O
Numerous/JJ/O computer/NN/O companies/NNS/O are/VBP/O having/VBG/O sales/NNS/O slumps/NNS/O and/CC/O earnings/NNS/O declines/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O very/RB/O few/JJ/O have/VBP/O had/VBN/O losses/NNS/O comparable/JJ/O to/TO/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O or/CC/O are/VBP/O carrying/VBG/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O debt/NN/O load/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Miller/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/IN/O after/IN/O a/DT/O sharp/JJ/O sales/NNS/O slump/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O and/CC/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O sales/NNS/O stabilized/VBD/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ././O
Experts/NNS/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O technique/NN/O say/VBP/O anyone/NN/O representing/VBG/O a/DT/O troubled/JJ/O company/NN/O must/MD/O walk/VB/O a/DT/O fine/JJ/O line/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O easy/JJ/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O customers/NNS/O are/VBP/O data/NNS/O processing/NN/O managers/NNS/O who/WP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O sure/JJ/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O suppliers/NNS/O are/VBP/O stable/JJ/O ,/,/O wellrun/JJ/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O around/RB/O to/TO/O fix/VB/O bugs/NNS/O and/CC/O upgrade/VB/O computers/NNS/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O university/NN/O is/VBZ/O considering/VBG/O installing/VBG/O a/DT/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O system/NN/O to/TO/O store/VB/O applications/NNS/O electronically/RB/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O overall/JJ/O product/NN/O line/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O still/RB/O not/RB/O as/RB/O good/JJ/O as/IN/O other/JJ/O vendors/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O they/PRP/O 've/VBP/O come/VBN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O way/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Steven/NNP/B-PERSON Wendler/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O consultant/NN/O with/IN/O market/NN/O researcher/NN/O Gartner/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Stamford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O priority/NN/O for/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O sales/NNS/O force/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O make/VB/O sure/JJ/O it/PRP/O holds/VBZ/O on/IN/O to/TO/O existing/JJ/O customers/NNS/O ././O
Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O installed/JJ/O base/NN/O is/VBZ/O one/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O greatest/JJS/O assets/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O those/DT/O customers/NNS/O remain/VBP/O extremely/RB/O loyal/JJ/O ././O
One/CD/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG salesman/NN/O who/WP/O left/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O recalls/VBZ/O that/IN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O products/NNS/O to/TO/O Eastman/NNP/B-ORG Kodak/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O he/PRP/O worked/VBD/O ``/``/O to/TO/O muster/VB/O support/NN/O from/IN/O internal/JJ/O allies/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O but/CC/O ``/``/O those/DT/O allies/NNS/O became/VBD/O skeptical/JJ/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O saw/VBD/O the/DT/O downtrend/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Lynch/NNP/B-PERSON left/VBD/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG this/DT/O summer/NN/O for/IN/O Oracle/NNP/B-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O software/NN/O vendor/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O financial/JJ/O problems/NNS/O are/VBP/O particularly/RB/O frustrating/JJ/O for/IN/O salespeople/NNS/O pushing/VBG/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O image/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O convert/VBP/O paper/NN/O forms/NNS/O to/TO/O electronic/JJ/O documents/NNS/O ././O
Consultants/NNS/O say/VBP/O that/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O technology/NN/O is/VBZ/O among/IN/O the/DT/O best/JJS/O available/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O image/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O Lilly/NNP/B-ORG executives/NNS/O told/VBD/O him/PRP/O they/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O take/VB/O the/DT/O risk/NN/O with/IN/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Tait/NNP/B-PERSON say/VB/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O blame/VB/O Lilly/RB/B-ORG ././O
Buyers/NNS/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O rely/VB/O on/IN/O a/DT/O supplier/NN/O ``/``/O continually/RB/O upgrading/VBG/O and/CC/O replacing/VBG/O the/DT/O product/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Eastate/NNP/B-ORG Homes/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O Indianapolis/NNP/B-GPE contractor/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O hard/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O salesperson/NN/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O off/RP/O feelings/NNS/O of/IN/O discouragement/NN/O ././O
Brian/NNP/B-PERSON Petre/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O Wang/NNP/B-ORG salesman/NN/O in/IN/O upstate/JJ/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O have/VBP/O pride/NN/O in/IN/O your/PRP$/O job/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O think/VBP/O you/PRP/O can/MD/O go/VB/O out/RB/O and/CC/O turn/VB/O things/NNS/O around/RB|RP/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O tough/JJ/O thing/NN/O when/WRB/O you/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O ././O
Discouragement/NN/O feeds/VBZ/O on/IN/O itself/PRP/O ././O
One/CD/O key/NN/O for/IN/O salespeople/NNS/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O boost/VB/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O morale/NN/O ././O
Paul/NNP/B-PERSON Hellman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Framingham/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O sales/NNS/O and/CC/O management/NN/O consultant/NN/O and/CC/O author/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Ready/JJ/O ,/,/O Aim/VB/O ,/,/O You/PRP/O 're/VBP/O Hired/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O The/DT/O bad/JJ/O news/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O rejected/VBN/O more/RBR/O ././O
