U.S./NNP/B-GPE steel/NN/O imports/NNS/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O fell/VBD/O 14/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O year/NN/O earlier/JJR/O to/TO/O 1,531,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Iron/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O trade/NN/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O compilation/NN/O of/IN/O Commerce/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG data/NNS/O showed/VBD/O that/IN/O August/NNP/O imports/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O largest/JJS/O monthly/JJ/O total/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O up/IN/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O July/NNP/O 's/POS/O 1,458,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O but/CC/O below/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O 's/VBZ/O high/JJ/O of/IN/O 1,979,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O in/IN/O June/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
August/NNP/O imports/NNS/O claimed/VBD/O 18.5/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O ,/,/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O 19.3/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O and/CC/O 20.5/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O latest/JJS/O month/NN/O 's/POS/O figures/NNS/O show/VB/O that/IN/O imports/NNS/O of/IN/O steel/NN/O from/IN/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG nations/NNS/O fell/VBD/O to/TO/O 466,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O from/IN/O 481,000/CD/O a/DT/O month/NN/O earlier/RB/O ,/,/O while/IN/O imports/NNS/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE rose/VBD/O to/TO/O 323,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O from/IN/O 288,000/CD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
Imports/NNS/O from/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE rose/VBD/O to/TO/O 272,000/CD/O tons/NNS/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O from/IN/O 209,000/CD/O in/IN/O July/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Imported/NNP/I-ORG Steel/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O imports/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O eight/CD/O months/NNS/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O were/VBD/O below/IN/O the/DT/O level/NN/O allowed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Voluntary/NNP/O Restraint/NNP/O Agreement/NNP/O program/NN/O ././O
