This/DT/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O season/NN/O for/IN/O revivals/NNS/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Though/NNP/O the/DT/O Cubs/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O championship/NN/O season/NN/O ended/VBD/O with/IN/O the/DT/O National/NNP/B-ORG League/NNP/I-ORG playoffs/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O revival/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Organic/NNP/I-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG production/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O Bleacher/NN/O Bums/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O play/NN/O in/IN/O nine/CD/O innings/NN/O set/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Wrigley/NNP/B-FAC Field/NNP/I-FAC bleachers/NNS/O ,/,/O continues/VBZ/O within/IN/O spitting/NN/O distance/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ballpark/NN/O ././O
Revivals/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O different/JJ/O sort/NN/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O offered/VBN/O by/IN/O our/PRP$/O two/CD/O major/JJ/O theater/NN/O troupes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Goodman/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Each/DT/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O problematic/JJ/O than/IN/O an/DT/O unexpected/JJ/O divisional/JJ/O baseball/NN/O championship/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O both/DT/O help/VBP/O explain/VB/O why/WRB/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE remains/VBZ/O a/DT/O vital/JJ/O center/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O regional/JJ/O theater/NN/O movement/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Goodman/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O offering/VBG/O a/DT/O modernized/JJ/O version/NN/O of/IN/O Moliere/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Misanthrope/NN/O ''/''/O through/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 4/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O original/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O comedy/NN/O about/IN/O Alceste/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O sees/VBZ/O falseness/NN/O and/CC/O vanity/NN/O in/IN/O everyone/NN/O except/IN/O himself/PRP/O ././O
He/PRP/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O jealous/JJ/O friend/NN/O of/IN/O Philinte/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O jealous/JJ/O lover/NN/O of/IN/O Celimene/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O play/NN/O is/VBZ/O filled/VBN/O with/IN/O intrigue/NN/O ,/,/O dishonesty/NN/O and/CC/O injustice/NN/O ././O
Otherwise/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O scene/NN/O remained/VBD/O Celimene/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O house/NN/O in/IN/O 1666/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O Wilbur/NNP/B-PERSON translation/NN/O is/VBZ/O remarkable/JJ/O --/:/O well/RB/O worth/JJ/O a/DT/O read/VBN/O and/CC/O even/RB/O better/RBR/O seen/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O theater/NN/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O ever/RB/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O opportunity/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O happen/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O coming/VBG/O to/TO/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ,/,/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O fail/VB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O look/NN/O at/IN/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Falls/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O The/DT/O Misanthrope/NN/O ''/''/O at/IN/O the/DT/O Goodman/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Falls/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O Goodman/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O artistic/JJ/O director/NN/O ,/,/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O recent/JJ/O adaptation/NN/O by/IN/O Neil/NNP/B-PERSON Bartlett/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O significantly/RB/O adapted/VBD/O it/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bartlett/NNP/B-PERSON had/VBD/O slimmed/VBN/O Moliere/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O cast/NN/O of/IN/O characters/NNS/O to/TO/O six/CD/O and/CC/O set/VBN/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE media/NN/O world/NN/O of/IN/O Thatcherite/JJ/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Mr./NNP/O Falls/NNP/B-PERSON transfers/VBZ/O the/DT/O setting/NN/O to/TO/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O transforms/VBZ/O the/DT/O characters/NNS/O into/IN/O what/WP/O passes/VBZ/O for/IN/O aristocracy/NN/O there/RB/O --/:/O agents/NNS/O ,/,/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O actors/NNS/O ,/,/O writers/NNS/O and/CC/O sycophants/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O works/VBZ/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bartlett/NNP/B-PERSON managed/VBD/O to/TO/O more/RBR/O or/CC/O less/RBR/O maintain/VB/O Moliere/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O Alexandrine/JJ/O verse/NN/O form/NN/O ,/,/O 12/CD/O syllable/NN/O lines/NNS/O in/IN/O rhyming/VBG/O couplets/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Falls/NNP/B-PERSON kept/VBD/O the/DT/O form/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Americanized/VBD/O it/PRP/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Bartlett/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O further/JJ/O help/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O this/DT/O version/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O references/NNS/O to/TO/O Steven/NNP/B-PERSON Spielberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Spago/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O ``/``/O thirtysomething/NN/O ''/''/O attracts/VBZ/O younger/JJR/O audiences/NNS/O who/WP/O might/MD/O stay/VB/O away/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O classical/JJ/O version/NN/O ,/,/O then/RB/O Messrs./NNPS/O Bartlett/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Falls/NNP/B-PERSON are/VBP/O justified/JJ/O in/IN/O abandoning/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Wilbur/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Steppenwolf/NNP/I-ORG Theatre/NNP/I-ORG Company/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O back/RB/O from/IN/O a/DT/O critical/JJ/O and/CC/O box/NN/O office/NN/O success/NN/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O its/PRP$/O adaptation/NN/O of/IN/O Steinbeck/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Grapes/NNS/O of/IN/O Wrath/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O opened/VBD/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O season/NN/O with/IN/O Harold/NNP/B-PERSON Pinter/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON ``/``/O The/DT/O Homecoming/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O first/RB/O produced/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Royal/NNP/I-ORG Shakespeare/NNP/I-ORG Company/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1965/CD/O ././O
Back/RB/O then/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Pinter/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O not/RB/O only/RB/O the/DT/O angry/JJ/O young/JJ/O British/JJ/O playwright/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O also/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O to/TO/O use/VB/O silences/NNS/O and/CC/O sentence/NN/O fragments/NNS/O and/CC/O menacing/JJ/O stares/NNS/O ,/,/O almost/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O exclusion/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O we/PRP/O previously/RB/O understood/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O theatrical/JJ/O dialogue/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Homecoming/NN/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O first/RB/O produced/VBN/O on/IN/O this/DT/O side/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Atlantic/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O actors/NNS/O and/CC/O directors/NNS/O were/VBD/O reverential/JJ/O ././O
Silences/NNS/O were/VBD/O lengthy/JJ/O --/:/O nobody/NN/O moved/VBD/O or/CC/O gestured/VBD/O ././O
Nobody/NN/O smiled/VBD/O onstage/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O nobody/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O audience/NN/O was/VBD/O encouraged/VBN/O to/TO/O laugh/VB/O ././O
This/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O theater/NN/O was/VBD/O new/JJ/O to/TO/O us/PRP/O ././O
Also/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O a/DT/O funny/JJ/O time/NN/O over/IN/O here/RB/O ,/,/O what/WP/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Vietnam/NNP/O War/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O '68/CD/O Democratic/JJ/O convention/NN/O ,/,/O assassinations/NNS/O and/CC/O riots/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O under/IN/O Jerry/NNP/B-PERSON Perry/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON direction/NN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG production/NN/O ,/,/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O play/VB/O through/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 19/CD/O ,/,/O breaks/VBZ/O through/IN/O the/DT/O flat/JJ/O and/CC/O boring/JJ/O ritual/NN/O that/IN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Homecoming/NN/O ''/''/O had/VBD/O become/VBN/O ././O
Encouraged/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Wilder/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sly/JJ/O grins/NNS/O ,/,/O embarrassed/JJ/O grimaces/NNS/O and/CC/O sputtering/JJ/O rages/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O audience/NN/O gets/VBZ/O the/DT/O joke/NN/O and/CC/O begins/VBZ/O to/TO/O laugh/VB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O act/NN/O ././O
Three/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O family/NN/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O two/CD/O sons/NNS/O ,/,/O Lenny/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Joey/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O live/VBP/O off/IN/O the/DT/O flesh/NN/O :/:/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O retired/JJ/O butcher/NN/O ,/,/O Lenny/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O pimp/NN/O and/CC/O Joey/NNP/B-PERSON an/DT/O aspiring/JJ/O boxer/NN/O ././O
Sam/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O brother/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O escaped/VBN/O the/DT/O flesh/NN/O by/IN/O working/VBG/O as/IN/O a/DT/O liveried/JJ/O chauffeur/NN/O and/CC/O never/RB/O seeking/VBG/O a/DT/O wife/NN/O ././O
Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O eldest/JJS/O of/IN/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O sons/NNS/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O made/VBN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O dramatic/JJ/O escape/NN/O by/IN/O becoming/VBG/O a/DT/O professor/NN/O of/IN/O philosophy/NN/O at/IN/O an/DT/O American/JJ/O university/NN/O ././O
Though/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O clearly/RB/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O wife/NN/O who/WP/O held/VBD/O sway/NN/O here/RB/O until/IN/O her/PRP$/O death/NN/O ,/,/O now/RB/O none/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O male/JJ/O residents/NNS/O of/IN/O this/DT/O misbegotten/JJ/O household/NN/O can/MD/O challenge/VB/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O play/NN/O concerns/VBZ/O Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O homecoming/NN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O wife/NN/O of/IN/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O Ruth/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Curiously/NNP/O ,/,/O Randall/NNP/B-PERSON Arney/NNP/I-PERSON as/IN/O Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON seems/VBZ/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O cast/NN/O member/NN/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O zombie/NN/O approach/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O Pinter/NNP/B-PERSON character/NN/O ././O
As/IN/O Ruth/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Moira/NNP/B-PERSON Harris/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O large/JJ/O and/CC/O beautiful/JJ/O woman/NN/O who/WP/O may/MD/O be/VB/O our/PRP$/O next/JJ/O Colleen/NNP/B-PERSON Dewhurst/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O begins/VBZ/O almost/RB/O immediately/RB/O to/TO/O overpower/VB/O each/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O men/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O ,/,/O Teddy/NNP/B-PERSON returns/VBZ/O alone/RB/O to/TO/O America/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O Ruth/NNP/B-PERSON in/IN/O Max/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O chair/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Grapes/NNS/O of/IN/O Wrath/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Sagan/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O president/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O board/NN/O of/IN/O directors/NNS/O ,/,/O quietly/RB/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O buy/VB/O a/DT/O piece/NN/O of/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O rapidly/RB/O reviving/VBG/O North/NNP/B-FAC Halsted/NNP/I-FAC Street/NNP/I-FAC restaurant/NN/O and/CC/O theater/NN/O district/NN/O ././O
``/``/O If/IN/O we/PRP/O wanted/VBD/O to/TO/O stage/VB/O `/``/O Death/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Salesman/NN/O ,/,/O '/''/O ``/``/O Mr./NNP/O Sagan/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Willie/NNP/B-PERSON Loman/NNP/I-PERSON would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O live/VB/O in/IN/O a/DT/O ranch/NN/O house/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O low/JJ/O ceiling/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG needs/VBZ/O the/DT/O extra/JJ/O seats/NNS/O even/RB/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O the/DT/O fly/NN/O space/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O currently/RB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O away/RP/O many/JJ/O potential/JJ/O subscribers/NNS/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O 13,000/CD/O who/WP/O can/MD/O be/VB/O accommodated/VBN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O present/JJ/O digs/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O attention/NN/O that/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE theater/NN/O has/VBZ/O received/VBN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O decade/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O one/CD/O new/JJ/O building/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O devoted/VBN/O to/TO/O it/PRP/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sagan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O former/JJ/O publisher/NN/O and/CC/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O developer/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O put/VBN/O together/RB/O an/DT/O $/$/O 8/CD/O million/CD/O financial/JJ/O package/NN/O that/WDT/O includes/VBZ/O approximately/RB/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O tax/NN/O exempt/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O issued/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE State/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/I-GPE Illinois/NNP/I-GPE -LRB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O that/IN/O a/DT/O state/NN/O has/VBZ/O used/VBN/O its/PRP$/O educational/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O authority/NN/O to/TO/O support/VB/O construction/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O theater/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O approximately/RB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O grants/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Endowment/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Arts/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG MacArthur/NNP/I-ORG Foundation/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O other/JJ/O deep/JJ/O pockets/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O confident/JJ/O ,/,/O can/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O board/NN/O members/NNS/O alone/RB/O have/VBP/O pledged/VBN/O $/$/O 800,000/CD/O and/CC/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O beginning/VBG/O to/TO/O massage/VB/O local/JJ/O foundations/NNS/O and/CC/O corporations/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sagan/NNP/B-PERSON compares/VBZ/O the/DT/O importance/NN/O of/IN/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG with/IN/O Orson/NNP/B-PERSON Welles/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Mercury/NNP/B-ORG Theater/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O the/DT/O '30s/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O Welles/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O theater/NN/O company/NN/O turned/VBD/O out/RP/O to/TO/O have/VB/O a/DT/O brief/JJ/O --/:/O one/PRP/O might/MD/O say/VB/O a/DT/O mercurial/JJ/O --/:/O existence/NN/O ././O
What/WP/O will/MD/O Mr./NNP/O Sagan/NNP/B-PERSON do/VB/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O new/JJ/O theater/NN/O building/NN/O if/IN/O the/DT/O allure/NN/O of/IN/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Broadway/NNP/B-FAC proves/VBZ/O too/RB/O much/RB/O for/IN/O such/JJ/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG stalwarts/NNS/O as/IN/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Malkovich/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O Dangerous/JJ/O Liaisons/NNS/O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O Joan/NNP/B-PERSON Allen/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Heidi/NNP/O Chronicles/NNS/O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Glenne/NNP/B-PERSON Headly/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O ``/``/O Lonesome/JJ/O Dove/NN/O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O crumbles/VBZ/O ?/./O
``/``/O That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O OK/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Sagan/NNP/B-PERSON replies/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O Let/VB/O this/DT/O building/NN/O be/VB/O Steppenwolf/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O legacy/NN/O to/TO/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE theater/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
