Just/RB/O after/IN/O midnight/NN/O Monday/NNP/O ,/,/O federal/JJ/O spending/NN/O started/VBD/O to/TO/O drop/VB/O by/IN/O $/$/O 16/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
What/WP/O do/VBP/O you/PRP/O say/VB/O we/PRP/O all/DT/O close/VBP/O down/RP/O the/DT/O poker/NN/O game/NN/O ,/,/O go/VBP/O home/NN/O and/CC/O bank/VBP/O the/DT/O $/$/O 16/CD/O billion/CD/O ?/./O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O essentially/RB/O what/WP/O budget/NN/O director/NN/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Darman/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O suggesting/VBG/O ,/,/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O think/VBP/O he/PRP/O deserves/VBZ/O as/RB/O much/JJ/O support/NN/O as/IN/O he/PRP/O can/MD/O get/VB/O ././O
If/IN/O human/JJ/O beings/NNS/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O cut/VB/O federal/JJ/O spending/NN/O honestly/RB/O --/:/O and/CC/O they/PRP/O ca/MD/O n't/RB/O --/:/O let/VB/O the/DT/O computers/NNS/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O with/IN/O a/DT/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG complicity/NN/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O manipulating/VBG/O the/DT/O spending/NN/O accounts/NNS/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O cover/NN/O of/IN/O omnibus/JJ/O appropriations/NNS/O bills/NNS/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Indeed/RB/O without/IN/O earlier/JJR/O manipulations/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O current/NN/O sequester/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 16/CD/O billion/CD/O would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O even/RB/O larger/JJR/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
We/PRP/O suspect/VBP/O voters/NNS/O are/VBP/O fed/VBN/O up/RP/O with/IN/O the/DT/O finagling/NN/O ././O
Consider/VB/O ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O that/IN/O even/RB/O yesterday/NN/O 's/VBZ/O widely/RB/O publicized/VBN/O sequester/NN/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O traduced/VBN/O if/IN/O business/NN/O as/IN/O usual/JJ/O is/VBZ/O allowed/VBN/O to/TO/O prevail/VB/O ././O
Social/NNP/B-ORG Security/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O spending/NN/O for/IN/O poor/JJ/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O exempted/VBN/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Associated/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG account/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Monday/NNP/O sequester/NN/O order/NN/O signed/VBN/O by/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON neatly/RB/O captured/VBD/O the/DT/O contempt/NN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG shows/VBZ/O toward/IN/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O legally/RB/O binding/JJ/O commitment/NN/O :/:/O
Mr./NNP/O Darman/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O inclination/NN/O to/TO/O save/VB/O the/DT/O sequester/NN/O was/VBD/O backed/VBN/O up/RP/O yesterday/NN/O by/IN/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/O Secretary/NNP/O Marlin/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzwater/NNP/I-PERSON :/:/O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O some/DT/O feeling/NN/O here/RB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O cuts/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O go/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O will/MD/O reduce/VB/O spending/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O very/RB/O effective/JJ/O fashion/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
This/DT/O attitude/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O waved/VBD/O away/RP/O by/IN/O sophisticates/NNS/O around/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE as/RB/O little/JJ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O tough/JJ/O talk/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O looks/VBZ/O to/TO/O us/PRP/O like/IN/O a/DT/O golden/JJ/O opportunity/NN/O for/IN/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O chop/VB/O off/RP/O at/IN/O the/DT/O knees/NNS/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O talk/NN/O about/IN/O a/DT/O timid/JJ/O ,/,/O unserious/JJ/O presidency/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O be/VB/O acting/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O public/JJ/O interest/NN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O let/VBD/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE elites/NNS/O who/WP/O manipulate/VBP/O these/DT/O budgets/NNS/O --/:/O the/DT/O bureaucrats/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O lobbyists/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O congressional/JJ/O staffers/NNS/O --/:/O live/VB/O for/IN/O just/RB/O one/CD/O year/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O restricted/JJ/O diet/NN/O ././O
Ask/VB/O Tommy/NNP/B-PERSON Lasorda/NNP/I-PERSON ;/:/O thin/JJ/O is/VBZ/O in/RB/O ././O
Another/DT/O major/JJ/O factor/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O positive/JJ/O trend/NN/O was/VBD/O Ronald/NNP/B-PERSON Reagan/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON decision/NN/O early/RB/O in/IN/O his/PRP$/O presidency/NN/O to/TO/O fight/VB/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O war/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O expenditure/NN/O side/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O raising/VBG/O taxes/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O elites/NNS/O ever/RB/O succeed/VBP/O in/IN/O bursting/VBG/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O dam/NN/O ,/,/O Americans/NNPS/O will/MD/O be/VB/O engulfed/VBN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O red/JJ/O sea/NN/O of/IN/O new/JJ/O spending/NN/O programs/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O federalized/JJ/O child/NN/O care/NN/O ././O
Child/NN/O care/NN/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O many/JJ/O ``/``/O extraneous/JJ/O ''/''/O bills/NNS/O pulled/VBN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O reconciliation/NN/O bill/NN/O last/JJ/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
House/NNP/B-ORG Speaker/NNP/O Foley/NNP/B-PERSON ought/MD/O to/TO/O deliver/VB/O that/DT/O promise/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O way/NN/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O supposed/VBN/O to/TO/O work/VB/O ,/,/O with/IN/O politicians/NNS/O taking/VBG/O responsibility/NN/O for/IN/O votes/NNS/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O constituents/NNS/O can/MD/O identify/VB/O ,/,/O instead/RB/O of/IN/O concealing/VBG/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O great/JJ/O reconciliation/NN/O garbage/NN/O truck/NN/O ././O
Those/DT/O days/NNS/O are/VBP/O gone/VBN/O ././O
Nor/CC/O do/VBP/O we/PRP/O see/VB/O any/DT/O reason/NN/O to/TO/O believe/VB/O that/IN/O a/DT/O metropolitan/JJ/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O gotten/VBN/O fat/JJ/O and/CC/O rich/JJ/O and/CC/O lazy/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O shadow/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O colossus/NN/O will/MD/O change/VB/O much/RB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O initiative/NN/O ././O
Save/VB/O the/DT/O sequester/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O let/VB/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE scream/NN/O ././O
