``/``/O The/DT/O New/JJ/O Crowd/NN/O ''/''/O by/IN/O Judith/NNP/B-PERSON Ramsey/NNP/I-PERSON Ehrlich/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Barry/NNP/B-PERSON J./NNP/I-PERSON Rehfeld/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O Little/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/I-ORG Brown/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O 444/CD/O pages/NNS/O ,/,/O $/$/O 19.95/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O describes/VBZ/O the/DT/O displacing/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O ``/``/O our/PRP$/O crowd/NN/O ''/''/O Jewish/JJ/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O banking/NN/O grandees/NNS/O by/IN/O such/JJ/O new/JJ/O business/NN/O barons/NNS/O as/IN/O Saul/NNP/B-PERSON Steinberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Carl/NNP/B-PERSON Icahn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Sanford/NNP/B-PERSON Weill/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Bruce/NNP/B-PERSON Wasserstein/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
These/DT/O two/CD/O New/NNP/O Crowd/NNP/O families/NNS/O lived/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O apartment/NN/O building/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Postel/NNP/B-PERSON penthouse/NN/O perched/VBN/O on/IN/O top/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Gutfreund/NNP/B-PERSON duplex/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O penthouse/NN/O elevator/NN/O started/VBD/O up/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Gutfreund/NNP/B-PERSON landing/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Susan/NNP/B-PERSON Gutfreund/NNP/I-PERSON used/VBD/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O off/RP/O its/PRP$/O light/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O give/VB/O the/DT/O impression/NN/O that/IN/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O no/DT/O higher/JJR/O floor/NN/O ././O
Eventually/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Postel/NNP/B-PERSON broke/VBD/O his/PRP$/O toe/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O dark/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O this/DT/O ,/,/O a/DT/O crane/NN/O needed/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O mounted/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Postels/NNPS/B-PERSON '/POS/O terrace/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Postels/NNPS/B-PERSON did/VBD/O not/RB/O give/VB/O permission/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O Gutfreund/NNP/B-PERSON workers/NNS/O went/VBD/O ahead/RB/O anyway/RB/O ,/,/O only/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O captured/VBN/O ``/``/O in/FW/O flagrante/FW/O ''/''/O by/IN/O Joan/NNP/B-PERSON Postel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O police/NN/O ././O
Nothing/NN/O less/RBR/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seemed/VBD/O ,/,/O could/MD/O console/VB/O them/PRP/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O traumas/NNS/O ././O
Where/WRB/O had/VBD/O all/PDT/O the/DT/O money/NN/O come/VBN/O from/IN/O ?/./O
``/``/O `/``/O Get/VB/O off/IN/O your/PRP$/O .../:/O ,/,/O '/''/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O bellow/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O authors/NNS/O ././O
Rising/VBG/O in/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O became/VBD/O powerful/JJ/O and/CC/O bland/JJ/O ,/,/O though/IN/O his/PRP$/O new/JJ/O wife/NN/O ,/,/O Susan/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O made/VBD/O him/PRP/O shine/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O gossip/NN/O columns/NNS/O with/IN/O her/PRP$/O profligate/JJ/O spending/NN/O habits/NNS/O and/CC/O flamboyant/JJ/O frocks/NNS/O ././O
Limited/JJ/B-ORG partner/NN/O Billy/NNP/B-PERSON Salomon/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O family/NN/O name/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O door/NN/O for/IN/O 70/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O hoped/VBN/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O there/RB/O forever/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O consulted/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Gutfreund/NNP/B-PERSON collected/VBD/O $/$/O 32/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O while/IN/O Billy/NNP/B-PERSON Salomon/NNP/I-PERSON got/VBD/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O much/RB/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O if/IN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O conducted/VBN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O felt/VBD/O betrayed/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O later/RB/O said/VBD/O ././O
Worse/RBR/O ,/,/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O timing/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O off/RB/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O profits/NNS/O ,/,/O unlike/IN/O Phibro/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O ,/,/O soared/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O it/PRP/O held/VBN/O out/RP/O ,/,/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O have/VB/O gotten/VBN/O an/DT/O even/RB/O bigger/JJR/O bundle/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O book/NN/O also/RB/O recounts/VBZ/O the/DT/O not/RB/O dissimilar/JJ/O maneuvers/NNS/O surrounding/VBG/O the/DT/O changing/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O guard/NN/O at/IN/O Lehman/NNP/B-ORG Bros./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O other/JJ/O grand/JJ/O old/JJ/O firms/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O earlier/JJR/O generation/NN/O of/IN/O ``/``/O our/PRP$/O crowd/NN/O ''/''/O bankers/NNS/O --/:/O Belmonts/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O Warburgs/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O Lehmans/NNPS/B-PERSON ,/,/O Baches/NNPS/B-PERSON and/CC/O Schiffs/NNPS/B-PERSON --/:/O had/VBD/O stressed/VBN/O above/IN/O all/DT/O probity/NN/O ,/,/O tradition/NN/O ,/,/O continuity/NN/O and/CC/O reputation/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O harsh/JJ/O world/NN/O of/IN/O today/NN/O 's/POS/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O they/PRP/O have/VBP/O lost/VBN/O out/RP/O to/TO/O more/RBR/O aggressive/JJ/O and/CC/O sometimes/RB/O less/RBR/O scrupulous/JJ/O successors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O cuckoo/NN/O prefers/VBZ/O the/DT/O nests/NNS/O of/IN/O other/JJ/O birds/NNS/O and/CC/O heaves/VBD/O out/RP/O their/PRP$/O eggs/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O guard/NN/O hired/VBD/O the/DT/O New/NNP/O Crowd/NNP/O people/NNS/O :/:/O It/PRP/O brought/VBD/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O cuckoos/NNS/O ././O
So/RB/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Old/NNP/O Crowd/NNP/O toppled/VBD/O from/IN/O the/DT/O branch/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O should/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O too/RB/O surprised/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O old/JJ/O guard/NN/O had/VBD/O every/DT/O right/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O to/TO/O disdain/VB/O the/DT/O newcomers/NNS/O '/POS/O new/JJ/O ways/NNS/O of/IN/O making/VBG/O money/NN/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O greenmail/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O A/DT/O Fortune/NNP/B-ORG article/NN/O on/IN/O Saul/NNP/B-PERSON Steinberg/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O entitled/VBN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O Fear/NN/O and/CC/O Loathing/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Corporate/JJ/O Boardrooms/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Their/PRP$/O other/JJ/O staple/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O corporate/JJ/O takeovers/NNS/O ,/,/O often/RB/O hostile/JJ/O and/CC/O financed/VBN/O by/IN/O junk/NN/O bonds/NNS/O ././O
Hostile/JJ/O takeovers/NNS/O are/VBP/O quite/PDT/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O phenomenon/NN/O ././O
Sometimes/RB/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O constructive/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O often/RB/O not/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O if/IN/O a/DT/O raider/NN/O takes/VBZ/O over/RP/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O is/VBZ/O weak/JJ/O ,/,/O the/DT/O shareholder/NN/O never/RB/O gets/VBZ/O his/PRP$/O recovery/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O raiders/NNS/O ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O have/VBP/O evolved/VBN/O their/PRP$/O own/JJ/O pattern/NN/O for/IN/O spending/VBG/O their/PRP$/O new/JJ/O millions/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O described/VBN/O in/IN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O New/JJ/O Crowd/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O they/PRP/O take/VBP/O on/RP/O ambitious/JJ/O new/JJ/O wives/NNS/O ,/,/O move/VBP/O to/TO/O Greenwich/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O or/CC/O Bedford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O buy/VBP/O OK/JJ/O pictures/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O let/VBP/O their/PRP$/O wives/NNS/O share/VB/O the/DT/O wealth/NN/O with/IN/O decorators/NNS/O ././O
Having/VBG/O donated/VBN/O heavily/RB/O to/TO/O museums/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O demand/VBP/O a/DT/O place/NN/O on/IN/O their/PRP$/O boards/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O book/NN/O is/VBZ/O patronizing/JJ/O about/IN/O this/DT/O nouveau/JJ/O riche/JJ/O struggle/NN/O for/IN/O respectability/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O tawdry/JJ/O aspects/NNS/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O on/IN/O balance/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O charity/NN/O game/NN/O helps/VBZ/O America/NNP/B-GPE ././O
If/IN/O those/DT/O who/WP/O have/VBP/O the/DT/O money/NN/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O involved/JJ/O with/IN/O the/DT/O museums/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O charities/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O City/NNP/B-ORG Hall/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O badly/RB/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O rightly/RB/O observed/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O main/JJ/O thing/NN/O wrong/JJ/O with/IN/O tainted/JJ/O money/NN/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O t'/PRP/O ai/VBZ/O nt/RB/O enough/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
A/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/O Crowd/NNP/O operators/NNS/O have/VBP/O crossed/VBN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O immoral/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O illegal/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O have/VBP/O ended/VBN/O up/RP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O slammer/NN/O or/CC/O paying/VBG/O huge/JJ/O fines/NNS/O :/:/O
Ivan/NNP/B-PERSON Boesky/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Dennis/NNP/B-PERSON Levine/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Martin/NNP/B-PERSON Siegel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Victor/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Steven/NNP/B-PERSON Posner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O now/RB/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Milken/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O perhaps/RB/O Leona/NNP/B-PERSON Helmsley/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O glitzy/JJ/O office/NN/O that/WDT/O Ivan/NNP/B-PERSON Boesky/NNP/I-PERSON vacated/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O prison/NN/O cell/NN/O had/VBD/O previously/RB/O contained/VBN/O commodity/NN/O operators/NNS/O Marc/NNP/B-PERSON Rich/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O ``/``/B-PERSON Pinky/NNP/I-PERSON ''/''/I-PERSON Green/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O today/NN/O fugitives/NNS/O from/IN/O a/DT/O potential/JJ/O century/NN/O apiece/RB/O of/IN/O jail/NN/O sentences/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Old/NNP/O Crowd/NNP/O is/VBZ/O deeply/RB/O concerned/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O backlash/NN/O from/IN/O all/PDT/O this/DT/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O phenomenon/NN/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O specifically/RB/O Jewish/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O always/RB/O been/VBN/O true/JJ/O that/IN/O those/DT/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O club/NN/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O climb/VB/O in/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O will/MD/O cut/VB/O corners/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O process/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Boesky/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O a/DT/O piker/NN/O compared/VBN/O to/TO/O Jay/NNP/B-PERSON Gould/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Fiske/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O and/CC/O Commodore/NNP/O Vanderbilt/NNP/B-PERSON thought/VBD/O nothing/NN/O of/IN/O bribing/VBG/O judges/NNS/O and/CC/O legislators/NNS/O ././O
So/RB/O who/WP/O knows/VBZ/O ?/./O
In/IN/O a/DT/O generation/NN/O or/CC/O two/CD/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/O Crowd/NNP/O may/MD/O attain/VB/O true/JJ/O respectability/NN/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O displaced/VBN/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O later/JJ/O flock/NN/O of/IN/O unscrupulous/JJ/O raptors/NNS/O ././O
Or/CC/O perhaps/RB/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O suffered/VBN/O enough/RB/O ,/,/O will/MD/O realize/VB/O that/DT/O finance/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O service/NN/O industry/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O change/VB/O its/PRP$/O ethos/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Train/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O president/NN/O of/IN/O Train/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/I-ORG Smith/NNP/I-ORG Investment/NNP/I-ORG Counsel/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ././O
