After/IN/O touring/VBG/O the/DT/O area/NN/O ,/,/O California/NNP/B-GPE Gov./NNP/O George/NNP/B-PERSON Deukmejian/NNP/I-PERSON late/RB/O yesterday/NN/O called/VBD/O for/IN/O an/DT/O inquiry/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O freeway/NN/O 's/POS/O collapse/NN/O ,/,/O blaming/VBG/O the/DT/O disaster/NN/O on/IN/O substandard/JJ/O construction/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Associated/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O ././O
Caltrans/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Sacramento/NNP/B-GPE said/VBD/O total/JJ/O damage/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O collapsed/JJ/O highway/NN/O is/VBZ/O estimated/VBN/O at/IN/O around/IN/O $/$/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
That/DT/O temblor/NN/O measured/VBD/O 6.1/CD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Richter/NNP/O scale/NN/O ;/:/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O was/VBD/O
So/RB/O why/WRB/O even/RB/O consider/VB/O stacking/VBG/O freeways/NNS/O now/RB/O ?/./O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O run/VBN/O out/RP/O of/IN/O places/NNS/O to/TO/O build/VB/O freeways/NNS/O in/IN/O L.A./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O place/NN/O to/TO/O go/VB/O is/VBZ/O up/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O O'Connell/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O although/IN/O he/PRP/O acknowledges/VBZ/O there/EX/O are/VBP/O many/JJ/O obstacles/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O cost/NN/O ././O
Reasons/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O collapse/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Nimitz/NNP/I-FAC Freeway/NNP/I-FAC were/VBD/O sketchy/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O most/RBS/O structural/JJ/O engineers/NNS/O attributed/VBD/O the/DT/O destruction/NN/O to/TO/O improper/JJ/O reinforcement/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O columns/NNS/O that/WDT/O supported/VBD/O the/DT/O decks/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ground/NN/O beneath/IN/O the/DT/O highway/NN/O is/VBZ/O largely/RB/O landfill/NN/O and/CC/O can/MD/O become/VB/O unstable/JJ/O ,/,/O or/CC/O ``/``/O liquefy/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O in/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O quake/NN/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O pillars/NNS/O did/VBD/O have/VB/O long/JJ/O metal/NN/O bars/NNS/O running/VBG/O vertically/RB/O through/IN/O them/PRP/O for/IN/O reinforcement/NN/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O apparently/RB/O lacked/VBD/O an/DT/O adequate/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O metal/NN/O ``/``/O ties/NNS/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O run/VBP/O horizontally/RB/O through/IN/O the/DT/O column/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Leo/NNP/B-PERSON Parker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O structural/JJ/O engineer/NN/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Caltrans/NNP/B-ORG today/NN/O uses/VBZ/O a/DT/O variation/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O design/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Parker/NNP/B-PERSON describes/VBZ/O ,/,/O with/IN/O spiraling/JJ/O steel/NN/O rods/NNS/O inside/RB/O ././O
Officials/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O agency/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O any/DT/O immediate/JJ/O explanation/NN/O why/WRB/O the/DT/O reinforcement/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O hold/VB/O up/RP/O ././O
Caltrans/NNP/B-ORG reinforced/VBD/O the/DT/O highway/NN/O in/IN/O 1977/CD/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 55/CD/O million/CD/O statewide/JJ/O project/NN/O ,/,/O using/VBG/O steel/NN/O cables/NNS/O to/TO/O tie/VB/O the/DT/O decks/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O freeway/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O columns/NNS/O and/CC/O prevent/VB/O the/DT/O structure/NN/O from/IN/O swaying/VBG/O in/IN/O a/DT/O quake/NN/O ././O
Caltrans/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O Jim/NNP/B-PERSON Drago/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Sacramento/NNP/B-GPE declined/VBD/O to/TO/O identify/VB/O the/DT/O engineering/NN/O firm/NN/O that/WDT/O did/VBD/O the/DT/O reinforcement/NN/O work/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O firm/NN/O brought/VBD/O in/RP/O to/TO/O strengthen/VB/O the/DT/O structure/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O liable/JJ/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O results/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O certainly/RB/O raise/VBP/O questions/NNS/O about/IN/O whether/IN/O reasonable/JJ/O care/NN/O was/VBD/O taken/VBN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Messina/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O ././O
Given/VBN/O the/DT/O seismic/JJ/O history/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC Area/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O ``/``/O it/PRP/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O that/IN/O a/DT/O 6.9/CD/O earthquake/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O foreseeable/JJ/O event/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Caltrans/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Drago/NNP/B-PERSON defended/VBD/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O work/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Nimitz/NNP/I-FAC Freeway/NNP/I-FAC ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O work/NN/O was/VBD/O done/VBN/O properly/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Basically/RB/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O had/VBD/O a/DT/O severe/JJ/O earthquake/NN/O of/IN/O significant/JJ/O duration/NN/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O just/RB/O something/NN/O the/DT/O structure/NN/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O withstand/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Ironically/RB/O ,/,/O Caltrans/NNP/B-ORG this/DT/O year/NN/O began/VBD/O working/VBG/O on/IN/O a/DT/O second/JJ/O round/NN/O of/IN/O seismic/JJ/O reinforcements/NNS/O of/IN/O freeways/NNS/O around/IN/O the/DT/O state/NN/O ,/,/O this/DT/O time/NN/O wrapping/VBG/O freeway/NN/O columns/NNS/O in/IN/O ``/``/O steel/NN/O blankets/NNS/O ''/''/O to/TO/O reinforce/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O only/RB/O bridges/NNS/O supported/VBN/O with/IN/O single/JJ/O rows/NNS/O of/IN/O columns/NNS/O were/VBD/O top/JJ/O priority/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-FAC Nimitz/NNP/I-FAC Freeway/NNP/I-FAC ,/,/O supported/VBN/O by/IN/O double/JJ/O rows/NNS/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O left/VBN/O out/RP/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Drago/NNP/B-PERSON explained/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O reason/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O the/DT/O technology/NN/O is/VBZ/O such/JJ/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O not/RB/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O retrofit/VB/O multi-column/JJ/O structures/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON McCoy/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O John/NNP/B-PERSON R./NNP/I-PERSON Emshwiller/NNP/I-PERSON in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
