A/O new/O drug/O to/O prevent/O the/O rejection/O of/O transplanted/O organs/O has/O been/O successfully/O used/O on/O more/O than/O 100/O patients/O at/O the/B-ORG University/I-ORG of/I-ORG Pittsburgh/I-ORG ,/O according/O to/O researchers/O ./O
But/O researchers/O say/O the/O drug/O ,/O called/O FK/O -/O 506/O ,/O could/O revolutionize/O the/O transplantation/O field/O by/O reducing/O harmful/O side/O effects/O and/O by/O lowering/O rejection/O rates/O ./O
The/O drug/O ,/O discovered/O in/O 1984/O ,/O is/O metabolized/O from/O soil/O fungus/O found/O in/O Japan/B-GPE ./O
The/O Pittsburgh/B-GPE patients/O are/O the/O first/O humans/O to/O be/O given/O the/O drug/O ,/O which/O is/O made/O by/O Fujisawa/B-ORG Pharmaceutical/I-ORG Co/I-ORG ./O
``/O We/O 're/O shocked/O by/O it/O ,/O because/O it/O 's/O worked/O so/O fast/O ,/O ''/O said/O Dr./O Thomas/B-PERSON E./I-PERSON Starzl/I-PERSON ,/O director/O of/O the/B-ORG University/I-ORG of/I-ORG Pittsburgh/I-ORG Transplantation/I-ORG Program/I-ORG ,/O at/O a/O news/O conference/O here/O yesterday/O ./O
They/O are/O also/O encouraged/O by/O the/O relatively/O mild/O side/O effects/O of/O FK/O -/O 506/O ,/O compared/O with/O cyclosporine/O ,/O which/O can/O cause/O renal/O failure/O ,/O morbidity/O ,/O nausea/O and/O other/O problems/O ./O
Researchers/O could/O n't/O estimate/O the/O cost/O of/O the/O drug/O when/O it/O reaches/O the/O market/O ,/O but/O they/O said/O FK/O -/O 506/O will/O enable/O patients/O to/O cut/O hospital/O stays/O by/O 50/O %/O and/O reduce/O the/O number/O of/O blood/O tests/O used/O to/O monitor/O the/O dosage/O of/O cyclosporine/O and/O other/O drugs/O among/O transplant/O recipients/O ./O
He/O said/O that/O the/O research/O team/O had/O no/O financial/O stake/O in/O the/O drug/O ./O
``/O We/O 've/O known/O for/O six/O months/O the/O effect/O of/O this/O drug/O ,/O and/O our/O advice/O to/O our/O people/O has/O been/O not/O to/O buy/O the/O company/O 's/O stock/O ,/O ''/O Dr./O Starzl/B-PERSON said/O ,/O adding/O that/O profiting/O from/O FK/O -/O 506/O would/O n't/O be/O ethical/O ./O
