Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Investors/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O reduced/VBD/O its/PRP$/O rating/NN/O on/IN/O $/$/O 281/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O senior/JJ/O and/CC/O subordinated/VBN/O debt/NN/O of/IN/O this/DT/O thrift/NN/O holding/VBG/O company/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O C/NNP/O from/IN/O Ca/NNP/O ,/,/O saying/VBG/O it/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O bondholders/NNS/O will/MD/O recover/VB/O only/RB/O ``/``/O negligible/JJ/O principal/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O confirmed/VBD/O American/NNP/B-ORG Continental/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG preferred/VBN/O stock/NN/O rating/NN/O at/IN/O C/NNP/O ././O
CENTRUST/NNP/B-ORG SAVINGS/NNP/I-ORG BANK/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O --/:/O
The/DT/O rating/NN/O agency/NN/O said/VBD/O about/RB/O $/$/O 85/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O securities/NNS/O was/VBD/O affected/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O downgrades/NNS/O were/VBD/O prompted/VBN/O ,/,/O Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG said/VBD/O ,/,/O by/IN/O the/DT/O continuing/VBG/O turmoil/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O junk/NN/O bond/NN/O market/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O suspension/NN/O of/IN/O dividends/NNS/O on/IN/O CenTrust/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG preferred/VBN/O stock/NN/O ././O
Moody/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG also/RB/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O believed/VBD/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O 63/CD/O CenTrust/NNP/B-ORG branches/NNS/O to/TO/O Great/JJ/B-ORG Western/NNP/I-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG could/MD/O ,/,/O if/IN/O completed/VBN/O ,/,/O endanger/VB/O the/DT/O thrift/NN/O 's/POS/O funding/NN/O and/CC/O market/NN/O position/NN/O ././O
