The/DT/O bill/NN/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O restrict/VB/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG borrowings/NNS/O only/RB/O ,/,/O unless/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O receives/VBZ/O specific/JJ/O congressional/JJ/O authorization/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O financing/NN/O system/NN/O was/VBD/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O law/NN/O in/IN/O order/NN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O bailout/NN/O spending/NN/O from/IN/O swelling/VBG/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O deficit/NN/O ././O
Another/DT/O $/$/O 20/CD/O billion/CD/O would/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O through/IN/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O pay/VBP/O lower/JJR/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O requires/VBZ/O ``/``/O working/NN/O ''/''/O capital/NN/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O the/DT/O bad/JJ/O assets/NNS/O of/IN/O thrifts/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O ,/,/O until/IN/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O can/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O separately/RB/O ././O
That/DT/O debt/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O paid/VBN/O off/RP/O as/IN/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O are/VBP/O sold/VBN/O ,/,/O leaving/VBG/O the/DT/O total/JJ/O spending/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O bailout/NN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 50/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O or/CC/O $/$/O 166/CD/O billion/CD/O including/VBG/O interest/NN/O over/IN/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O that/WDT/O clearly/RB/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O be/VB/O resolved/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Cooke/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O executive/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Absent/VB/O other/JJ/O working/NN/O capital/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O be/VB/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O delay/VB/O other/JJ/O thrift/NN/O resolutions/NNS/O until/IN/O cash/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O raised/VBN/O by/IN/O selling/VBG/O the/DT/O bad/JJ/O assets/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O wait/VB/O until/IN/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O collected/VBN/O on/IN/O those/DT/O assets/NNS/O before/IN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O move/VB/O forward/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O complicated/VBN/O language/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O new/JJ/O law/NN/O has/VBZ/O muddied/VBN/O the/DT/O fight/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O law/NN/O does/VBZ/O allow/VB/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O borrow/VB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG up/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 5/CD/O billion/CD/O at/IN/O any/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O total/JJ/O obligations/NNS/O may/MD/O not/RB/O exceed/VB/O $/$/O 50/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/DT/O figure/NN/O is/VBZ/O derived/VBN/O after/IN/O including/VBG/O notes/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O debt/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O subtracting/VBG/O from/IN/O it/PRP/O the/DT/O market/NN/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O assets/NNS/O the/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG holds/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O That/DT/O secrecy/NN/O leads/VBZ/O to/TO/O a/DT/O proposal/NN/O like/IN/O the/DT/O one/CD/O from/IN/O Ways/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Means/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O me/PRP/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O draconian/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O RTC/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O have/VB/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O a/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O prior/JJ/O consultation/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Hill/NNP/B-ORG if/IN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O that/DT/O kind/NN/O of/IN/O flexibility/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG Ways/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Means/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O hold/VB/O a/DT/O hearing/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O next/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O ././O
