Maxus/NNP/B-ORG Energy/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Dallas/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O discovered/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O oil/NN/O field/NN/O northeast/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O previously/RB/O discovered/VBN/O Intan/NNP/B-LOC Field/NNP/I-LOC in/IN/O the/DT/O southeast/JJ/O Sumatra/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/O of/IN/O Indonesia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Maxus/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O run/VB/O a/DT/O production/NN/O test/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O three/CD/O discovery/NN/O wells/NNS/O it/PRP/O drilled/VBD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O field/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O about/RB/O 1.6/CD/O miles/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Intan/NNP/I-LOC Field/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O because/IN/O the/DT/O wells/NNS/O are/VBP/O similar/JJ/O to/TO/O others/NNS/O drilled/VBN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O Intan/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O Widuri/NNP/B-LOC fields/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-LOC Intan/NNP/I-LOC Field/NNP/I-LOC has/VBZ/O estimated/VBN/O reserves/NNS/O of/IN/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-LOC Widuri/NNP/I-LOC Field/NNP/I-LOC has/VBZ/O estimated/VBN/O reserves/NNS/O of/IN/O 225/CD/O million/CD/O barrels/NNS/O ././O
Maxus/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O operator/NN/O and/CC/O owns/VBZ/O a/DT/O 56/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O field/NN/O ,/,/O called/VBD/O Northeast/NNP/B-LOC Intan/NNP/I-LOC ././O
