Gitano/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Regatta/NNP/B-ORG Sport/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O apparel/NN/O maker/NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O assumption/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 3/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O contingent/JJ/O debt/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O held/VBN/O by/IN/O Clifford/NNP/B-PERSON Parker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Regatta/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/JJ/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O manage/VB/O Regatta/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O operations/NNS/O under/IN/O Gitano/NNP/B-ORG ././O
In/IN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O Regatta/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O have/VB/O sales/NNS/O ``/``/O in/IN/O excess/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O ''/''/O and/CC/O will/MD/O show/VB/O a/DT/O profit/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Parker/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
This/DT/O fall/NN/O ,/,/O Gitano/NNP/B-ORG began/VBD/O manufacturing/VBG/O moderately/RB/O priced/VBN/O clothes/NNS/O aimed/VBN/O at/IN/O department/NN/O stores/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Gloria/NNP/B-ORG Vanderbilt/NNP/I-ORG trademark/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O Gitano/NNP/B-ORG recently/RB/O acquired/VBD/O ././O
