J.P./NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O signed/VBD/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O Builders/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/I-ORG Hardware/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O Nalcor/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Beverly/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O group/NN/O consists/VBZ/O of/IN/O Weslock/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O JPI/NNP/B-ORG Modern/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
J.P./NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Ann/NNP/B-GPE Arbor/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mich./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O completes/VBZ/O a/DT/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O program/NN/O to/TO/O divest/VB/O itself/PRP/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O hardware/NN/O and/CC/O plumbing/NN/O supplies/NNS/O operations/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O remaining/JJ/O business/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O manufacture/NN/O and/CC/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O engine/NN/O and/CC/O transmissions/NNS/O products/NNS/O for/IN/O industrial/JJ/O and/CC/O transportation/NN/O applications/NNS/O ././O
