There/EX/O 's/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O unusual/JJ/O about/IN/O business/NN/O groups/NNS/O pushing/VBG/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O government/NN/O spending/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O created/VBN/O in/IN/O 1943/CD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O organization/NN/O that/WDT/O made/VBD/O its/PRP$/O name/NN/O fighting/VBG/O a/DT/O Roosevelt/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O proposal/NN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O over/RP/O all/DT/O defense/NN/O housing/NN/O production/NN/O ././O
Yet/RB/O on/IN/O matters/NNS/O close/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O er/UH/O ,/,/O home/NN/O .../:/O
``/``/O The/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG budget/NN/O has/VBZ/O dropped/VBN/O by/IN/O more/JJ/O than/IN/O 70/CD/O %/NN/O since/IN/O 1980/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O argues/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Colton/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 've/VBP/O taken/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O our/PRP$/O fair/JJ/O share/NN/O ././O
I/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O a/DT/O problem/NN/O if/IN/O other/JJ/O programs/NNS/O had/VBD/O taken/VBN/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O hit/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG support/NN/O for/IN/O subsidies/NNS/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O housing/NN/O crunch/NN/O ;/:/O over/IN/O the/DT/O years/NNS/O the/DT/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O backed/VBN/O a/DT/O host/NN/O of/IN/O public/JJ/O programs/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O once/RB/O pushed/VBD/O for/IN/O a/DT/O national/JJ/O housing/NN/O production/NN/O goal/NN/O set/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O regularly/RB/O advanced/VBN/O anti-recession/JJ/O housing/NN/O measures/NNS/O ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O explains/VBZ/O one/CD/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG official/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG remains/VBZ/O susceptible/JJ/O to/TO/O internal/JJ/O pressure/NN/O from/IN/O members/NNS/O that/WDT/O specialize/VBP/O in/IN/O subsidized/VBN/O production/NN/O ././O
Indirect/JJ/O subsidies/NNS/O ,/,/O through/IN/O the/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O instance/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O little/RB/O better/JJR/O ././O
More/RBR/O important/JJ/O ,/,/O housing/NN/O programs/NNS/O run/VBN/O by/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O VA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O FmHA/NNP/B-ORG are/VBP/O awash/RB/O in/IN/O red/JJ/O ink/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG alone/RB/O lost/VBD/O $/$/O 4.2/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1988/CD/O ;/:/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O equity/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O ,/,/O essentially/RB/O its/PRP$/O reserve/NN/O fund/NN/O ,/,/O fell/VBD/O to/TO/O minus/IN/O $/$/O 2.9/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O pump/VB/O in/RP/O $/$/O 2.28/CD/O billion/CD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O VA/NNP/B-ORG housing/NN/O program/NN/O since/IN/O 1984/CD/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O fund/NN/O afloat/RB/O and/CC/O the/DT/O VA/NNP/B-ORG requested/VBD/O an/DT/O additional/JJ/O $/$/O 120/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O just/RB/O ended/VBD/O ././O
All/DT/O told/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O already/RB/O guarantees/VBZ/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 900/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O mortgages/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O its/PRP$/O nicely/RB/O produced/VBN/O publication/NN/O ``/``/O Where/WRB/O Will/MD/O Our/PRP$/O Children/NNS/O Live/VB/O ?/./O ''/''/O the/DT/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG does/VBZ/O acknowledge/VB/O that/IN/O ``/``/O of/IN/O course/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O housing/NN/O affordability/NN/O can/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O provided/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
But/CC/O while/IN/O the/DT/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O suggested/VBN/O actions/NNS/O that/IN/O states/NNS/O and/CC/O localities/NNS/O should/MD/O take/VB/O to/TO/O reduce/VB/O regulatory/JJ/O barriers/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O association/NN/O has/VBZ/O proposed/VBN/O no/DT/O activist/JJ/O legislative/JJ/O program/NN/O --/:/O comparable/JJ/O to/TO/O ,/,/O say/VB/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O detailed/VBN/O request/NN/O for/IN/O more/JJR/O federal/JJ/O subsidies/NNS/O --/:/O to/TO/O eliminate/VB/O counterproductive/JJ/O controls/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O association/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O whose/WP$/O 156,000/CD/O members/NNS/O build/VBP/O fewer/JJR/O than/IN/O 25/CD/O units/NNS/O a/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O like/IN/O many/JJ/O other/JJ/O business/NN/O lobbies/NNS/O ././O
Explains/VBZ/O Sheila/NNP/B-PERSON MacDonald/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Taxpayers/NNP/I-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG :/:/O ``/``/O It/PRP/O treads/VBZ/O in/IN/O two/CD/O worlds/NNS/O ././O
Unfortunately/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O organization/NN/O 's/POS/O desire/NN/O for/IN/O pork/NN/O tends/VBZ/O to/TO/O override/VB/O its/PRP$/O commitment/NN/O to/TO/O overall/JJ/O fiscal/JJ/O responsibility/NN/O ././O
Two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG lobbied/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O $/$/O 19/CD/O billion/CD/O omnibus/NN/O housing/NN/O bill/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O organization/NN/O ``/``/O basically/RB/O dropped/VBD/O out/RP/O of/IN/O the/DT/O taxpayers/NNS/O '/POS/O coalition/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Ms./NNP/O MacDonald/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
As/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Colton/NNP/B-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/O NAHB/NNP/B-ORG acknowledges/VBZ/O :/:/O ``/``/O Government/NNP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O solve/VB/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O .../:/O ././O
The/DT/O real/JJ/O key/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O working/VBG/O and/CC/O interest/NN/O rates/NNS/O down/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
More/JJR/O money/NN/O for/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O deficit/NN/O and/CC/O destabilize/VB/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O ;/:/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O to/TO/O municipalities/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O wrecking/VBG/O their/PRP$/O local/JJ/O housing/NN/O markets/NNS/O will/MD/O further/RBR/O insulate/VB/O them/PRP/O from/IN/O the/DT/O destructive/JJ/O effects/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O policies/NNS/O ././O
Is/VBZ/O this/DT/O what/WP/O the/DT/O home/NN/O builders/NNS/O want/VBP/O ?/./O
Mr./NNP/O Bandow/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O a/DT/O Cato/NNP/B-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG fellow/NN/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O See/VB/O related/VBN/O story/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O And/CC/O Bills/NNS/O to/TO/O Make/VB/O Wishes/NNS/O Come/VB/O True/JJ/O ''/''/O --/:/O WSJ/NNP/B-ORG Oct./NNP/O 17/CD/O ,/,/O 1989/CD/O ././O
