A/DT/O UNIFIED/JJ/O EUROPE/NNP/B-LOC poses/VBZ/O labor/NN/O problems/NNS/O and/CC/O prospects/NNS/O for/IN/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE firms/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O ``/``/O social/JJ/O dimension/NN/O ''/''/O --/:/O worker/NN/O concerns/NNS/O --/:/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG plan/NN/O to/TO/O open/VB/O its/PRP$/O internal/JJ/O borders/NNS/O in/IN/O 1992/CD/O could/MD/O set/VB/O the/DT/O effort/NN/O ``/``/O off/IN/O the/DT/O rails/NNS/O ''/''/O if/IN/O not/RB/O done/VBN/O reasonably/RB/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG senior/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Doyle/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
U.S./NNP/B-GPE companies/NNS/O wanting/VBG/O to/TO/O expand/VB/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC face/VBP/O ``/``/O tough/JJ/O pressure/NN/O ''/''/O from/IN/O unions/NNS/O in/IN/O nations/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O which/WDT/O play/VBP/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O consulting/NN/O role/NN/O in/IN/O management/NN/O decisions/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ././O
FMC/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Baxter/NNP/B-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG say/VBP/O unions/NNS/O also/RB/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O like/VB/O plant/NN/O relocations/NNS/O and/CC/O needed/VBN/O restructuring/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O means/VBZ/O layoffs/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O employers/NNS/O have/VBP/O already/RB/O begun/VBN/O moving/VBG/O to/TO/O southern/JJ/O countries/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O wages/NNS/O are/VBP/O low/JJ/O and/CC/O unions/NNS/O are/VBP/O weaker/JJR/O ;/:/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O trained/VBN/O labor/NN/O and/CC/O managers/NNS/O will/MD/O rise/VB/O there/RB/O ,/,/O FMC/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O ././O
Pfizer/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Fluor/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O GE/NNP/B-ORG see/VBP/O big/JJ/O ``/``/O EC/NNP/B-ORG 92/CD/O ''/''/O pluses/NNS/O :/:/O a/DT/O push/NN/O for/IN/O job/NN/O training/NN/O and/CC/O ease/NN/O in/IN/O moving/VBG/O and/CC/O finding/VBG/O workers/NNS/O ././O
CLUBBING/VBG/O A/DT/O FAN/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O Baltimore/NNP/B-GPE Orioles/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O fault/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O players/NNS/O were/VBD/O heckled/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O patron/NN/O during/IN/O a/DT/O July/NNP/O 4/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O game/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Martinsville/NNP/B-GPE Phillies/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O fan/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O punched/VBN/O and/CC/O kicked/VBN/O by/IN/O one/CD/O player/NN/O and/CC/O that/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O broke/VBD/O his/PRP$/O jaw/NN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O baseball/NN/O bat/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O dismissed/VBD/O the/DT/O fan/NN/O 's/POS/O suit/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O team/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O ruling/VBG/O the/DT/O Orioles/NNP/B-ORG innocent/JJ/O of/IN/O negligent/JJ/O hiring/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O not/RB/O responsible/JJ/O for/IN/O a/DT/O fight/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O outside/IN/O the/DT/O players/NNS/O '/POS/O employment/NN/O ././O
PROPOSALS/NNS/O ARISE/VBP/O for/IN/O coping/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O shortage/NN/O of/IN/O nurses/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O Association/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Academic/NNP/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Centers/NNP/I-ORG report/NN/O urges/VBZ/O freeing/VBG/O nurses/NNS/O from/IN/O duties/NNS/O that/WDT/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O require/VB/O special/JJ/O skills/NNS/O ././O
MRA/NNP/B-ORG Staffing/NNP/I-ORG Systems/NNP/I-ORG signs/VBZ/O up/RP/O nurses/NNS/O for/IN/O paid/VBN/O travel/NN/O ,/,/O promising/VBG/O annual/JJ/O income/NN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 50,000/CD/O and/CC/O free/JJ/O or/CC/O subsidized/VBN/O housing/NN/O ././O
TREATING/VBG/O EMPLOYEES/NNS/O with/IN/O respect/NN/O is/VBZ/O crucial/JJ/O for/IN/O managers/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O consultant/NN/O Hay/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG after/IN/O surveys/NNS/O of/IN/O a/DT/O million/CD/O workers/NNS/O ././O
SPRUCING/VBG/O UP/RP/O THE/DT/O DIGS/NNS/O :/:/O About/RB/O 200/CD/O employees/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Maryland/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Economic/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Employment/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O four/CD/O months/NNS/O painted/VBD/O walls/NNS/O ,/,/O polished/VBD/O and/CC/O carpeted/VBD/O floors/NNS/O ,/,/O bought/VBD/O plants/NNS/O ,/,/O cleaned/VBD/O windows/NNS/O and/CC/O blinds/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O hung/VBD/O pictures/NNS/O at/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O Baltimore/NNP/B-GPE office/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O 3,000/CD/O hours/NNS/O of/IN/O work/NN/O will/MD/O save/VB/O the/DT/O state/NN/O $/$/O 55,000/CD/O ././O
CURBING/VBG/O WAGE/NN/O BOOSTS/NNS/O will/MD/O get/VB/O high/JJ/O priority/NN/O again/RB/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O collective/JJ/O bargaining/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Bureau/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Affairs/NNP/I-ORG survey/NN/O of/IN/O 250/CD/O companies/NNS/O with/IN/O pacts/NNS/O expiring/VBG/O next/JJ/O year/NN/O indicates/VBZ/O ././O
A/DT/O third/JJ/O of/IN/O 439/CD/O companies/NNS/O surveyed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Employee/NNP/I-ORG Relocation/NNP/I-ORG Council/NNP/I-ORG report/VBP/O a/DT/O rise/NN/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O sales/NNS/O losses/NNS/O over/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
RJR/NNP/B-ORG Nabisco/NNP/I-ORG pays/VBZ/O up/IN/O to/TO/O $/$/O 30,000/CD/O of/IN/O losses/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O improvements/NNS/O ././O
Goodrich/NNP/B-ORG wo/MD/O n't/RB/O ensure/VB/O loss/NN/O coverage/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O will/MD/O prevent/VB/O a/DT/O ``/``/O catastrophic/JJ/O loss/NN/O ''/''/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O given/VBN/O some/DT/O employees/NNS/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O purchase/NN/O price/NN/O when/WRB/O values/NNS/O fell/VBD/O from/IN/O concern/NN/O over/IN/O dangers/NNS/O posed/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O disposal/NN/O site/NN/O ././O
Federal/NNP/B-ORG Express/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Ford/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O National/NNP/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG will/MD/O buy/VB/O the/DT/O home/NN/O or/CC/O let/VB/O the/DT/O worker/NN/O sell/VB/O to/TO/O an/DT/O outside/JJ/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O usually/RB/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O cover/VB/O a/DT/O loss/NN/O ././O
THE/DT/O CHECKOFF/NN/O :/:/O The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Academy/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Engineering/NNP/I-ORG gives/VBZ/O two/CD/O inventors/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O semiconductor/NN/O microchip/NN/O a/DT/O $/$/O 350,000/CD/O achievement/NN/O award/NN/O .../:/O ././O
