The/DT/O restrictions/NNS/O would/MD/O cover/VB/O all/DT/O but/CC/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O domestic/JJ/O air/NN/O traffic/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O represent/VB/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O expansion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O smoking/NN/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O flights/NNS/O of/IN/O two/CD/O hours/NNS/O or/CC/O less/JJR/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O practical/JJ/O matter/NN/O ,/,/O flights/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC West/NNP/I-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC to/TO/O Hawaii/NNP/B-GPE would/MD/O be/VB/O covered/VBN/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O under/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O limit/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O language/NN/O would/MD/O exempt/VB/O longer/JJR/O routes/NNS/O beginning/VBG/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC Coast/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Within/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O ban/NN/O has/VBZ/O had/VBD/O aggressive/JJ/O support/NN/O from/IN/O Sen./NNP/O Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lautenberg/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O used/VBN/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG Appropriations/NNP/I-ORG subcommittee/NN/O chairman/NN/O to/TO/O garner/VB/O votes/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O initiative/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O is/VBZ/O attached/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 26/CD/O billion/CD/O fiscal/JJ/O 1990/CD/O transportation/NN/O bill/NN/O within/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Lautenberg/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O jurisdiction/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O compromise/NN/O is/VBZ/O laced/VBN/O with/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 205/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O road/NN/O projects/NNS/O earmarked/VBN/O by/IN/O members/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O funds/NNS/O sought/VBD/O by/IN/O major/JJ/O airports/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ././O
From/IN/O the/DT/O outset/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O tobacco/NN/O industry/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O uncertain/JJ/O as/IN/O to/TO/O what/WP/O strategy/NN/O to/TO/O follow/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O retains/VBZ/O support/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG leadership/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O influence/NN/O of/IN/O grower/NN/O states/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O North/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Majority/NNP/O Whip/NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Gray/NNP/I-PERSON owes/VBZ/O a/DT/O political/JJ/O debt/NN/O to/TO/O Southern/JJ/O agriculture/NN/O lawmakers/NNS/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O rise/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE Democrat/NNP/O used/VBD/O his/PRP$/O position/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O to/TO/O salvage/VB/O the/DT/O exemption/NN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O total/JJ/O ban/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O stark/JJ/O lesson/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O power/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O appropriations/NNS/O committees/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG deliberately/RB/O killed/VBD/O a/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O projects/NNS/O backed/VBN/O by/IN/O lawmakers/NNS/O in/IN/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Illinois/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Pennsylvania/NNP/B-GPE who/WP/O had/VBD/O voted/VBN/O against/IN/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O leadership/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG floor/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Anybody/NN/O can/MD/O vote/VB/O as/IN/O they/PRP/O want/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Rep./NNP/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Lehman/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Fla./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG conferees/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O But/CC/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O make/VBP/O a/DT/O request/NN/O ,/,/O you/PRP/O should/MD/O support/VB/O the/DT/O committee/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Within/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Aviation/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O final/JJ/O bill/NN/O promises/VBZ/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O spending/NN/O for/IN/O facilities/NNS/O and/CC/O equipment/NN/O by/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 20/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O total/JJ/O operations/NNS/O would/MD/O rise/VB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 3.84/CD/O billion/CD/O --/:/O a/DT/O 12/CD/O %/NN/O boost/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O facilities/NNS/O account/NN/O includes/VBZ/O $/$/O 40/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O ambitious/JJ/O new/JJ/O airport/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O competition/NN/O for/IN/O these/DT/O funds/NNS/O created/VBD/O shifting/VBG/O alliances/NNS/O between/IN/O urban/JJ/O lawmakers/NNS/O representing/VBG/O established/VBN/O airports/NNS/O in/IN/O Philadelphia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Michigan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O carriers/NNS/O to/TO/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O United/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Continental/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Leery/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O --/:/O and/CC/O ,/,/O critics/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O competition/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O airlines/NNS/O have/VBP/O sought/VBN/O to/TO/O gain/VB/O leverage/NN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O of/IN/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Texas/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O Continental/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Transport/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG were/VBD/O prominent/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O lobbying/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O industry/NN/O sought/VBD/O to/TO/O impose/VB/O conditions/NNS/O that/WDT/O would/MD/O have/VB/O delayed/VBN/O funds/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O project/NN/O until/IN/O Denver/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O airlines/NNS/O had/VBD/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O leases/NNS/O for/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O gates/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O this/DT/O was/VBD/O rejected/VBN/O in/IN/O favor/NN/O of/IN/O much/RB/O looser/JJR/O language/NN/O directing/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O review/VB/O the/DT/O costs/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O phase/NN/O ,/,/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O cost/VB/O about/RB/O $/$/O 2/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Though/IN/O smaller/JJR/O in/IN/O total/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O preserve/VB/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 30.6/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O controversial/JJ/O subsidies/NNS/O to/TO/O carriers/NNS/O serving/VBG/O rural/JJ/O or/CC/O isolated/VBN/O airports/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O sum/NN/O is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O double/RB/O what/WP/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O approved/VBN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O qualified/VBN/O airports/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O by/IN/O 22/CD/O under/IN/O new/JJ/O distance/NN/O requirements/NNS/O and/CC/O limits/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O level/NN/O of/IN/O subsidy/NN/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG previously/RB/O cut/VBD/O six/CD/O airports/NNS/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O impact/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O changes/NNS/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O eliminate/VB/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O excessive/JJ/O cases/NNS/O where/WRB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O paying/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O for/IN/O each/DT/O passenger/NN/O in/IN/O subsidies/NNS/O ././O
Among/IN/O rail/NN/O and/CC/O highway/NN/O accounts/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O provides/VBZ/O $/$/O 615/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O Amtrak/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O including/VBG/O $/$/O 85/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O capital/NN/O improvements/NNS/O ././O
