Included/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O are/VBP/O Cluett/NNP/B-ORG units/NNS/O that/WDT/O make/VBP/O men/NNS/O 's/POS/O shirts/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Arrow/NNP/B-ORG name/NN/O ,/,/O socks/NNS/O under/IN/O the/DT/O Gold/NNP/B-ORG Toe/NNP/I-ORG name/NN/O and/CC/O menswear/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O Schoeneman/NNP/B-ORG division/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O companies/NNS/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O Bidermann/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O receipt/NN/O of/IN/O financing/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O regulatory/JJ/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O approvals/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O concluded/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O end/NN/O of/IN/O November/NNP/O ././O
He/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O elaborate/VB/O on/IN/O other/JJ/O asset/NN/O sales/NNS/O being/VBG/O considered/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Farley/NNP/B-PERSON followed/VBD/O a/DT/O similar/JJ/O pattern/NN/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O acquired/VBD/O Northwest/NNP/B-ORG Industries/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O then/RB/O sold/VBN/O much/JJ/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O assets/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O kept/VBD/O Fruit/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Loom/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O underwear/NN/O maker/NN/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O still/RB/O controls/VBZ/O and/CC/O serves/VBZ/O as/IN/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O year/NN/O ended/VBN/O Sept./NNP/O 30/CD/O ,/,/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O Cluett/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 37/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 757/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Bidermann/NNP/B-ORG sells/VBZ/O clothes/NNS/O under/IN/O various/JJ/O labels/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Yves/NNP/B-ORG Saint/NNP/I-ORG Laurent/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Bill/NNP/B-ORG Robinson/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O men/NNS/O and/CC/O Ralph/NNP/B-ORG Lauren/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O women/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O company/NN/O had/VBD/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O $/$/O 400/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
