In/IN/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O give/VB/O new/JJ/O momentum/NN/O to/TO/O European/NNP/B-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG plans/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O currency/NN/O ,/,/O EC/NNP/B-ORG government/NN/O leaders/NNS/O are/VBP/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O set/VB/O a/DT/O date/NN/O for/IN/O starting/VBG/O formal/JJ/O talks/NNS/O on/IN/O amending/VBG/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O founding/NN/O Treaty/NNP/O of/IN/O Rome/NNP/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O diplomatic/JJ/O sources/NNS/O in/IN/O Brussels/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O most/JJS/O EC/NNP/B-ORG leaders/NNS/O agree/VBP/O that/IN/O talks/NNS/O should/MD/O begin/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O half/NN/O of/IN/O 1990/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O will/MD/O make/VB/O a/DT/O declaration/NN/O on/IN/O that/DT/O during/IN/O a/DT/O summit/NN/O meeting/NN/O in/IN/O Strasbourg/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O on/IN/O Dec./NNP/O 8/CD/O and/CC/O 9/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O only/JJ/O strong/JJ/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O changing/VBG/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG treaty/NN/O comes/VBZ/O from/IN/O British/NNP/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Margaret/NNP/B-PERSON Thatcher/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O opposed/VBN/O to/TO/O creating/VBG/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O EC/NNP/B-ORG currency/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O convening/VBG/O the/DT/O intergovernmental/JJ/O conference/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O require/VB/O unanimity/NN/O ././O
Setting/VBG/O a/DT/O date/NN/O to/TO/O start/VB/O treaty/NN/O negotiations/NNS/O has/VBZ/O no/DT/O legal/JJ/O significance/NN/O in/IN/O itself/PRP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O could/MD/O be/VB/O viewed/VBN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O psychological/JJ/O push/NN/O ././O
French/NNP/O President/NNP/O Francois/NNP/B-PERSON Mitterrand/NNP/I-PERSON fought/VBD/O to/TO/O set/VB/O a/DT/O date/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG summit/NN/O in/IN/O Madrid/NNP/B-GPE last/JJ/O June/NNP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O move/NN/O was/VBD/O scuttled/VBN/O because/RB/O of/IN/O opposition/NN/O by/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Thatcher/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O West/NNP/O German/NNP/O Chancellor/NNP/O Helmut/NNP/B-PERSON Kohl/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Diplomatic/JJ/O sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Kohl/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O now/RB/O agree/VB/O to/TO/O set/VB/O a/DT/O date/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O conference/NN/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O clear/JJ/O that/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O still/RB/O committed/VBN/O to/TO/O EC/NNP/B-ORG unity/NN/O ././O
