The/DT/O collapsed/VBN/O plan/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O UAL/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O spurred/VBD/O quick/JJ/O action/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O ,/,/O introduced/VBD/O Wednesday/NNP/O and/CC/O approved/VBD/O by/IN/O the/DT/O subcommittee/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O voice/NN/O vote/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O taken/VBN/O up/RP/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG Works/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG tomorrow/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O floor/NN/O vote/NN/O by/IN/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O urged/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O measure/NN/O drew/VBD/O criticism/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O parting/VBG/O shot/NN/O from/IN/O financier/NN/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Trump/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O yesterday/NN/O withdrew/VBD/O his/PRP$/O takeover/NN/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O subcommittee/NN/O Chairman/NNP/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Oberstar/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Minn./NNP/B-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Trump/NNP/B-PERSON criticized/VBD/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O as/IN/O an/DT/O explicit/JJ/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O thwart/VB/O his/PRP$/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O collapse/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O ././O
Elaine/NNP/B-PERSON Chao/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O deputy/NN/O transportation/NN/O secretary/NN/O ,/,/O also/RB/O sent/VBD/O a/DT/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O express/VB/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O opposition/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O bill/NN/O ``/``/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O present/JJ/O form/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Rep./NNP/O Oberstar/NNP/B-PERSON brushed/VBD/O off/RP/O Mr./NNP/O Trump/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O allegations/NNS/O as/IN/O an/DT/O ``/``/O excuse/NN/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O deal/NN/O failing/VBG/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O letter/NN/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O come/VBN/O from/IN/O Transportation/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Samuel/NNP/B-PERSON Skinner/NNP/I-PERSON indicated/VBD/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O wiggle/NN/O room/NN/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O administration/NN/O 's/POS/O position/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Oberstar/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O other/JJ/O committee/NN/O members/NNS/O repeatedly/RB/O stressed/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O a/DT/O response/NN/O to/TO/O any/DT/O particular/JJ/O market/NN/O situation/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O cited/VBD/O the/DT/O UAL/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG examples/NNS/O as/IN/O reasons/NNS/O to/TO/O move/VB/O quickly/RB/O to/TO/O enact/VB/O this/DT/O legislation/NN/O ././O
Aides/NNS/O both/DT/O in/IN/O the/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O withdrawal/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Trump/NNP/B-PERSON bid/NN/O for/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O deflate/VB/O efforts/NNS/O to/TO/O push/VB/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O still/RB/O on/IN/O the/DT/O fast/JJ/O track/NN/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O still/RB/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O one/CD/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG aide/NN/O ././O
Currently/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O transportation/NN/O secretary/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O have/VB/O clearly/RB/O established/VBN/O authority/NN/O to/TO/O block/NN/O mergers/NNS/O ,/,/O but/CC/O can/MD/O take/VB/O the/DT/O drastic/JJ/O step/NN/O of/IN/O revoking/VBG/O the/DT/O operating/NN/O certificate/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O carrier/NN/O the/DT/O official/NN/O considers/VBZ/O unfit/JJ/O ././O
It/PRP/O also/RB/O would/MD/O require/VB/O the/DT/O acquiring/VBG/O party/NN/O to/TO/O notify/VB/O the/DT/O transportation/NN/O secretary/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O all/DT/O information/NN/O relevant/JJ/O to/TO/O determining/VBG/O the/DT/O intent/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O more/JJR/O information/NN/O is/VBZ/O needed/VBN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O secretary/NN/O would/MD/O have/VB/O authority/NN/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O the/DT/O review/NN/O period/NN/O 20/CD/O days/NNS/O ././O
