Agip/NNP/B-ORG S.p/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG A./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Societe/NNP/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Elf/NNP/I-ORG Aquitaine/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O state/NN/O oil/NN/O companies/NNS/O of/IN/O Italy/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O respectively/RB/O ,/,/O submitted/VBD/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O Gatoil/NNP/B-ORG Suisse/NNP/I-ORG S.A/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O price/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O Gatoil/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Swiss/NNP/O oil/NN/O concern/NN/O was/VBD/O examining/VBG/O the/DT/O offer/NN/O ,/,/O submitted/VBD/O last/JJ/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O offers/NNS/O ,/,/O also/RB/O submitted/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
Those/DT/O two/CD/O offers/NNS/O were/VBD/O private/JJ/O and/CC/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O identify/VB/O the/DT/O bidding/VBG/O companies/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O spokesman/NN/O further/RBR/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O two/CD/O more/JJR/O offers/NNS/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O from/IN/O other/JJ/O companies/NNS/O within/IN/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
Gatoil/NNP/B-ORG Suisse/NNP/I-ORG owns/VBZ/O an/DT/O oil/NN/O refinery/NN/O in/IN/O Switzerland/NNP/B-GPE with/IN/O a/DT/O capacity/NN/O of/IN/O 70,000/CD/O barrels/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O along/IN/O with/IN/O a/DT/O network/NN/O of/IN/O gasoline/NN/O retailing/VBG/O outlets/NNS/O ././O
