Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Park/NNP/B-GPE Ridge/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O retained/VBD/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Rental/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O pressing/VBG/O need/NN/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O doing/VBG/O it/PRP/O so/IN/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O concentrate/VB/O on/IN/O our/PRP$/O core/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O renting/VBG/O automobiles/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O abroad/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O William/NNP/B-PERSON Slider/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Hertz/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O executive/JJ/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O are/VBP/O only/RB/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O at/IN/O the/DT/O right/JJ/O price/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O before/IN/O depreciation/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 90/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O supplier/NN/O of/IN/O rental/JJ/O equipment/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O U.K/NNP/B-GPE ././O
