In/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O prelude/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O resumption/NN/O of/IN/O talks/NNS/O between/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O striking/VBG/O Machinists/NNS/B-ORG union/NN/O members/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O federal/JJ/O mediator/NN/O said/VBD/O representatives/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O sides/NNS/O will/MD/O meet/VB/O with/IN/O him/PRP/O tomorrow/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O could/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O meeting/NN/O or/CC/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O short/JJ/O one/CD/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Doug/NNP/B-PERSON Hammond/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O mediator/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O called/VBD/O the/DT/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O a/DT/O first/JJ/O step/NN/O toward/IN/O a/DT/O resumption/NN/O of/IN/O negotiations/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O encouraged/VBN/O that/IN/O talks/NNS/O are/VBP/O scheduled/VBN/O again/RB/O but/CC/O beyond/IN/O that/DT/O ,/,/O we/PRP/O have/VBP/O made/VBN/O no/DT/O expression/NN/O of/IN/O expectations/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Boeing/VBG/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Currently/RB/O ,/,/O average/JJ/O pay/NN/O for/IN/O machinists/NNS/O is/VBZ/O $/$/O 13.39/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O ,/,/O Boeing/VBG/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Now/RB/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O 13th/JJ/O day/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O strike/NN/O has/VBZ/O idled/VBN/O about/RB/O 55,000/CD/O machinists/NNS/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O started/VBN/O to/TO/O delay/VB/O delivery/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O jetliners/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O a/DT/O strike/NN/O fund/NN/O of/IN/O about/RB/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O union/NN/O had/VBD/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O prepared/VBN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O strike/NN/O ././O
After/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O week/NN/O on/IN/O strike/NN/O ,/,/O union/NN/O members/NNS/O will/MD/O begin/VB/O receiving/VBG/O $/$/O 100/CD/O a/DT/O week/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O fund/NN/O ././O
Work/NN/O at/IN/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG continues/VBZ/O with/IN/O supervisors/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O non-striking/JJ/O personnel/NNS/O manning/VBG/O the/DT/O lines/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O at/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O Wichita/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Kan./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O plant/NN/O ,/,/O about/RB/O 2,400/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O 11,700/CD/O machinists/NNS/O still/RB/O are/VBP/O working/VBG/O ,/,/O Boeing/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
Boeing/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O declined/VBN/O to/TO/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O many/JJ/O employees/NNS/O are/VBP/O working/VBG/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O giant/JJ/O Renton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wash./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O plant/NN/O ././O
Union/NN/O officials/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
