For/IN/O the/DT/O moment/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O ,/,/O euphoria/NN/O has/VBZ/O replaced/VBN/O anxiety/NN/O on/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O ././O
Among/IN/O those/DT/O sighing/VBG/O with/IN/O relief/NN/O was/VBD/O John/NNP/B-PERSON H./NNP/I-PERSON Gutfreund/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O Salomon/NNP/B-ORG Brothers/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O who/WP/O took/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O 's/POS/O trading/NN/O floor/NN/O to/TO/O monitor/VB/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O events/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O the/DT/O rally/NN/O gained/VBD/O strength/NN/O at/IN/O 3:15/CD/O p.m./NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O smiled/VBD/O broadly/RB/O ,/,/O brandished/VBD/O his/PRP$/O unlit/NN/O cigar/NN/O and/CC/O slapped/VBD/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON Shopkorn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O his/PRP$/O top/JJ/O stock/NN/O trader/NN/O ,/,/O on/IN/O the/DT/O back/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O first/JJ/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O seemed/VBD/O as/IN/O if/IN/O history/NN/O might/MD/O repeat/VB/O itself/PRP/O ././O
As/IN/O trading/NN/O opened/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O morning/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O stocks/NNS/O of/IN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O biggest/JJS/O companies/NNS/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O open/VB/O for/IN/O trading/NN/O because/IN/O a/DT/O wave/NN/O of/IN/O sell/NN/O orders/NNS/O was/VBD/O overwhelming/VBG/O buyers/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O 10:10/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Dow/NNP/I-ORG Industrials/NNP/I-ORG were/VBD/O off/JJ/O 63.52/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O of/IN/O UAL/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O troubles/NNS/O had/VBD/O kicked/VBN/O off/RP/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O plunge/NN/O ,/,/O still/RB/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O opened/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O then/RB/O ,/,/O as/RB/O quickly/RB/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O fallen/VBN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O began/VBD/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O around/RP/O ././O
It/PRP/O ended/VBD/O with/IN/O a/DT/O gain/NN/O of/IN/O 88.12/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O close/NN/O ,/,/O volume/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE exchange/NN/O totaled/VBD/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 416/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O fourth/JJ/O highest/JJS/O on/IN/O record/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG handled/VBD/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O volume/NN/O without/IN/O any/DT/O obvious/JJ/O strain/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O sharp/JJ/O contrast/NN/O to/TO/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O of/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
Overall/JJ/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG stocks/NNS/O lost/VBD/O money/NN/O than/IN/O gained/VBN/O ././O
And/CC/O many/JJ/O arbitragers/NNS/O ,/,/O already/RB/O reeling/VBG/O from/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O collapse/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O UAL/NNP/B-ORG deal/NN/O ,/,/O were/VBD/O further/RBR/O hurt/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O proposed/VBN/O takeover/NN/O of/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O parent/NN/O of/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O collapsed/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE stock/NN/O exchange/NN/O was/VBD/O hardest/RBS/O hit/VBN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O blue/JJ/O chips/NNS/O there/RB/O falling/VBG/O 12.8/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O midday/NN/O rally/NN/O left/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O major/JJ/O index/NN/O off/IN/O 3.2/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O leading/VBG/O stock/NN/O index/NN/O fell/VBD/O only/RB/O 1.8/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O surprisingly/RB/O lackluster/NN/O trading/NN/O ././O
Investors/NNS/O big/JJ/O and/CC/O small/JJ/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O learned/VBD/O valuable/JJ/O lessons/NNS/O since/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O :/:/O In/IN/O this/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O computerized/VBN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O huge/JJ/O corrections/NNS/O or/CC/O runups/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O hours/NNS/O '/POS/O time/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O expected/VBN/O ././O
Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Boesel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O money/NN/O manager/NN/O for/IN/O T./NNP/B-ORG Rowe/NNP/I-ORG Price/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Baltimore/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O There/EX/O was/VBD/O less/JJR/O panic/NN/O than/IN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O :/:/O We/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O through/IN/O it/PRP/O once/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Many/JJ/O other/JJ/O factors/NNS/O played/VBD/O a/DT/O part/NN/O in/IN/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O comeback/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG signaled/VBD/O its/PRP$/O willingness/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O liquidity/NN/O ;/:/O the/DT/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O major/JJ/O banks/NNS/O inched/VBD/O downward/RB/O early/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
Foreign/JJ/O stock/NN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O kicked/VBD/O off/RP/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O selling/NN/O spree/NN/O ,/,/O began/VBD/O the/DT/O day/NN/O off/JJ/O by/IN/O relatively/RB/O modest/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O falling/VBG/O sharply/RB/O in/IN/O overnight/JJ/O trading/NN/O to/TO/O 139.10/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O bounced/VBD/O back/RB/O strongly/RB/O to/TO/O 141.8/CD/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O easing/VBG/O fears/NNS/O that/IN/O foreigners/NNS/O would/MD/O unload/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE stocks/NNS/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O widely/RB/O disseminated/VBN/O opinion/NN/O among/IN/O most/JJS/O market/NN/O experts/NNS/O that/IN/O a/DT/O crash/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O in/IN/O store/NN/O also/RB/O helped/VBD/O calm/VB/O investors/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O major/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O came/VBD/O into/IN/O work/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O blue/JJ/O chips/NNS/O they/PRP/O felt/VBD/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O sharply/RB/O undervalued/VBN/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O amid/IN/O all/DT/O the/DT/O backslapping/VBG/O and/CC/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O relief/NN/O over/IN/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O events/NNS/O ,/,/O some/DT/O market/NN/O professionals/NNS/O cautioned/VBD/O that/IN/O there/EX/O is/VBZ/O nothing/NN/O present/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O market/NN/O system/NN/O to/TO/O prevent/VB/O another/DT/O dizzying/JJ/O drop/NN/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O is/VBZ/O too/RB/O much/JJ/O complacency/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O money/NN/O manager/NN/O Barry/NNP/B-PERSON Schrager/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
The/DT/O average/NN/O plunged/VBD/O some/DT/O 600/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 1.7/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O 20/CD/O minutes/NNS/O of/IN/O trading/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O selling/NN/O wave/NN/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O conviction/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O market/NN/O first/RB/O surged/VBD/O upward/RB/O by/IN/O 200/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O then/RB/O drifted/VBD/O lower/RBR/O ,/,/O closing/VBG/O down/RB/O 647/CD/O ././O
Unlike/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O major/JJ/O investors/NNS/O chose/VBD/O to/TO/O sit/VB/O this/DT/O calamity/NN/O out/RP/O ././O
Clients/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O all/DT/O staying/VBG/O out/IN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG trader/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O relative/JJ/O calm/NN/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE proved/VBD/O little/JJ/O comfort/NN/O to/TO/O markets/NNS/O opening/VBG/O up/RP/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O opening/NN/O was/VBD/O delayed/VBN/O a/DT/O half/JJ/O hour/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O crush/NN/O of/IN/O sell/NN/O orders/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O beginning/NN/O was/VBD/O chaotic/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Nigel/NNP/B-PERSON Longley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O broker/NN/O for/IN/O Commerzbank/NNP/B-ORG
The/DT/O screen/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O sea/NN/O of/IN/O red/NN/O ././O
When/WRB/O trading/NN/O opened/VBD/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE at/IN/O 9:30/CD/O a.m./NN/O EDT/NNP/O ,/,/O stocks/NNS/O fell/VBD/O sharply/RB/O --/:/O as/IN/O expected/VBN/O ././O
Futures/NNS/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O opened/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O level/NN/O suggesting/VBG/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O fall/VB/O by/IN/O about/RB/O 60/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
With/IN/O sell/NN/O orders/NNS/O piled/VBD/O up/RP/O from/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O about/RB/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O stocks/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG could/MD/O n't/RB/O open/VB/O on/IN/O time/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O 9:45/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O industrial/JJ/O average/NN/O had/VBD/O dropped/VBN/O 27/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O 10/CD/O a.m./NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O down/RB/O 49/CD/O ././O
Ten/CD/O minutes/NNS/O later/RBR/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG hit/VBD/O bottom/NN/O -/:/O down/RB/O 63.52/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O another/DT/O 2.5/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O shortly/RB/O before/IN/O then/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O of/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O 's/POS/O sharpest/JJS/O traders/NNS/O say/VBP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O sensed/VBD/O a/DT/O turn/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O first/JJ/O thing/NN/O that/WDT/O caught/VBD/O my/PRP$/O eye/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O encouraging/VBG/O was/VBD/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG bonds/NNS/O were/VBD/O off/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Austin/NNP/B-PERSON George/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O stock/NN/O trading/VBG/O at/IN/O T./NNP/B-ORG Rowe/NNP/I-ORG Price/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Shortly/RB/O after/IN/O 10/CD/O a.m./NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Major/NNP/O Market/NNP/O Index/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG futures/NNS/O contract/VB/O of/IN/O 20/CD/O stocks/NNS/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O mimic/VB/O the/DT/O DJIA/NNP/O ,/,/O exploded/VBD/O upward/RB/O ././O
Stock/NN/O traders/NNS/O were/VBD/O buoyed/VBN/O --/:/O because/IN/O an/DT/O upturn/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O MMI/NNP/O had/VBD/O also/RB/O started/VBN/O the/DT/O recovery/NN/O in/IN/O stocks/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Tuesday/NNP/O following/NN/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O MMI/NNP/O has/VBZ/O gone/VBN/O better/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O shouted/VBD/O a/DT/O trader/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE office/NN/O of/IN/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Shearson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O London/NNP/B-GPE trading/VBG/O room/NN/O went/VBD/O wild/JJ/O ././O
Then/RB/O ,/,/O nine/CD/O minutes/NNS/O later/RB/O ,/,/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O suddenly/RB/O rebounded/VB/O to/TO/O a/DT/O gain/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Rally/VB/O ,/,/O rally/VB/O ,/,/O rally/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O shouted/VBD/O Shearson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Andy/NNP/B-PERSON Rosen/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O panic/NN/O buying/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Japanese/NNP/O were/VBD/O said/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O heavy/NN/O buyers/NNS/O ././O
German/NNP/O and/CC/O Dutch/NNP/O investors/NNS/O reportedly/RB/O loaded/VBD/O up/RP/O on/IN/O Kellogg/NNP/B-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
By/IN/O 10:25/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O turned/VBN/O up/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O prompting/VBG/O cheers/NNS/O on/IN/O trading/VBG/O desks/NNS/O and/CC/O exchange/NN/O floors/NNS/O ././O
Among/IN/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG specialists/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O cry/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O Pull/VB/O your/PRP$/O offers/NNS/O ''/''/O --/:/O meaning/NN/O that/IN/O specialists/NNS/O soon/RB/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O higher/JJR/O prices/NNS/O for/IN/O their/PRP$/O shares/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O bedlam/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O upside/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O one/CD/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG specialist/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O technical/JJ/O strength/NN/O spurred/VBD/O buying/NN/O from/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O black/JJ/O boxes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O computer/NN/O programs/NNS/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O trigger/VB/O large/JJ/O stock/NN/O purchases/NNS/O during/IN/O bullish/JJ/O periods/NNS/O ././O
Typical/JJ/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O Batterymarch/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Dean/NNP/B-PERSON LeBaron/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O LeBaron/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O manages/VBZ/O $/$/O 10/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O We/PRP/O turned/VBD/O the/DT/O trading/NN/O system/NN/O on/RP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O whatever/WDT/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O programmed/VBN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Asked/VBN/O what/WP/O stocks/VBZ/O the/DT/O computer/NN/O bought/VBD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O money/NN/O manager/NN/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O ././O ''/''/O
Not/RB/O everybody/NN/O was/VBD/O making/VBG/O money/NN/O ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O ,/,/O clearing/NN/O firms/NNS/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O makers/NNS/O to/TO/O get/VB/O out/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O positions/NNS/O at/IN/O any/DT/O cost/NN/O Monday/NNP/O morning/NN/O ././O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O test/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O rally/NN/O came/VBD/O at/IN/O about/RB/O 2/CD/O p.m./NN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG at/IN/O 2600/CD/O ,/,/O up/RB/O 31/CD/O points/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Clough/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O strategist/NN/O at/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O bargain/NN/O hunting/NN/O had/VBD/O explained/VBN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strength/NN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O that/DT/O point/NN/O and/CC/O that/DT/O many/JJ/O market/NN/O professionals/NNS/O were/VBD/O anticipating/VBG/O a/DT/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Moreover/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O announcement/NN/O that/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O magnate/NN/O and/CC/O sometime/JJ/O raider/NN/O Donald/NNP/B-PERSON Trump/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O withdrawing/VBG/O his/PRP$/O offer/NN/O for/IN/O AMR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG might/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O rattle/VB/O traders/NNS/O ././O
Instead/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O rally/NN/O only/RB/O paused/VBD/O for/IN/O about/RB/O 25/CD/O minutes/NNS/O and/CC/O then/RB/O steamed/VBD/O forward/RB/O as/IN/O institutions/NNS/O resumed/VBD/O buying/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O market/NN/O closed/VBD/O minutes/NNS/O after/IN/O reaching/VBG/O its/PRP$/O high/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O of/IN/O
Across/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O took/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O events/NNS/O in/IN/O stride/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O remaining/VBG/O generally/RB/O uneasy/JJ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O in/IN/O general/NN/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Norman/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O mayor/NN/O of/IN/O Ava/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mo./NNP/B-GPE :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O invest/VB/O in/IN/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
I/PRP/O much/RB/O prefer/VBP/O money/NN/O I/PRP/O can/MD/O put/VB/O my/PRP$/O hands/NNS/O on/IN/O ././O ''/''/O
While/IN/O Mayor/NNP/O Norman/NNP/B-PERSON found/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O performance/NN/O Monday/NNP/O reassuring/VBG/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O remains/VBZ/O uneasy/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O half/PDT/O the/DT/O experts/NNS/O saying/VBG/O one/CD/O thing/NN/O and/CC/O half/NN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O ''/''/O about/IN/O the/DT/O course/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O economy/NN/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O Gordon/NNP/B-PERSON Fines/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O money/NN/O manager/NN/O at/IN/O IDS/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Minneapolis/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O ``/``/O You/PRP/O 're/VBP/O on/IN/O a/DT/O roller/NN/O coaster/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O that/DT/O may/MD/O last/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O public/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O cautious/JJ/O ././O
