BMA/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Mo./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O weighing/VBG/O ``/``/O strategic/JJ/O alternatives/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O for/IN/O its/PRP$/O Business/NNP/B-ORG Men/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Assurance/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O contacting/VBG/O possible/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O life/NN/O and/CC/O health/NN/O insurance/NN/O operation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Men/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Assurance/NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O represented/VBD/O about/RB/O $/$/O 288/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O $/$/O 488/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O revenue/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O unit/NN/O 's/POS/O operating/VBG/O income/NN/O was/VBD/O about/RB/O $/$/O 10/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O spokesman/NN/O ././O
