Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Park/NNP/B-GPE Ridge/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.J./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O retained/VBD/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Markets/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Rental/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG unit/NN/O ././O
Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O operating/NN/O profit/NN/O before/IN/O depreciation/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 90/CD/O million/CD/O on/IN/O revenue/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O in/IN/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Hertz/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O supplier/NN/O of/IN/O rental/JJ/O equipment/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O France/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Spain/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O U.K/NNP/B-GPE ././O
