BSN/NNP/B-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O leading/VBG/O French/JJ/O food/NN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O Birkel/NNP/B-ORG G.m.b/NNP/I-ORG ././I-ORG H./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O pasta/NN/O maker/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O acquisition/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O move/NN/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O line/NN/O with/IN/O BSN/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strategy/NN/O of/IN/O gradually/RB/O building/VBG/O its/PRP$/O share/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O European/JJ/O pasta/NN/O market/NN/O through/IN/O external/JJ/O growth/NN/O ././O
BSN/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O initially/RB/O acquire/VB/O a/DT/O 15/CD/O %/NN/O interest/NN/O in/IN/O Birkel/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O closely/RB/O held/VBN/O concern/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O French/JJ/O group/NN/O has/VBZ/O an/DT/O agreement/NN/O giving/VBG/O it/PRP/O the/DT/O right/NN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O all/DT/O the/DT/O shares/NNS/O outstanding/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O this/DT/O could/MD/O be/VB/O completed/VBN/O within/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O BSN/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O takeover/NN/O was/VBD/O submitted/VBN/O for/IN/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O cartel/NN/O office/NN/O ,/,/O BSN/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
It/PRP/O has/VBZ/O 750/CD/O workers/NNS/O at/IN/O three/CD/O production/NN/O units/NNS/O in/IN/O southwest/JJS/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O leading/VBG/O producer/NN/O of/IN/O pasta/NN/O sauces/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O acquisition/NN/O strengthens/VBZ/O BSN/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O position/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O European/JJ/O pasta/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O French/JJ/O group/NN/O currently/RB/O ranks/VBZ/O second/JJ/O after/IN/O Barilla/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Italy/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O whose/WP$/O sales/NNS/O are/VBP/O chiefly/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Italian/JJ/O market/NN/O ././O
