Frank/NNP/B-PERSON Lloyd/NNP/I-PERSON Wright/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O reported/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O said/VBD/O once/RB/O that/IN/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O tipped/VBD/O the/DT/O world/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O side/NN/O ,/,/O everything/NN/O loose/JJ/O would/MD/O end/VB/O up/RP/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Interestingly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Environmental/NNP/I-ORG Defense/NNP/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O having/VBG/O nothing/NN/O to/TO/O do/VB/O with/IN/O this/DT/O one/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O initiative/NN/O bars/VBZ/O the/DT/O sale/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O crops/NNS/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O meet/VB/O the/DT/O initiative/NN/O 's/POS/O standards/NNS/O ././O
Kansas/NNP/B-GPE wheat/NN/O farmers/NNS/O and/CC/O Florida/NNP/B-GPE fruit/NN/O growers/NNS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O adjust/VB/O or/CC/O give/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE market/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O proposed/VBN/O initiative/NN/O would/MD/O mandate/VB/O a/DT/O reduction/NN/O of/IN/O carbon/NN/O dioxide/NN/O of/IN/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O key/NN/O here/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O ambition/NN/O of/IN/O state/NN/O Attorney/NNP/O General/NNP/O John/NNP/B-PERSON Van/NNP/I-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON Kamp/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O running/VBG/O for/IN/O governor/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Van/NNP/B-PERSON de/NNP/I-PERSON Kamp/NNP/I-PERSON is/VBZ/O the/DT/O one/CD/O who/WP/O collected/VBD/O the/DT/O plans/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O various/JJ/O radical/JJ/O environmental/JJ/O groups/NNS/O and/CC/O cobbled/VBD/O them/PRP/O into/IN/O a/DT/O single/JJ/O unwieldy/JJ/O initiative/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O placed/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O ballot/NN/O for/IN/O election/NN/O on/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 6/CD/O ,/,/O 1990/CD/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O also/RB/O the/DT/O day/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O gubernatorial/JJ/O election/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O initiative/NN/O seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O crafted/VBN/O to/TO/O include/VB/O all/DT/O the/DT/O hot/JJ/O issues/NNS/O that/WDT/O set/VBD/O off/IN/O the/DT/O wealthy/JJ/O Hollywood/NNP/B-GPE weepers/NNS/O who/WP/O donate/VBP/O money/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O initiative/NN/O is/VBZ/O being/VBG/O labeled/VBN/O The/DT/O Big/NNP/O Green/NNP/O ,/,/O but/CC/O maybe/RB/O it/PRP/O should/MD/O be/VB/O called/VBN/O The/DT/O Big/NNP/O Greenback/NNP/O ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O state/NN/O that/WDT/O recently/RB/O passed/VBD/O the/DT/O Prop./NNP/O 65/CD/O anti-toxic/JJ/O initiative/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O initiative/NN/O creates/VBZ/O a/DT/O free/JJ/O floating/JJ/O state/NN/O environmental/JJ/O officer/NN/O to/TO/O sue/VB/O companies/NNS/O or/CC/O government/NN/O agencies/NNS/O that/WDT/O do/VBP/O things/NNS/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O like/VB/O ././O
That/DT/O means/VBZ/O the/DT/O NRDC/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O such/JJ/O groups/NNS/O no/RB/O longer/RBR/O would/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O spend/VB/O as/IN/O much/JJ/O money/NN/O on/IN/O litigation/NN/O ;/:/O taxpayers/NNS/O would/MD/O bear/VB/O the/DT/O cost/NN/O ././O
George/NNP/B-PERSON Bush/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O may/MD/O decide/VB/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O President/NNP/O who/WP/O lost/VBD/O control/NN/O of/IN/O interstate/JJ/O commerce/NN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O attorney/NN/O general/JJ/O from/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
