Burmah/NNP/B-ORG Oil/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O British/NNP/O independent/JJ/O oil/NN/O and/CC/O specialty/NN/O chemicals/NNS/O marketing/NN/O concern/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O SHV/NNP/B-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG N.V./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O Netherlands/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O built/VBN/O up/RP/O a/DT/O 6.7/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O ././O
James/NNP/B-PERSON Alexander/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O Burmah/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O SHV/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O previously/RB/O owned/VBN/O ``/``/O a/DT/O little/JJ/O under/IN/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O Burmah/NNP/B-ORG for/IN/O about/RB/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Dutch/NNP/O company/NN/O had/VBD/O n't/RB/O notified/VBN/O Burmah/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/O its/PRP$/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O increasing/VBG/O the/DT/O stake/NN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
SHV/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O merged/VBD/O its/PRP$/O North/NNP/B-LOC Sea/NNP/I-LOC oil/NN/O and/CC/O gas/NN/O operations/NNS/O with/IN/O those/DT/O of/IN/O Calor/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O pegged/VBN/O by/IN/O speculators/NNS/O as/IN/O a/DT/O possible/JJ/O suitor/NN/O for/IN/O Burmah/NNP/B-ORG Oil/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O recent/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O ././O
SHV/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O owns/VBZ/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Calor/NNP/B-ORG ././O
