United/NNP/B-ORG Biscuits/NNP/I-ORG -LRB-/-LRB-/I-ORG Holdings/NNP/I-ORG -RRB-/-RRB-/I-ORG PLC/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O British/JJ/O food/NN/O producer/NN/O ,/,/O announced/VBD/O the/DT/O creation/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O European/JJ/O group/NN/O to/TO/O bring/VB/O together/RB/O its/PRP$/O trading/NN/O interests/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O region/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O group/NN/O will/MD/O comprise/VB/O all/DT/O of/IN/O United/NNP/B-ORG Biscuit/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG manufacturing/NN/O and/CC/O marketing/NN/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O food/NN/O sector/NN/O apart/RB/O from/IN/O those/DT/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
United/NNP/B-ORG Biscuits/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O the/DT/O combined/VBN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O include/VB/O businesses/NNS/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O McVities/NNP/B-ORG biscuits/NNS/O and/CC/O Terry/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG confectionery/NN/I-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O have/VB/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O #/#/O 1.5/CD/O billion/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 2.35/CD/O billion/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O trading/NN/O profit/NN/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O #/#/O 160/CD/O million/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 251/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O new/JJ/O structure/NN/O will/MD/O enable/VB/O United/NNP/B-ORG Biscuits/NNP/I-ORG to/TO/O focus/VB/O clearly/RB/O upon/IN/O opportunities/NNS/O for/IN/O planned/VBN/O growth/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O 1990s/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Bob/NNP/B-PERSON Clarke/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O deputy/JJ/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O group/NN/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O United/NNP/B-ORG Biscuits/NNP/I-ORG agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O sell/VB/O its/PRP$/O entire/JJ/O restaurant/NN/O operations/NNS/O to/TO/O Grand/NNP/B-ORG Metropolitan/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/O #/#/O 180/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
