Laidlaw/NNP/B-ORG Transportation/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O raised/VBD/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O ADT/NNP/B-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Bermuda/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O 29.4/CD/O %/NN/O from/IN/O 28/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O Laidlaw/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O increase/VB/O its/PRP$/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O ADT/NNP/B-ORG beyond/IN/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O ``/``/O without/IN/O a/DT/O great/JJ/O deal/NN/O of/IN/O thought/NN/O ''/''/O because/IN/O of/IN/O British/JJ/O takeover/NN/O regulations/NNS/O that/WDT/O require/VBP/O a/DT/O company/NN/O acquiring/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O an/DT/O offer/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O rest/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O shareholders/NNS/O ././O
ADT/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O security/NN/O services/NNS/O and/CC/O auctions/NNS/O company/NN/O ,/,/O trades/VBZ/O on/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Stock/NNP/B-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Laidlaw/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O 47%-controlled/CD/O by/IN/O Canadian/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Montreal/NNP/B-GPE transportation/NN/O ,/,/O resources/NNS/O and/CC/O industrial/JJ/O holding/VBG/O concern/NN/O ././O
