Health/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Human/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNP/I-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Louis/NNP/B-PERSON Sullivan/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O chosen/VBN/O Antonia/NNP/B-PERSON Novello/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O be/VB/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O surgeon/NN/O general/NN/O ,/,/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
If/IN/O she/PRP/O is/VBZ/O nominated/VBN/O by/IN/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O confirmed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Dr./NNP/O Novello/NNP/B-PERSON would/MD/O succeed/VB/O C./NNP/B-PERSON Everett/NNP/I-PERSON Koop/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O rattled/VBD/O liberals/NNS/O and/CC/O conservatives/NNS/O alike/RB/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O outspoken/JJ/O views/NNS/O on/IN/O a/DT/O range/NN/O of/IN/O health/NN/O issues/NNS/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Novello/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O expert/NN/O on/IN/O pediatric/JJ/O kidney/NN/O diseases/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O deputy/JJ/O director/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Child/NNP/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Human/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG ././O
She/PRP/O has/VBZ/O also/RB/O served/VBN/O on/IN/O several/JJ/O task/NN/O forces/NNS/O on/IN/O acquired/VBN/O immune/JJ/O deficiency/NN/O syndrome/NN/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Novello/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O office/NN/O said/VBD/O she/PRP/O would/MD/O n't/RB/O talk/VB/O with/IN/O reporters/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O refused/VBD/O to/TO/O release/VB/O any/DT/O information/NN/O about/IN/O her/PRP/O ././O
