Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O critical/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O for/IN/O not/RB/O sending/VBG/O enough/JJ/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O so/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O send/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O version/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O CARE/NNP/O package/NN/O ././O
Last/JJ/O month/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG voted/VBD/O to/TO/O send/VB/O a/DT/O delegation/NN/O of/IN/O congressional/JJ/O staffers/NNS/O to/TO/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O assist/VB/O its/PRP$/O legislature/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Sejm/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O democratic/JJ/O procedures/NNS/O ././O
Senator/NNP/O Pete/NNP/B-PERSON Domenici/NNP/I-PERSON calls/VBZ/O this/DT/O effort/NN/O ``/``/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O gift/NN/O of/IN/O democracy/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O Poles/NNS/O might/MD/O do/VB/O better/RBR/O to/TO/O view/VB/O it/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O Trojan/NNP/O Horse/NNP/O ././O
Maybe/RB/O after/IN/O the/DT/O staffers/NNS/O explain/VBP/O their/PRP$/O work/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Poles/NNS/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 'd/MD/O be/VB/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O come/VB/O back/RB/O and/CC/O do/VB/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O for/IN/O the/DT/O American/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O
