EAST/NNS/O GERMANS/NNS/O RALLIED/VBD/O as/IN/O officials/NNS/O reportedly/RB/O sought/VBD/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O ouster/NN/O ././O
Police/NNS/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O intervene/VB/O ././O
Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Baker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O a/DT/O foreign/JJ/O policy/NN/O speech/NN/O ,/,/O called/VBD/O for/IN/O the/DT/O reunification/NN/O of/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O saying/VBG/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O ``/``/O legitimate/JJ/O right/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O German/JJ/O people/NNS/O ././O
Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON blamed/VBD/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE press/NN/O for/IN/O contributing/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O mounting/VBG/O problems/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O curbs/NNS/O would/MD/O cover/VB/O all/DT/O but/CC/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O percentage/NN/O of/IN/O flights/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O represent/VB/O an/DT/O expansion/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O flights/NNS/O of/IN/O less/JJR/O than/IN/O two/CD/O hours/NNS/O ././O
E./NNP/B-PERSON Robert/NNP/I-PERSON Wallach/NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O sentenced/VBN/O by/IN/O a/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE judge/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O six/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O and/CC/O fined/VBN/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O racketeering/NN/O conviction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Wedtech/NNP/B-ORG scandal/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O space/NN/O agency/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O weather/NN/O or/CC/O protesters/NNS/O to/TO/O block/VB/O the/DT/O liftoff/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O is/VBZ/O preparing/VBG/O to/TO/O extend/VB/O a/DT/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O federal/JJ/O financing/NN/O of/IN/O research/NN/O using/VBG/O fetal/JJ/O tissue/NN/O ,/,/O government/NN/O sources/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O temporary/JJ/O prohibition/NN/O was/VBD/O imposed/VBN/O in/IN/O March/NNP/O 1988/CD/O ././O
Delegates/NNS/O from/IN/O 91/CD/O nations/NNS/O endorsed/VBD/O a/DT/O ban/NN/O on/IN/O world/NN/O ivory/NN/O trade/NN/O in/IN/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O to/TO/O rescue/VB/O the/DT/O endangered/VBN/O elephant/NN/O from/IN/O extinction/NN/O ././O
Five/CD/O African/JJ/O nations/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O would/MD/O continue/VB/O selling/VBG/O the/DT/O valuable/JJ/O tusks/NNS/O ././O
Mubarak/NNP/B-PERSON held/VBD/O reconciliation/NN/O talks/NNS/O with/IN/O Gadhafi/NNP/B-PERSON at/IN/O the/DT/O Egyptian/JJ/O resort/NN/O of/IN/O Mersa/NNP/B-FAC Metruh/NNP/I-FAC ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O Libyan/JJ/O leader/NN/O 's/POS/O first/JJ/O trip/NN/O to/TO/O Egypt/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O 16/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O announced/VBD/O a/DT/O reduction/NN/O in/IN/O formalities/NNS/O for/IN/O travel/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O show/VB/O any/DT/O real/JJ/O signs/NNS/O of/IN/O resuming/VBG/O full/JJ/O diplomatic/JJ/O ties/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O Egyptian/JJ/O president/NN/O said/VBD/O he/PRP/O would/MD/O visit/VB/O Libya/NNP/B-GPE today/NN/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O the/DT/O talks/NNS/O ././O
Seoul/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Pyongyang/NNP/B-GPE reached/VBD/O a/DT/O tentative/JJ/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O visits/NNS/O between/IN/O families/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O divided/VBN/O Korean/JJ/O peninsula/NN/O ././O
Such/JJ/O family/NN/O reunions/NNS/O would/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O second/JJ/O since/IN/O 1945/CD/O ././O
Differences/NNS/O remained/VBD/O between/IN/O the/DT/O North/JJ/O and/CC/O South/JJ/O Korean/JJ/O governments/NNS/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ,/,/O over/IN/O conditions/NNS/O for/IN/O the/DT/O exchanges/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O main/JJ/O white/JJ/O opposition/NN/O party/NN/O warned/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O release/NN/O Sunday/NNP/O of/IN/O eight/CD/O black/JJ/O political/JJ/O prisoners/NNS/O risked/VBD/O bringing/VBG/O chaos/NN/O and/CC/O eventual/JJ/O black/JJ/O Marxist/JJ/O rule/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG White/NNP/I-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O ``/``/O fully/RB/O satisfied/VBN/O ''/''/O with/IN/O CIA/NNP/B-ORG Director/NNP/O Webster/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O the/DT/O intelligence/NN/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O performance/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O Oct./NNP/O 3/CD/O failed/VBN/O coup/NN/O in/IN/O Panama/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O legislature/NN/O approved/VBD/O limits/NNS/O on/IN/O automatic/JJ/O wage/NN/O increases/NNS/O without/IN/O special/JJ/O provisions/NNS/O for/IN/O food/NN/O price/NN/O rises/NNS/O ././O
Separately/RB/O ,/,/O Secretary/NNP/O of/IN/O State/NNP/B-ORG Baker/NNP/B-PERSON complained/VBD/O about/IN/O a/DT/O U.N./NNP/B-ORG aide/NN/O who/WP/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O told/VBD/O the/DT/O Contras/NNS/B-ORG to/TO/O disband/VB/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O regional/JJ/O peace/NN/O accord/NN/O ././O
