It/PRP/O ended/VBD/O with/IN/O a/DT/O gain/NN/O of/IN/O 88.12/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Big/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG handled/VBD/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O volume/NN/O without/IN/O any/DT/O obvious/JJ/O strain/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O sharp/JJ/O contrast/NN/O to/TO/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O of/IN/O 1987/CD/O ././O
Overall/JJ/O ,/,/O more/JJR/O Big/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG stocks/NNS/O lost/VBD/O money/NN/O than/IN/O gained/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE stock/NN/O exchange/NN/O was/VBD/O hardest/RBS/O hit/VBN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O with/IN/O blue/JJ/O chips/NNS/O there/RB/O falling/VBG/O 12.8/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Investors/NNS/O big/JJ/O and/CC/O small/JJ/O say/VBP/O they/PRP/O learned/VBD/O valuable/JJ/O lessons/NNS/O since/IN/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O :/:/O In/IN/O this/DT/O age/NN/O of/IN/O computerized/VBN/O trading/NN/O ,/,/O huge/JJ/O corrections/NNS/O or/CC/O runups/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O hours/NNS/O '/POS/O time/NN/O must/MD/O be/VB/O expected/VBN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O other/JJ/O factors/NNS/O played/VBD/O a/DT/O part/NN/O in/IN/O yesterday/NN/O 's/POS/O comeback/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Reserve/NNP/I-ORG signaled/VBD/O its/PRP$/O willingness/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O liquidity/NN/O ;/:/O the/DT/O interest/NN/O rate/NN/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O loans/NNS/O to/TO/O major/JJ/O banks/NNS/O inched/VBD/O downward/RB/O early/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O ././O
Foreign/JJ/O stock/NN/O markets/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O kicked/VBD/O off/RP/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O with/IN/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O selling/NN/O spree/NN/O ,/,/O began/VBD/O the/DT/O day/NN/O off/JJ/O by/IN/O relatively/RB/O modest/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O dollar/NN/O ,/,/O after/IN/O falling/VBG/O sharply/RB/O in/IN/O overnight/JJ/O trading/NN/O to/TO/O 139.10/CD/O yen/NNS/O ,/,/O bounced/VBD/O back/RB/O strongly/RB/O to/TO/O 141.8/CD/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O easing/VBG/O fears/NNS/O that/IN/O foreigners/NNS/O would/MD/O unload/VB/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE stocks/NNS/O ././O
Many/JJ/O major/JJ/O institutions/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O came/VBD/O into/IN/O work/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O some/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O blue/JJ/O chips/NNS/O they/PRP/O felt/VBD/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O sharply/RB/O undervalued/VBN/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O average/NN/O plunged/VBD/O some/DT/O 600/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O or/CC/O 1.7/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O 20/CD/O minutes/NNS/O of/IN/O trading/NN/O ././O
Clients/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O all/DT/O staying/VBG/O out/IN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O ,/,/O one/CD/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG trader/NN/O says/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O relative/JJ/O calm/NN/O in/IN/O Tokyo/NNP/B-GPE proved/VBD/O little/JJ/O comfort/NN/O to/TO/O markets/NNS/O opening/VBG/O up/RP/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Frankfurt/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O opening/NN/O was/VBD/O delayed/VBN/O a/DT/O half/JJ/O hour/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O crush/NN/O of/IN/O sell/NN/O orders/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O screen/NN/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O sea/NN/O of/IN/O red/NN/O ././O
Futures/NNS/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE had/VBD/O opened/VBN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O level/NN/O suggesting/VBG/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O fall/VB/O by/IN/O about/RB/O 60/CD/O points/NNS/O ././O
Ten/CD/O minutes/NNS/O later/RBR/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG hit/VBD/O bottom/NN/O -/:/O down/RB/O 63.52/CD/O points/NNS/O ,/,/O another/DT/O 2.5/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Stock/NN/O traders/NNS/O were/VBD/O buoyed/VBN/O --/:/O because/IN/O an/DT/O upturn/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O MMI/NNP/O had/VBD/O also/RB/O started/VBN/O the/DT/O recovery/NN/O in/IN/O stocks/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Tuesday/NNP/O following/NN/O Black/NNP/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
Shearson/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O London/NNP/B-GPE trading/VBG/O room/NN/O went/VBD/O wild/JJ/O ././O
Japanese/NNP/O were/VBD/O said/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O heavy/NN/O buyers/NNS/O ././O
German/NNP/O and/CC/O Dutch/NNP/O investors/NNS/O reportedly/RB/O loaded/VBD/O up/IN/O on/IN/O Kellogg/NNP/B-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
This/DT/O technical/JJ/O strength/NN/O spurred/VBD/O buying/NN/O from/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O black/JJ/O boxes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O computer/NN/O programs/NNS/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O trigger/VB/O large/JJ/O stock/NN/O purchases/NNS/O during/IN/O bullish/JJ/O periods/NNS/O ././O
Typical/JJ/O ,/,/O perhaps/RB/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O Batterymarch/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Dean/NNP/B-PERSON LeBaron/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Charles/NNP/B-PERSON Clough/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O strategist/NN/O at/IN/O Merrill/NNP/B-ORG Lynch/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O bargain/NN/O hunting/NN/O had/VBD/O explained/VBN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O strength/NN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O that/DT/O point/NN/O and/CC/O that/DT/O many/JJ/O market/NN/O professionals/NNS/O were/VBD/O anticipating/VBG/O a/DT/O drop/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Dow/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O public/NN/O is/VBZ/O still/RB/O cautious/JJ/O ././O
