We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O about/IN/O to/TO/O see/VB/O if/IN/O advertising/NN/O works/VBZ/O ././O
This/DT/O time/NN/O around/RP/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O 're/VBP/O moving/VBG/O even/RB/O faster/RBR/O ././O
PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG filmed/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O television/NN/O commercial/NN/O at/IN/O 4/CD/O p.m./NN/O EDT/NNP/O yesterday/NN/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O it/PRP/O on/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O by/IN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O ././O
Fidelity/NNP/B-ORG Investments/NNP/I-ORG placed/VBD/O new/JJ/O ads/NNS/O in/IN/O newspapers/NNS/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O wrote/VBD/O another/DT/O new/JJ/O ad/NN/O appearing/VBG/O today/NN/O ././O
Shearson/NNP/B-ORG Lehman/NNP/I-ORG Hutton/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG by/IN/O yesterday/NN/O afternoon/NN/O had/VBD/O already/RB/O written/VBN/O new/JJ/O TV/NN/O ads/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O considered/VBD/O running/VBG/O them/PRP/O during/IN/O tomorrow/NN/O night/NN/O 's/POS/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O broadcast/NN/O but/CC/O decided/VBD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O market/NN/O recovered/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O brokerage/NN/O firms/NNS/O learned/VBD/O a/DT/O lesson/NN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O time/NN/O around/RP/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O frightened/JJ/O investors/NNS/O flooded/VBD/O the/DT/O phone/NN/O lines/NNS/O and/CC/O fled/VBD/O the/DT/O market/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O panic/NN/O ././O
This/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O firms/NNS/O were/VBD/O ready/JJ/O ././O
Fidelity/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O for/IN/O example/NN/O ,/,/O prepared/VBN/O ads/NNS/O several/JJ/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O in/IN/O case/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O market/NN/O plunge/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O too/RB/O late/JJ/O to/TO/O think/VB/O about/IN/O on/IN/O Friday/NNP/O ././O
Today/NN/O 's/POS/O Fidelity/NNP/B-ORG ad/NN/O goes/VBZ/O a/DT/O step/NN/O further/RBR/O ,/,/O encouraging/VBG/O investors/NNS/O to/TO/O stay/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O or/CC/O even/RB/O to/TO/O plunge/VB/O in/IN/O with/IN/O Fidelity/NNP/B-ORG ././O
It/PRP/O goes/VBZ/O on/RB/O to/TO/O plug/VB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O diversified/JJ/O Fidelity/NNP/B-ORG funds/NNS/O by/IN/O name/NN/O ././O
PaineWebber/NN/B-ORG also/RB/O was/VBD/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O gear/VB/O up/RP/O quickly/RB/O thanks/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O 1987/CD/O crash/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O spot/NN/O was/VBD/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O appear/VB/O three/CD/O times/NNS/O on/IN/O CNN/NNP/B-ORG last/JJ/O night/NN/O ././O
PaineWebber/NNP/B-ORG considered/VBD/O an/DT/O even/RB/O harder/JJR/O sell/NN/O ,/,/O recommending/VBG/O specific/JJ/O stocks/NNS/O ././O
Ad/NN/O Notes/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Eskandarian/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O resigned/VBD/O his/PRP$/O Della/NNP/B-ORG Femina/NNP/I-ORG post/NN/O in/IN/O September/NNP/O ,/,/O becomes/VBZ/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O of/IN/O Arnold/NNP/O ././O
John/NNP/B-PERSON Verret/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O retain/VB/O the/DT/O title/NN/O of/IN/O president/NN/O ././O
Separately/NNP/O ,/,/O McDonald/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Oak/NNP/B-GPE Brook/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Ill./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O named/VBD/O Arnold/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O handle/VB/O its/PRP$/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 4/CD/O million/CD/O cooperative/JJ/O ad/NN/O account/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Hartford/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O area/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O account/NN/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O handled/VBN/O by/IN/O Della/NNP/B-ORG Femina/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/I-ORG McNamee/NNP/I-ORG WCRS/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O magazine/NN/O will/MD/O distribute/VB/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O gross/JJ/O revenues/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O supplement/NN/O as/IN/O grants/NNS/O to/TO/O innovative/JJ/O teachers/NNS/O ././O
