An/DT/O American/JJ/O journalist/NN/O now/RB/O is/VBZ/O standing/VBG/O trial/NN/O in/IN/O Namibia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
This/DT/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O place/NN/O that/DT/O world/NN/O opinion/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O celebrating/VBG/O over/IN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O expectation/NN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O hold/VB/O an/DT/O election/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE journalist/NN/O 's/POS/O ``/``/O crime/NN/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O writing/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O head/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O commission/NN/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O overseeing/VBG/O the/DT/O election/NN/O 's/POS/O fairness/NN/O ,/,/O Bryan/NNP/B-PERSON O'Linn/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O was/VBD/O openly/RB/O sympathetic/JJ/O to/TO/O SWAPO/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O on/IN/O trial/NN/O over/IN/O charges/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O violated/VBD/O a/DT/O proclamation/NN/O ,/,/O issued/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O South/JJ/O African/JJ/O administrator/NN/O general/NN/O earlier/RBR/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O made/VBD/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O crime/NN/O punishable/JJ/O by/IN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O in/IN/O prison/NN/O for/IN/O any/DT/O person/NN/O to/TO/O ``/``/O insult/VB/O ,/,/O disparate/JJ/O or/CC/O belittle/VB/O ''/''/O the/DT/O election/NN/O commission/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON affair/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O bode/VB/O well/RB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O future/NN/O of/IN/O democracy/NN/O or/CC/O freedom/NN/O of/IN/O anything/NN/O in/IN/O Namibia/NNP/B-GPE when/WRB/O SWAPO/NNP/B-ORG starts/VBZ/O running/VBG/O the/DT/O government/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O elections/NNS/O are/VBP/O set/VBN/O for/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 7/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O interviewed/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O O'Linn/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O head/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O commission/NN/O charged/VBN/O with/IN/O investigating/VBG/O electoral/JJ/O intimidation/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O reported/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O O'Linn/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O openly/RB/O sympathetic/JJ/O to/TO/O SWAPO/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O indeed/RB/O had/VBD/O defended/VBN/O its/PRP$/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O court/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O arrested/VBN/O and/CC/O charged/VBN/O along/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O others/NNS/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O Namibia/NNP/B-GPE this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O the/DT/B-ORG State/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Lawyers/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG for/IN/I-ORG Freedom/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG the/DT/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG have/VBP/O protested/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O detention/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O arrest/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O latest/JJS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O incidents/NNS/O that/WDT/O threaten/VBP/O to/TO/O derail/VB/O Namibia/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O elections/NNS/O ././O
Both/DT/O South/NNP/O African/NNP/O and/CC/O SWAPO/NNP/B-ORG extremists/NNS/O are/VBP/O intimidating/VBG/O voters/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O habit/NN/O of/IN/O arranging/VBG/O peace/NN/O settlements/NNS/O and/CC/O then/RB/O washing/VBG/O its/PRP$/O hands/NNS/O over/IN/O the/DT/O tragic/JJ/O results/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O now/RB/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O chance/NN/O to/TO/O redress/VB/O that/DT/O record/NN/O in/IN/O Namibia/NNP/B-GPE ././O
