Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O until/IN/O Nov./NNP/O 13/CD/O to/TO/O resolve/VB/O the/DT/O dispute/NN/O ././O
Questioned/VBN/O about/IN/O the/DT/O seeming/JJ/O contradiction/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Canadian/JJ/O government/NN/O views/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O 's/POS/O report/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O aide/NN/O for/IN/O Mrs./NNP/O Hills/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O had/VBD/O clearly/RB/O ruled/VBN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O trade/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O illegal/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE trade/NN/O representative/NN/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O put/VB/O a/DT/O dollar/NN/O estimate/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O losses/NNS/O resulting/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O export/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O ././O
Canada/NNP/B-GPE initially/RB/O had/VBD/O an/DT/O export/NN/O prohibition/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O replaced/VBN/O by/IN/O regulations/NNS/O requiring/VBG/O that/DT/O such/JJ/O fish/NN/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O brought/VBN/O ashore/RB/O in/IN/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE by/IN/O commercial/JJ/O fishermen/NNS/O prior/RB/O to/TO/O export/VB/O ././O
This/DT/O action/NN/O was/VBD/O defended/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O government/NN/O on/IN/O conservation/NN/O grounds/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O fully/RB/O expect/VBP/O that/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE will/MD/O comply/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O panel/NN/O 's/POS/O ruling/NN/O ''/''/O that/IN/O the/DT/O ``/``/O landing/NN/O requirement/NN/O ''/''/O also/RB/O must/MD/O be/VB/O ended/VBN/O ,/,/O she/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
She/PRP/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O Canadian/JJ/O restrictions/NNS/O must/MD/O be/VB/O removed/VBN/O before/IN/O such/JJ/O contracts/NNS/O are/VBP/O concluded/VBN/O ././O
