San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O officials/NNS/O gave/VBD/O the/DT/O media/NNS/O high/JJ/O marks/NNS/O for/IN/O helping/VBG/O people/NNS/O find/VB/O shelter/NN/O and/CC/O obtain/VB/O emergency/NN/O information/NN/O after/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O catastrophic/JJ/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O telling/VBG/O people/NNS/O what/WDT/O roads/NNS/O are/VBP/O closed/JJ/O and/CC/O just/RB/O keeping/VBG/O the/DT/O public/NN/O informed/JJ/O has/VBZ/O helped/VBN/O to/TO/O keep/VB/O the/DT/O panic/NN/O down/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O James/NNP/B-PERSON Ball/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O station/NN/O supervisor/NN/O at/IN/O Daly/NNP/B-ORG City/NNP/I-ORG Police/NNP/I-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Ball/NNP/B-PERSON noted/VBD/O that/IN/O television/NN/O stations/NNS/O featured/VBD/O people/NNS/O holding/VBG/O up/RP/O phone/NN/O books/NNS/O ,/,/O explaining/VBG/O where/WRB/O to/TO/O call/VB/O for/IN/O help/NN/O ././O
Radio/NN/O stations/NNS/O provided/VBD/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O number/NN/O for/IN/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O smelled/VBD/O gas/NN/O but/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O turn/VB/O off/RP/O their/PRP$/O gas/NN/O supply/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG San/NNP/I-ORG Francisco/NNP/I-ORG Examiner/NNP/I-ORG issued/VBD/O a/DT/O special/JJ/O edition/NN/O around/IN/O noon/NN/O yesterday/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O filled/VBN/O entirely/RB/O with/IN/O earthquake/NN/O news/NN/O and/CC/O information/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Examiner/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG San/NNP/I-ORG Francisco/NNP/I-ORG Chronicle/NNP/I-ORG were/VBD/O able/JJ/O to/TO/O publish/VB/O despite/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O quake/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O occurred/VBD/O close/RB/O to/TO/O deadline/NN/O for/IN/O many/JJ/O newspapers/NNS/O ././O
