Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O approached/VBN/O by/IN/O ``/``/O about/IN/O half/PDT/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O ''/''/O companies/NNS/B-ORG interested/JJ/O in/IN/O buying/VBG/O all/DT/O or/CC/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O spirits/NNS/O business/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Analysts/NNS/O expect/VBP/O the/DT/O spirits/NNS/O operations/NNS/O and/CC/O some/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE vineyards/NNS/B-LOC that/WDT/O also/RB/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O fetch/VB/O about/IN/O #/#/O 500/CD/O million/CD/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 788.8/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Also/RB/O for/IN/O sale/NN/O are/VBP/O Buckingham/NNP/B-ORG Wile/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O distributes/VBZ/O Cutty/NNP/B-ORG Sark/NNP/I-ORG blended/JJ/O whiskey/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Atlas/NNP/B-ORG Peak/NNP/I-ORG Vineyards/NNPS/I-ORG in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Napa/NNP/B-LOC Valley/NNP/I-LOC ././O
Beefeater/NNP/B-ORG alone/RB/O is/VBZ/O worth/JJ/O as/IN/O much/RB/O as/IN/O #/#/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG bought/VBD/O the/DT/O Beefeater/NNP/B-ORG distillery/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O for/IN/O #/#/O 174.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
That/DT/O purchase/NN/O represented/VBD/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O by/IN/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O venerable/JJ/O British/JJ/O brewer/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O become/VB/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O player/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O global/JJ/O liquor/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O squeezed/VBN/O by/IN/O giant/JJ/O rivals/NNS/O amid/IN/O widespread/JJ/O consolidation/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O concentrate/VB/O on/IN/O beer/NN/O and/CC/O its/PRP$/O newer/JJR/O hotel/NN/O and/CC/O restaurant/NN/O operations/NNS/O ././O
For/IN/O rival/JJ/O liquor/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG auction/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O rare/JJ/O opportunity/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O valuable/JJ/O brands/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O very/RB/O often/RB/O something/NN/O like/IN/O this/DT/O comes/VBZ/O up/RP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Ron/NNP/B-PERSON Littleboy/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O liquor/NN/O company/NN/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O Nomura/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Institute/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O division/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O off/RP/O quite/RB/O rapidly/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O predicted/VBD/O Neill/NNP/B-PERSON Junor/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O analyst/NN/O at/IN/O London/NNP/B-GPE brokers/NNS/O County/NNP/B-ORG NatWest/NNP/I-ORG WoodMac/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Among/IN/O possible/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O ,/,/O Grand/NNP/B-ORG Metropolitan/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG might/MD/O find/VB/O Beefeater/NNP/B-ORG a/DT/O useful/JJ/O addition/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O portfolio/NN/O ././O
Grand/NNP/B-ORG Met/NNP/I-ORG owns/VBZ/O Bombay/NNP/B-ORG gin/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O No./NN/O 3/CD/O imported/VBN/O gin/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O rival/JJ/O Guinness/NNP/B-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O the/DT/O No./NN/O 1/CD/O imported/VBN/O brand/NN/O ,/,/O Tanqueray/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG spirits/NNS/O auction/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O extremely/RB/O interesting/JJ/O development/NN/O .../:/O and/CC/O naturally/RB/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O considering/VBG/O it/PRP/O carefully/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Grand/NNP/B-ORG Met/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Guinness/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O several/JJ/O leading/VBG/O whiskey/NN/O brands/NNS/O plus/CC/O Gordon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O gin/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O No./NN/O 1/CD/O gin/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O less/RBR/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O bid/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG spirits/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O Guinness/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
Seagram/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O gin/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O No./NN/O 2/CD/O gin/NN/O brand/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O company/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O own/VB/O any/DT/O of/IN/O the/DT/O major/JJ/O gin/NN/O brands/NNS/O imported/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
A/DT/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O ././O
Such/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O increasingly/RB/O being/VBG/O left/RB/O behind/RB/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O global/JJ/O liquor/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Nomura/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Littleboy/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Brands/NNPS/I-ORG would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O ././O
But/CC/O analysts/NNS/O estimate/VBP/O their/PRP$/O trading/NN/O profit/NN/O at/IN/O #/#/O 30/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O total/JJ/O pretax/JJ/O profit/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBN/O Feb./NNP/O 25/CD/O of/IN/O #/#/O 223.2/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O #/#/O 2.26/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O spirits/NNS/O auction/NN/O occurs/VBZ/O amid/IN/O a/DT/O parallel/JJ/O shakeup/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O beer/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
Earlier/RB/O this/DT/O year/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O government/NN/O announced/VBD/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O foster/VB/O increased/VBN/O competition/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
British/JJ/O brewers/NNS/O currently/RB/O own/VBP/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O pubs/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O in/RB/O turn/RB/O sell/VBP/O only/RB/O the/DT/O breweries/NNS/O '/POS/O beer/NN/O and/CC/O soft/JJ/O drinks/NNS/O ././O
Under/IN/O new/JJ/O rules/NNS/O ,/,/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O pubs/NNS/O would/MD/O become/VB/O ``/``/O free/JJ/O houses/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O selling/VBG/O beers/NNS/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O choice/NN/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG now/RB/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O its/PRP$/O brewing/NN/O interests/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O grab/VB/O a/DT/O share/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O to/TO/O free/JJ/O houses/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O paid/VBD/O #/#/O 50.7/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O regional/JJ/O British/JJ/O brewer/NN/O Boddington/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O about/IN/O 13/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O beer/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O license/NN/O to/TO/O brew/VB/O and/CC/O distribute/VB/O Heineken/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Stella/NNP/B-ORG Artois/NNP/I-ORG beers/NNS/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O focus/VB/O on/IN/O its/PRP$/O newer/JJR/O hotel/NN/O ,/,/O liquor/NN/O store/NN/O and/CC/O restaurant/NN/O businesses/NNS/O in/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O North/NNP/B-LOC America/NNP/I-LOC ././O
In/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O those/DT/O interests/NNS/O include/VBP/O the/DT/O Beefeater/NNP/B-ORG steakhouse/NN/O chain/NN/O and/CC/O joint/JJ/O ownership/NN/O with/IN/O PepsiCo/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O Pizza/NNP/B-ORG Hut/NNP/I-ORG chain/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Canada/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG owns/VBZ/O The/DT/O Keg/NNP/B-ORG chain/NN/O of/IN/O steak/NN/O and/CC/O seafood/NN/O restaurants/NNS/O ././O
Focusing/VBG/O on/IN/O beer/NN/O ,/,/O restaurants/NNS/O and/CC/O hotels/NNS/O means/VBZ/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O can/MD/O concentrate/VB/O our/PRP$/O skills/NNS/O and/CC/O resources/NNS/O more/RBR/O effectively/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Peter/NNP/B-PERSON Jarvis/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O managing/NN/O director/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O spirits/NNS/O business/NN/O ``/``/O would/MD/O require/VB/O substantial/JJ/O additional/JJ/O investment/NN/O to/TO/O enable/VB/O it/PRP/O to/TO/O compete/VB/O effectively/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O division/NN/O of/IN/O global/JJ/O players/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O announced/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Jarvis/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O 48/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O become/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O March/NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O retain/VB/O the/DT/O honorary/JJ/O title/NN/O of/IN/O non-executive/JJ/O chairman/NN/O ././O
