Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Maynard/NNP/I-PERSON offered/VBD/O the/DT/O world/NN/O a/DT/O faster/JJR/O way/NN/O to/TO/O break/VB/O eggs/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O put/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON out/IN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O act/NN/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
His/PRP$/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Misa/NNP/B-ORG Manufacturing/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O under/IN/O federal/JJ/O bankruptcy/NN/O law/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O since/RB/O been/VBN/O liquidated/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O entrepreneur/NN/O to/TO/O bump/VB/O up/IN/O against/IN/O entrenched/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O answer/NN/O lies/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O nature/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O larger/JJR/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O egg/NN/O processors/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O crack/VBP/O ,/,/O inspect/VBP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O sanitize/VBP/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O eggs/NNS/O ,/,/O turning/VBG/O them/PRP/O into/IN/O powdered/JJ/O ,/,/O liquified/JJ/O or/CC/O frozen/JJ/O egg/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O idea/NN/O behind/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Egg/NNP/I-FAC King/NNP/I-FAC is/VBZ/O pretty/JJ/O simple/NN/O :/:/O put/VB/O the/DT/O eggs/NNS/O into/IN/O a/DT/O cylinder/NN/O that/WDT/O contains/VBZ/O perforated/JJ/O baskets/NNS/O ,/,/O spin/VB/O them/PRP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O speed/NN/O to/TO/O break/VB/O the/DT/O shells/NNS/O and/CC/O strain/VB/O the/DT/O edible/JJ/O part/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O baskets/NNS/O ././O
Such/JJ/O centrifugal/JJ/O egg/NN/O breakers/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O around/IN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O 1890s/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O main/JJ/O reason/NN/O :/:/O salmonella/NN/O ././O
Chickens/NNS/O carry/VBP/O this/DT/O bacteria/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O can/MD/O cause/VB/O upset/JJ/O stomachs/NNS/O and/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O rare/JJ/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O death/NN/O among/IN/O people/NNS/O ././O
Hens/NNS/O sometimes/RB/O pass/VBP/O salmonella/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O eggs/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O found/VBN/O on/IN/O unclean/JJ/O shells/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON claims/VBZ/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O manageable/JJ/O problem/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O salmonella/NN/O cases/NNS/O involving/VBG/O products/NNS/O that/WDT/O may/MD/O have/VB/O used/VBN/O eggs/NNS/O broken/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/B-FAC Egg/NNP/I-FAC King/NNP/I-FAC stemmed/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O failure/NN/O to/TO/O adequately/RB/O cook/VB/O the/DT/O products/NNS/O ././O
Opponents/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O buy/VB/O such/JJ/O arguments/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O early/JJ/O battleground/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Department/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Agriculture/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O also/RB/O lobbied/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Food/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O company/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O was/VBD/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Ana/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O enlisted/VBD/O his/PRP$/O local/JJ/O congressman/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O battle/NN/O was/VBD/O joined/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O forces/NNS/O finally/RB/O defeated/VBD/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O floor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Representatives/NNPS/I-ORG to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
An/DT/O antitrust/JJ/O suit/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O filed/VBD/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE federal/JJ/O court/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Egg/NNP/I-ORG Producers/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O only/RB/O added/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O entrepreneur/NN/O 's/POS/O woes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O dismissed/VBD/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O ordered/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O over/IN/O $/$/O 100,000/CD/O in/IN/O legal/JJ/O fees/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O defendants/NNS/O '/POS/O lawyers/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O pushed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O into/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O court/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON recently/RB/O fell/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O horse/NN/O and/CC/O fractured/VBD/O his/PRP$/O arm/NN/O ././O
