Tandy/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O signed/VBD/O a/DT/O definitive/JJ/O agreement/NN/O to/TO/O acquire/VB/O two/CD/O units/NNS/O of/IN/O Datatronic/NNP/B-ORG AB/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Stockholm/NNP/B-GPE for/IN/O cash/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O amount/NN/O was/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Tandy/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O acquire/VB/O rights/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Victor/NNP/O and/CC/O Micronic/NNP/O names/NNS/O for/IN/O computers/NNS/O ././O
During/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O the/DT/O Datatronic/NNP/B-ORG subsidiaries/NNS/O had/VBD/O combined/VBN/O sales/NNS/O in/IN/O excess/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 200/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Closing/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O is/VBZ/O subject/JJ/O to/TO/O certain/JJ/O conditions/NNS/O and/CC/O regulatory/JJ/O approvals/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O company/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
