An/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 33/CD/O million/CD/O was/VBD/O added/VBN/O for/IN/O university/NN/O and/CC/O science/NN/O grants/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O $/$/O 1.5/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O Smith/NNP/B-ORG College/NNP/I-ORG ././O
More/JJR/O than/IN/O $/$/O 1.8/CD/O million/CD/O is/VBZ/O allocated/VBN/O for/IN/O pensions/NNS/O and/CC/O expenses/NNS/O for/IN/O former/JJ/O presidents/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O official/JJ/O residence/NN/O of/IN/O Vice/NNP/O President/NNP/O Quayle/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O more/RBR/O than/IN/O doubled/VBN/O ,/,/O with/IN/O $/$/O 200,000/CD/O designated/VBN/O for/IN/O improvements/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O property/NN/O ././O
Even/RB/O the/DT/O Office/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Budget/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O remembered/VBN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O extra/JJ/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O offset/VB/O pay/NN/O costs/NNS/O that/IN/O other/JJ/O government/NN/O departments/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O asked/VBD/O to/TO/O absorb/VB/O ././O
Within/IN/O the/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O nearly/RB/O $/$/O 1.95/CD/O billion/CD/O is/VBZ/O provided/VBN/O for/IN/O processing/VBG/O tax/NN/O returns/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O 12/CD/O %/NN/O increase/NN/O over/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1989/CD/O and/CC/O double/JJ/O what/WP/O the/DT/O government/NN/O was/VBD/O spending/VBG/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ././O
Investigation/NN/O and/CC/O taxpayer/NN/O service/NN/O accounts/NNS/O would/MD/O grow/VB/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1.6/CD/O billion/CD/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG specifically/RB/O added/VBD/O $/$/O 7.4/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O stepped/VBN/O up/RB/O criminal/JJ/O investigations/NNS/O of/IN/O money/NN/O laundering/NN/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O drug/NN/O traffic/NN/O ././O
Despite/IN/O administration/NN/O reservations/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O plan/NN/O has/VBZ/O had/VBN/O the/DT/O quiet/JJ/O backing/NN/O of/IN/O customs/NNS/O officials/NNS/O as/RB/O well/RB/O as/IN/O influential/JJ/O lawmakers/NNS/O from/IN/O Cessna/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O home/NN/O state/NN/O ,/,/O Kansas/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Repeal/NN/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O likely/RB/O now/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O Treasury/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG bill/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O used/VBN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O vehicle/NN/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O the/DT/O profile/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O and/CC/O block/VB/O any/DT/O action/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O interim/NN/O ././O
Less/RBR/O noticed/JJ/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O bit/NN/O of/IN/O legislative/JJ/O legerdemain/NN/O by/IN/O Houston/NNP/B-GPE Republicans/NNPS/O on/IN/O behalf/NN/O of/IN/O HEI/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O Texas/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O retroactively/RB/O ``/``/O move/VB/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Missouri/NNP/B-GPE hospital/NN/O from/IN/O one/CD/O county/NN/B-GPE to/TO/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O to/TO/O justify/VB/O higher/JJR/O Medicare/NNP/B-ORG reimbursements/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O development/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O private/JJ/O meeting/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O this/DT/O morning/NN/O between/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG Appropriations/NNPS/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG Chairman/NNP/O Jamie/NNP/B-PERSON Whitten/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Miss/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O and/CC/O Sen./NNP/O Dale/NNP/B-PERSON Bumpers/NNP/I-PERSON -LRB-/-LRB-/O D./NNP/O ,/,/O Ark/NNP/B-GPE ././I-GPE -RRB-/-RRB-/O in/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O end/VB/O a/DT/O dispute/NN/O which/WDT/O for/IN/O two/CD/O weeks/NNS/O has/VBZ/O delayed/VBN/O action/NN/O on/IN/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 44/CD/O billion/CD/O agriculture/NN/O bill/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O program/NN/O 's/POS/O nonprofit/JJ/O sponsors/NNS/O received/VBD/O $/$/O 900,000/CD/O in/IN/O fiscal/JJ/O 1989/CD/O through/IN/O an/DT/O Extension/NNP/O Service/NNP/O grant/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Whitten/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O adamant/JJ/O in/IN/O insisting/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
