The/DT/O amount/NN/O would/MD/O help/VB/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE cope/VB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O few/JJ/O weeks/NNS/O after/IN/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O anticipated/JJ/O quake/NN/O ,/,/O while/IN/O waiting/VBG/O for/IN/O federal/JJ/O assistance/NN/O to/TO/O arrive/VB/O ././O
After/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE Mayor/NNP/O Art/NNP/B-PERSON Agnos/NNP/I-PERSON spoke/VBD/O on/IN/O television/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O need/NN/O for/IN/O building/NN/O inspectors/NNS/O to/TO/O check/VB/O the/DT/O soundness/NN/O of/IN/O buildings/NNS/O ,/,/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE dispatched/VBD/O 32/CD/O inspectors/NNS/O to/TO/O help/VB/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O county/NN/O of/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE placed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O firefighters/NNS/O and/CC/O sheriffs/NNS/O on/IN/O alert/JJ/O ,/,/O ready/JJ/O to/TO/O send/VB/O in/IN/O reinforcements/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O alerted/VBD/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE that/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O has/VBZ/O 1,000/CD/O hospital/NN/O beds/NNS/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O disposal/NN/O ././O
Two/CD/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE radio/NN/O stations/NNS/O initiated/VBD/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG donation/NN/O campaigns/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O one/CD/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE bank/NN/O manager/NN/O forked/VBD/O over/RP/O $/$/O 150,000/CD/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O money/NN/O for/IN/O relief/NN/O purposes/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
It/PRP/O is/VBZ/O also/RB/O pulling/VBG/O 20/CD/O people/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Puerto/NNP/B-GPE Rico/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O who/WP/O were/VBD/O helping/VBG/O Huricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O victims/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O sending/VBG/O them/PRP/O to/TO/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE instead/RB/O ././O
