Yuba/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O ranked/VBD/O dead/JJ/O last/NN/O among/IN/O 329/CD/O metro/NN/O areas/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O almanac/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O making/VBG/O new/JJ/O friends/NNS/O and/CC/O enemies/NNS/O on/IN/O Oct./NNP/O 27/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O an/DT/O updated/VBN/O version/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O released/VBN/O ././O
Pittsburgh/NNP/B-GPE figures/VBZ/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O be/VB/O dethroned/VBN/O but/CC/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O its/PRP$/O ouster/NN/O graciously/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O city/NN/O 's/POS/O Office/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Promotion/NNP/I-ORG plans/VBZ/O media/NNS/O events/NNS/O to/TO/O welcome/VB/O its/PRP$/O successor/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O encouraging/VBG/O a/DT/O graceful/JJ/O transition/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Kay/NNP/I-PERSON Poppenberg/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O the/DT/O organization/NN/O 's/POS/O president/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Our/PRP$/O attitude/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O the/DT/O ranking/NN/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O is/VBZ/O like/IN/O Miss/NNP/B-PERSON America/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Once/RB/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O Miss/NNP/B-PERSON America/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O you/PRP/O 're/VBP/O always/RB/O Miss/NNP/B-PERSON America/NNP/I-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
Many/JJ/O Atlantans/NNPS/O thought/VBD/O Pittsburgh/NNP/B-GPE was/VBD/O an/DT/O unworthy/JJ/O heir/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O columnist/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Atlanta/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Constitution/NNP/I-ORG wrote/VBD/O :/:/O ``/``/O Who/WP/O did/VBD/O the/DT/O research/NN/O for/IN/O this/DT/O report/NN/O ?/./O
Two/CD/O guys/NNS/O from/IN/O Gary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ind./NNP/B-GPE ?/./O ''/''/O
Not/RB/O so/RB/O ././O
Co-authors/NNS/O David/NNP/B-PERSON Savageau/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Richard/NNP/B-PERSON Boyer/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O live/VBP/O in/IN/O Gloucester/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Asheville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O respectively/RB/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Savageau/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O earthquake/NN/O or/CC/O not/RB/O ,/,/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE makes/VBZ/O the/DT/O list/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O attention/NN/O also/RB/O rivets/VBZ/O on/IN/O who/WP/O finishes/VBZ/O last/RB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Pine/NNP/B-GPE Bluff/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Ark./NNP/B-GPE --/:/O which/WDT/O finished/VBD/O third/RB/O to/TO/O last/RB/O in/IN/O 1981/CD/O and/CC/O second/RB/O to/TO/O last/RB/O in/IN/O 1985/CD/O --/:/O is/VBZ/O certainly/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O running/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O hate/VBP/O to/TO/O dignify/VB/O the/DT/O publication/NN/O by/IN/O commenting/VBG/O on/IN/O the/DT/O obscene/JJ/O rating/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mayor/NNP/B-PERSON Carolyn/NNP/I-PERSON Robinson/NNP/I-PERSON says/VBZ/O ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O cities/NNS/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O rebut/VB/O the/DT/O book/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O like/IN/O fighting/VBG/O your/PRP$/O way/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O fog/NN/O ././O
You/PRP/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O know/VB/O which/WDT/O way/NN/O to/TO/O punch/VB/O ././O
