Without/IN/O federal/JJ/O subsidies/NNS/O to/TO/O developers/NNS/O of/IN/O beach/NN/O houses/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O economic/JJ/O and/CC/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O by/IN/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O in/IN/O South/NNP/B-GPE Carolina/NNP/I-GPE would/MD/O have/VB/O been/VBN/O much/RB/O less/JJR/O ,/,/O as/RB/O highlighted/VBN/O by/IN/O your/PRP$/O Oct./NNP/O 3/CD/O editorial/NN/O ``/``/O Subsidizing/VBG/O Disaster/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O you/PRP/O mentioned/VBD/O ,/,/O subsidies/NNS/O for/IN/O development/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O number/NN/O of/IN/O barrier/NN/O islands/NNS/O were/VBD/O curtailed/VBN/O in/IN/O 1982/CD/O by/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Coastal/NNP/I-ORG Barrier/NNP/I-ORG Resource/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Taxpayers/NNPS/I-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG would/MD/O like/VB/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O add/VB/O 800,000/CD/O acres/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O 453,000/CD/O of/IN/O shoreline/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O system/NN/O by/IN/O enacting/VBG/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Coastal/NNP/O Barrier/NNP/O Improvement/NNP/O Act/NNP/O of/IN/O 1989/CD/O ././O ''/''/O
This/DT/O bill/NN/O simply/RB/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O if/IN/O you/PRP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O develop/VB/O property/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O barrier/NN/O island/NN/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O so/RB/O without/IN/O taxpayer/NN/O support/NN/O ././O
Already/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O 1982/CD/O legislation/NN/O has/VBZ/O saved/VBN/O an/DT/O estimated/VBN/O $/$/O 800/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Marshall/NNP/B-PERSON Y./NNP/I-PERSON Taylor/NNP/I-PERSON
Communications/NNPS/O Director/NNP/O
National/NNP/B-ORG Taxpayers/NNPS/I-ORG Union/NNP/I-ORG
