Neither/DT/O side/NN/O would/MD/O comment/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O parties/NNS/O are/VBP/O currently/RB/O negotiating/VBG/O over/IN/O who/WP/O would/MD/O manage/VB/O the/DT/O building/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O emptied/VBN/O of/IN/O 6,000/CD/O employees/NNS/O from/IN/O Sears/NNP/B-ORG '/POS/O merchandise/NN/O group/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O moving/VBG/O elsewhere/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O manager/NN/O will/MD/O face/VB/O the/DT/O daunting/JJ/O task/NN/O of/IN/O leasing/VBG/O 1.8/CD/O million/CD/O square/JJ/O feet/NNS/O in/IN/O a/DT/O relatively/RB/O soft/JJ/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE real/JJ/O estate/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Convertible/JJ/O mortgages/NNS/O have/VBP/O become/VBN/O an/DT/O increasingly/RB/O popular/JJ/O way/NN/O to/TO/O finance/VB/O prestigious/JJ/O buildings/NNS/O of/IN/O late/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O main/JJ/O advantage/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O convertible/JJ/O mortgage/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O sale/NN/O and/CC/O therefore/RB/O does/VBZ/O not/RB/O trigger/VB/O costly/JJ/O transfer/NN/O taxes/NNS/O and/CC/O reappraisal/NN/O ././O
Sears/NNP/B-ORG then/RB/O went/VBD/O back/RB/O to/TO/O AEW/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O Boston/NNP/B-GPE pension/NN/O adviser/NN/O that/WDT/O had/VBD/O proposed/VBN/O a/DT/O convertible/JJ/O debt/NN/O deal/NN/O during/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O round/NN/O of/IN/O bids/NNS/O last/JJ/O spring/NN/O ././O
AEW/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O $/$/O 3.5/CD/O billion/CD/O of/IN/O real/JJ/O estate/NN/O investments/NNS/O nationwide/RB/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O ././O
