IBM/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Armonk/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O dominated/VBN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O for/IN/O decades/NNS/O ././O
Digital/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Maynard/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O hopes/VBZ/O to/TO/O stage/VB/O a/DT/O repeat/NN/O performance/NN/O in/IN/O mainframes/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O spent/VBN/O almost/RB/O $/$/O 1/CD/O billion/CD/O developing/VBG/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O technology/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O spoiler/NN/O ,/,/O nimble/JJ/O Tandem/NNP/B-ORG Computers/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Cupertino/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O jumped/VBD/O into/IN/O the/DT/O fray/NN/O earlier/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O with/IN/O an/DT/O aggressively/RB/O priced/VBN/O entry/NN/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG appears/VBZ/O more/RBR/O worried/JJ/O about/IN/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O broad/JJ/O base/NN/O of/IN/O customers/NNS/O waiting/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O ,/,/O dubbed/VBD/O the/DT/O VAX/NNP/O 9000/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O surge/NN/O in/IN/O competition/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O stir/VB/O new/JJ/O life/NN/O into/IN/O the/DT/O huge/JJ/O mainframe/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O growth/NN/O has/VBZ/O slowed/VBN/O to/TO/O single/JJ/O digits/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O traditional/JJ/O mainframe/NN/O rivals/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Unisys/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Control/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O NCR/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O have/VBP/O struggled/VBN/O recently/RB/O ././O
Digital/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O promising/VBG/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O approach/NN/O ././O
Robert/NNP/B-PERSON M./NNP/I-PERSON Glorioso/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O for/IN/O high/JJ/O performance/NN/O systems/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O mainframe/NN/O is/VBZ/O designed/VBN/O not/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O central/JJ/O computer/NN/O around/IN/O which/WDT/O everything/NN/O revolves/VBZ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O decentralized/JJ/O network/NN/O weaving/VBG/O together/RB/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O workstations/NNS/O ,/,/O personal/JJ/O computers/NNS/O ,/,/O printers/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O devices/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O challengers/NNS/O will/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O price/NN/O advantage/NN/O ././O
Digital/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O tag/VB/O its/PRP$/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O from/IN/O about/IN/O $/$/O 1.24/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 4.4/CD/O million/CD/O and/CC/O up/RB/O ,/,/O depending/VBG/O on/IN/O configuration/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O 's/VBZ/O about/IN/O half/NN/O the/DT/O price/NN/O of/IN/O comparably/RB/O equipped/VBN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG mainframes/NNS/O ././O
Tandem/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O pricing/NN/O is/VBZ/O just/RB/O as/RB/O aggressive/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O heightened/JJ/O competition/NN/O will/MD/O hit/VB/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG at/IN/O a/DT/O difficult/JJ/O time/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O computer/NN/O giant/NN/O 's/POS/O current/JJ/O mainframe/NN/O line/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O well/RB/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O huge/JJ/O profit/NN/O margins/NNS/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O starting/VBG/O to/TO/O show/VB/O its/PRP$/O age/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O new/JJ/O 3090s/NNS/O due/JJ/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O will/MD/O boost/VB/O performance/NN/O by/IN/O only/RB/O about/IN/O 8/CD/O %/NN/O to/TO/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O five/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG --/:/O and/CC/O 40/CD/O times/NNS/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O Tandem/NNP/B-ORG --/:/O and/CC/O wields/VBZ/O enormous/JJ/O market/NN/O power/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O counts/VBZ/O among/IN/O its/PRP$/O customers/NNS/O a/DT/O majority/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O corporations/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O entrust/VBP/O their/PRP$/O most/RBS/O critical/JJ/O business/NN/O information/NN/O to/TO/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG computers/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O key/NN/O marketing/NN/O target/NN/O for/IN/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O big/JJ/O customers/NNS/O who/WP/O already/RB/O own/VBP/O both/DT/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG systems/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O such/JJ/O company/NN/O is/VBZ/O Bankers/NNPS/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG Co/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Stanley/NNP/B-PERSON Rose/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O vice/NN/O president/NN/O ,/,/O technological/JJ/O and/CC/O strategic/JJ/O planning/NN/O at/IN/O Bankers/NNPS/B-ORG Trust/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O says/VBZ/O that/IN/O despite/IN/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O low/JJ/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O about/IN/O to/TO/O unplug/VB/O our/PRP$/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG mainframes/NNS/O for/IN/O a/DT/O DEC/NNP/B-ORG machine/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O bases/VBZ/O the/DT/O estimate/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O survey/NN/O of/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O largest/JJS/O customers/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O model/NN/O available/JJ/O will/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O 210/CD/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O appeal/VB/O to/TO/O many/JJ/O technical/JJ/O and/CC/O scientific/JJ/O buyers/NNS/O interested/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O optional/JJ/O super-charger/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O vector/NN/O processor/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Terry/NNP/B-PERSON Shannon/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O International/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O market/NN/O research/NN/O concern/NN/O ././O
Four/CD/O more/JJR/O models/NNS/O ,/,/O aimed/VBD/O squarely/RB/O at/IN/O IBM/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O commercial/JJ/O customers/NNS/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O shipping/VBG/O in/IN/O late/JJ/O June/NNP/O ././O
Most/JJS/O analysts/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O expect/VB/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O mainframes/NNS/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O contributing/VBG/O significantly/RB/O to/TO/O revenue/NN/O before/IN/O the/DT/O fiscal/JJ/O first/JJ/O quarter/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O begins/VBZ/O next/JJ/O July/NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
Digital/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O new/JJ/O line/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O long/JJ/O time/NN/O coming/VBG/O ././O
IBM/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O face/VB/O still/RB/O more/JJR/O competition/NN/O in/IN/O coming/VBG/O months/NNS/O ././O
Source/NN/O :/:/O International/NNP/B-ORG Data/NNP/I-ORG Corp/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Copyright/NN/O 1989/CD/O by/IN/O Reed/NNP/B-ORG Publishing/NNP/I-ORG USA/NNP/I-ORG ././O
