Enron/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Houston/NNP/B-ORG natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O pipeline/NN/O company/NN/O ,/,/O would/MD/O design/VB/O ,/,/O construct/VB/O and/CC/O run/VB/O the/DT/O plant/NN/O ././O
Gas/NN/O to/TO/O fuel/VB/O it/PRP/O would/MD/O be/VB/O piped/VBN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC North/NNP/I-LOC Sea/NNP/I-LOC ././O
A/DT/O subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Imperial/NNP/B-ORG Chemical/NNP/I-ORG Industries/NNPS/I-ORG would/MD/O buy/VB/O electricity/NN/O and/CC/O steam/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O proposed/JJ/O station/NN/O ././O
Surplus/JJ/O power/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O open/JJ/O market/NN/O ,/,/O Enron/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
