Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Maynard/NNP/I-PERSON offered/VBD/O the/DT/O world/NN/O a/DT/O faster/JJR/O way/NN/O to/TO/O break/VB/O eggs/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O thanks/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O egg/NN/O industry/NN/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O break/VB/O him/PRP/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O have/VBP/O done/VBN/O a/DT/O pretty/RB/O good/JJ/O job/NN/O ././O
They/PRP/O tried/VBD/O to/TO/O put/VB/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON out/IN/O of/IN/O business/NN/O by/IN/O an/DT/O act/NN/O of/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ././O
His/PRP$/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Misa/NNP/B-ORG Manufacturing/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O forced/VBN/O to/TO/O seek/VB/O protection/NN/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O under/IN/O federal/JJ/O bankruptcy/NN/O law/NN/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O since/RB/O been/VBN/O liquidated/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O entrepreneur/NN/O to/TO/O bump/VB/O up/RP/O against/IN/O entrenched/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O his/PRP$/O case/NN/O is/VBZ/O notable/JJ/O both/DT/O for/IN/O the/DT/O scale/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O fight/NN/O --/:/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O often/RB/O that/IN/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O hearing/NN/O is/VBZ/O held/VBN/O to/TO/O determine/VB/O whether/IN/O one/CD/O small/JJ/O businessman/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O threat/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O republic/NN/O --/:/O and/CC/O for/IN/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O tells/VBZ/O about/IN/O the/DT/O pitfalls/NNS/O of/IN/O marketing/NN/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O product/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O one/PRP/O might/MD/O ask/VB/O why/WRB/O people/NNS/O who/WP/O sell/VBP/O eggs/NNS/O would/MD/O fight/VB/O someone/NN/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O make/VB/O it/PRP/O easier/RBR/O to/TO/O crack/VB/O them/PRP/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O answer/NN/O lies/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O nature/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O industry/NN/O ././O
Many/JJ/O larger/JJR/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O are/VBP/O also/RB/O egg/NN/O processors/NNS/O ,/,/O who/WP/O crack/VBP/O ,/,/O inspect/VBP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O sanitize/VBP/O billions/NNS/O of/IN/O eggs/NNS/O ,/,/O turning/VBG/O them/PRP/O into/IN/O powdered/JJ/O ,/,/O liquified/JJ/O or/CC/O frozen/JJ/O egg/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O for/IN/O companies/NNS/O that/WDT/O use/VBP/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O eggs/NNS/O a/DT/O day/NN/O ,/,/O breaking/VBG/O them/PRP/O by/IN/O hand/NN/O can/MD/O get/VB/O ,/,/O well/RB/O ,/,/O out/IN/O of/IN/O hand/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O idea/NN/O behind/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Egg/NNP/I-FAC King/NNP/I-FAC is/VBZ/O pretty/JJ/O simple/NN/O :/:/O put/VB/O the/DT/O eggs/NNS/O into/IN/O a/DT/O cylinder/NN/O that/WDT/O contains/VBZ/O perforated/JJ/O baskets/NNS/O ,/,/O spin/VB/O them/PRP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O high/JJ/O speed/NN/O to/TO/O break/VB/O the/DT/O shells/NNS/O and/CC/O strain/VB/O the/DT/O edible/JJ/O part/NN/O through/IN/O the/DT/O baskets/NNS/O ././O
Because/IN/O fresh/JJ/O eggs/NNS/O are/VBP/O less/RBR/O expensive/JJ/O than/IN/O processed/VBN/O ones/NNS/O ,/,/O a/DT/O big/JJ/O egg/NN/O user/NN/O can/MD/O recover/VB/O the/DT/B-FAC Egg/NNP/I-FAC King/NNP/I-FAC 's/POS/I-FAC $/$/O 3,390/CD/O cost/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Such/JJ/O centrifugal/JJ/O egg/NN/O breakers/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O around/IN/O since/IN/O the/DT/O 1890s/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O when/WRB/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON came/VBD/O forward/RB/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O machine/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O early/JJ/O 1970s/NNS/O nobody/NN/O else/JJ/O was/VBD/O offering/VBG/O them/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O main/JJ/O reason/NN/O :/:/O salmonella/NN/O ././O
Chickens/NNS/O carry/VBP/O this/DT/O bacteria/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O can/MD/O cause/VB/O upset/JJ/O stomachs/NNS/O and/CC/O ,/,/O in/IN/O rare/JJ/O cases/NNS/O ,/,/O death/NN/O among/IN/O people/NNS/O ././O
Hens/NNS/O sometimes/RB/O pass/VBP/O salmonella/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O eggs/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O it/PRP/O can/MD/O also/RB/O be/VB/O found/VBN/O on/IN/O unclean/JJ/O shells/NNS/O ././O
Thus/RB/O ,/,/O any/DT/O machine/NN/O that/WDT/O breaks/VBZ/O large/JJ/O amounts/NNS/O of/IN/O eggs/NNS/O at/IN/O once/RB/O has/VBZ/O the/DT/O potential/NN/O to/TO/O spread/VB/O salmonella/NN/O if/IN/O a/DT/O bad/JJ/O egg/NN/O gets/VBZ/O in/IN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O good/JJ/O ones/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON claims/VBZ/O this/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O manageable/JJ/O problem/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O nearly/RB/O 4,000/CD/O machines/NNS/O in/IN/O use/NN/O ,/,/O there/EX/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O no/DT/O salmonella/NN/O problems/NNS/O as/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O instructions/NNS/O were/VBD/O followed/VBN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON boasts/VBZ/O ././O
He/PRP/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O salmonella/NN/O cases/NNS/O involving/VBG/O products/NNS/O that/WDT/O may/MD/O have/VB/O used/VBN/O eggs/NNS/O broken/VBN/O by/IN/O an/DT/B-FAC Egg/NNP/I-FAC King/NNP/I-FAC stemmed/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O failure/NN/O to/TO/O adequately/RB/O cook/VB/O the/DT/O products/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O he/PRP/O says/VBZ/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O no/RB/O more/JJR/O a/DT/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O banning/VBG/O Egg/NNP/B-FAC Kings/NNPS/I-FAC than/IN/O bad/JJ/O drivers/NNS/O are/VBP/O a/DT/O reason/NN/O for/IN/O banning/VBG/O cars/NNS/O ././O
Opponents/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O buy/VB/O such/JJ/O arguments/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O Human/JJ/O nature/NN/O being/VBG/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O people/NNS/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O always/RB/O follow/VB/O instructions/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Guzewich/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O food/NN/O protection/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE state/NN/O Health/NNP/B-ORG Department/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Leading/VBG/O the/DT/O assault/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Egg/NNP/I-FAC King/NNP/I-FAC has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O United/NNP/B-ORG Egg/NNP/I-ORG Producers/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Decatur/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ga./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O trade/NN/O group/NN/O has/VBZ/O issued/VBN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O briefing/NN/O book/NN/O ''/''/O that/WDT/O claims/VBZ/O the/DT/O machine/NN/O is/VBZ/O ``/``/O a/DT/O health/NN/O hazard/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O trying/VBG/O ``/``/O to/TO/O make/VB/O a/DT/O fast/JJ/O buck/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O expense/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/O UEP/NNP/B-ORG declines/VBZ/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O attorney/NN/O ,/,/O Alfred/NNP/B-PERSON Frawley/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O says/VBZ/O the/DT/O group/NN/O 's/POS/O actions/NNS/O are/VBP/O motivated/VBN/O solely/RB/O by/IN/O ``/``/O health/NN/O concerns/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
An/DT/O early/JJ/O battleground/NN/O was/VBD/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE Department/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Agriculture/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Unfortunately/RB/O for/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O another/DT/O branch/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O USDA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Agricultural/NNP/I-ORG Marketing/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O was/VBD/O in/IN/O charge/NN/O of/IN/O eggs/NNS/O ././O
After/IN/O receiving/VBG/O complaints/NNS/O from/IN/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O ,/,/O this/DT/O branch/NN/O got/VBD/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O branch/NN/O to/TO/O rescind/VB/O its/PRP$/O approval/NN/O ,/,/O thus/RB/O limiting/VBG/O the/DT/O machine/NN/O 's/POS/O potential/JJ/O market/NN/O to/TO/O bakeries/NNS/O and/CC/O restaurants/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O establishments/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O n't/RB/O regulated/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O USDA/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O also/RB/O lobbied/VBD/O the/DT/B-ORG Food/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Drug/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O FDA/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O a/DT/O 1985/CD/O letter/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Egg/NNP/I-ORG Producers/NNPS/I-ORG said/VBD/O that/IN/O there/EX/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O little/JJ/O likelihood/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O a/DT/O health/NN/O problem/NN/O as/RB/O long/RB/O as/IN/O instructions/NNS/O were/VBD/O followed/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O whose/WP$/O company/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O was/VBD/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-GPE Ana/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O enlisted/VBD/O his/PRP$/O local/JJ/O congressman/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O battle/NN/O was/VBD/O joined/VBN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O forces/NNS/O finally/RB/O defeated/VBD/O the/DT/O measure/NN/O ,/,/O though/IN/O it/PRP/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O vote/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O floor/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Representatives/NNPS/I-ORG to/TO/O do/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Even/RB/O then/RB/O ,/,/O opponents/NNS/O managed/VBD/O to/TO/O get/VB/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O hearing/NN/O to/TO/O examine/VB/O what/WP/O one/CD/O congressman/NN/O called/VBD/O an/DT/O ``/``/O unscrupulous/JJ/O ''/''/O method/NN/O for/IN/O breaking/VBG/O eggs/NNS/O ././O
Foiled/VBN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O get/VB/O a/DT/O national/JJ/O ban/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O egg/NN/O producers/NNS/O turned/VBD/O their/PRP$/O attention/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O states/NNS/O ././O
So/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O New/NNP/B-GPE Jersey/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Nebraska/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Georgia/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Michigan/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Minnesota/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O outlawed/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O device/NN/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O health/NN/O concerns/NNS/O ././O
An/DT/O antitrust/JJ/O suit/NN/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O filed/VBD/O in/IN/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE federal/JJ/O court/NN/O against/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG United/NNP/I-ORG Egg/NNP/I-ORG Producers/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O others/NNS/O only/RB/O added/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O entrepreneur/NN/O 's/POS/O woes/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O judge/NN/O dismissed/VBD/O the/DT/O suit/NN/O and/CC/O ordered/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O company/NN/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O over/IN/O $/$/O 100,000/CD/O in/IN/O legal/JJ/O fees/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/O defendants/NNS/O '/POS/O lawyers/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O the/DT/O ruling/NN/O pushed/VBD/O his/PRP$/O company/NN/O into/IN/O bankruptcy/NN/O court/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O he/PRP/O has/VBZ/O moved/VBN/O to/TO/O Oklahoma/NNP/B-GPE where/WRB/O costs/NNS/O are/VBP/O lower/JJR/O ,/,/O and/CC/O started/VBD/O a/DT/O new/JJ/O company/NN/O ,/,/O Adsi/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O to/TO/O market/VB/O his/PRP$/O machine/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O so/RB/O far/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O change/NN/O of/IN/O scenery/NN/O has/VBZ/O n't/RB/O ended/VBD/O his/PRP$/O string/NN/O of/IN/O bad/JJ/O breaks/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Maynard/NNP/B-PERSON recently/RB/O fell/VBD/O from/IN/O a/DT/O horse/NN/O and/CC/O fractured/VBD/O his/PRP$/O arm/NN/O ././O
