Federal/NNP/B-ORG Paper/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O completed/VBD/O the/DT/O previously/RB/O announced/VBN/O purchase/NN/O of/IN/O Imperial/NNP/B-ORG Cup/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O closely/RB/O held/JJ/O maker/NN/O of/IN/O paper/NN/O cups/NNS/O based/VBN/O in/IN/O Kenton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Terms/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O disclosed/VBN/O ././O
Imperial/NNP/B-ORG Cup/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O annual/JJ/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O approximately/RB/O $/$/O 75/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Federal/NNP/B-ORG Paper/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG sells/VBZ/O paper/NN/O and/CC/O wood/NN/O products/NNS/O ././O
