Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG already/RB/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O approached/VBN/O by/IN/O ``/``/O about/IN/O half/PDT/O a/DT/O dozen/NN/O ''/''/O companies/NNS/B-ORG interested/JJ/O in/IN/O buying/VBG/O all/DT/O or/CC/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O spirits/NNS/O business/NN/O ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Beefeater/NNP/B-ORG alone/RB/O is/VBZ/O worth/JJ/O as/IN/O much/RB/O as/IN/O #/#/O 300/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O analysts/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG bought/VBD/O the/DT/O Beefeater/NNP/B-ORG distillery/NN/O two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O for/IN/O #/#/O 174.5/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
That/DT/O purchase/NN/O represented/VBD/O an/DT/O attempt/NN/O by/IN/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O venerable/JJ/O British/JJ/O brewer/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O become/VB/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O player/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O global/JJ/O liquor/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
Grand/NNP/B-ORG Met/NNP/I-ORG owns/VBZ/O Bombay/NNP/B-ORG gin/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O No./NN/O 3/CD/O imported/VBN/O gin/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O rival/JJ/O Guinness/NNP/B-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O the/DT/O No./NN/O 1/CD/O imported/VBN/O brand/NN/O ,/,/O Tanqueray/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG spirits/NNS/O auction/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O an/DT/O extremely/RB/O interesting/JJ/O development/NN/O .../:/O and/CC/O naturally/RB/O we/PRP/O 'll/MD/O be/VB/O considering/VBG/O it/PRP/O carefully/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O a/DT/O Grand/NNP/B-ORG Met/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Guinness/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O several/JJ/O leading/VBG/O whiskey/NN/O brands/NNS/O plus/CC/O Gordon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O gin/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O world/NN/O 's/POS/O No./NN/O 1/CD/O gin/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O considered/VBN/O less/RBR/O likely/JJ/O to/TO/O bid/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG spirits/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O Guinness/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O declined/VBD/O to/TO/O comment/VB/O ././O
A/DT/O Seagram/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O in/IN/O New/NNP/B-GPE York/NNP/I-GPE would/MD/O n't/RB/O comment/VB/O ././O
Such/JJ/O companies/NNS/O ``/``/O are/VBP/O increasingly/RB/O being/VBG/O left/RB/O behind/RB/O ''/''/O in/IN/O the/DT/O global/JJ/O liquor/NN/O business/NN/O ,/,/O says/VBZ/O Nomura/NN/B-ORG 's/POS/O Mr./NNP/O Littleboy/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG had/VBD/O total/JJ/O pretax/JJ/O profit/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O year/NN/O ended/VBN/O Feb./NNP/O 25/CD/O of/IN/O #/#/O 223.2/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O on/IN/O sales/NNS/O of/IN/O #/#/O 2.26/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O spirits/NNS/O auction/NN/O occurs/VBZ/O amid/IN/O a/DT/O parallel/JJ/O shakeup/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O beer/NN/O industry/NN/O ././O
British/JJ/O brewers/NNS/O currently/RB/O own/VBP/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O pubs/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O in/RB/O turn/RB/O sell/VBP/O only/RB/O the/DT/O breweries/NNS/O '/POS/O beer/NN/O and/CC/O soft/JJ/O drinks/NNS/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG now/RB/O intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O bolster/VB/O its/PRP$/O brewing/NN/O interests/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O grab/VB/O a/DT/O share/NN/O of/IN/O sales/NNS/O to/TO/O free/JJ/O houses/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O company/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O paid/VBD/O #/#/O 50.7/CD/O million/CD/O for/IN/O regional/JJ/O British/JJ/O brewer/NN/O Boddington/NNP/B-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG PLC/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O has/VBZ/O about/IN/O 13/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O British/JJ/O beer/NN/O market/NN/O ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O license/NN/O to/TO/O brew/VB/O and/CC/O distribute/VB/O Heineken/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O Stella/NNP/B-ORG Artois/NNP/I-ORG beers/NNS/O in/IN/O Britain/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Whitbread/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O announced/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Jarvis/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O 48/CD/O ,/,/O will/MD/O become/VB/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O March/NNP/O 1/CD/O ././O
He/PRP/O will/MD/O retain/VB/O the/DT/O honorary/JJ/O title/NN/O of/IN/O non-executive/JJ/O chairman/NN/O ././O
