One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O most/RBS/O remarkable/JJ/O features/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O forced/JJ/O marches/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O ethnic/JJ/O Turks/NNPS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O Bulgaria/NNP/B-GPE over/IN/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O five/CD/O months/NNS/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O lack/NN/O of/IN/O international/JJ/O attention/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O deportation/NN/O of/IN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 315,000/CD/O men/NNS/O ,/,/O women/NNS/O and/CC/O children/NNS/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Bulgarian/JJ/O regime/NN/O adds/VBZ/O up/RP/O to/TO/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O migrations/NNS/O seen/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O postwar/JJ/O years/NNS/O ././O
Yet/CC/O some/DT/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O advancing/VBG/O a/DT/O chilling/VBG/O casuistry/NN/O :/:/O that/IN/O what/WP/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O seeing/VBG/O is/VBZ/O somehow/RB/O the/DT/O understandable/JJ/O result/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O historical/JJ/O sins/NNS/O committed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Turks/NNPS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O 16th/JJ/O century/NN/O ././O
Today/NN/O 's/POS/O Turks/NNPS/O in/IN/O Bulgaria/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O in/IN/O other/JJ/O words/NNS/O ,/,/O deserve/VBP/O what/WP/O is/VBZ/O coming/VBG/O to/TO/O them/PRP/O four/CD/O centuries/NNS/O later/RB/O ././O
As/IN/O if/IN/O this/DT/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O enough/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Judiciary/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O into/IN/O the/DT/O act/NN/O ././O
There/EX/O can/MD/O be/VB/O no/RB/O quibbling/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Armenians/NNPS/O endured/VBD/O terrible/JJ/O suffering/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O one/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O wonder/VB/O what/WP/O possible/RB/O good/JJ/O such/PDT/O a/DT/O resolution/NN/O will/MD/O achieve/VB/O ././O
It/PRP/O puts/VBZ/O great/JJ/O strain/NN/O on/IN/O a/DT/O longstanding/JJ/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE friendship/NN/O with/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O country/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O America/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O strongest/JJS/O allies/NNS/O in/IN/O NATO/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O resolution/NN/O also/RB/O comes/VBZ/O at/IN/O a/DT/O time/NN/O when/WRB/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O seeking/VBG/O help/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE United/NNP/I-GPE States/NNPS/I-GPE in/IN/O resolving/VBG/O its/PRP$/O Bulgarian/JJ/O emigration/NN/O controversy/NN/O and/CC/O pursuing/VBG/O democratic/JJ/O reforms/NNS/O that/WDT/O may/MD/O lead/VB/O to/TO/O membership/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG ././O
Turkey/NNP/B-GPE has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O fighting/VBG/O its/PRP$/O past/NN/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O thus/RB/O far/RB/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O only/RB/O partially/RB/O successful/JJ/O ././O
Must/MD/O it/PRP/O now/RB/O accept/VB/O that/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O strongest/JJS/O allies/NNS/O blames/VBZ/O it/PRP/O for/IN/O the/DT/O genocide/NN/O of/IN/O another/DT/O people/NNS/O ?/./O
Such/JJ/O sentiment/NN/O only/RB/O encourages/VBZ/O the/DT/O adverse/JJ/O feelings/NNS/O toward/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE that/WDT/O surfaced/VBD/O when/WRB/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE asked/VBD/O for/IN/O assistance/NN/O in/IN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O Bulgarian/JJ/O emigration/NN/O crisis/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Dole/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O odd/JJ/O effort/NN/O notwithstanding/IN/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O political/JJ/O problems/NNS/O lie/VBP/O with/IN/O the/DT/O Europeans/NNPS/O ././O
Part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O some/DT/O Europeans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O with/IN/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE seems/VBZ/O to/TO/O stem/VB/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O location/NN/O --/:/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O really/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ././O
Why/WRB/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O wonder/VBP/O ,/,/O should/MD/O it/PRP/O belong/VB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG ?/./O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O when/WRB/O these/DT/O rationalizations/NNS/O fall/VBP/O on/IN/O deaf/JJ/O ears/NNS/O that/IN/O the/DT/O old/JJ/O standby/NN/O of/IN/O retribution/NN/O for/IN/O treatment/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Ottoman/NNP/I-GPE Empire/NNP/I-GPE comes/VBZ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O fore/NN/O ././O
No/DT/O one/NN/O has/VBZ/O to/TO/O accept/VB/O the/DT/O sins/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Ottoman/NNP/I-GPE Empire/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O reject/VB/O that/DT/O argument/NN/O ././O
Turkey/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O any/DT/O event/NN/O is/VBZ/O long/JJ/O past/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O country/NN/O has/VBZ/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O accepted/VBN/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 500,000/CD/O refugees/NNS/O from/IN/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O four/CD/O bordering/VBG/O nations/NNS/O ././O
Kurds/NNPS/O ,/,/O suffering/VBG/O what/WP/O many/JJ/O people/NNS/O consider/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O a/DT/O current/JJ/O extermination/NN/O campaign/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O hands/NNS/O of/IN/O Syria/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Iraq/NNP/B-GPE have/VBP/O inundated/VBN/O eastern/JJ/O Turkey/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Now/RB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O their/PRP$/O fellow/NN/O Turks/NNPS/O arriving/VBG/O as/IN/O refugees/NNS/O from/IN/O Bulgaria/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O Turkish/JJ/O refugee/NN/O tragedy/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O ongoing/JJ/O crisis/NN/O can/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O ignored/VBN/O and/CC/O shuttled/VBN/O off/RB/O to/TO/O that/DT/O notorious/JJ/O dustbin/NN/O of/IN/O history/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O become/VBN/O so/RB/O convenient/JJ/O recently/RB/O ././O
Surely/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O past/JJ/O suffering/NN/O of/IN/O any/DT/O people/NNS/O at/IN/O any/DT/O time/NN/O can/MD/O not/RB/O be/VB/O simply/RB/O filed/VBN/O away/RB/O and/CC/O forgotten/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O what/WP/O the/DT/B-ORG Senate/NNP/I-ORG Judiciary/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O done/VBN/O in/IN/O supporting/VBG/O the/DT/O strongly/RB/O worded/VBN/O Armenian/JJ/O resolution/NN/O achieves/VBZ/O no/DT/O useful/JJ/O end/NN/O ;/:/O it/PRP/O merely/RB/O produces/VBZ/O more/JJR/O controversy/NN/O and/CC/O embittered/JJ/O memories/NNS/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O enough/JJ/O difficulty/NN/O dealing/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O realities/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O world/NN/O as/IN/O it/PRP/O currently/RB/O exists/VBZ/O ././O
Bulgaria/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O government/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O behaving/VBG/O beyond/IN/O the/DT/O pale/NN/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE does/VBZ/O its/PRP$/O values/NNS/O no/DT/O credit/NN/O by/IN/O ignoring/VBG/O that/IN/O while/IN/O casting/VBG/O its/PRP$/O votes/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O past/NN/O ././O
