As/IN/O the/DT/O citizens/NNS/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O surrounding/VBG/O communities/NNS/O began/VBD/O assessing/VBG/O the/DT/O damage/NN/O from/IN/O Tuesday/NNP/O 's/POS/O devastating/JJ/O earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG began/VBD/O assessing/VBG/O the/DT/O damage/NN/O from/IN/O what/WP/O some/DT/O said/VBD/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O failure/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O comprehensive/JJ/O coverage/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O 's/POS/O initial/JJ/O moments/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O In/IN/O terms/NNS/O of/IN/O coverage/NN/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O disaster/NN/O equal/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O earthquakes/NNS/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Eric/NNP/B-PERSON Premner/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O president/NN/O for/IN/O broadcasting/NN/O of/IN/O King/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O owns/VBZ/O the/DT/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG affiliate/NN/O in/IN/O Seattle/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Wash/NNP/B-GPE ././O
While/IN/O rival/JJ/O ABC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG outstripped/VBD/O the/DT/O competition/NN/O in/IN/O live/JJ/O coverage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O event/NN/O by/IN/O sheer/JJ/O luck/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/O network/NN/O was/VBD/O broadcasting/VBG/O the/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O from/IN/O Candlestick/NNP/O Park/NNP/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O struck/VBD/O --/:/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG was/VBD/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O its/PRP$/O signal/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O hour/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O attribute/VB/O the/DT/O lackluster/JJ/O performance/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O natural/JJ/O disaster/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Premner/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O So/CC/O before/IN/O I/PRP/O start/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O really/RB/O critical/JJ/O of/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O I/PRP/O would/MD/O like/VB/O to/TO/O know/VB/O more/JJR/O about/IN/O what/WP/O happened/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
There/EX/O were/VBD/O no/DT/O complaints/NNS/O from/IN/O affiliates/NNS/O of/IN/O CBS/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Cable/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Network/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Turner/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG System/NNP/I-ORG Inc/NNP/I-ORG ././O
But/CC/O that/DT/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O the/DT/O case/NN/O at/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O dogged/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O image/NN/O of/IN/O not/RB/O being/VBG/O aggressive/JJ/O on/IN/O major/JJ/O breaking/JJ/O stories/NNS/O ././O
Last/JJ/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O affiliates/NNS/O bitterly/RB/O complained/VBD/O to/TO/O network/VB/O executives/NNS/O about/IN/O the/DT/O poor/JJ/O coverage/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O student/NN/O uprising/NN/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O was/VBD/O not/RB/O pleased/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O slow/JJ/O start/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O neither/DT/O was/VBD/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Guy/NNP/B-PERSON Hempel/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O general/JJ/O manager/NN/O of/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG affiliate/NN/O WAVE/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O Louisville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ky/NNP/B-GPE ././O
A/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O National/NNP/B-ORG Broadcasting/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O network/NN/O was/VBD/O ``/``/O looking/VBG/O into/IN/O what/WP/O happened/VBN/O ././O ''/''/O
Don/NNP/B-PERSON Browne/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O director/NN/O of/IN/O news/NN/O at/IN/O NBC/NNP/B-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O an/DT/O interview/NN/O that/IN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O get/VB/O a/DT/O signal/NN/O out/IN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ././O
We/PRP/O were/VBD/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O box/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O was/VBD/O horrible/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O comment/NN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O hearing/VBG/O is/VBZ/O that/IN/O we/PRP/O were/VBD/O slow/JJ/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O box/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O beat/VBD/O everyone/NN/O else/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O stretch/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
NBC/NNP/B-ORG broadcast/VBD/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O entire/JJ/O night/NN/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O not/RB/O go/VB/O off/IN/O the/DT/O air/NN/O until/IN/O noon/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O quake/NN/O postponed/VBD/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O and/CC/O fourth/JJ/O games/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O series/NN/O is/VBZ/O scheduled/VBN/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O Tuesday/NNP/O evening/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ././O
``/``/O There/EX/O are/VBP/O no/DT/O commercials/NNS/O to/TO/O make/VB/O up/RP/O for/IN/O since/IN/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O eventually/RB/O broadcast/VB/O the/DT/O World/NNP/O Series/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O network/NN/O spokesman/NN/O ././O
