Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O stock/NN/O market/NN/O plunge/NN/O claimed/VBD/O its/PRP$/O second/JJ/O victim/NN/O among/IN/O the/DT/O scores/NNS/O of/IN/O futures/NNS/O and/CC/O options/NNS/O trading/NN/O firms/NNS/O here/RB/O ././O
Petco/NNP/B-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O an/DT/O options/NNS/O trading/NN/O firm/NN/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O family/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O deceased/JJ/O former/JJ/O Chicago/NNP/B-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG chairman/NN/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Peters/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O is/VBZ/O getting/VBG/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O trade/NN/O clearing/NN/O ,/,/O or/CC/O processing/NN/O and/CC/O guaranteeing/NN/O ,/,/O business/NN/O after/IN/O sustaining/VBG/O a/DT/O multimillion/JJ/O dollar/NN/O loss/NN/O Friday/NNP/O ,/,/O options/NNS/O industry/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Nearly/RB/O 75/CD/O options/NNS/O traders/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG who/WP/O cleared/VBD/O trades/NNS/O through/IN/O Petco/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O including/VBG/O a/DT/O handful/NN/O of/IN/O traders/NNS/O who/WP/O lost/VBD/O between/IN/O $/$/O 500,000/CD/O to/TO/O $/$/O 1/CD/O million/CD/O themselves/PRP/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O debacle/NN/O ,/,/O are/VBP/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O transfer/VB/O their/PRP$/O business/NN/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O clearing/NN/O firms/NNS/O ,/,/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
Timothy/NNP/B-PERSON Vincent/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Petco/NNP/B-ORG chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O confirmed/VBD/O that/IN/O Petco/NNP/B-ORG was/VBD/O withdrawing/VBG/O from/IN/O the/DT/O clearing/NN/O business/NN/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O owners/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O got/VBD/O a/DT/O look/NN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O potential/JJ/O risks/NNS/O in/IN/O this/DT/O business/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O after/IN/O Monday/NNP/O they/PRP/O felt/VBD/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O want/VB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O exposed/VBN/O any/DT/O more/JJR/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O Petco/NNP/B-ORG remained/VBD/O in/IN/O compliance/NN/O with/IN/O all/DT/O industry/NN/O capital/NN/O requirements/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O 's/POS/O rapid/JJ/O plunge/NN/O Friday/NNP/O and/CC/O Monday/NNP/O 's/POS/O rebound/NN/O ././O
A/DT/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O declined/VBD/O comment/NN/O on/IN/O Petco/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Over/IN/O the/DT/O weekend/NN/O Fossett/NNP/B-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O another/DT/O options/NNS/O trading/NN/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O transferred/VBD/O the/DT/O clearing/NN/O accounts/NNS/O of/IN/O about/IN/O 160/CD/O traders/NNS/O to/TO/O First/NNP/B-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O unit/NN/O of/IN/O Continental/NNP/B-ORG Bank/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O because/IN/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O n't/RB/O meet/VB/O regulatory/JJ/O capital/NN/O requirements/NNS/O after/IN/O Friday/NNP/O 's/POS/O market/NN/O slide/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O unprecedented/JJ/O transfer/NN/O of/IN/O accounts/NNS/O underscored/VBD/O the/DT/O options/NNS/O industry/NN/O 's/POS/O desire/NN/O not/RB/O to/TO/O have/VB/O its/PRP$/O credibility/NN/O tarnished/VBN/O by/IN/O potentially/RB/O widespread/JJ/O trading/NN/O defaults/NNS/O on/IN/O Monday/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O CBOE/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O American/NNP/B-ORG Stock/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Options/NNPS/B-ORG Clearing/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Stephen/NNP/B-PERSON Fossett/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O owner/NN/O of/IN/O Fossett/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O joined/VBN/O in/IN/O putting/VBG/O up/RP/O $/$/O 50/CD/O million/CD/O to/TO/O guarantee/VB/O the/DT/O accounts/NNS/O at/IN/O First/NNP/B-ORG Options/NNPS/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O head/NN/O of/IN/O another/DT/O small/JJ/O options/NNS/O clearing/NN/O firm/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O asked/VBD/O not/RB/O to/TO/O be/VB/O identified/VBN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O heightened/JJ/O volatility/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O financial/JJ/O markets/NNS/O in/IN/O recent/JJ/O years/NNS/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O increasingly/RB/O difficult/JJ/O for/IN/O any/DT/O but/IN/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O financial/JJ/O trading/NN/O firms/NNS/O to/TO/O shoulder/VB/O the/DT/O risk/NN/O inherent/JJ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O highly/RB/O leveraged/JJ/O options/NNS/O and/CC/O futures/NNS/O business/NN/O ././O
Prior/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O introduction/NN/O of/IN/O financial/JJ/O futures/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O late/JJ/O 1970s/NNS/O ,/,/O most/JJS/O trading/NN/O firms/NNS/O clustered/VBN/O around/IN/O the/DT/O LaSalle/NNP/B-FAC Street/NNP/I-FAC financial/JJ/O district/NN/O here/RB/O were/VBD/O family/NN/O operations/NNS/O handed/VBD/O down/RB/O from/IN/O one/CD/O generation/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O ././O
Most/JJS/O also/RB/O were/VBD/O relatively/RB/O undercapitalized/JJ/O compared/VBN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O size/NN/O of/IN/O most/JJS/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O securities/NNS/O firms/NNS/O ././O
