A/DT/O group/NN/O of/IN/O investors/NNS/O ,/,/O including/VBG/O Giancarlo/NNP/B-PERSON Parretti/NNP/I-PERSON 's/POS/I-PERSON Pathe/NNP/B-ORG Communications/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Sasea/NNP/B-ORG Holding/NNP/I-ORG S.A./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O have/VBP/O agreed/VBN/O to/TO/O buy/VB/O 76.66/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Odeon/NNP/B-ORG Finanziaria/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O financially/RB/O troubled/JJ/O Italian/JJ/O TV/NN/O station/NN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O sort/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Chapter/NN/O 11/CD/O situation/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O added/VBD/O ,/,/O referring/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE bankruptcy/NN/O law/NN/O that/WDT/O protects/VBZ/O companies/NNS/O from/IN/O creditors/NNS/O while/IN/O they/PRP/O restructure/VBP/O ././O
He/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O details/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O recapitalization/NN/O still/RB/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O be/VB/O worked/VBN/O out/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O that/DT/O Pathe/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O take/VB/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O Odeon/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Rome/NNP/B-GPE film/NN/O producer/NN/O Bruno/NNP/B-PERSON Lucisano/NNP/I-PERSON will/MD/O take/VB/O 10/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O remaining/VBG/O 16.66/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O currently/RB/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O Sasea/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O will/MD/O eventually/RB/O be/VB/O sold/VBN/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O investors/NNS/O ././O
Calisto/NNP/B-PERSON Tanzi/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O Odeon/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O owner/NN/O ,/,/O will/MD/O retain/VB/O his/PRP$/O 23.34/CD/O %/NN/O stake/NN/O ././O
Italy/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Supreme/NNP/B-ORG Court/NNP/I-ORG this/DT/O year/NN/O ordered/VBD/O Parliament/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O write/VB/O a/DT/O law/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O regulate/VB/O media/NNS/O ownership/NN/O ././O
