The/DT/O Berlin/NNP/O Wall/NNP/O still/RB/O stands/VBZ/O ././O
But/CC/O the/DT/O man/NN/O who/WP/O built/VBD/O it/PRP/O has/VBZ/O fallen/VBN/O ././O
East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE yesterday/NN/O removed/VBD/O Erich/NNP/B-PERSON Honecker/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O staunchest/JJS/O holdouts/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O reform/NN/O rumbling/VBG/O through/IN/O the/DT/O Communist/JJ/O world/NN/O ,/,/O in/IN/O an/DT/O effort/NN/O to/TO/O win/VB/O back/RB/O the/DT/O confidence/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O increasingly/RB/O rebellious/JJ/O citizens/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O while/IN/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O move/NN/O that/WDT/O stunned/VBD/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC ,/,/O it/PRP/O hardly/RB/O ushers/VBZ/O in/RB/O an/DT/O era/NN/O of/IN/O reform/NN/O --/:/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O anytime/RB/O soon/RB/O ././O
East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O clear/JJ/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O no/DT/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O the/DT/B-ORG Communist/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG now/RB/O shares/VBZ/O power/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O democratically/RB/O elected/JJ/O Solidarity/NNP/B-ORG union/NN/O ././O
Nor/CC/O is/VBZ/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O yesterday/NN/O the/DT/O parliament/NN/O approved/VBD/O constitutional/JJ/O changes/NNS/O meant/VBD/O to/TO/O help/VB/O turn/VB/O the/DT/O Communist/JJ/O nation/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O multiparty/JJ/O democracy/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O any/DT/O change/NN/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE has/VBZ/O enormous/JJ/O implications/NNS/O ,/,/O for/IN/O both/DT/O East/NNP/O and/CC/O West/NNP/O ././O
-LRB-/-LRB-/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O twice/RB/O hospitalized/VBN/O this/DT/O summer/NN/O for/IN/O a/DT/O gall/NN/O bladder/NN/O ailment/NN/O and/CC/O his/PRP$/O physical/JJ/O condition/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O intense/JJ/O speculation/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Western/JJ/O media/NNS/O ././O -RRB-/-RRB-/O
Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O formally/RB/O named/VBN/O to/TO/O all/DT/O three/CD/O positions/NNS/O once/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O parliament/NN/O convenes/VBZ/O later/RB/O this/DT/O week/NN/O ././O
His/PRP$/O grip/NN/O on/IN/O power/NN/O unraveled/VBN/O this/DT/O summer/NN/O as/IN/O thousands/NNS/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O countrymen/NNS/O ,/,/O dissatisfied/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O harshness/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O rule/NN/O ,/,/O fled/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O ././O
Thousands/NNS/O more/JJR/O have/VBP/O taken/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O month/NN/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE largest/JJS/O wave/NN/O of/IN/O domestic/JJ/O unrest/NN/O since/IN/O a/DT/O workers/NNS/O '/POS/O uprising/NN/O in/IN/O 1953/CD/O ././O
In/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O took/VBD/O a/DT/O characteristically/RB/O cautious/JJ/O and/CC/O skeptical/JJ/O view/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O leadership/NN/O change/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O official/JJ/O line/NN/O was/VBD/O to/TO/O offer/VB/O warmer/JJR/O ties/NNS/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O provided/VBN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O willing/JJ/O to/TO/O institute/VB/O reforms/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O strong/JJ/O doubts/NNS/O that/IN/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O reformer/NN/O ././O
Because/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O very/RB/O much/JJ/O in/IN/O accord/NN/O with/IN/O the/DT/O policies/NNS/O of/IN/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ././O ''/''/O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O on/IN/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O television/NN/O last/JJ/O night/NN/O that/IN/O there/EX/O will/MD/O be/VB/O no/DT/O sharing/NN/O of/IN/O power/NN/O with/IN/O pro-democracy/JJ/O groups/NNS/O ././O
He/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O while/IN/O dialogue/NN/O is/VBZ/O important/JJ/O ,/,/O enough/JJ/O forums/NNS/O already/RB/O exist/VBP/O ``/``/O in/IN/O which/WDT/O different/JJ/O interests/NNS/O ''/''/O can/MD/O express/VB/O themselves/PRP/O ././O
The/DT/O removal/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O apparently/RB/O the/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O bitter/JJ/O infighting/NN/O within/IN/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O ranks/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Communist/JJ/O party/NN/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O government/NN/O sources/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O several/JJ/O senior/JJ/O Politburo/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O fought/VBD/O over/IN/O the/DT/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O to/TO/O delay/VB/O any/DT/O decisions/NNS/O about/IN/O a/DT/O leadership/NN/O change/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O ,/,/O with/IN/O public/JJ/O demonstrations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O country/NN/O growing/VBG/O in/IN/O size/NN/O and/CC/O intensity/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O several/JJ/O key/JJ/O allies/NNS/O lost/VBD/O out/RB/O in/IN/O this/DT/O battle/NN/O ,/,/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O ././O
Those/DT/O allies/NNS/O included/VBD/O Politburo/NNP/B-ORG members/NNS/O Guenter/NNP/B-PERSON Mittag/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O has/VBZ/O long/RB/O headed/VBN/O economic/JJ/O affairs/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Joachim/NNP/B-PERSON Hermann/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O information/NN/O policy/NN/O ././O
Both/DT/O men/NNS/O were/VBD/O also/RB/O relieved/VBN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O duties/NNS/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
Although/IN/O other/JJ/O resignations/NNS/O may/MD/O follow/VB/O ,/,/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O still/RB/O not/RB/O clear/JJ/O to/TO/O what/WDT/O extent/NN/O the/DT/O change/NN/O in/IN/O party/NN/O personnel/NNS/O will/MD/O alter/VB/O the/DT/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O resistance/NN/O to/TO/O fundamental/JJ/O change/NN/O ././O
Clearly/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O central/JJ/O figure/NN/O in/IN/O this/DT/O process/NN/O is/VBZ/O Egon/NNP/B-PERSON Krenz/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
Born/VBN/O in/IN/O 1937/CD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O Baltic/NNP/B-LOC Sea/NNP/I-LOC town/NN/O now/RB/O part/NN/O of/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O eight/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O when/WRB/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O ended/VBN/O ././O
Like/IN/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O Chancellor/NNP/O Helmut/NNP/B-PERSON Kohl/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O he/PRP/O represents/VBZ/O the/DT/O postwar/JJ/O generation/NN/O that/WDT/O has/VBZ/O grown/VBN/O up/RB/O during/IN/O Germany/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O division/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O have/VBP/O had/VBN/O strikingly/RB/O similar/JJ/O career/NN/O paths/NNS/O ,/,/O both/DT/O having/VBG/O served/VBN/O as/IN/O chief/JJ/O of/IN/O internal/JJ/O security/NN/O before/IN/O their/PRP$/O rise/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O top/JJ/O party/NN/O position/NN/O ././O
Notably/RB/O ,/,/O one/CD/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O few/JJ/O official/JJ/O visits/NNS/O overseas/RB/O came/VBD/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O months/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O visited/VBD/O China/NNP/B-GPE after/IN/O the/DT/O massacre/NN/O in/IN/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O later/RB/O defended/VBD/O the/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O government/NN/O 's/POS/O response/NN/O during/IN/O a/DT/O separate/JJ/O visit/NN/O to/TO/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ././O
East/JJ/O German/JJ/O Protestantism/NNP/O in/IN/O particular/JJ/O fears/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O in/IN/O part/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O an/DT/O incident/NN/O in/IN/O January/NNP/O 1988/CD/O when/WRB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O believed/VBN/O to/TO/O have/VB/O ordered/VBN/O the/DT/O arrest/NN/O of/IN/O hundreds/NNS/O of/IN/O dissidents/NNS/O who/WP/O had/VBD/O sought/VBN/O refuge/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Church/NNP/B-ORG ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON also/RB/O has/VBZ/O a/DT/O reputation/NN/O for/IN/O being/VBG/O politically/RB/O savvy/JJ/O ././O
His/PRP$/O shrewd/JJ/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O read/VB/O the/DT/O shifting/VBG/O popular/JJ/O mood/NN/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O best/RBS/O illustrated/VBN/O by/IN/O his/PRP$/O apparent/JJ/O break/NN/O with/IN/O his/PRP$/O old/JJ/O mentor/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Indeed/RB/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O to/TO/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O government/NN/O sources/NNS/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O power/NN/O struggle/NN/O that/WDT/O toppled/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
In/IN/O recent/JJ/O days/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON has/VBZ/O sought/VBN/O to/TO/O project/VB/O a/DT/O kinder/JJR/O image/NN/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O a/DT/O report/NN/O widely/RB/O circulating/VBG/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Berlin/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O it/PRP/O was/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON who/WP/O ordered/VBD/O police/NNS/O to/TO/O stop/VB/O using/VBG/O excessive/JJ/O force/NN/O against/IN/O demonstrators/NNS/O in/IN/O Leipzig/NNP/B-GPE ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O not/RB/O a/DT/O reformer/NN/O --/:/O he/PRP/O wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O have/VB/O the/DT/O image/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O reformer/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
As/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O image/NN/O polishing/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O take/VB/O modest/JJ/O steps/NNS/O toward/IN/O reform/NN/O to/TO/O rebuild/VB/O confidence/NN/O among/IN/O the/DT/O people/NNS/O and/CC/O reassert/VB/O the/DT/O party/NN/O 's/POS/O authority/NN/O ././O
Besides/IN/O sacking/VBG/O other/JJ/O senior/JJ/O Politburo/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O who/WP/O allied/VBD/O themselves/PRP/O with/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O loosen/VB/O controls/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O news/NN/O media/NNS/O ,/,/O free/JJ/O up/RP/O travel/NN/O restrictions/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O establish/VB/O a/DT/O dialogue/NN/O with/IN/O various/JJ/O dissident/JJ/O groups/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O will/MD/O it/PRP/O be/VB/O enough/RB/O ?/./O
West/JJ/O German/JJ/O government/NN/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O Western/JJ/O analysts/NNS/O are/VBP/O doubtful/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O He/PRP/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O signify/VB/O what/WP/O people/NNS/O want/VBP/O ,/,/O so/CC/O the/DT/O unrest/NN/O will/MD/O go/VB/O on/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Oldenburg/NNP/B-PERSON predicts/VBZ/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O same/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O expectations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O great/JJ/O and/CC/O will/MD/O continue/VB/O to/TO/O grow/VB/O ././O
Says/VBZ/O one/CD/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O official/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O What/WP/O 's/VBZ/O necessary/JJ/O now/RB/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O process/NN/O of/IN/O democratization/NN/O ././O
Not/RB/O just/RB/O that/IN/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O heard/VBN/O but/CC/O that/IN/O their/PRP$/O interests/NNS/O are/VBP/O being/VBG/O taken/VBN/O seriously/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Chancellor/NNP/O Kohl/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O has/VBZ/O invited/VBN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON to/TO/O open/VB/O discussions/NNS/O with/IN/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE on/IN/O a/DT/O wide/JJ/O range/NN/O of/IN/O subjects/NNS/O ././O
Reports/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O press/NN/O ,/,/O citing/VBG/O sources/NNS/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O suggest/VBP/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O serve/VB/O only/RB/O as/IN/O a/DT/O bridge/NN/O between/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O a/DT/O genuine/JJ/O reform/NN/O leader/NN/O ././O
Adding/VBG/O to/TO/O that/DT/O speculation/NN/O is/VBZ/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O reputation/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O heavy/JJ/O drinker/NN/O ,/,/O who/WP/O is/VBZ/O said/VBD/O to/TO/O also/RB/O suffer/VB/O from/IN/O diabetes/NN/O ././O
``/``/O This/DT/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O dynamic/JJ/O process/NN/O and/CC/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O experiencing/VBG/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O step/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O the/DT/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE official/NN/O adds/VBZ/O ././O
The/DT/O selection/NN/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON may/MD/O also/RB/O disappoint/VB/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Soviet/JJ/O leader/NN/O Mikhail/NNP/B-PERSON Gorbachev/NNP/I-PERSON has/VBZ/O pressed/VBN/O hard/RB/O for/IN/O a/DT/O change/NN/O in/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE rigid/JJ/O stance/NN/O ././O
If/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON sticks/VBZ/O to/TO/O rigid/JJ/O policies/NNS/O the/DT/O pressure/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE could/MD/O intensify/VB/O ././O
In/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON sent/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON a/DT/O congratulatory/JJ/O telegram/NN/O that/WDT/O appeared/VBD/O to/TO/O urge/VB/O the/DT/O new/JJ/O leadership/NN/O to/TO/O heed/VB/O growing/VBG/O calls/NNS/O for/IN/O change/NN/O ././O
According/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O Soviet/JJ/O news/NN/O agency/NN/O Tass/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O ``/``/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON expressed/VBD/O the/DT/O conviction/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O leadership/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Socialist/NNP/I-ORG Unity/NNP/I-ORG Party/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/O -LCB-/-LRB-/B-GPE East/NNP/I-GPE -RCB-/-RRB-/I-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O being/VBG/O sensitive/JJ/O to/TO/O the/DT/O demands/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O ,/,/O .../:/O will/MD/O find/VB/O solutions/NNS/O to/TO/O complicated/JJ/O problems/NNS/O the/DT/O GDR/NNP/B-GPE -LCB-/-LRB-/O German/NNP/B-GPE Democratic/NNP/I-GPE Republic/NNP/I-GPE -RCB-/-RRB-/O encountered/VBD/O ././O ''/''/O
A/DT/O force/NN/O of/IN/O younger/JJR/O pro-Gorbachev/JJ/B-PERSON members/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O has/VBZ/O for/IN/O some/DT/O time/NN/O been/VBN/O pushing/VBG/O for/IN/O relaxation/NN/O within/IN/O their/PRP$/O country/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O older/JJR/O generation/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O torn/VBN/O between/IN/O a/DT/O fear/NN/O of/IN/O tampering/VBG/O with/IN/O the/DT/O status/NN/O quo/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O fear/NN/O of/IN/O what/WP/O might/MD/O happen/VB/O if/IN/O they/PRP/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O ././O
Unlike/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O nations/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O bloc/NN/O ,/,/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE is/VBZ/O a/DT/O creature/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Cold/NNP/O War/NNP/O ././O
Erasing/VBG/O the/DT/O differences/NNS/O still/RB/O dividing/VBG/O Europe/NNP/B-LOC ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O vast/JJ/O international/JJ/O reordering/NN/O that/DT/O implies/VBZ/O ,/,/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O endanger/VB/O the/DT/O statehood/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE or/CC/O a/DT/O Hungary/JJ/B-GPE ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O could/MD/O ultimately/RB/O lead/VB/O to/TO/O German/JJ/O reunification/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O disappearance/NN/O of/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE from/IN/O the/DT/O map/NN/O ././O
Which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Old/JJ/O Guard/NN/O fears/VBZ/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O 'm/VBP/O sure/JJ/O they/PRP/O 'll/MD/O formulate/VB/O a/DT/O reform/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O a/DT/O recipe/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O GDR/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O future/NN/O as/IN/O a/DT/O separately/RB/O identifiable/JJ/O state/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O Michael/NNP/B-PERSON Simmons/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O British/JJ/O journalist/NN/O whose/WP$/O book/NN/O on/IN/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O entitled/VBN/O ``/``/O The/DT/O Unloved/NNP/O Country/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O was/VBD/O published/VBN/O this/DT/O month/NN/O ././O
Up/IN/O to/TO/O now/RB/O ,/,/O that/IN/O recipe/NN/O has/VBZ/O consisted/VBN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O dogged/JJ/O effort/NN/O by/IN/O former/JJ/O leader/NN/O Walter/NNP/B-PERSON Ulbricht/NNP/I-PERSON to/TO/O establish/VB/O the/DT/O country/NN/O 's/POS/O international/JJ/O legitimacy/NN/O ,/,/O followed/VBN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O campaign/NN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O the/DT/B-LOC East/NNP/I-LOC bloc/NN/I-LOC 's/POS/I-LOC only/JJ/O successful/JJ/O Stalinist/JJ/O economy/NN/O into/IN/O a/DT/O consumer/NN/O paradise/NN/O ././O
Neither/DT/O man/NN/O achieved/VBD/O perfection/NN/O ././O
Early/RB/O in/IN/O 1987/CD/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O his/PRP$/O team/NN/O stopped/VBD/O paying/VBG/O thin/JJ/O compliments/NNS/O to/TO/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O joined/VBD/O with/IN/O Romania/NNP/B-GPE in/IN/O rejecting/VBG/O any/DT/O necessity/NN/O for/IN/O adjustments/NNS/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O systems/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O media/NNS/O soon/RB/O began/VBD/O presenting/VBG/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O speeches/NNS/O only/RB/O as/IN/O sketchy/JJ/O summaries/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O giving/VBG/O space/NN/O to/TO/O his/PRP$/O opponents/NNS/O ././O
By/IN/O late/JJ/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O they/PRP/O were/VBD/O banning/VBG/O Soviet/JJ/O publications/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O country/NN/O abandoned/VBD/O its/PRP$/O former/JJ/O devotion/NN/O to/TO/O socialist/JJ/O unity/NN/O and/CC/O took/VBD/O to/TO/O insisting/VBG/O instead/RB/O that/IN/O each/DT/O country/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O bloc/NN/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O travel/VB/O its/PRP$/O own/JJ/O road/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON spoke/VBD/O of/IN/O ``/``/O generally/RB/O valid/JJ/O objective/JJ/O laws/NNS/O of/IN/O socialism/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O left/VBD/O no/DT/O room/NN/O for/IN/O debate/NN/O ././O
With/IN/O this/DT/O year/NN/O 's/POS/O dislocations/NNS/O in/IN/O China/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O the/DT/B-GPE Soviet/NNP/I-GPE Union/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O the/DT/O drive/NN/O to/TO/O democracy/NN/O in/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Hungary/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O leadership/NN/O grew/VBD/O still/RB/O more/RBR/O defensive/JJ/O ././O
Politburo/NNP/B-ORG member/NN/O Joachim/NNP/B-PERSON Herrman/NNP/I-PERSON confessed/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O ``/``/O grave/JJ/O concern/NN/O ''/''/O over/IN/O Hungarian/JJ/O democracy/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Under/IN/O the/DT/O banner/NN/O that/WDT/O proclaims/VBZ/O the/DT/O `/``/O renewal/NN/O of/IN/O socialism/NN/O ,/,/O '/''/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O forces/NNS/O are/VBP/O at/IN/O work/NN/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O striving/VBG/O to/TO/O eliminate/VB/O socialism/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O loyal/JJ/O voices/NNS/O ,/,/O in/IN/O and/CC/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O Communist/JJ/O party/NN/O ,/,/O saw/VBD/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O unrest/NN/O coming/VBG/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O signs/NNS/O were/VBD/O economic/JJ/O ././O
Despite/IN/O heavily/RB/O subsidized/JJ/O consumer/NN/O industries/NNS/O ,/,/O East/NNPS/O Germans/NNPS/O have/VBP/O for/IN/O years/NNS/O watched/VBN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O pull/VB/O farther/RB/O out/RP/O ahead/RB/O ././O
In/IN/O 1988/CD/O ,/,/O for/IN/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O time/NN/O ,/,/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O came/VBD/O to/TO/O a/DT/O dead/JJ/O stop/NN/O ././O
Gingerly/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O economists/NNS/O began/VBD/O to/TO/O blame/VB/O central/JJ/O planning/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O writers/NNS/O in/IN/O theoretical/JJ/O journals/NNS/O even/RB/O raised/VBD/O the/DT/O notion/NN/O of/IN/O introducing/VBG/O democracy/NN/O ,/,/O at/IN/O least/JJS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O workplace/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O summer/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O independent/JJ/O reform/NN/O movement/NN/O was/VBD/O saying/VBG/O out/RB/O loud/RB/O what/WP/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O only/RB/O whispered/VBN/O before/RB/O ././O
But/CC/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O stalwart/JJ/O socialists/NNS/O ././O
Their/PRP$/O proclaimed/JJ/O purpose/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O cleanse/VB/O East/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Stalinist/JJ/O muck/NN/O ,/,/O not/RB/O to/TO/O merge/VB/O with/IN/O the/DT/O West/NNP/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O pastors/NNS/O has/VBZ/O envisioned/VBN/O a/DT/O ``/``/O new/JJ/O utopia/NN/O ''/''/O of/IN/O ``/``/O creative/JJ/O socialism/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
Meanwhile/RB/O ,/,/O the/DT/O man/NN/O Mr./NNP/O Krenz/NNP/B-PERSON replaces/VBZ/O has/VBZ/O left/VBN/O an/DT/O indelible/JJ/O mark/NN/O on/IN/O East/JJ/O German/JJ/O society/NN/O ././O
Imprisoned/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Nazis/NNPS/B-ORG during/IN/O World/NNP/O War/NNP/O II/NNP/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O political/JJ/O beliefs/NNS/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON typified/VBD/O the/DT/O postwar/JJ/O generation/NN/O of/IN/O committed/JJ/O Communist/JJ/O leaders/NNS/O in/IN/O Eastern/NNP/B-LOC Europe/NNP/I-LOC who/WP/O took/VBD/O their/PRP$/O cues/NNS/O from/IN/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ././O
He/PRP/O was/VBD/O a/DT/O ``/``/O socialist/JJ/O warrior/NN/O ''/''/O who/WP/O felt/VBD/O rankled/VBN/O by/IN/O West/NNP/B-GPE Germany/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE enormous/JJ/O postwar/JJ/O prosperity/NN/O and/CC/O the/DT/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE government/NN/O 's/POS/O steadfast/JJ/O refusal/NN/O to/TO/O recognize/VB/O the/DT/O legitimacy/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O state/NN/O ././O
Finally/RB/O ,/,/O during/IN/O his/PRP$/O first/JJ/O and/CC/O only/JJ/O state/NN/O visit/NN/O to/TO/O Bonn/NNP/B-GPE two/CD/O years/NNS/O ago/RB/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O won/VBD/O some/DT/O measure/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O recognition/NN/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O long/RB/O sought/VBN/O ././O
But/CC/O ultimately/RB/O he/PRP/O was/VBD/O undone/VBN/O by/IN/O forces/NNS/O unleashed/VBN/O by/IN/O his/PRP$/O own/JJ/O comrade/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Gorbachev/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
Mr./NNP/O Honecker/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O removal/NN/O ``/``/O was/VBD/O bound/VBN/O to/TO/O happen/VB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O says/VBZ/O one/CD/O aide/NN/O to/TO/O Chancellor/NNP/O Kohl/NNP/B-PERSON ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O was/VBD/O only/RB/O a/DT/O matter/NN/O of/IN/O time/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG European/NNP/I-ORG Community/NNP/I-ORG Commission/NNP/I-ORG increased/VBD/O its/PRP$/O forecast/NN/O for/IN/O economic/JJ/O growth/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O EC/NNP/B-ORG in/IN/O 1989/CD/O to/TO/O 3.5/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O slightly/RB/O higher/JJR/O than/IN/O its/PRP$/O June/NNP/O projection/NN/O of/IN/O 3.25/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
EC/NNP/B-ORG inflation/NN/O was/VBD/O seen/VBN/O at/IN/O 4.8/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1989/CD/O ,/,/O higher/JJR/O than/IN/O 1988/CD/O 's/POS/O 3.6/CD/O %/NN/O price/NN/O rise/NN/O ././O
However/RB/O ,/,/O inflation/NN/O for/IN/O 1990/CD/O was/VBD/O seen/VBN/O slowing/VBG/O to/TO/O 4.5/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Leading/VBG/O EC/NNP/B-ORG growth/NN/O forecasts/NNS/O in/IN/O 1989/CD/O was/VBD/O Ireland/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O seen/VBN/O growing/VBG/O 5/CD/O %/NN/O at/IN/O constant/JJ/O prices/NNS/O ././O
Slower/JJR/O growth/NN/O countries/NNS/O included/VBD/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O at/IN/O 2.5/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O U.K./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O at/IN/O 2.25/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Denmark/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O at/IN/O 1.75/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
Inflation/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O highest/JJS/O in/IN/O Greece/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O where/WRB/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O projected/VBN/O at/IN/O 14.25/CD/O %/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Portugal/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O at/IN/O 13/CD/O %/NN/O ././O
At/IN/O the/DT/O other/JJ/O end/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O spectrum/NN/O ,/,/O West/JJ/O German/JJ/O inflation/NN/O was/VBD/O forecast/VBN/O at/IN/O 3/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1989/CD/O and/CC/O 2.75/CD/O %/NN/O in/IN/O 1990/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O South/NNP/O Korean/NNP/O coffee/NN/O market/NN/O ,/,/O consisting/VBG/O mostly/RB/O of/IN/O instant/JJ/O coffee/NN/O ,/,/O was/VBD/O estimated/VBN/O at/IN/O about/IN/O 100/CD/O billion/CD/O won/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O $/$/O 150.7/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O ././O
Brands/NNS/O made/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Kraft/NNP/B-ORG General/NNP/I-ORG Foods/NNPS/I-ORG unit/NN/O of/IN/O Philip/NNP/B-ORG Morris/NNP/I-ORG Cos./NNP/I-ORG had/VBD/O about/IN/O 95/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O share/NN/O ././O
Nestle/NNP/B-ORG currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O only/RB/O about/IN/O a/DT/O 2/CD/O %/NN/O share/NN/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O Taster/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Choice/NNP/I-ORG coffee/NN/O ././O
Poland/NNP/B-GPE plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O start/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O soon/RB/O on/IN/O purchasing/VBG/O natural/JJ/O gas/NN/O from/IN/O Iran/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O official/JJ/O Islamic/NNP/B-ORG Republic/NNP/I-ORG News/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG reported/VBD/O ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O said/VBD/O Polish/JJ/O Prime/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Tadeusz/NNP/B-PERSON Mazowiecki/NNP/I-PERSON told/VBD/O Iranian/JJ/O Deputy/NNP/O Foreign/NNP/O Minister/NNP/O Mahmoud/NNP/B-PERSON Vaezi/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O Poland/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O willingess/NN/O to/TO/O purchase/VB/O the/DT/O gas/NN/O during/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Vaezi/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O current/JJ/O visit/NN/O to/TO/O Warsaw/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O mention/VB/O possible/JJ/O quantities/NNS/O and/CC/O did/VBD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O how/WRB/O the/DT/O gas/NN/O would/MD/O be/VB/O delivered/VBN/O ././O
A/DT/O Chinese/JJ/O official/NN/O harshly/RB/O criticized/VBN/O plans/NNS/O to/TO/O close/VB/O a/DT/O British/JJ/O naval/JJ/O base/NN/O in/IN/O downtown/NN/O Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Hong/NNP/B-GPE Kong/NNP/I-GPE officials/NNS/O announced/VBD/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O base/NN/O will/MD/O be/VB/O relocated/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O small/JJ/O island/NN/O to/TO/O allow/VB/O downtown/NN/O redevelopment/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O Beijing/NNP/B-GPE wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O use/VB/O the/DT/O base/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG People/NNS/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Liberation/NNP/I-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG after/IN/O 1997/CD/O ,/,/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O territory/NN/O returns/VBZ/O to/TO/O Chinese/JJ/O sovereignty/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O Israeli/JJ/O and/CC/O Soviet/JJ/O national/JJ/O airlines/NNS/O have/VBP/O reached/VBN/O preliminary/JJ/O agreement/NN/O for/IN/O launching/VBG/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O direct/JJ/O flights/NNS/O between/IN/O Tel/NNP/B-GPE Aviv/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Moscow/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O Israeli/JJ/O airline/NN/O ,/,/O El/NNP/B-ORG Al/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O said/VBD/O ././O
He/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O concluding/VBG/O the/DT/O deal/NN/O requires/VBZ/O approval/NN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O governments/NNS/O of/IN/O both/DT/O countries/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O have/VBP/O never/RB/O had/VBN/O direct/JJ/O air/NN/O links/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O chairman/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O director/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/B-GPE Republic/NNP/I-GPE of/IN/I-GPE Singapore/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE leading/VBG/O property/NN/O companies/NNS/O ,/,/O City/NNP/B-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O or/CC/O CDL/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O were/VBD/O charged/VBN/O yesterday/RB/O with/IN/O criminal/JJ/O breach/NN/O of/IN/O trust/NN/O of/IN/O some/DT/O 800,000/CD/O Singapore/NNP/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O about/IN/O US$/$/O 409,000/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ././O
Kwek/NNP/B-PERSON Hong/NNP/I-PERSON Png/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chairman/NN/O of/IN/O CDL/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O and/CC/O director/NN/O Quek/NNP/B-PERSON Leng/NNP/I-PERSON Chye/NNP/I-PERSON were/VBD/O arrested/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O republic/NN/O 's/POS/O Corrupt/NNP/B-ORG Practices/NNPS/I-ORG Investigation/NNP/I-ORG Bureau/NNP/I-ORG Tuesday/NNP/O night/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O charges/NNS/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O culmination/NN/O of/IN/O weeks/NNS/O of/IN/O rumors/NNS/O concerning/VBG/O CDL/NNP/B-ORG that/WDT/O have/VBP/O depressed/VBN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O share/NN/O price/NN/O and/CC/O to/TO/O a/DT/O lesser/JJR/O extent/NN/O the/DT/O shares/NNS/O of/IN/O all/DT/O companies/NNS/O owned/VBN/O by/IN/O CDL/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O controlling/JJ/O Quek/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O ,/,/O brokers/NNS/O in/IN/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE say/VBP/O ././O
The/DT/O Queks/NNPS/B-PERSON control/VBP/O the/DT/B-ORG Hong/NNP/I-ORG Leong/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O has/VBZ/O widespread/JJ/O interests/NNS/O in/IN/O manufacturing/NN/O ,/,/O property/NN/O and/CC/O finance/NN/O in/IN/O both/DT/O Malaysia/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE ././O
News/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O arrest/NN/O and/CC/O charging/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O helped/VBD/O to/TO/O push/VB/O prices/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O Singapore/NNP/B-GPE Stock/NNP/O market/NN/O sharply/RB/O lower/RBR/O in/IN/O early/JJ/O trading/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O brokers/NNS/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O the/DT/O market/NN/O and/CC/O CDL/NNP/B-ORG shares/NNS/O recovered/VBD/O once/IN/O it/PRP/O became/VBD/O apparent/JJ/O the/DT/O charges/NNS/O were/VBD/O limited/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O two/CD/O men/NNS/O personally/RB/O ././O
One/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O two/CD/O British/JJ/O companies/NNS/O still/RB/O making/VBG/O hard/JJ/O toilet/NN/O paper/NN/O stopped/VBD/O production/NN/O of/IN/O it/PRP/O ././O
British/NNP/B-ORG Tissues/NNPS/I-ORG decided/VBD/O to/TO/O do/VB/O away/RB/O with/IN/O its/PRP$/O hard/JJ/O paper/NN/O after/IN/O a/DT/O major/JJ/O customer/NN/O ,/,/O British/NNP/B-ORG Rail/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O switched/VBD/O to/TO/O softer/JJR/O tissues/NNS/O for/IN/O train/NN/O bathrooms/NNS/O .../:/O ././O
The/DT/O paper/NN/O said/VBD/O the/DT/O bricks/NNS/O were/VBD/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O build/VB/O homes/NNS/O and/CC/O furnaces/NNS/O and/CC/O ,/,/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O wall/NN/O ``/``/O is/VBZ/O in/IN/O terrible/JJ/O shape/NN/O ././O
