The/DT/O government/NN/O moved/VBD/O aggressively/RB/O to/TO/O open/VB/O the/DT/O spigots/NNS/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O aid/NN/O for/IN/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O reservoir/NN/O of/IN/O emergency/NN/O funds/NNS/O must/MD/O be/VB/O replenished/VBN/O soon/RB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O aid/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON signed/VBD/O a/DT/O disaster/NN/O declaration/NN/O covering/VBG/O seven/CD/O Northern/JJ/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC counties/NNS/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O an/DT/O unusually/RB/O wide/JJ/O array/NN/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O moved/VBD/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O specialized/JJ/O assistance/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O Hugo/NNP/O 's/POS/O wake/NN/O ,/,/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG allocated/VBD/O $/$/O 1.1/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O relief/NN/O funds/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O White/NNP/B-ORG House/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O Marlin/NNP/B-PERSON Fitzwater/NNP/I-PERSON said/VBD/O $/$/O 273/CD/O million/CD/O of/IN/O that/DT/O money/NN/O remains/VBZ/O and/CC/O could/MD/O be/VB/O diverted/VBN/O for/IN/O quick/JJ/O expenditures/NNS/O related/VBN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ././O
Now/RB/O ,/,/O though/RB/O ,/,/O enormous/JJ/O costs/NNS/O for/IN/O earthquake/NN/O relief/NN/O will/MD/O pile/VB/O on/IN/O top/NN/O of/IN/O outstanding/JJ/O costs/NNS/O for/IN/O hurricane/NN/O relief/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O attempting/VBG/O yet/RB/O to/TO/O estimate/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
But/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Fitzwater/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ,/,/O ``/``/O There/EX/O will/MD/O be/VB/O ,/,/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O quite/RB/O obviously/RB/O ,/,/O a/DT/O very/RB/O large/JJ/O amount/NN/O of/IN/O money/NN/O required/VBN/O from/IN/O all/DT/O levels/NNS/O of/IN/O government/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
In/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O lawmakers/NNS/O already/RB/O are/VBP/O looking/VBG/O for/IN/O ways/NNS/O to/TO/O add/VB/O relief/NN/O funds/NNS/O ././O
Money/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O added/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O pending/VBG/O spending/NN/O bill/NN/O covering/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Emergency/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O coordinates/VBZ/O federal/JJ/O disaster/NN/O relief/NN/O ././O
More/RBR/O likely/JJ/O ,/,/O relief/NN/O funds/NNS/O could/MD/O be/VB/O added/VBN/O to/TO/O an/DT/O omnibus/JJ/O spending/NN/O bill/NN/O that/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O to/TO/O begin/VB/O considering/VBG/O next/JJ/O week/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O just/RB/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O relief/NN/O dollars/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O spread/VBN/O thin/RB/O ;/:/O its/PRP$/O relief/NN/O manpower/NN/O also/RB/O is/VBZ/O stretched/VBN/O ././O
FEMA/NNP/B-ORG still/RB/O has/VBZ/O special/JJ/O disaster/NN/O centers/NNS/O open/RB/O to/TO/O handle/VB/O the/DT/O aftermath/NN/O of/IN/O Hugo/NNP/O ,/,/O and/CC/O spokesman/NN/O Russell/NNP/B-PERSON Clanahan/NNP/I-PERSON acknowledged/VBD/O that/IN/O ``/``/O we/PRP/O 're/VBP/O pretty/RB/O thin/JJ/O ././O ''/''/O
Mr./NNP/O Clanahan/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG now/RB/O possibly/RB/O may/MD/O have/VB/O the/DT/O heaviest/JJS/O caseload/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O history/NN/O ././O
To/TO/O further/RBR/O complicate/VB/O relief/NN/O efforts/NNS/O ,/,/O the/DT/O privately/RB/O funded/JJ/O American/NNP/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG also/RB/O finds/VBZ/O itself/PRP/O strapped/VBN/O for/IN/O funds/NNS/O after/IN/O its/PRP$/O big/JJ/O Hugo/NNP/O operation/NN/O ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O been/VBN/O a/DT/O bad/JJ/O month/NN/O money-wise/JJ/O and/CC/O every/DT/O other/JJ/O way/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Sally/NNP/B-PERSON Stewart/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O spokeswoman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O It/PRP/O just/RB/O makes/VBZ/O it/PRP/O a/DT/O little/RB/O rough/JJ/O when/WRB/O you/PRP/O have/VBP/O to/TO/O worry/VB/O about/IN/O the/DT/O budget/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
The/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O opened/VBN/O 30/CD/O shelters/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ,/,/O serving/VBG/O 5,000/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
All/PDT/O the/DT/O precise/JJ/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O aid/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O sent/VBN/O to/TO/O California/NNP/B-GPE wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O determined/VBN/O until/IN/O state/NN/O officials/NNS/O make/VBP/O specific/JJ/O requests/NNS/O to/TO/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O agency/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
And/CC/O in/IN/O the/DT/O confusion/NN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O ``/``/O the/DT/O information/NN/O flow/NN/O is/VBZ/O a/DT/O little/RB/O slow/JJ/O coming/VBG/O in/RB/O from/IN/O the/DT/O affected/JJ/O area/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Carl/NNP/B-PERSON Suchocki/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O a/DT/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
Still/RB/O ,/,/O some/DT/O aid/NN/O is/VBZ/O moving/VBG/O westward/RB/O from/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE almost/RB/O immediately/RB/O ././O
HUD/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O make/VB/O available/JJ/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 100/CD/O Bay/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/I-LOC houses/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O under/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG loans/NNS/O but/CC/O now/RB/O are/VBP/O vacant/JJ/O after/IN/O the/DT/O houses/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O inspected/VBN/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O sound/JJ/O ././O
Another/DT/O federal/JJ/O agency/NN/O not/RB/O normally/RB/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O disaster/NN/O relief/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/B-ORG Internal/NNP/I-ORG Revenue/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O moved/VBD/O quickly/RB/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O waive/VB/O certain/JJ/O tax/NN/O penalties/NNS/O for/IN/O earthquake/NN/O victims/NNS/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O return/NN/O deadlines/NNS/O or/CC/O make/VB/O payments/NNS/O because/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O 's/POS/O devastation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O announce/VB/O specific/JJ/O relief/NN/O procedures/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O coming/VBG/O days/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O advantage/NN/O that/IN/O federal/JJ/O officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O in/IN/O handling/VBG/O earthquake/NN/O relief/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O military/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC San/NNP/I-LOC Francisco/NNP/I-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ,/,/O facilities/NNS/O that/WDT/O provide/VBP/O a/DT/O ready/JJ/O base/NN/O of/IN/O supplies/NNS/O and/CC/O workers/NNS/O ././O
Even/RB/O before/IN/O the/DT/O full/JJ/O extent/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O devastation/NN/O was/VBD/O known/VBN/O ,/,/O Defense/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Dick/NNP/B-PERSON Cheney/NNP/I-PERSON ordered/VBD/O the/DT/O military/JJ/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O command/NN/O center/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O prepare/VB/O to/TO/O respond/VB/O to/TO/O various/JJ/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG requests/NNS/O for/IN/O assistance/NN/O ././O
By/IN/O yesterday/NN/O afternoon/NN/O ,/,/O Air/NNP/B-ORG Force/NNP/I-ORG transport/NN/O planes/NNS/O began/VBD/O moving/VBG/O additional/JJ/O rescue/NN/O and/CC/O medical/JJ/O supplies/NNS/O ,/,/O physicians/NNS/O ,/,/O communications/NNS/O equipment/NN/O and/CC/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG personnel/NNS/O to/TO/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
A/DT/O military/JJ/O jet/NN/O flew/VBD/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O delegation/NN/O and/CC/O senior/JJ/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O to/TO/O survey/VB/O the/DT/O damage/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O the/DT/O Pentagon/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O dozens/NNS/O of/IN/O additional/JJ/O crews/NNS/O and/CC/O transport/NN/O aircraft/NNS/O were/VBD/O on/IN/O alert/JJ/O ``/``/O awaiting/VBG/O orders/NNS/O to/TO/O move/VB/O emergency/NN/O supplies/NNS/O ././O ''/''/O
Some/DT/O victims/NNS/O also/RB/O were/VBD/O treated/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Letterman/NNP/I-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Naval/NNP/I-ORG Hospital/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O 20/CD/O military/JJ/O police/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O Presidio/NNP/B-FAC ,/,/O a/DT/O military/JJ/O base/NN/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O are/VBP/O assisting/VBG/O with/IN/O traffic/NN/O control/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O a/DT/O Navy/NNP/B-ORG ship/NN/O was/VBD/O moved/VBN/O from/IN/O a/DT/O naval/JJ/O station/NN/O at/IN/O Treasure/NNP/B-GPE Island/NNP/I-GPE near/IN/O the/DT/B-FAC Bay/NNP/I-FAC Bridge/NNP/I-FAC to/TO/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE to/TO/O help/VB/O fight/VB/O fires/NNS/O ././O
To/TO/O help/VB/O residents/NNS/O in/IN/O Northern/JJ/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC rebuild/VB/O ,/,/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG intends/VBZ/O to/TO/O set/VB/O up/RP/O 17/CD/O disaster/NN/O assistance/NN/O offices/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O area/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O next/JJ/O several/JJ/O days/NNS/O and/CC/O to/TO/O staff/VB/O them/PRP/O with/IN/O 400/CD/O to/TO/O 500/CD/O workers/NNS/O from/IN/O various/JJ/O agencies/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O Robert/NNP/B-PERSON Volland/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O chief/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O individual/JJ/O assistance/NN/O division/NN/O ././O
And/CC/O federal/JJ/O officials/NNS/O are/VBP/O promising/VBG/O to/TO/O move/VB/O rapidly/RB/O with/IN/O federal/JJ/O highway/NN/O aid/NN/O to/TO/O rebuild/VB/O the/DT/O area/NN/O 's/POS/O severely/RB/O damaged/JJ/O road/NN/O system/NN/B-FAC ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Highway/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O relief/NN/O program/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O states/NNS/O and/CC/O local/JJ/O governments/NNS/O repair/VB/O federally/RB/O funded/JJ/O highways/NNS/B-FAC and/CC/O bridges/NNS/O seriously/RB/O damaged/JJ/O by/IN/O natural/JJ/O disasters/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O account/NN/O currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O $/$/O 220/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
And/CC/O though/IN/O federal/JJ/O law/NN/O dictates/VBZ/O that/IN/O only/RB/O $/$/O 100/CD/O million/CD/O can/MD/O be/VB/O disbursed/VBN/O from/IN/O that/DT/O fund/NN/O in/IN/O any/DT/O one/CD/O state/NN/O per/IN/O disaster/NN/O ,/,/O administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O expect/VBP/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O move/VB/O in/RB/O to/TO/O authorize/VB/O spending/VBG/O more/JJR/O now/RB/O in/IN/O California/NNP/B-GPE ././O
To/TO/O get/VB/O that/DT/O money/NN/O ,/,/O states/NNS/O must/MD/O go/VB/O through/IN/O an/DT/O elaborate/JJ/O approval/NN/O process/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O officials/NNS/O expect/VBP/O red/JJ/O tape/NN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O cut/VBN/O this/DT/O time/NN/O ././O
Keith/NNP/B-PERSON Mulrooney/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O special/JJ/O assistant/NN/O to/TO/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Highway/NNP/I-ORG Administrator/NNP/I-ORG Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Larson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O 1971/CD/O San/NNP/B-GPE Fernando/NNP/I-GPE earthquake/NN/O in/IN/O Southern/NNP/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O the/DT/O state/NN/O set/VBD/O tougher/JJR/O standards/NNS/O for/IN/O bridges/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O with/IN/O federal/JJ/O aid/NN/O ,/,/O began/VBD/O a/DT/O program/NN/O to/TO/O retrofit/VB/O highways/NNS/B-FAC and/CC/O bridges/NNS/O for/IN/O earthquake/NN/O hazards/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O phase/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O completed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O phases/NNS/O are/VBP/O continuing/VBG/O ././O
Laurie/NNP/B-PERSON McGinley/NNP/I-PERSON contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
