Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O is/VBZ/O seething/VBG/O over/IN/O the/DT/O rules/NNS/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O would/MD/O curtail/VB/O the/DT/O tax/NN/O deductibility/NN/O of/IN/O debt/NN/O used/VBN/O in/IN/O most/JJS/O LBOs/NNS/O ././O
Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O has/VBZ/O all/DT/O but/CC/O conceded/VBD/O on/IN/O the/DT/O issue/NN/O and/CC/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O lobbying/VBG/O for/IN/O the/DT/O less/RBR/O onerous/JJ/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG version/NN/O of/IN/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O provisions/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O would/MD/O kill/VB/O that/DT/O deduction/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O label/VB/O any/DT/O such/JJ/O debt/NN/O as/IN/O equity/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O deductible/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O second/JJ/O provision/NN/O passed/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O House/NNP/B-ORG would/MD/O eliminate/VB/O a/DT/O rule/NN/O allowing/VBG/O companies/NNS/O that/IN/O post/NN/O losses/NNS/O resulting/VBG/O from/IN/O LBO/NN/O debt/NN/O to/TO/O receive/VB/O refunds/NNS/O of/IN/O taxes/NNS/O paid/VBN/O over/IN/O the/DT/O previous/JJ/O three/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
Several/JJ/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O officials/NNS/O say/VBP/O the/DT/O proposed/VBN/O legislation/NN/O already/RB/O is/VBZ/O having/VBG/O an/DT/O impact/NN/O ././O
An/DT/O investment/NN/O group/NN/O led/VBN/O by/IN/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE 's/POS/O Pritzker/NNP/B-PERSON family/NN/O recently/RB/O lowered/VBD/O a/DT/O $/$/O 3.35/CD/O billion/CD/O bid/NN/O for/IN/O American/NNP/B-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Beverly/NNP/B-GPE Hills/NNPS/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O because/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O threat/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O legislation/NN/O ././O
One/CD/O possible/JJ/O solution/NN/O for/IN/O Wall/NNP/O Street/NNP/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O increase/VB/O the/DT/O equity/NN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O transaction/NN/O --/:/O that/DT/O is/VBZ/O ,/,/O give/VB/O lenders/NNS/O a/DT/O bigger/JJR/O stake/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O surviving/VBG/O company/NN/O rather/RB/O than/IN/O just/RB/O interest/NN/O payments/NNS/O ././O
Another/DT/O solution/NN/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O tax/NN/O lawyer/NN/O who/WP/O requested/VBD/O anonymity/NN/O ,/,/O is/VBZ/O for/IN/O firms/NNS/O to/TO/O use/VB/O convertible/JJ/O bonds/NNS/O that/WDT/O sell/VBP/O at/IN/O a/DT/O discount/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O bill/NN/O would/MD/O then/RB/O declare/VB/O that/IN/O the/DT/O debt/NN/O is/VBZ/O equity/NN/O and/CC/O therefore/RB/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O deductible/JJ/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG bill/NN/O would/MD/O only/RB/O deny/VB/O the/DT/O deduction/NN/O until/IN/O interest/NN/O is/VBZ/O actually/RB/O paid/VBN/O ././O
The/DT/O Senate/NNP/B-ORG estimates/VBZ/O that/IN/O its/PRP$/O version/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O provision/NN/O would/MD/O yield/VB/O $/$/O 17/CD/O million/CD/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O year/NN/O and/CC/O a/DT/O total/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 409/CD/O million/CD/O over/IN/O five/CD/O years/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O House/NNP/B-ORG version/NN/O would/MD/O raise/VB/O slightly/RB/O more/JJR/O ././O
