Computer/NNP/B-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG International/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Garden/NNP/B-GPE City/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O N.Y./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O and/CC/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG Equipment/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O they/PRP/O agreed/VBD/O to/TO/O jointly/RB/O develop/VB/O software/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O manage/VB/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O Vax/NNP/O computers/NNS/O ././O
Computer/NNP/B-ORG Associates/NNPS/I-ORG has/VBZ/O carved/VBN/O out/RP/O a/DT/O huge/JJ/O business/NN/O selling/VBG/O such/JJ/O software/NN/O for/IN/O use/NN/O in/IN/O managing/NN/O networks/NNS/O of/IN/O International/NNP/B-ORG Business/NNP/I-ORG Machines/NNPS/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG computers/NNS/O but/CC/O needs/VBZ/O to/TO/O find/VB/O new/JJ/O markets/NNS/O if/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O maintain/VB/O its/PRP$/O growth/NN/O rate/NN/O of/IN/O 30/CD/O %/NN/O and/CC/O more/JJR/O each/DT/O year/NN/O ././O
For/IN/O one/CD/O thing/NN/O ,/,/O Digital/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O Maynard/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Mass./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O has/VBZ/O sold/VBN/O fewer/JJR/O machines/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O machines/NNS/O are/VBP/O typically/RB/O easier/JJR/O to/TO/O operate/VB/O ,/,/O so/IN/O customers/NNS/O require/VBP/O less/JJR/O assistance/NN/O from/IN/O software/NN/O ././O
