The/DT/B-ORG Associated/NNP/I-ORG Press/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG earthquake/NN/O coverage/NN/O drew/VBD/O attention/NN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O phenomenon/NN/O that/WDT/O deserves/VBZ/O some/DT/O thought/NN/O by/IN/O public/JJ/O officials/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O policy/NN/O makers/NNS/O ././O
Private/JJ/O relief/NN/O agencies/NNS/O ,/,/O such/JJ/O as/IN/O the/DT/O Salvation/NNP/B-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O Red/NNP/B-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O mobilized/VBD/O almost/RB/O instantly/RB/O to/TO/O help/VB/O people/NNS/O ,/,/O while/IN/O the/DT/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE bureaucracy/NN/O ``/``/O took/VBD/O hours/NNS/O getting/VBG/O into/IN/O gear/NN/O ././O ''/''/O
One/CD/O news/NN/O show/NN/O we/PRP/O saw/VBD/O yesterday/NN/O even/RB/O displayed/VBD/O 25/CD/O federal/JJ/O officials/NNS/O meeting/VBG/O around/IN/O a/DT/O table/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O recall/VBP/O that/IN/O the/DT/O mayor/NN/O of/IN/O Charleston/NNP/B-GPE complained/VBD/O bitterly/RB/O about/IN/O the/DT/O federal/JJ/O bureaucracy/NN/O 's/POS/O response/NN/O to/TO/O Hurricane/NNP/O Hugo/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O sense/NN/O grows/VBZ/O that/IN/O modern/JJ/O public/JJ/O bureaucracies/NNS/O simply/RB/O do/VBP/O n't/RB/O perform/VB/O their/PRP$/O assigned/VBN/O functions/NNS/O well/RB/O ././O
