Mr./NNP/O Sung/NNP/B-PERSON formerly/RB/O worked/VBD/O at/IN/O General/NNP/B-ORG Electric/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O research/NN/O on/IN/O synthetic/JJ/O diamonds/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O criminal/JJ/O charges/NNS/O brought/VBN/O against/IN/O him/PRP/O involved/VBN/O GE/NNP/B-ORG technology/NN/O ,/,/O according/VBG/O the/DT/O court/NN/O documents/NNS/O ././O
If/IN/O convicted/VBN/O ,/,/O he/PRP/O could/MD/O be/VB/O imprisoned/VBN/O for/IN/O up/IN/O to/TO/O 10/CD/O years/NNS/O and/CC/O fined/VBN/O $/$/O 250,000/CD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Sung/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O earlier/RB/O denied/VBD/O the/DT/O allegations/NNS/O against/IN/O him/PRP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O lawsuit/NN/O by/IN/O Norton/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O GE/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Norton/NNP/B-ORG makes/VBZ/O sandpaper/NN/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O abrasives/NNS/O ,/,/O diamond/NN/O tools/NNS/O ,/,/O specialty/JJ/O plastics/NNS/O and/CC/O ceramics/NNS/O ././O
