The/DT/O government/NN/O moved/VBD/O aggressively/RB/O to/TO/O open/VB/O the/DT/O spigots/NNS/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O aid/NN/O for/IN/O victims/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O California/NNP/B-GPE earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O its/PRP$/O reservoir/NN/O of/IN/O emergency/NN/O funds/NNS/O must/MD/O be/VB/O replenished/VBN/O soon/RB/O if/IN/O the/DT/O aid/NN/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O continue/VB/O ././O
President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON signed/VBD/O a/DT/O disaster/NN/O declaration/NN/O covering/VBG/O seven/CD/O Northern/JJ/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC counties/NNS/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/O federal/JJ/O government/NN/O is/VBZ/O n't/RB/O even/RB/O attempting/VBG/O yet/RB/O to/TO/O estimate/VB/O how/WRB/O much/JJ/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O will/MD/O cost/VB/O it/PRP/O ././O
Money/NN/O could/MD/O be/VB/O added/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O pending/VBG/O spending/NN/O bill/NN/O covering/VBG/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Emergency/NNP/I-ORG Management/NNP/I-ORG Agency/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O coordinates/VBZ/O federal/JJ/O disaster/NN/O relief/NN/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Clanahan/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG now/RB/O possibly/RB/O may/MD/O have/VB/O the/DT/O heaviest/JJS/O caseload/NN/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O history/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Red/NNP/I-ORG Cross/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O opened/VBN/O 30/CD/O shelters/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ,/,/O serving/VBG/O 5,000/CD/O people/NNS/O ././O
All/PDT/O the/DT/O precise/JJ/O types/NNS/O of/IN/O federal/JJ/O aid/NN/O that/WDT/O will/MD/O be/VB/O sent/VBN/O to/TO/O California/NNP/B-GPE wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O determined/VBN/O until/IN/O state/NN/O officials/NNS/O make/VBP/O specific/JJ/O requests/NNS/O to/TO/O FEMA/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O agency/NN/O officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O ././O
HUD/NNP/B-ORG officials/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O will/MD/O make/VB/O available/JJ/O as/RB/O many/JJ/O as/IN/O 100/CD/O Bay/NNP/B-LOC area/NN/I-LOC houses/NNS/O that/WDT/O are/VBP/O under/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG loans/NNS/O but/CC/O now/RB/O are/VBP/O vacant/JJ/O after/IN/O the/DT/O houses/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O inspected/VBN/O to/TO/O ensure/VB/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O sound/JJ/O ././O
Another/DT/O federal/JJ/O agency/NN/O not/RB/O normally/RB/O associated/VBN/O with/IN/O disaster/NN/O relief/NN/O --/:/O the/DT/B-ORG Internal/NNP/I-ORG Revenue/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG --/:/O moved/VBD/O quickly/RB/O as/RB/O well/RB/O ././O
The/DT/O IRS/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O will/MD/O waive/VB/O certain/JJ/O tax/NN/O penalties/NNS/O for/IN/O earthquake/NN/O victims/NNS/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O meet/VB/O return/NN/O deadlines/NNS/O or/CC/O make/VB/O payments/NNS/O because/RB/O of/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O 's/POS/O devastation/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O agency/NN/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O announce/VB/O specific/JJ/O relief/NN/O procedures/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O coming/VBG/O days/NNS/O ././O
One/CD/O advantage/NN/O that/IN/O federal/JJ/O officials/NNS/O have/VBP/O in/IN/O handling/VBG/O earthquake/NN/O relief/NN/O is/VBZ/O the/DT/O large/JJ/O number/NN/O of/IN/O military/JJ/O facilities/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC San/NNP/I-LOC Francisco/NNP/I-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ,/,/O facilities/NNS/O that/WDT/O provide/VBP/O a/DT/O ready/JJ/O base/NN/O of/IN/O supplies/NNS/O and/CC/O workers/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O military/JJ/O jet/NN/O flew/VBD/O a/DT/O congressional/JJ/O delegation/NN/O and/CC/O senior/JJ/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON administration/NN/O officials/NNS/O to/TO/O survey/VB/O the/DT/O damage/NN/O ././O
Some/DT/O victims/NNS/O also/RB/O were/VBD/O treated/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Letterman/NNP/I-ORG Army/NNP/I-ORG Medical/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O at/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Naval/NNP/I-ORG Hospital/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Highway/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG has/VBZ/O an/DT/O emergency/NN/O relief/NN/O program/NN/O to/TO/O help/VB/O states/NNS/O and/CC/O local/JJ/O governments/NNS/O repair/VB/O federally/RB/O funded/JJ/O highways/NNS/B-FAC and/CC/O bridges/NNS/O seriously/RB/O damaged/JJ/O by/IN/O natural/JJ/O disasters/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O account/NN/O currently/RB/O has/VBZ/O $/$/O 220/CD/O million/CD/O ././O
Keith/NNP/B-PERSON Mulrooney/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O special/JJ/O assistant/NN/O to/TO/O Federal/NNP/B-ORG Highway/NNP/I-ORG Administrator/NNP/I-ORG Thomas/NNP/B-PERSON Larson/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O also/RB/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O after/IN/O the/DT/O 1971/CD/O San/NNP/B-GPE Fernando/NNP/I-GPE earthquake/NN/O in/IN/O Southern/NNP/B-LOC California/NNP/I-LOC ,/,/O the/DT/O state/NN/O set/VBD/O tougher/JJR/O standards/NNS/O for/IN/O bridges/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O with/IN/O federal/JJ/O aid/NN/O ,/,/O began/VBD/O a/DT/O program/NN/O to/TO/O retrofit/VB/O highways/NNS/B-FAC and/CC/O bridges/NNS/O for/IN/O earthquake/NN/O hazards/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O first/JJ/O phase/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O program/NN/O has/VBZ/O been/VBN/O completed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O two/CD/O other/JJ/O phases/NNS/O are/VBP/O continuing/VBG/O ././O
Laurie/NNP/B-PERSON McGinley/NNP/I-PERSON contributed/VBD/O to/TO/O this/DT/O article/NN/O ././O
