Sterling/NNP/B-ORG Software/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O lost/VBD/O its/PRP$/O bid/NN/O to/TO/O supply/VB/O software/NN/O services/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-ORG National/NNP/I-ORG Aeronautics/NNP/I-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Space/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG Ames/NNP/B-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Center/NNP/I-ORG at/IN/O Moffett/NNP/B-GPE Field/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Calif/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Sterling/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O estimated/VBD/O the/DT/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O at/IN/O $/$/O 150/CD/O million/CD/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O NASA/NNP/B-ORG selected/VBD/O another/DT/O bidder/NN/O for/IN/O final/JJ/O negotiations/NNS/O ././O
As/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O ,/,/O last/JJ/O March/NNP/O the/DT/O General/NNP/B-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG board/NN/O of/IN/O contract/NN/O appeals/NNS/O directed/VBD/O NASA/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O reopen/VB/O negotiations/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O contract/NN/O ././O
Sterling/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O had/VBD/O requested/VBN/O a/DT/O briefing/NN/O by/IN/O NASA/NNP/B-ORG but/CC/O had/VBD/O not/RB/O decided/VBN/O whether/IN/O to/TO/O protest/VB/O the/DT/O agency/NN/O 's/POS/O latest/JJS/O decision/NN/O ././O
