Bridge/NN/O and/CC/O highway/NN/O collapses/NNS/O will/MD/O disrupt/VB/O truck/NN/O and/CC/O auto/NN/O transportation/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-LOC Francisco/NNP/I-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/O for/IN/O months/NNS/O to/TO/O come/VB/O ././O
Air/NN/O traffic/NN/O at/IN/O San/NNP/B-FAC Francisco/NNP/I-FAC International/NNP/I-FAC Airport/NNP/I-FAC was/VBD/O running/VBG/O about/IN/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O normal/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O afternoon/NN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O airport/NN/O officals/NNS/O said/VBD/O they/PRP/O expect/VBP/O a/DT/O return/NN/O to/TO/O full/JJ/O operations/NNS/O by/IN/O Saturday/NNP/O ././O
The/DT/O major/JJ/O gateway/NN/O to/TO/O Asia/NNP/B-LOC and/CC/O one/CD/O of/IN/O the/DT/O nation/NN/O 's/POS/O 10/CD/O busiest/JJS/O airports/NNS/O was/VBD/O closed/VBN/O to/TO/O all/DT/O but/CC/O emergency/NN/O traffic/NN/O from/IN/O the/DT/O time/NN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O hit/VBN/O Tuesday/NNP/O afternoon/NN/O ,/,/O until/IN/O 6/CD/O a.m./RB/O PDT/NNP/O yesterday/NN/O when/WRB/O controllers/NNS/O returned/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O tower/NN/O ././O
Getting/VBG/O to/TO/O and/CC/O from/IN/O the/DT/O airport/NN/O in/IN/O coming/VBG/O weeks/NNS/O may/MD/O be/VB/O the/DT/O problem/NN/O ,/,/O however/RB/O ././O
``/``/O People/NNS/O 's/POS/O ability/NN/O to/TO/O drive/VB/O throughout/IN/O the/DT/O bay/NN/O area/NN/O is/VBZ/O greatly/RB/O restricted/VBN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O spokesman/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG American/NNP/I-ORG Automobile/NNP/I-ORG Association/NNP/I-ORG ././O
``/``/O Some/DT/O foodstuff/NN/O shipments/NNS/O will/MD/O probably/RB/O resume/VB/O Thursday/NNP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O Right/RB/O now/RB/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O roads/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC are/VBP/O closed/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O list/NN/O of/IN/O closings/NNS/O changes/VBZ/O about/IN/O every/DT/O 20/CD/O minutes/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O -LCB-/-LRB-/O Wednesday/NNP/O -RCB-/-RRB-/O morning/NN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Mateo/NNP/I-GPE bridge/NN/O was/VBD/O open/JJ/O and/CC/O now/RB/O we/PRP/O are/VBP/O informed/VBN/O that/IN/O it/PRP/O is/VBZ/O closed/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Schumacher/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
United/NNP/B-ORG Parcel/NNP/I-ORG Service/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Greenwich/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Conn./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O operations/NNS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE area/NN/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O reduced/VBN/O to/TO/O 40/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O normal/JJ/O ././O
A/DT/O UPS/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O although/IN/O none/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O company/NN/O 's/POS/O terminals/NNS/O ,/,/O trucks/NNS/O or/CC/O airplanes/NNS/O were/VBD/O damaged/VBN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O ,/,/O road/NN/O shutdowns/NNS/O and/CC/O power/NN/O failures/NNS/O have/VBP/O impeded/VBN/O its/PRP$/O pickup/NN/O and/CC/O delivery/NN/O of/IN/O packages/NNS/O ././O
But/CC/O freight/NN/O railroads/NNS/O reported/VBD/O that/DT/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O their/PRP$/O facilities/NNS/B-FAC was/VBD/O relatively/RB/O minor/JJ/O ,/,/O with/IN/O Santa/NNP/B-ORG Fe/NNP/I-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG rail/NN/O unit/NN/O the/DT/O least/RBS/O affected/JJ/O by/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O ././O
Santa/NNP/B-ORG Fe/NNP/I-ORG stopped/VBD/O freight/NN/O trains/NNS/O Tuesday/NNP/O night/NN/O while/IN/O its/PRP$/O officials/NNS/O inspected/VBD/O track/NN/O but/CC/O resumed/VBD/O service/NN/O at/IN/O 10:45/CD/O p.m./RB/O when/WRB/O they/PRP/O found/VBD/O no/DT/O damage/NN/O ././O
Union/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG rail/NN/O unit/NN/O said/VBD/O that/IN/O except/IN/O for/IN/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O shipping/NN/O containers/NNS/O in/IN/O its/PRP$/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE yard/NN/O ,/,/O its/PRP$/O track/NN/O ,/,/O bridges/NNS/O and/CC/O structures/NNS/O were/VBD/O unharmed/JJ/O ././O
That/DT/O railroad/NN/O is/VBZ/O operating/VBG/O trains/NNS/O but/CC/O with/IN/O delays/NNS/O caused/VBN/O by/IN/O employees/NNS/O unable/JJ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O to/TO/O work/NN/O ././O
But/CC/O service/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O line/NN/O is/VBZ/O expected/VBN/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O by/IN/O noon/NN/O today/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O had/VBD/O no/DT/O serious/JJ/O damage/NN/O on/IN/O the/DT/O railroad/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O a/DT/O Southern/NNP/B-ORG Pacific/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O have/VBP/O no/DT/O problem/NN/O to/TO/O our/PRP$/O freight/NN/O service/NN/O at/IN/O all/DT/O expect/IN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O fact/NN/O businesses/NNS/O are/VBP/O shut/VBN/O down/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
Amtrak/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O suspended/VBD/O train/NN/O service/NN/O into/IN/O its/PRP$/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE station/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O sustained/VBD/O ``/``/O heavy/JJ/O structural/JJ/O damage/NN/O ''/''/O during/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O passenger/NN/O railroad/NN/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O terminated/VBD/O some/DT/O runs/NNS/O in/IN/O Sacramento/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O relying/VBG/O on/IN/O buses/NNS/O to/TO/O ferry/VB/O passengers/NNS/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ././O
Amtrak/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O planned/VBD/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O some/DT/O train/NN/O operations/NNS/O to/TO/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE late/JJ/O yesterday/NN/O ././O
The/DT/B-ORG Bay/NNP/I-ORG Area/NNP/I-ORG Rapid/NNP/I-ORG Transit/NNP/I-ORG ``/``/O withstood/VBD/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O perfectly/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O adding/VBG/O that/IN/O the/DT/O rail/NN/O system/NN/O was/VBD/O running/VBG/O a/DT/O full/JJ/O fleet/NN/O of/IN/O 45/CD/O trains/NNS/O during/IN/O the/DT/O day/NN/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O an/DT/O alternative/NN/O for/IN/O highway/NN/O travelers/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O highway/NN/O system/NN/O is/VBZ/O screwed/VBN/O up/RP/O ''/''/O by/IN/O the/DT/O earthquake/NN/O ,/,/O Mr./NNP/O Engelken/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O The/DT/O transit/NN/O system/NN/O is/VBZ/O how/WRB/O people/NNS/O are/VBP/O going/VBG/O to/TO/O be/VB/O getting/VBG/O around/RB/O ././O ''/''/O
He/PRP/O added/VBD/O that/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE 's/POS/I-GPE trolley/NN/O cars/NNS/O and/CC/O trolley/NN/O buses/NNS/O were/VBD/O also/RB/O running/VBG/O at/IN/O full/JJ/O service/NN/O levels/NNS/O ././O
Terminals/NNS/O at/IN/O San/NNP/B-FAC Francisco/NNP/I-FAC International/NNP/I-FAC also/RB/O were/VBD/O damaged/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O tower/NN/O itself/PRP/O was/VBD/O intact/JJ/O ././O
Tuesday/NNP/O night/NN/O ,/,/O thousands/NNS/O were/VBD/O diverted/VBN/O to/TO/O other/JJ/O airports/NNS/O and/CC/O had/VBD/O to/TO/O wait/VB/O a/DT/O day/NN/O to/TO/O resume/VB/O travel/NN/O ././O
Runways/NNS/O at/IN/O San/NNP/B-FAC Francisco/NNP/I-FAC were/VBD/O n't/RB/O damaged/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O traffic/NN/O was/VBD/O being/VBG/O limited/VBN/O yesterday/NN/O to/TO/O 27/CD/O arrivals/NNS/O and/CC/O 27/CD/O departures/NNS/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O --/:/O down/IN/O from/IN/O 33/CD/O to/TO/O 45/CD/O an/DT/O hour/NN/O normally/RB/O --/:/O mainly/RB/O because/IN/O the/DT/O noise/NN/O level/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O control/NN/O tower/NN/O was/VBD/O overwhelming/JJ/O without/IN/O the/DT/O windows/NNS/O ,/,/O an/DT/O FAA/NNP/B-ORG spokeswoman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
While/IN/O the/DT/O airport/NN/O was/VBD/O closed/VBN/O ,/,/O flights/NNS/O were/VBD/O diverted/VBN/O to/TO/O airports/NNS/O in/IN/O Sacramento/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Stockton/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O Reno/NNP/B-GPE and/CC/O Las/NNP/B-GPE Vegas/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O Nev./NNP/B-GPE ;/:/O and/CC/O Los/NNP/B-GPE Angeles/NNP/I-GPE ././O
United/NNP/B-ORG Airlines/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O largest/JJS/O carrier/NN/O at/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE ,/,/O was/VBD/O operating/VBG/O only/RB/O 50/CD/O %/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O scheduled/JJ/O service/NN/O in/IN/O and/CC/O out/IN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O area/NN/O because/IN/O of/IN/O damage/NN/O to/TO/O its/PRP$/O terminal/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O in/IN/O turn/NN/O was/VBD/O causing/VBG/O delays/NNS/O for/IN/O travelers/NNS/O headed/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/B-LOC Bay/NNP/I-LOC area/NN/I-LOC ././O
A/DT/O United/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O 14/CD/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O 21/CD/O gates/NNS/O were/VBD/O unusable/JJ/O ,/,/O mainly/RB/O because/IN/O of/IN/O water/NN/O damage/NN/O caused/VBN/O when/WRB/O a/DT/O sprinkler/NN/O system/NN/O was/VBD/O triggered/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O tremors/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O United/NNP/B-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O none/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O people/NNS/O were/VBD/O injured/VBN/O at/IN/O the/DT/O airport/NN/O ;/:/O in/IN/O fact/NN/O ,/,/O as/IN/O the/DT/O airport/NN/O was/VBD/O being/VBG/O evacuated/VBN/O Tuesday/NNP/O night/NN/O ,/,/O two/CD/O babies/NNS/O were/VBD/O born/VBN/O ././O
Yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/O United/NNP/B-ORG ticket/NN/O counter/NN/O was/VBD/O active/JJ/O ,/,/O with/IN/O people/NNS/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O get/VB/O flights/NNS/O out/RB/O ,/,/O but/CC/O the/DT/O airline/NN/O said/VBD/O demand/NN/O for/IN/O seats/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O city/NN/O also/RB/O was/VBD/O active/JJ/O ,/,/O with/IN/O people/NNS/O trying/VBG/O to/TO/O get/VB/O there/RB/O to/TO/O help/VB/O family/NN/O and/CC/O friends/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O airports/NNS/O in/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Jose/NNP/I-GPE and/CC/O Oakland/NNP/B-GPE were/VBD/O both/DT/O fully/RB/O operational/JJ/O by/IN/O noon/NN/O yesterday/NN/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Aviation/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O ././O
``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O that/DT/O 's/VBZ/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O nonstop/JJ/O commercial/JJ/O passenger/NN/O flight/NN/O from/IN/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE to/TO/O land/VB/O here/RB/O ,/,/O ''/''/O an/DT/O airport/NN/O spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
A/DT/O Japan/NNP/B-ORG Air/NNP/I-ORG Lines/NNPS/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O its/PRP$/O flights/NNS/O into/IN/O and/CC/O out/IN/O of/IN/O San/NNP/B-GPE Francisco/NNP/I-GPE were/VBD/O n't/RB/O affected/VBN/O ,/,/O but/CC/O getting/VBG/O information/NN/O about/IN/O its/PRP$/O operations/NNS/O was/VBD/O difficult/JJ/O ././O
Its/PRP$/O telecommunications/NN/O headquarters/NN/O in/IN/O Burlingame/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Calif./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O knocked/VBN/O out/RP/O since/IN/O the/DT/O quake/NN/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O in/IN/O the/DT/O dark/JJ/O ,/,/O ''/''/O he/PRP/O said/VBD/O ././O
