Mr./NNP/O Holmes/NNP/B-PERSON was/VBD/O the/DT/O subject/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O page/NN/O one/CD/O profile/NN/O in/IN/O The/DT/B-ORG Wall/NNP/I-ORG Street/NNP/I-ORG Journal/NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O 1984/CD/O ,/,/O after/IN/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG questioned/VBD/O him/PRP/O about/IN/O ties/NNS/O between/IN/O him/PRP/O and/CC/O companies/NNS/O he/PRP/O touted/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O newsletter/NN/O ././O
Without/IN/O any/DT/O admission/NN/O or/CC/O denial/NN/O of/IN/O guilt/NN/O by/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Holmes/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O that/DT/O agreement/NN/O settled/VBD/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG charges/NNS/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Holmes/NNP/B-PERSON sold/VBD/O unregistered/JJ/O securities/NNS/O and/CC/O misled/VBD/O investors/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O charges/NNS/O filed/VBN/O last/JJ/O week/NN/O in/IN/O federal/JJ/O district/NN/O court/NN/O in/IN/O Charlotte/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O N.C./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O the/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG alleged/VBD/O that/IN/O Venture/NNP/B-ORG Capitalists/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O Venture/NNP/B-ORG Finance/NNP/I-ORG Corp./NNP/I-ORG and/CC/O New/NNP/B-ORG Ventures/NNPS/I-ORG Fund/NNP/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O all/DT/O of/IN/O Charlotte/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O failed/VBD/O repeatedly/RB/O to/TO/O file/VB/O proper/JJ/O documents/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O SEC/NNP/B-ORG also/RB/O charged/VBD/O that/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Holmes/NNP/B-PERSON acted/VBD/O as/IN/O an/DT/O officer/NN/O or/CC/O director/NN/O of/IN/O New/NNP/B-ORG Ventures/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O in/IN/O violation/NN/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O previous/JJ/O consent/NN/O agreement/NN/O ././O
``/``/O Some/DT/O companies/NNS/O were/VBD/O delinquent/JJ/O in/IN/O filings/NNS/O and/CC/O other/JJ/O actions/NNS/O ,/,/O all/DT/O of/IN/O which/WDT/O cost/VBP/O money/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O Mr./NNP/O Holmes/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O ././O
Two/CD/O of/IN/O Mr./NNP/O Holmes/NNP/B-PERSON 's/POS/O business/NN/O associates/NNS/O who/WP/O worked/VBD/O for/IN/O Venture/NNP/B-ORG Capitalists/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O Kimberly/NNP/B-PERSON Ann/NNP/I-PERSON Smith/NNP/I-PERSON and/CC/O Frederick/NNP/B-PERSON Byrum/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O also/RB/O consented/VBD/O to/TO/O being/VBG/O enjoined/VBN/O from/IN/O violations/NNS/O of/IN/O registration/NN/O provisions/NNS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O securities/NNS/O laws/NNS/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Byrum/NNP/B-PERSON and/CC/O Ms./NNP/O Smith/NNP/B-PERSON could/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O reached/VBN/O for/IN/O comment/NN/O ././O
In/IN/O consenting/VBG/O to/TO/O the/DT/O injunctions/NNS/O ,/,/O none/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O individuals/NNS/O or/CC/O companies/NNS/O admitted/VBD/O or/CC/O denied/VBD/O the/DT/O allegations/NNS/O ././O
