John/NNP/B-PERSON E./NNP/I-PERSON Hayes/NNP/I-PERSON Jr./NNP/I-PERSON was/VBD/O elected/VBN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O officer/NN/O ,/,/O succeeding/VBG/O David/NNP/B-PERSON S./NNP/I-PERSON Black/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O who/WP/O retired/VBD/O ././O
Mr./NNP/O Hayes/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 52/CD/O years/NNS/O old/JJ/O ,/,/O left/VBD/O Southwestern/NNP/B-ORG Bell/NNP/I-ORG Telephone/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG in/IN/O January/NNP/O ,/,/O where/WRB/O he/PRP/O had/VBD/O been/VBN/O chairman/NN/O ,/,/O president/NN/O and/CC/O chief/JJ/O executive/NN/O ,/,/O to/TO/O join/VB/O Triad/NNP/B-ORG Capital/NNP/I-ORG Partners/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O St./NNP/B-GPE Louis/NNP/I-GPE company/NN/O with/IN/O interests/NNS/O in/IN/O solid/JJ/O waste/NN/O and/CC/O recycling/NN/O ,/,/O telecommunications/NN/O and/CC/O international/JJ/O venture/NN/O capital/NN/O ././O
He/PRP/O has/VBZ/O resigned/VBN/O his/PRP$/O posts/NNS/O at/IN/O Triad/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O take/VB/O the/DT/O Kansas/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG positions/NNS/O ././O
Kansas/NNP/B-ORG Power/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O Mr./NNP/O Black/NNP/B-PERSON ,/,/O 61/CD/O ,/,/O chose/VBD/O early/JJ/O retirement/NN/O ././O
