Honda/NNP/B-ORG Motor/NNP/I-ORG Co./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O first/JJ/O Japanese/JJ/O auto/NN/O maker/NN/O to/TO/O ship/NN/O cars/NNS/O to/TO/O Japan/NNP/B-GPE from/IN/O the/DT/O U.S./NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O is/VBZ/O now/RB/O exporting/VBG/O more/JJR/O than/IN/O 5,000/CD/O Accord/NNP/O Coupes/NNP/O a/DT/O year/NN/O from/IN/O its/PRP$/O Marysville/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE ,/,/O factory/NN/O ././O
