The/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Mercantile/NNP/I-ORG Exchange/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O fined/VBD/O Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG $/$/O 500,000/CD/O and/CC/O accepted/VBD/O its/PRP$/O withdrawal/NN/O from/IN/O membership/NN/O as/IN/O part/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O settlement/NN/O of/IN/O disciplinary/JJ/O actions/NNS/O against/IN/O the/DT/O firm/NN/O ././O
Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG is/VBZ/O a/DT/O Chicago/NNP/B-GPE subsidiary/NN/O of/IN/O Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG Services/NNPS/I-ORG Ltd./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O London/NNP/B-GPE financial/JJ/O firm/NN/O that/WDT/O was/VBD/O implicated/VBN/O last/JJ/O year/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O scheme/NN/O to/TO/O launder/VB/O drug/NN/O money/NN/O ././O
The/DT/O case/NN/O is/VBZ/O pending/VBG/O ././O
In/IN/O June/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/B-ORG Chicago/NNP/I-ORG Board/NNP/I-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O suspended/VBD/O Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Financial/NNP/I-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG unit/NN/O withdrew/VBD/O from/IN/O Board/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG membership/NN/O voluntarily/RB/O in/IN/O August/NNP/O ,/,/O a/DT/O Board/NNP/B-ORG of/IN/I-ORG Trade/NNP/I-ORG spokesman/NN/O said/VBD/O ././O
Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG ,/,/O while/IN/O neither/CC/O admitting/VBG/O nor/CC/O denying/VBG/O the/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG charges/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O in/IN/O a/DT/O statement/NN/O that/IN/O the/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG charges/NNS/O were/VBD/O ``/``/O technical/JJ/O in/IN/O nature/NN/O ''/''/O and/CC/O that/IN/O ``/``/O no/DT/O customers/NNS/O were/VBD/O hurt/VBN/O ''/''/O as/IN/O a/DT/O result/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O violations/NNS/O cited/VBN/O by/IN/O the/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG ././O
The/DT/O Merc/NNP/B-ORG alleged/VBD/O that/IN/O ,/,/O among/IN/O other/JJ/O things/NNS/O ,/,/O from/IN/O April/NNP/O 1987/CD/O through/IN/O October/NNP/O 1988/CD/O Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG failed/VBD/O to/TO/O document/VB/O trades/NNS/O between/IN/O Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG and/CC/O people/NNS/O or/CC/O entities/NNS/O directly/RB/O or/CC/O indirectly/RB/O controlled/JJ/O by/IN/O Capcom/NNP/B-ORG Futures/NNPS/I-ORG shareholders/NNS/O ././O
