Called/VBN/O Patients/NNPS/O in/IN/O the/DT/O Know/NNP/O ,/,/O the/DT/O program/NN/O features/VBZ/O fact/NN/O sheets/NNS/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O easy/JJ/O to/TO/O understand/VB/O ././O
The/DT/O sheets/NNS/O tell/VBP/O how/WRB/O the/DT/O medicine/NN/O works/VBZ/O ,/,/O describe/VBP/O how/WRB/O to/TO/O use/VB/O it/PRP/O and/CC/O list/VBP/O its/PRP$/O possible/JJ/O side/NN/O effects/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O are/VBP/O designed/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O given/VBN/O to/TO/O patients/NNS/O by/IN/O their/PRP$/O doctors/NNS/O when/WRB/O the/DT/O medicines/NNS/O are/VBP/O prescribed/VBN/O and/CC/O include/VBP/O space/NN/O for/IN/O the/DT/O doctor/NN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O special/JJ/O instructions/NNS/O ././O
In/IN/O addition/NN/O ,/,/O Searle/NNP/B-ORG will/MD/O give/VB/O pharmacists/NNS/O brochures/NNS/O on/IN/O the/DT/O use/NN/O of/IN/O prescription/NN/O drugs/NNS/O for/IN/O distribution/NN/O in/IN/O their/PRP$/O stores/NNS/O ././O
Consumer/NN/O groups/NNS/O have/VBP/O long/RB/O advocated/VBN/O that/IN/O drug/NN/O companies/NNS/O and/CC/O doctors/NNS/O make/VB/O more/JJR/O information/NN/O available/JJ/O to/TO/O patients/NNS/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O believe/VBP/O that/IN/O every/DT/O drug/NN/O that/WDT/O 's/VBZ/O marketed/VBN/O to/TO/O a/DT/O consumer/NN/O should/MD/O have/VB/O a/DT/O consumer/NN/O label/NN/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Douglas/NNP/B-PERSON Teich/NNP/I-PERSON of/IN/O the/DT/B-ORG Public/NNP/I-ORG Citizen/NNP/I-ORG Health/NNP/I-ORG Research/NNP/I-ORG Group/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O a/DT/O Ralph/NNP/B-PERSON Nader/NNP/I-PERSON affiliate/NN/O ././O
Dr./NNP/O Teich/NNP/B-PERSON said/VBD/O Searle/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O ``/``/O the/DT/O only/JJ/O company/NN/O I/PRP/O know/VBP/O that/DT/O voluntarily/RB/O ''/''/O will/MD/O make/VB/O consumer/NN/O information/NN/O available/JJ/O ././O
``/``/O We/PRP/O think/VBP/O it/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O very/RB/O important/JJ/O to/TO/O provide/VB/O as/IN/O much/JJ/O information/NN/O as/IN/O possible/JJ/O on/IN/O the/DT/O drugs/NNS/O consumers/NNS/O take/VBP/O ,/,/O ''/''/O said/VBD/O Searle/NNP/B-ORG Chairman/NN/O Sheldon/NNP/B-PERSON Gilgore/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
