Granges/NNP/B-ORG Inc./NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O citing/VBG/O depressed/JJ/O gold/NN/O prices/NNS/O ,/,/O said/VBD/O it/PRP/O plans/VBZ/O to/TO/O suspend/VB/O operations/NNS/O for/IN/O an/DT/O indefinite/JJ/O period/NN/O at/IN/O its/PRP$/O Tartan/NNP/B-FAC gold/NN/O mine/NN/O in/IN/O Manitoba/NNP/B-GPE ././O
Tartan/NNP/B-FAC currently/RB/O produces/VBZ/O gold/NN/O at/IN/O a/DT/O cash/NN/O operating/NN/O cost/NN/O of/IN/O $/$/O 393/CD/O an/DT/O ounce/NN/O ,/,/O which/WDT/O is/VBZ/O high/JJ/O by/IN/O industry/NN/O standards/NNS/O and/CC/O $/$/O 25/CD/O or/CC/O so/RB/O above/IN/O the/DT/O current/JJ/O spot/NN/O price/NN/O ././O
Granges/NNP/B-ORG said/VBD/O it/PRP/O also/RB/O plans/VBZ/O in/IN/O the/DT/O third/JJ/O quarter/NN/O to/TO/O write/VB/O down/RP/O the/DT/O carrying/NN/O value/NN/O of/IN/O the/DT/O Tartan/NNP/B-FAC mine/NN/O by/IN/O 2.5/CD/O million/CD/O Canadian/JJ/O dollars/NNS/O -LRB-/-LRB-/O US$/$/O 2.12/CD/O million/CD/O -RRB-/-RRB-/O ,/,/O and/CC/O to/TO/O write/VB/O off/RP/O most/JJS/O of/IN/O the/DT/O C$/$/O 6.3/CD/O million/CD/O carrying/NN/O value/NN/O of/IN/O its/PRP$/O Windflower/NNP/B-ORG gold/NN/O property/NN/O in/IN/O British/NNP/B-GPE Columbia/NNP/I-GPE ././O
Granges/NNS/B-ORG did/VBD/O n't/RB/O say/VB/O what/WDT/O impact/NN/O the/DT/O moves/NNS/O would/MD/O have/VB/O on/IN/O total/JJ/O gold/NN/O output/NN/O or/CC/O earnings/NNS/O ,/,/O and/CC/O company/NN/O officials/NNS/O were/VBD/O n't/RB/O available/JJ/O ././O
