Many/JJ/O in/IN/O Washington/NNP/B-GPE say/VBP/O President/NNP/O Bush/NNP/B-PERSON will/MD/O have/VB/O to/TO/O raise/VB/O taxes/NNS/O to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O his/PRP$/O war/NN/O on/IN/O drugs/NNS/O ././O
We/PRP/O have/VBP/O a/DT/O better/JJR/O idea/NN/O :/:/O Dismantle/VB/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG to/TO/O pay/VB/O for/IN/O the/DT/O war/NN/O on/IN/O drugs/NNS/O ././O
Housing/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/I-ORG Urban/NNP/I-ORG Development/NNP/I-ORG 's/POS/I-ORG budget/NN/O is/VBZ/O $/$/O 17/CD/O billion/CD/O ././O
The/DT/O single/JJ/O most/RBS/O important/JJ/O contribution/NN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O could/MD/O make/VB/O now/RB/O to/TO/O help/VB/O the/DT/O poor/JJ/O is/VBZ/O to/TO/O get/VB/O the/DT/O specter/NN/O of/IN/O drugs/NNS/O out/IN/O of/IN/O their/PRP$/O neighborhoods/NNS/O ././O
This/DT/O month/NN/O ,/,/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG Secretary/NNP/O Jack/NNP/B-PERSON Kemp/NNP/I-PERSON unveiled/VBD/O a/DT/O series/NN/O of/IN/O proposed/VBN/O reforms/NNS/O to/TO/O improve/VB/O management/NN/O at/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG ././O
No/DT/O doubt/NN/O many/JJ/O of/IN/O his/PRP$/O ideas/NNS/O are/VBP/O worthy/JJ/O ,/,/O but/CC/O ultimately/RB/O he/PRP/O is/VBZ/O proposing/VBG/O to/TO/O make/VB/O fundamentally/RB/O flawed/JJ/O programs/NNS/O work/VB/O slightly/RB/O more/RBR/O fairly/RB/O and/CC/O efficiently/RB/O ././O
Congress/NNP/B-ORG is/VBZ/O unlikely/JJ/O to/TO/O go/VB/O even/RB/O that/DT/O far/RB/O ././O
Last/JJ/O week/NN/O ,/,/O Secretary/NNP/O Kemp/NNP/B-PERSON ran/VBD/O into/IN/O a/DT/O buzzsaw/NN/O of/IN/O criticism/NN/O from/IN/O House/NNP/B-ORG Banking/NNP/I-ORG Committee/NNP/I-ORG members/NNS/O ././O
These/DT/O development/NN/O grants/NNS/O mainly/RB/O enrich/VBP/O developers/NNS/O who/WP/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O put/VB/O up/RP/O shopping/NN/O centers/NNS/O and/CC/O parking/NN/O garages/NNS/O ././O
They/PRP/O also/RB/O give/VBP/O those/DT/O in/IN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG political/JJ/O credit/NN/O for/IN/O bringing/VBG/O home/NN/O the/DT/O pork/NN/O ,/,/O and/CC/O so/IN/O they/PRP/O are/VBP/O popular/JJ/O with/IN/O such/JJ/O Members/NNS/O as/IN/O Mary/NNP/B-PERSON Rose/NNP/I-PERSON Oakar/NNP/I-PERSON ././O
She/PRP/O says/VBZ/O it/PRP/O 'd/MD/O create/VB/O 600/CD/O jobs/NNS/O and/CC/O bring/VB/O Cleveland/NNP/B-GPE tourist/NN/O revenue/NN/O ././O
HUD/NNP/B-ORG says/VBZ/O the/DT/O project/NN/O does/VBZ/O n't/RB/O qualify/VB/O ,/,/O and/CC/O Mr./NNP/O Kemp/NNP/B-PERSON says/VBZ/O that/DT/O rock/NN/O 'n'/CC/O roll/NN/O musicians/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/O music/NN/O industry/NN/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O put/VB/O up/RP/O the/DT/O money/NN/O ././O
Rep./NNP/O Chalmers/NNP/B-PERSON Wylie/NNP/I-PERSON ,/,/O an/DT/O Ohio/NNP/B-GPE Republican/NNP/O ,/,/O rallied/VBD/O to/TO/O the/DT/O cause/NN/O :/:/O ``/``/O I/PRP/O think/VBP/O the/DT/O gentlelady/NN/O is/VBZ/O making/VBG/O an/DT/O important/JJ/O statement/NN/O ././O
We/PRP/O 're/VBP/O sure/RB/O some/DT/O theologian/NN/O can/MD/O explain/VB/O the/DT/O difference/NN/O between/IN/O what/WP/O the/DT/O Republican/JJ/O consultants/NNS/O have/VBP/O been/VBN/O doing/VBG/O with/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG and/CC/O what/WP/O these/DT/O gentleladies/NNS/O and/CC/O gentlemen/NNS/O want/VBP/O to/TO/O do/VB/O with/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG ././O
Our/PRP$/O view/NN/O is/VBZ/O that/DT/O given/VBN/O Congress/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O attitude/NN/O toward/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG ,/,/O the/DT/O place/NN/O probably/RB/O is/VBZ/O beyond/IN/O reform/NN/O ././O
That/DT/O includes/VBZ/O the/DT/O CDBG/NNP/O funds/NNS/O and/CC/O the/DT/B-ORG Federal/NNP/I-ORG Housing/NNP/I-ORG Administration/NNP/I-ORG ,/,/O which/WDT/O loans/VBZ/O out/RP/O money/NN/O for/IN/O private/JJ/O home/NN/O mortgages/NNS/O and/CC/O has/VBZ/O just/RB/O been/VBN/O discovered/VBN/O to/TO/O be/VB/O $/$/O 4/CD/O billion/CD/O in/IN/O the/DT/O hole/NN/O ././O
Selling/VBG/O the/DT/O FHA/NNP/B-ORG 's/POS/O loan/NN/O portfolio/NN/O to/TO/O the/DT/O highest/JJS/O bidder/NN/O would/MD/O save/VB/O the/DT/O taxpayers/NNS/O untold/JJ/O billions/NNS/O in/IN/O future/JJ/O losses/NNS/O ././O
Some/DT/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG money/NN/O actually/RB/O does/VBZ/O trickle/VB/O down/RB/O to/TO/O the/DT/O poor/JJ/O ,/,/O and/CC/O zeroing/VBG/O out/RP/O housing/NN/O middlemen/NNS/O would/MD/O free/VB/O up/RP/O more/JJR/O money/NN/O for/IN/O public/JJ/O housing/NN/O tenants/NNS/O to/TO/O manage/VB/O and/CC/O even/VB/O own/JJ/O their/PRP$/O units/NNS/O ././O
The/DT/O rest/NN/O ought/MD/O to/TO/O be/VB/O used/VBN/O to/TO/O clean/VB/O out/RP/O drugs/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O neighbhorhoods/NNS/O ././O
Rival/JJ/O gangs/NNS/O have/VBP/O turned/VBN/O cities/NNS/O into/IN/O combat/NN/O zones/NNS/O ././O
Innocent/JJ/O bystanders/NNS/O often/RB/O are/VBP/O the/DT/O victims/NNS/O ././O
A/DT/O man/NN/O in/IN/O a/DT/O wheelchair/NN/O was/VBD/O gunned/VBN/O down/RB/O in/IN/O the/DT/O crossfire/NN/O of/IN/O a/DT/O Miami/NNP/B-GPE drug/NN/O battle/NN/O ././O
Decent/JJ/O life/NN/O in/IN/O the/DT/O inner/JJ/O cities/NNS/O wo/MD/O n't/RB/O be/VB/O restored/VBN/O unless/IN/O the/DT/O government/NN/O reclaims/VBZ/O the/DT/O streets/NNS/O from/IN/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O gangs/NNS/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O still/RB/O unclear/JJ/O whether/IN/O Secretary/NNP/O Kemp/NNP/B-PERSON wants/VBZ/O to/TO/O completely/RB/O overhaul/VB/O the/DT/O engine/NN/O room/NN/O at/IN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG or/CC/O just/RB/O tighten/VB/O a/DT/O few/JJ/O screws/NNS/O here/RB/O and/CC/O there/RB/O ././O
No/DT/O doubt/NN/O he/PRP/O believes/VBZ/O the/DT/O place/NN/O can/MD/O be/VB/O salvaged/VBN/O ././O
It/PRP/O 's/VBZ/O time/NN/O to/TO/O scrap/VB/O the/DT/O politically/RB/O infested/JJ/O spending/NN/O machine/NN/O HUD/NNP/B-ORG has/VBZ/O become/VB/O and/CC/O channel/VB/O the/DT/O resources/NNS/O into/IN/O the/DT/O drug/NN/O war/NN/O ././O
